<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Socially Motivated Self Control</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joanne</forename><surname>Stasiak</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Santa Barbara</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joy</forename><surname>Ham</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Temple University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chelsea</forename><surname>Helion</surname></persName>
							<email>chelsea.helion@temple.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Temple University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Psychology Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Temple University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19122</postCode>
									<settlement>Philadelphia</settlement>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Socially Motivated Self Control</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:55+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>self control</term>
					<term>social influence</term>
					<term>decision-making SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 3 Socially Motivated Self Control</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Exercising self control can be remarkably difficult. How much of this difficulty is because individuals are overemphasizing the role that the &quot;self&quot; needs to play in executing it? Across three studies (N = 248 and 10,233 observations), we examined whether construing a self control domain in terms of its social implications improved decision-making. We found that thinking about a specific relationship relevant to the self control domain improved decision-making relative to other relationships, that merely thinking about the social ramifications of one&apos;s actions in the self control domain improved decision-making, and that these effects were moderated by the extent to which individuals reported higher levels of relational obligation to those around them. Taken together, these studies suggest that when it comes to self control, turning one&apos;s focus away from the self may sometimes lead to more effective outcomes.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>On their 1967 album "Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band", The Beatles famously sang about getting by with a little help from their friends <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Lennon and McCartney, 1967)</ref>.</p><p>Given that the band would break up a mere three years later, it is perhaps unlikely that they took their own advice. However, the general idea that our social relationships with others play a key role in our life's outcomes has amassed a great deal of supporting evidence in sociological <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Gove et al., 1983)</ref>, psychological <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Fitzsimons and Finkel, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hofmann et al., 2015)</ref>, and economic <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Allen, 2000)</ref> research. The present research examines the extent to which mental representations of interpersonal relationships can serve as self-control resources. Successfully meeting one's long-term goals impacts not just the self, but also has an effect on the lives and outcomes of close others. It is possible that this may serve as an effective motivation to enact self-control behaviors that individuals typically struggle to implement. The present research tests this hypothesis directly.</p><p>The real or imagined presence of others has been identified as a powerful influence on cognition and behavior since the earliest days of experimental psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Triplett, 1898)</ref>.</p><p>There is reason to suspect that social influence may be of particular import when it comes to enacting self-control behaviors. For example, the mere presence of others can influence behavioral selection <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Schmitt et al., 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Triplett, 1898;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Zajonc and Sales, 1966)</ref>, being reminded of important others can improve and influence task performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Baldwin et al., 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Shah, 2003a)</ref>, and feeling that one is not meeting the goals that a close other has for them is associated with negative psychological outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Higgins, 1987)</ref>. Moreover, extant research in emotion regulation posits a key role for social relationships <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Reeck et al., 2016)</ref>, such that other individuals can help us regulate and adaptively appraise our emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Doré et al., 2017)</ref>. Taken together, this indicates that social relationships may play an important, yet potentially understudied, role in motivating effective self-control behaviors.</p><p>In the present research, we test two hypotheses: 1) that construing a self-control SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 4 domain in terms of its social implications will facilitate better decision-making, and 2) that this facilitation will be heightened for individuals who report a stronger sense of relational obligation to others. The first hypothesis was motivated by extant research in emotion and moral cognition that found that individuals are more successful at self-control when they are motivated by other-oriented emotions, like gratitude <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(DeSteno et al., 2010)</ref>. Additionally, the extent to which self-control behavior is moralized is flexible, and associated with the endorsement of group-oriented moral values <ref type="bibr">(Mooijman et al., 2018)</ref>. If other-oriented cognition improves self-control, and the socio-moral implications of traditional self-control domains (e.g., financial decision-making, dieting, academic performance) are malleable, then flexibly construing decision-making in terms of its impact on others may serve to motivate self-control decisions in those domains.</p><p>The second hypothesis is motivated by the literature on interpersonal relationships and goal pursuit. Interdependence Theory posits that close relationships have a more powerful impact on an individual's decisions and goal pursuit <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Van Lange and Rusbult, 2011)</ref>. For example, an individual that has difficulty saving money may find it easier to do so when thinking about how their partner might benefit from their having a larger retirement nest egg. Consistent with this theory, prior research has found that goal pursuit led to feelings of increased interpersonal closeness when relationship partners were more instrumental to achieving the specific goal <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Fitzsimons and Shah, 2008)</ref>, that perceived closeness to an individual moderates the extent to which their goals are adopted for the self <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Shah, 2003a)</ref>, and that individuals are more likely to act pro-socially when they have been primed to think about a close friendship <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Fitzsimons and Bargh, 2003)</ref>. Merely activating the construct of one's interpersonal relationship (e.g., "think about your best friend") can activate goals that are important to the activated relationship <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Fitzsimons and Bargh, 2003)</ref>, and this goal transference can improve performance in the relevant task domain (e.g., persisting at a difficult anagram task) <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Shah, 2003a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Shah, , 2003b</ref>. Thus, construing a self-control domain in terms of its social implications may be particularly effective for individuals who report SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 5 stronger feelings of obligation to their interpersonal relationships (i.e., relational obligation).</p><p>The present research operationalizes self-control behavior as the choice between tasks consistent with one's long-term goals and tasks that present short-term temptation. We examine this question in the context of time-allocation choices between a goal-relevant, effortful task and a goal-irrelevant, entertaining task. This approach is consistent with how many self-control decisions play out in real-life -the choice to go to the gym, finish that work project before the deadline, or study for an upcoming exam necessarily involves not using that time for more enjoyable or easier pursuits like watching television, scrolling through social media, or partying with friends. To draw a parallel to research in emotion regulation, we can think of time allocation decisions as a form of situation selection <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Gross, 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Gross, , 1999</ref>, or putting oneself in a situation that increases the likelihood that we will achieve the outcomes that we would prefer.</p><p>To our knowledge, this research is the first to examine the influence of interpersonal relationships on the decision to exercise self-control. Testing decision-making in the context of time allocation decisions affords us two lenses through which to examine relational influence: 1) whether it influences the likelihood of choosing the self control option over the short-term temptation option, and 2) the degree to which it does so. For example, if one were to decide how to allocate the next hour, choosing to study for fifty minutes and watch television for ten demands more self control than choosing to study for 31 minutes and watch television for 29. This approach allows us to better examine the relative strength of the effect of interpersonal relationships on self-control behavior.</p><p>The present research examines whether adopting a social construal of a self-regulation domain can facilitate self-control, orienting decision-making towards long-term goal attainment, and the extent to which this effect may be moderated by feelings of relational obligation. We test this across three studies, all operationalizing self-control decision-making in the context of time allocation. In our first study, we examine whether mentally representing a specific individual that one associates with a specific self-control domain, prior SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 6 to decision-making, increases the likelihood of exercising self-control. In our second study, we zoom out, and examine whether a more general construal of the self-control domain as one where others will be impacted by one's choices increases the likelihood of exercising self-control. Finally, in our last study, we examine the extent to which the association of an interpersonal relationship with a self-control domain is malleable, and how that flexibility may influence decision-making. Data, code, and materials for all studies are available at https://osf.io/qg8xw/?view_only=e037f040b35e4323af73b8e7caa5ad25.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head><p>Our goal in Study 1 was to examine whether mental representations of specific others can increase the likelihood that an individual will exercise self-control when making future time allocation decisions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Fifty participants (26 females, 22 males, 2 non-binary or do not wish to identify, M age = 30.68, SD age = 10.13) were recruited from Prolific (https://www.prolific.co) and paid $10/hour for their participation. This sample size was chosen on the basis of both previous studies that examined relational influences on regulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Shah, 2003a)</ref> and on financial resource constraints. Experimental procedures were approved by the university's Institutional Review Board for Human Subjects. All subjects provided informed consent. In this and all studies, participants completed questionnaires via the Qualtrics survey platform (https://www.qualtrics.com), and completed the decision-making task on Pavlovia (https://www.pavlovia.org).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task Design</head><p>This study used a within-subjects design. Participants were informed that they would be making a series of time allocation decisions regarding a twenty-minute period at the end of the study. They were informed that this time would be spent doing a combination of SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 7 learning about responsible financial decision-making (i.e., self-control) and playing a video-game (i.e., short-term temptation). We chose the financial domain as we posited that it would be the most relevant to individuals on a platform wherein they are being paid for study participation. To increase the individual-level desirability of each option, participants chose their preference between three video games (Tetris, PacMan, Pinball) and three areas of financial literacy (i.e., saving, investing, spending). Next, participants were instructed to type the names of three people: 1) the name of the person who has been most instrumental in their financial success (Financial relationship), 2) the name of the person who they hang out with the most socially (Social relationship), and 3) the name of a celebrity they really like (Celebrity). The celebrity condition was included as an experimental control in order to isolate the contribution of relational influences specifically from social influence more generally.</p><p>Prior to the start of the task, participants were informed that one of their chosen allocations would be selected at random, and that they would complete the tasks in accordance with their choice for the randomly-selected trial. This was done to ensure that participants were motivated to make choices that matched their actual preferences. The task consisted of 60 trials, divided into 12 blocks of 5 trials each. Prior to the start of each block, one of the three names was randomly presented for 4 seconds. Participants were instructed to imagine that the person whose name they saw was in the room with them for the duration of the upcoming trials. While presentation order was randomized, each name was programmed to appear four times throughout the task. Following the name presentation, participants made a series of 5 decisions (trials) in a row. One allocation consistently favored the self-control task (i.e., 11 or more minutes allocated to the financial literacy task and 9 or fewer minutes allocated to the videogame) and one allocation consistently favored the short-term temptation (i.e., 11 or more minutes allocated to the videogame and 9 or fewer minutes allocated to the financial literacy task). No allocations involved an even split for both activities, requiring participants to make a decision that favored one task over the SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 8 other. Each decision trial was presented for 6 seconds, during which participants used the keyboard to indicate a preference for one of the time allocations. A 2-second fixation cross preceded and followed each decision trial <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1</ref>). Immediately following completion of the decision-making task, participants answered a series of questions regarding their attitudes about the two activities (the video game and financial literacy tasks) and the nature of their relationships with the individuals that they selected. Participants were asked to indicate the extent to which they wanted to play the videogame and the extent to which they wanted to do the financial literacy task (both on seven-point scales from 1 = "Not at all" to 7 = "Extremely"). Upon completion of the decision-making task, participants were presented with a randomly selected trial and were told that, following questionnaires (see below), they would be splitting the last 20 minutes of the study between the two tasks according to the time allocation choice they had made on the randomly selected trial.</p><p>Relational Obligation. Participants were asked to evaluate four dimensionsrelationship closeness, relationship duration, moral obligation, and concern over letting-down -for each of the three name prime relationships from the behavioral task.</p><p>Participants indicated how close they felt to each of the three people (on a scale of 1 = "Not close at all" to 7 = "Extremely close"), the duration of the relationship (i.e., "How long have you known this person?" (for financial and social relationships) and "How long have you known of this person?" (for the celebrity)) on a scale from 1 = "0 -3 months" to 7 = "10 or more years". They also indicated the extent to which they feel a sense of moral obligation to each person (on a scale of 1 = "Not at all" to 7 = "Extremely"), and how bad it would feel to let that person down (1 = "Not at all" to 7 = "Extremely"). In this and all studies, following the decision-making task, participants then completed a battery of individual difference measures meant to assess self-regulation tendencies across multiple domains. See Supplementary materials for summary statistics for these measures across all studies.</p><p>While participants were provided with study links to complete the video game or the financial tasks at the end of the study, they were not required to do the randomly selected twenty minute allocation. Participants were debriefed on this deception, and then paid for their participation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 10</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>On average, participants completed 59 (out of 60) trials, (SD = 2.04). Confirming that our two tasks differed in terms of their desirability, we found that individuals wanted to play the videogame (M = 5.38, SD = 1.43) more than they wanted to complete the financial literacy task (M = 3.54, SD = 1.93), t(49) = 4.81, 95% CI:(1.07, 2.61). We found that across all three conditions, moral obligation and concern about letting the individual down were positively and significantly correlated (Financial: r = .51, p &lt; .001; Social: r = .71, p &lt; .001; Celebrity: r = .46, p &lt; .001). We combined these variables to create a composite variable termed relational obligation <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 1)</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social relationships influence self-control decisions</head><p>We first examined whether the relational regulation manipulation influenced general choice behavior. We ran a generalized linear mixed-effects model using the "glmer" function implemented in the lme4 package <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bates et al., 2015)</ref> in R. The dependent variable was whether their choice on a given trial favored the videogame (coded as 1) or the financial literacy task (coded as 0). The independent variable was the relational regulation condition (within subjects, 3: Finance Relationship, Social Relationship, Celebrity), and we included a random intercept for participant.</p><p>Using a likelihood ratio test <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Winter, 2013)</ref>, we found that the model which included SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 11 the main effect of relational regulation condition fit the data significantly better (AIC = 2629.2, BIC = 2653.1) than the random-effects only model (AIC = 2780.3, BIC = 2792.3), χ 2 (2) = 155.13, p &lt; .001. We found a significant relationship between relational regulation condition and choice behavior, such that individuals were more likely to choose time allocations that favored the financial literacy task in financial relationship condition relative  <ref type="figure">(Figure 2a</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social relationships influence the amount of time allocated to the self-control task</head><p>We next examined whether the relational regulation manipulation influenced time allocation choices. We ran a linear mixed-effects model using the "lmer" function implemented in the lme4 package. The dependent variable was the difference (in minutes) between the time allocated to the financial literacy task relative to the videogame for the SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 12 participant's chosen option per trial. Positive numbers reflect more time allocated to the financial literacy task relative to the videogame. The independent variables were relational regulation condition (within subjects, 3: Finance Relationship, Social Relationship, Celebrity), and we included a random intercept for participant.</p><p>We found that the model which included the main effect of relational regulation condition fit the data significantly better (AIC = 21574, BIC = 21604) than the random-effects only model (AIC = 21699, BIC = 21717), χ 2 (2) = 128.82, p &lt; .001. We found a significant relationship between relational regulatory condition and time allocation, such that individuals were more likely to allocate more time for the financial literacy task in 12, se = .34, t = .35, p = .72) ( <ref type="figure">Figure 2b</ref>).</p><p>The results of study 1 provide promising initial evidence that social construal successfully facilitates self-control decision-making. However, two meaningful considerations remain. First, it is possible that the idiosyncratic relationships that participants reported SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 13 acted as more specific domain primes (i.e., it is possible that someone could have thought of their accountant as their financial relationship), rather than reflecting any genuine relational influence. Second, it is possible that these results may have been due to feelings of experimental demand. To address these possibilities, our next study examines social construal of a self-control domain more generally, and examines the extent to which social desirability -an individual difference associated with sensitivity to experimental demand <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Nederhof, 1985)</ref> -moderates any observed effects. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> . Interaction between relational condition and relational obligation. There was a significant interaction between relational condition and relational obligation, such that higher levels of relational obligation were associated with a increased time allocations in the financial relationship condition relative to the social and celebrity conditions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>The aim of study 2 was to examine whether considering social obligation in the context of a self-regulation domain more generally would facilitate regulatory behavior. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task Design</head><p>This was a between-subjects design, and following consent, participants were randomly assigned to either the control (n = 49) or social regulation (n = 50) condition. Participants in the social regulation condition were given the following prompt (displayed for 60 seconds):</p><p>"Please take a minute to think about how other people in your life would benefit from your meeting your financial goals."</p><p>Participants in the control condition were not given a pre-task relational prompt.</p><p>Participants then completed the same task as in studies 1-2, but consisting of 25 trials.</p><p>Immediately following completion of the decision-making task, participants answered a series of questions regarding their attitudes about the two activities (the video game and financial literacy tasks) and their financial goals more broadly. Participants were asked to indicate the extent to which they wanted to play the videogame and the extent to which they wanted to do the financial literacy task (both on seven-point scales from 1="Not at all" to 7 = "Extremely"). They also reported whether financial success was important to them (1="Not at all important" to 7 = "Extremely important").</p><p>Relational Obligation. Given that we were not having them generate a specific target, we modified the relational assessment questions to ask about their social motivation in the financial domain more generally (i.e., the extent to which they work to achieve their financial goals for themselves versus for others; 1 = "Entirely for myself" to 7 = "Entirely for others") (reverse-coded). They also reported the extent to which they feel a moral obligation SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 15 to others to achieve their financial goals (1 = "Not at all" to 7 = "Extremely"). These two measures were significantly correlated, r(97) = .39, p &lt; .001, and were combined into a measure of relational obligation. In addition, to more directly examine any association between demand and prior results, we also included the Social Desirability Scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Fischer and Fick, 1993)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>We again found that individuals wanted to play the videogame (M = 4.91, SD = 1.62) more than they wanted to complete the financial literacy task (M = 3.74, SD = 1.87), t(98) = 4.07, 95% CI:(.60, 1.74)). There were no differences in these measures across study conditions. Participants completed 24.17 trials on average (SD = 1.29). There were no significant differences in the task preference or relational obligation measures reported across conditions <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">(Table 2)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relational obligation moderates the effect of social construal on self-control decision-making</head><p>We first examined whether the social construal manipulation influenced general choice behavior in individuals who reported higher levels of relational obligation. We ran a generalized linear mixed-effects model: the dependent variable was whether their choice on a given trial favored the videogame (coded as 1) or the financial literacy task (coded as 0).</p><p>The independent variables were social construal condition (2: control, social construal), reported relational obligation in the financial domain (mean-centered), and their interaction, including a random intercept for participant. We found that the model which included the interaction term between condition and relational obligation fit the data significantly better (AIC = 1977.5, BIC = 2006.4) than a main-effects only model <ref type="bibr">(AIC = 1980</ref><ref type="bibr">.4, BIC = 2003</ref>.5), χ 2 (1) = 4.85, p = .028. This was due to a significant positive relationship between relational obligation and the likelihood of selecting the financial literacy task in the social SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 16 regulation condition (b = 1.19, se = 0.33, z = 3.65, OR = 3.28, p &lt; 0.001, 95%CI : .11, 1.99),</p><p>but not in the control condition (b = .14, se = .35, z = .40, OR = 1.15, p = 0.69) ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3a)</ref>. Relational obligation moderates the effect of social construal on the amount of time allocated to the self-control task</p><p>We next examined whether the social regulation manipulation influenced time allocation choices in individuals who were socially motivated in the financial domain. The dependent variable was whether the difference (in minutes) between the time allocated to the financial literacy task relative to the videogame for the participant's chosen option per trial. Positive numbers reflect more time allocated to the financial literacy task relative to the videogame. The independent variables were social construal condition (2: control, social construal), reported relational obligation (mean-centered), and their interaction. We found that the model which included the interaction term fit the data marginally better (AIC = 17556, BIC = 17591) than a main-effects only model (AIC = 17557, BIC = 17586), χ 2 (1) = 3.18, p = .074. A simple slopes analysis indicated that this interaction was due to a significantly positive association between relational obligation and selecting more time  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social desirability is positively associated with self-control decision-making.</head><p>We found a significant positive relationship between social desirability and both choice behavior (b = .24, se = .10, z = 2.5, OR = 1.27, p = .01, Wald 95%CI:(.05, .43), OR 95% CI:</p><p>(1.05, 1.54) and time allocation (b = .66, se = .27, t = 2.46, p = .015, Wald 95%CI:(.13, 1.19)). When this variable was included as a covariate in the interaction model between condition and social motivation predicting binary choice, the interaction continued to be a significant predictor: b = .98, se = .47, z = 2.06, OR = 2.34, p = .039, Wald 95%CI:(.05, 1.90), OR 95% CI: (1.05, 5.21). When this variable was included as a covariate in the interaction model between condition and social motivation predicting time allocation, SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 18 the interaction was no longer a marginally significant predictor: b = 2.09, se = 1.27, t = 1.64, p = .10, Wald 95%CI:(−.40, 4.57).</p><p>Taken together, the results of studies 1 and 2 indicate that social relationships, both in concrete and abstract terms, can have a meaningful influence on the extent to which an individual chooses to engage in self-control behavior. We found that these effects were moderately robust to sensitivity to experimenter demand (as indexed by individual differences in social desirability) when it came to actual choice behavior, but not in the amount of time allocated to each task.</p><p>In our final study, we extend the results of studies 1 and 2. In study 1, it is possible that by asking participants to think about the relationships that were most relevant to the self-control and social domains, it biased the retrieval process through which individuals selected a specific relationship. In study 3, we examine whether the social construal manipulation in study 2 can be applied to any close relationship in an individual's life, and whether that can influence self-control behavior. That is, we are interested in whether socially motivated self-control is dependent on how one thinks about a specific person.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head><p>In this study, participants were prompted to first think of two unique individuals in their lives who they are close to. Then, participants were instructed to think about how one of the individuals would benefit from the participant making good financial choices, and how the other individual would benefit from the participant prioritizing their social interactions with that individual. By having participants first generate two close individuals, and then later framing the relationships as domain-specific or not, we are able to examine the domain specificity of socially motivated self control. If we observe similar effects as found in studies 1 and 2, this would suggest that it is less important who one thinks of when making regulatory decisions, but rather how the relationship is construed at the point of regulation. If we do not observe similar effects, it would instead suggest that the initial retrieval of specific relationships constrains their regulatory utility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Ninety-nine (52 female, 47 male, 0 Nonbinary or do not wish to identify, M age = 36.83, SD age = 12.7) individuals were recruited from Prolific, and paid $10/hr for their participation. This sample size was chosen on the basis of this being a potentially weaker manipulation than the similar within-subjects design of Study 1 and on financial resource constraints.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task Design</head><p>As in studies 1 and 2, participants were told that they would be making decisions between two time allocations of 20 minutes. In this study, they were choosing between watching YouTube videos and the financial literacy task. We used videos rather than videogames for this study to increase generalizability, as watching videos may be a more popular and generally enjoyable activity than playing video games. Participants could select what type of videos (comedy videos, gaming videos, or music videos) and which finance tips (saving, investing, or spending tips) they would like to make decisions between.</p><p>Next, participants were instructed to type the names of two different people whom they are close to. Each name the participants typed was randomly assigned to either a 'financial-construal' or 'social-construal' condition. For the name assigned to the financial-construal condition, participants were prompted to think about two specific ways that person would benefit from [the participant] making good financial choices. To increase the salience of the relationship construals, participants were then instructed to type out keywords that represented these two benefits. For the name assigned to the social-construal condition, the participant was prompted to think about two specific ways that person would benefit from [the participant] spending more time with them, and were again instructed to type out these benefits in short keywords.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 20</head><p>The task consisted of 50 trials, divided into 10 blocks of 5 trials each. Prior to the start of each block, one of the two names was randomly presented for 4 seconds. While presentation order was randomized, each name was programmed to appear 5 times throughout the task. The trial structure was identical to that used in Studies 1 and 2; each trial consisted of two choices of time allocations, one which favored the videos and one which favored the finance tips.</p><p>Goal Association and Relational Obligation. Immediately after the decision-making task, we collected a measure of goal association for each individual generated by the participant. Goal association was operationalized by asking the extent to which participants associate each name with both financial goals and social goals (on a scale of 1 = "Not at all", to 7 = "Completely"). We also collected the same relational measures as in study 1 (closeness, duration, moral obligation, concern with letting down), social motivation, and the battery of self-regulation measures outlined in study 1. We found that moral obligation and concern about letting down were again significantly correlated with one another(r = .62, p &lt; .001), and we again combined these variables to create a composite variable termed relational obligation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>We examined the effect of our manipulation (social vs. finance construal) on the relationships participants initially identified. The manipulation was randomly assigned and completed after participants identified two close individuals. We found a marginal difference differences on the relational assessments of closeness, relationship duration, relational obligation, and desire to make proud <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">(Table 3)</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relational obligation moderates the relationship between relational construal and the likelihood of making self-control decisions</head><p>We first examined whether the social regulation manipulation influenced general choice behavior based on feelings of relational obligation. We ran a generalized linear mixed-effects model: the dependent variable was whether their choice on a given trial favored the financial task (coded as 1) or the video task (coded as 0). The independent variables were Social Regulation Condition (2: Finance construal, Social construal), relational obligation (mean-centered), and their interaction, including a random intercept for participant. Using a likelihood ratio test, we found that the model which included the interaction term between relational obligation and condition fit the data significantly better (AIC = 4666.1, BIC = 4698.6) than a main-effects only model (AIC = 4712.5, BIC = 4731.9), χ 2 (2) = 50.33, p &lt; .001. A simple slopes analysis indicated that relational SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 22 obligation had a stronger effect in the financial construal condition (b = .62, se = .09, z = 6.68, OR = 1.85, p &lt; .001) as compared to the social construal condition (b = .44, se = .08, z = 5.61, OR = 1.55, p &lt; .001) ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4a</ref>).</p><p>Relational obligation moderates the relationship between relational construal and the amount of time allocated to the self-control task</p><p>We next examined whether the social regulation manipulation influenced time allocation choices in individuals who were socially motivated in the financial domain. The dependent variable was whether the difference (in minutes) between the time allocated to the financial literacy task relative to the videogame for the participant's chosen option per trial. Positive numbers reflect more time allocated to the financial literacy task relative to the videogame. The independent variables were Social Regulation Condition (2: Finance construal, Social construal), relational obligation (mean-centered), and their interaction, including a random intercept for participant.</p><p>Using a likelihood ratio test, we found that the model which included the interaction term between relational obligation and condition fit the data significantly better (AIC = 37487, BIC = 37526) than the main-effects only model (AIC = 37500, BIC = 37532), χ 2 (1) = 15.15, p &lt; .001.) A simple slopes analysis indicated that this was due to relational obligation having a stronger positive effect in the financial construal condition (b = 2.35, se = .24, t = 9.74) as compared to the social construal condition (b = 1.18, se = .23, t = 5.08) <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">(Figure 4b</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social desirability is positively associated with self-control decision-making</head><p>We again found a significant positive relationship between social desirability and both choice behavior (b = .28, se = .08, z = 3.59, OR = 1.33, p &lt; .001, Wald 95%CI:(.13, .44), OR 95% CI: (1.14, 1.55)) and time allocation (b = .72, se = .19, t = 3.78, p &lt; .001, Wald 95%CI:(.35, 1.09)). When this variable was included as a covariate in the interaction model between construal condition and relational obligation predicting binary choice, the SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 23 interaction continued to be a significant predictor: b = .17, se = .08, z = 2.21, OR = 1.19, p = .027, Wald 95%CI:(.02, .33), OR 95% CI: (1.02, 1.39). When this variable was included as a covariate in the interaction model between construal condition and relational obligation predicting time allocation, the interaction was no longer a significant predictor: b = .36, se = .29, t = 1.24, p = .21, Wald 95%CI:(−.21, .93). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>The present research found that participants who felt a stronger sense of relational obligation were better at exercising self-control when the choice was framed as one with social implications. This was the case when they thought of specific relationships that they associated with the self-control domain, when they were tasked with re-framing the SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 24 self-control domain as one that affected others in general, and when they were encouraged to consider how their choices in the self-control domain would influence a specific relationship in their lives. Although individuals overall did not want to complete the self-control task, those who reported stronger feelings of relational obligation were able to marshal these feelings in order to make decisions that favored long-term goals over short-term interests.</p><p>These results both support and extend existing work on the impact of social influences on self-control. Consistent with earlier research, we found that invoking the mental representations of one's interpersonal relationships can motivate relational and goal-relevant behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Fitzsimons and Bargh, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Fitzsimons and Shah, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Shah, 2003a</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Shah, , 2003b</ref>.</p><p>Uniquely, this work is the first to examine how our representations of others can inform the decision to exercise self-control in and of itself . We found that mentally representing the self-control domain in terms of its implications for others increases the likelihood that individuals put themselves in future situations that will promote long-term goal achievement. This is notable given prior research on self-control, which finds that situational selection is both highly effective <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Milyavskaya et al., 2021)</ref> and is able to be implemented successfully across the lifespan <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Livingstone and Isaacowitz, 2021)</ref>. Taken together, this indicates that identifying factors that facilitate adaptive situation selection may meaningfully help individuals reach their long-term goals.</p><p>In addition, this research focuses on a somewhat realistic self-control dilemmazero-sum time allocation. We found that individuals who felt a stronger sense of relational obligation to others were not only more likely to select situations that favored long-term goals over short-term rewards (i.e., when the time split more strongly favored the self-control domain), but also tended to make these decisions when the time designated for the two activities were notably different (i.e., when the time split was more asymmetric). It is worth noting that we found both of these effects (choice behavior and time allocation) to be strongly associated with social desirability. In the case of these studies, consideration about what others may think and its influence on behavior is perhaps both a limitation and SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 25 a strength. That is, it is likely that a social construal of self-control would most effectively influence decision-making for individuals who are more strongly influenced by the real or imagined desires of others.</p><p>The present research suggests that social construal of self control represents a motivational process. While relational obligation moderated the effect of the social construal, when social framing was absent (i.e., the control conditions in studies 2 and 3), relational obligation had no effect on self-control choice or time-allocation. The impact of an individual's relational obligation is dependent on the activation of a motivating social construal. This suggests that the social construal manipulation potentially activates a motivational construct that, being intrinsically valued differently by different individuals, is either more or less effective in guiding behavior. Future research should examine the extent to which construing other typically "non-social" domains as being socially relevant (e.g., memory retrieval, learning) may motivate behavior.</p><p>Future Directions &amp; Limitations. This research raises a number of questions that can be addressed in future work. First and foremost, we have approached socially motivated self-control as having a positive influence on regulatory decision-making, but it is also possible that its impact could be negative for an individuals' long-term self-efficacy and ability to set independent goals. Second, it is possible that the effect could be stronger for definitionally interpersonal goals, or goals that directly impact the quality and longevity of the interpersonal relationship itself <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Fitzsimons and Bargh, 2003)</ref>. Additionally, the influence of socially motivated self-control may change across the lifespan, given that individuals go through different developmental stages wherein they are more or less dependent upon others <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Moretti and Higgins, 1999)</ref> and value others' opinions more <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Somerville et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Finally, the influence of social construal of self-regulation on self-control is likely to vary across cultures based on cultural differences in self-construal <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Gardner et al., 1999)</ref>.</p><p>Exercising self-control can be remarkably difficult. Whether it's waiting for the second marshmallow, getting up to go to the gym, or not immediately spending that tax return, SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 26 acting in a way that privileges long-term goals over short-term temptation can sometimes feel impossible. This research indicates that remembering the potential impact of our self-control choices on the lives of those around us may temper this difficulty. Or, put differently, relying on a little help from our friends may help us to navigate that long and winding road a bit better.</p><p>DOSPERT, IRI, TFEQ, AES, and GES as predictors in our generalized linear mixed effects model predicting binary self-control choice. None of the individual difference measures had significant effects on binary self-control choice, and we retained a significant interaction between the relational regulation condition and relational obligation (b = −0.3, se = 0.13, t = 2.29, p = 0.02). Additionally, we compared our interaction model with (AIC = 2616.1, BIC = 2705.9) and without (AIC = 2611.8, BIC = 2653.8) the self-regulation measures, using a likelihood-ratio test, and found that the degree to which they explain the data does not significantly differ (χ 2 = 11.73, p = 0.16). Second, we included all self-regulation measures in our linear mixed effects model predicting time-allocation choices. None of the self-regulation measures predicted choice behavior, and we retained our interaction (b = −1.42, se = 0.42, t = 3.42, p = 0.0006). We compared the models with (AIC = 21552, BIC = 21648) and without the self-regulation measures (AIC = 21548, BIC = 21596), using a likelihood ratio test, and found that inclusion of individual differences did not explain more variance in time-allocation choices (χ 2 = 11.62, p = 0.17).</p><p>Third, we ran a generalized linear mixed effect model predicting binary self-control choice with only self-regulation measures as the predictors, and found no significant predictors of self-control choice. Finally, we ran a linear mixed effect model predicting time-allocation, which included only the self-regulation measures as predictors, and found that no measure predicted time-allocation choices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>In Study 2, we detected a significant interaction between social construal and relational obligation predicting binary choice and time-allocation, but this interaction was not significant for time-allocation when social desirability was included in the model. When self-regulation measures were included in the generalized linear mixed effect model predicting binary self-control choice, general self-efficacy predicted fewer self-control choices (b = −0.91, se = 0.46, t = 1.99, p = 0.05). We also retained the interaction between social SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 32 construal and relational obligation (b = 1.1, se = 0.46, t = 2.38, p = 0.017) and the main effect of social desirability (b = 0.25, se = 0.12, t = 2.11, p = 0.03). When self-regulation measures were included in the linear mixed effects model predicting time-allocation, general self-efficacy predicted less self-control related time-allocation (b = −3.17, se = 1.32, t = 2.4, p = 0.02). The main effect of social desirability was only marginally significant (b = 0.56, se = 0.33, p = 0.09), and the interaction became marginally significant (b = 2.42, se = 1.28, t = 1.89, p = 0.06). We then ran a model predicting time-allocation with the interaction between social construal and relational obligation, social desirability, and general self-efficacy as the main predictors with participant as a random intercept. We found that the interaction between social construal and relational obligation predicted greater time-allocation to self-control behaviors, such that higher levels of relational obligation moderated the effect of the social construal condition (b = 2.54, se = 1.26, t = 2.01, p = 0.05). Social desirability predicted greater time-allocation SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 33 to self-control behaviors (b = 0.66, se = 0.29, t = 2.3, p = 0.02), and general self-efficacy predicted less time-allocation to self-control behaviors (b = −2.01, se = 0.93, t = 2.16, p = 0.03). The model including general self-efficacy (AIC = 17552, BIC = 17599) explained significantly more variance than the model including only the interaction and social desirability (AIC = 17555, BIC = 17596), χ 2 = 4.87, p = 0.03. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head><p>In Study 3, we found that an interaction between relational regulation condition and relational obligation, moderated by social desirability, predicted binary self-control choice.</p><p>Time-allocation was predicted by social desirability, and main effects of relation regulation and relational obligation, but there was no interaction. When self-regulation measures were included in the generalized linear mixed effect model predicting binary self-control choice, SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 34 we retained the interaction and social desirability as a moderator, and IRI predicted fewer self-control choices (b = −0.64, se = 0.31, t = 2.08, p = 0.04). However, when we ran the model with the initial predictors and IRI only, IRI was no longer significant. Additionally, the model including IRI (AIC = 4658.9, BIC = 4697.4) did not explain more variance than the initial model (AIC = 4658.5, 4697.4), χ 2 = 1.55, p = 0.21. When self-regulation measures were included in the linear mixed-effects model predicting time allocation, we retained main effects of social regulation condition, relational obligation, and social desirability, and IRI predicted less time allocated to self-control behaviors (b = −1.84, se = 0.75, t = 2.44, p = 0.02). We then ran a model predicting time-allocation with the interaction between social regulation and relational obligation, main effect of social desirability, and main effect of interpersonal reactivity. We retained all the previous main effects including a significant effect of IRI (b = 1.36, se = 0.66, t = 2.05, p = 0.04).</p><p>Additionally, the model including IRI (AIC = 36584, BIC = 36636) explained more variance than the model without IRI (AIC = 36586, 36632), χ 2 = 4.27, p = 0.04.</p><p>SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 35 </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Trial structure for the decision-making task in Study 1. After selecting their preferred game type and finance tips, participants identified three individuals: 1) the person they most associated with their financial goals, 2) the person they most associated with their social goals, and 3) a celebrity (social control condition). Participants completed 60 trials of time allocation selections. Each allocation favored one task over the other. SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 9</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>to the social relationship condition, (b = −1.47, se = .12, OR = .23, z = 11.85, Wald 95% CI:(−1.72, −1.23), 95% OR CI:(.18, .29)), and relative to the celebrity control condition (b = −.97, se = .12, z = 8.10, OR = .38, Wald 95% CI:(−1.20, −.73), 95% OR CI:(.30, .48)). Individuals were also more likely to choose time allocations that favored the financial literacy task in the celebrity control condition relative to the social relationship condition (b = −.50, se = .12, z = 4.13, OR = .60, Wald 95% CI:(−.74, −.26), OR 95% CI:(.47, .77)). Relational obligation moderates the effect of social relationships on self-control decisions. We found a significant interaction between relational obligation, relational target, and the likelihood of selecting the financial literacy task (Interaction model = AIC: 2611.8, BIC: 2653.8; relative to main-effects model: χ 2 (3) = 23.33, p &lt; .001). A simple-slopes analysis indicated that this was due to a significant negative relationship between relational obligation and relational regulation target for the social relationship (b = −.41, se = .09, OR = .66, z = 4.53, p &lt; .001) and celebrity condition (b = −.17, se = .07, z = 2.45, OR = .84, p = .01), but not in the financial relationship condition (b = −.10, se = .11, z = .94, OR = .90, p = .35)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>the financial relationship condition relative to the social relationship condition,(b = −4.63,   se = .41, t(2898.23) = 11.27, Wald 95% CI:(−5.43, −3.82)), and relative to the celebrity control condition (b = −3.08, se = .41, t(2898.14) = 7.49, Wald 95% CI:(2.28, 3.89)).Individuals were also more likely to choose time allocations that favored the financial literacy task in the celebrity control condition relative to the social relationship condition (b = 1.55, se = .41, t(2898.16) = 3.77, Wald 95% CI:(.74, 2.35)).Relational obligation moderates the effect of social relationships on the amount of time allocated to the self-control task. We also found a significant interaction between relational obligation, relational target, and time allocation decisions(Interaction model: AIC = 21548, BIC = 21596; relative to main-effects model: χ 2 (3) = 31.97, p &lt; .001). Simple slopes analysis again indicated that this was due to a significant negative relationship between relational obligation and relational regulation target for the social relationship (b = −1.34, se = .27, t = 5.04, p &lt; .001) and celebrity condition (b = −.70, se = .23, t = 3.02, p &lt; .001), but not in the financial relationship condition (b = .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>financial literacy task in the social regulation condition, b = 2.81, se = .84, SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 17 t = 3.34, p &lt; .001, but not in the control condition, b = .56, se = .96, t = .59, p = .56(Figure 3b).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Relationship between social motivation, social regulation, and the decision-making task. a.There was a significant positive association between social motivation and likelihood of selecting the financial literacy task in the social regulation condition. b. There was a significantly positive association between social motivation and time allocated to the financial literacy task in the social regulation condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>between the extent to which the participant associated the individual with the finance construal (M = 4.91, SD = 1.58) with financial goals as compared to the individual associated with the social construal (M = 4.35, SD = 1.76), t(98) = 1.76, p = .081 95% CI:[−.048, .85]. We found a significant difference between the extent to which the participant associated the individual with the finance construal (M = 4.91, SD = 1.58) with social goals as compared to the individual associated with the social construal SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 21 (M = 5.35, SD = 1.46), t(98) = 2.54, p = .012 95% CI:[−.097, −.79]. There were no</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Relationship between relational construal, relational obligation, and the decision-making task. a.There was a significant positive association between relational obligation and likelihood of selecting the financial literacy task in the financial construal condition. b. There was a significantly positive association between relational obligation and time allocated to the financial literacy task in the financial construal condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Relationship Assessment Measures for Study 1, Split by Condition</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Relationship Assessment Measures</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Item</cell><cell cols="2">Finance M(SD) Social M(SD)</cell><cell>Celebrity M(SD)</cell></row><row><cell>Closeness</cell><cell>5.63(1.38)</cell><cell>6.14(1.11)</cell><cell>2.39(1.63)</cell></row><row><cell>Relationship duration</cell><cell>6.24(1.13)</cell><cell>5.47(1.36)</cell><cell>4.88(2.08)</cell></row><row><cell>Relational obligation</cell><cell>5.84(1.02)</cell><cell>5.71(1.22)</cell><cell>2.95(1.55)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 14MethodOne hundred participants were recruited from Prolific (https://www.prolific.co) and paid $10/hour for their participation. One participant failed to complete the protocol, leaving us with a final sample of 99 participants (42 females, 55 males, 2 Nonbinary or do not wish to identify, M age = 35.37, SD age = 11.78). This sample size was chosen on the basis of financial resource constraints.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Goal Assessment Measures for Study 2, Split by Condition</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Goal Assessment Measures</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Item</cell><cell cols="2">Social Regulation M(SD) Control M(SD)</cell><cell>M Diff.</cell></row><row><cell>Want to do videogame</cell><cell>4.82(1.76)</cell><cell>5.00(1.49)</cell><cell>.18</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Want to do finance task 3.82(1.91)</cell><cell>3.65(1.84)</cell><cell>.17</cell></row><row><cell>Finance Importance</cell><cell>5.46(1.33)</cell><cell>5.49(1.08)</cell><cell>.03</cell></row><row><cell>Moral Obligation</cell><cell>4.48(1.71)</cell><cell>4.53(1.61)</cell><cell>.05</cell></row><row><cell>Social Motivation</cell><cell>3.42(1.53)</cell><cell>3.57(1.62)</cell><cell>.15</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Relationship Assessment Measures for Study 3</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Relationship Assessment Measures</cell></row><row><cell>Item</cell><cell>Finance</cell><cell>Social</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Construal</cell><cell>Construal</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>M(SD)</cell><cell>M(SD)</cell></row><row><cell>Closeness</cell><cell cols="2">6.17(0.84) 6.13(0.95)</cell></row><row><cell>Relationship Duration</cell><cell>6.20(.99)</cell><cell>6.24(1.03)</cell></row><row><cell>Relational Obligation</cell><cell cols="2">5.91(1.07) 5.93(1.11)</cell></row><row><cell>Desire to Make Proud</cell><cell cols="2">6.10(1.16) 6.07(1.29)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table A1</head><label>A1</label><figDesc>Self-Regulation Measures for Study 1, Split by Condition</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Self Regulation Measures</cell></row><row><cell>Item</cell><cell>M(SD)</cell></row><row><cell>BIS Total</cell><cell>88.46(18.39)</cell></row><row><cell>General Self-Efficacy</cell><cell>29.74(5.30)</cell></row><row><cell>IRI</cell><cell>93.92(11.96)</cell></row><row><cell>CFC</cell><cell>40.1(9.36)</cell></row><row><cell>DOSPERT</cell><cell>99.06(21.68)</cell></row><row><cell>DOSPERT-Social</cell><cell>27.7(5.03)</cell></row><row><cell>DERS</cell><cell>80.06(22.7)</cell></row><row><cell>Academic Self-Efficacy</cell><cell>85.24(19.82)</cell></row><row><cell>Three Factor Eating</cell><cell>42.54(8.35)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table A2</head><label>A2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Self-Regulation Measures for Study 2, Split by Condition</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Self Regulation Measures</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Item</cell><cell cols="2">Social Regulation M(SD) Control M(SD)</cell><cell>M Diff.</cell></row><row><cell>BIS Total</cell><cell>81.32(14.0)</cell><cell>85.28(15.9)</cell><cell>3.96</cell></row><row><cell>General Self-Efficacy</cell><cell>30.08(4.86)</cell><cell>30.28(5.24)</cell><cell>.20</cell></row><row><cell>IRI</cell><cell>96.82(13.3)</cell><cell>96.08(12.2)</cell><cell>.74</cell></row><row><cell>CFC</cell><cell>42.04(1.71)</cell><cell>39.82(1.61)</cell><cell>.05</cell></row><row><cell>DOSPERT</cell><cell>92.36(20.2)</cell><cell>93.53(20.6)</cell><cell>1.17</cell></row><row><cell>DOSPERT-Social</cell><cell>26.56(5.10)</cell><cell>26.73(4.95)</cell><cell>.17</cell></row><row><cell>DERS</cell><cell>71.96(21.7)</cell><cell>78.79(21.0)</cell><cell>6.83</cell></row><row><cell>Academic Self-Efficacy</cell><cell>90.58(15.9)</cell><cell>84.47(17.9)</cell><cell>6.11</cell></row><row><cell>Three Factor Eating</cell><cell>48.62(7.71)</cell><cell>49.86(8.14)</cell><cell>1.24</cell></row><row><cell>Social Desirability</cell><cell>6.04(3.35)</cell><cell>5.63(3.08)</cell><cell>.41</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table A3</head><label>A3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Self-Regulation Measures for Study 3</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Self Regulation Measures</cell></row><row><cell>Item</cell><cell>M(SD)</cell></row><row><cell>BIS Total</cell><cell>78.59(17.97)</cell></row><row><cell>General Self-Efficacy</cell><cell>31.40(5.40)</cell></row><row><cell>IRI</cell><cell>95.29(14.58)</cell></row><row><cell>CFC</cell><cell>41.92(9.93)</cell></row><row><cell>DOSPERT</cell><cell>86.52(20.05)</cell></row><row><cell>DOSPERT-Social</cell><cell>26.29(5.61)</cell></row><row><cell>DERS</cell><cell>71.54(22.67)</cell></row><row><cell>Academic Self-Efficacy</cell><cell>89.39(17.53)</cell></row><row><cell>Three Factor Eating</cell><cell>36.25(9.31)</cell></row><row><cell>Social Desirability</cell><cell>6.40(3.39)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Materials</head><p>Across all three studies we collected measures of individual differences in self-regulation.</p><p>These included the Barratt Impulsiveness Scale (BIS), the Difficulty with Emotion Regulation Scale (DERS), the Considerations of Future Consequences Scale (CFC), the Domain Specific Risk-Taking Scale (DOSPERT), the Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI), the Three-Factor Eating Questionnaire (TFEQ), and indications of both academic (AES) and general self-efficacy (GES). In the supplementary analyses we included these measures as predictors in our models to address three questions:</p><p>1. Are our tasks recruiting domain-general or non-social self-control processes, independent of our social manipulation? 2. Are our observed social self-regulation effects retained when we account for individual differences in self-control?</p><p>3. Is social self-regulation, when compared to individual differences, a stronger predictor of self-control behavior in our tasks?</p><p>To answer these questions, within each study we included self-regulation measures in our models predicting binary self-control choice and time-allocation choice, and conduct model comparisons to determine whether more variance is explained with or without inclusion of individual differences. Additionally, we tested models including only the self-regulation measures as predictors, predicting either binary self-control choice or time-allocation choice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head><p>In Study 1 we detected a significant interaction between the relational regulation condition and self-reported relational obligation, both for predicting binary self-control choices and time allocation self-control choices. First, we included the BIS, DERS, CFC,</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social networks and self-employment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of socio-economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="487" to="501" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Priming relationship schemas: My advisor and the pope are watching me from the back of my mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Carrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Lopez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="454" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mächler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bolker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18637/jss.v067.i01</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.18637/jss.v067.i01" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Desteno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Bartlett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Dickens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gratitude as moral sentiment: Emotion-guided cooperation in economic exchange</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">289</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Helping others regulate emotion predicts increased regulation of one&apos;s own emotions and decreased symptoms of depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Doré</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Burr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Picard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Ochsner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="729" to="739" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring social desirability: Short forms of the marlowe-crowne social desirability scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Educational and Psychological measurement</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="417" to="424" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thinking of you: Nonconscious pursuit of interpersonal goals associated with relationship partners</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fitzsimons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bargh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">148</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpersonal influences on self-regulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fitzsimons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How goal instrumentality shapes relationship evaluations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fitzsimons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">319</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">i&quot; value freedom, but &quot;we&quot; value relationships: Self-construal priming mirrors cultural differences in judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Gardner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gabriel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="326" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does marriage have positive effects on the psychological well-being of the individual?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Gove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Style</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of health and social behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="122" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The emerging field of emotion regulation: An integrative review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review of general psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="271" to="299" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion and emotion regulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of personality: Theory and research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="525" to="552" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-discrepancy: A theory relating self and affect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">319</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Close relationships and self-regulation: How relationship satisfaction facilitates momentary goal pursuit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hofmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fitzsimons</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">434</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">With a little help from my friends</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lennon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mccartney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Age and emotion regulation in daily life: Frequency, strategies, tactics, and effectiveness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Livingstone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Isaacowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>39. SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL 28</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-control in daily life: Prevalence and effectiveness of diverse self-control strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Milyavskaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Saunders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Inzlicht</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="634" to="651" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mooijman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Meindl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Oyserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Monterosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dehghani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Doris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resisting temptation for the good of the group: Binding moral values and the moralization of self-control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">585</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Own versus other standpoints in self-regulation: Developmental antecedents and functional consequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Moretti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review of General Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="188" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Methods of coping with social desirability bias: A review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Nederhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European journal of social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="280" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The social regulation of emotion: An integrative, cross-disciplinary model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Reeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Ames</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Ochsner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mere presence and social facilitation: One more time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Schmitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Goore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of experimental social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="242" to="248" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic for the people: How representations of significant others implicitly affect goal pursuit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">661</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The motivational looking glass: How significant others implicitly affect goal appraisals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">424</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Somerville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ruberry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dyke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Glover</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Casey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The medial prefrontal cortex and the emergence of self-conscious emotion in adolescence</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1554" to="1562" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dynamogenic factors in pacemaking and competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Triplett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American journal of psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="507" to="533" />
			<date type="published" when="1898" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SOCIALLY MOTIVATED SELF CONTROL</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Interdependence theory. Handbook of theories of social psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Van Lange</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rusbult</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="272" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Linear models and linear mixed effects models in R with linguistic applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Winter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1308.5499</idno>
		<ptr target="http://arxiv.org/abs/1308.5499" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social facilitation of dominant and subordinate responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Zajonc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sales</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="168" />
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
