<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The impact of ethical feedback on emotions and moral decisions: a labor market experiment *</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexia</forename><surname>Gaudeul</surname></persName>
							<email>alexia.gaudeul@ec.europa.eu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Competence Centre for Behavioural Insights</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">European Commission</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Brussels</settlement>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katharina</forename><surname>Gangl</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oliver</forename><surname>Kirchkamp</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Economics and Business Administration</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Friedrich Schiller University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Jena</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Louisa</forename><surname>Kulke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Developmental Psychology with Educational Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universität Bremen</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Advanced Studies</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">‡ Behavioural Economics Research Group</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Vienna</settlement>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The impact of ethical feedback on emotions and moral decisions: a labor market experiment *</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.17605/OSF.IO/6HFGC</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T13:59+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>appraisal theory</term>
					<term>ethical feedback</term>
					<term>labor market experiment</term>
					<term>emotions</term>
					<term>mediation analysis JEL Classification: C91</term>
					<term>D83</term>
					<term>M14</term>
					<term>M54</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>We explore the influence of ethical feedback, such as praise or condemnation, on moral decisions. We focus on the emotions triggered by this type of feedback and the link between those emotions and moral decisions. Our study relies on studying behavior in an experimental labor market, where participants make incentivized decisions that have a moral component. We find that managers set higher wages when they expect to receive feedback from workers. However, wages are lower if feedback is given publicly rather than privately. We also find that emotions play a significant role when translating feedback into decisions. Positive emotions resulting from good feedback lead to downward adjustments in wages. We suggest further research into differences between public and private feedback.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>We investigate the impact of moral feedback, such as praise or condemnation, on moral decisions. We focus on the role of emotions (or "affects") in translating feedback into decisions.</p><p>We measure the effect of ethical feedback and how much of this effect is mediated by emotions. We also consider differences between the effect of private and public feedback.</p><p>In our experiment, a decision-maker ("manager") performs work alongside another person ("worker"). This generates a payoff, which the manager splits with the worker by paying a wage. The worker then gives either positive or negative ethical feedback about that wage. We measure the manager's emotions when exposed to this feedback. The manager is then matched with another worker and the process repeats two more times. This experiment allows us to relate feedback, emotions and decisions.</p><p>There are some differences between our work and related work in the fields of ethics, psychology and economics. Research in the field of management ethics relies on case studies of HR appraisals systems. They show that ethical feedback can promote ethical behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Heslin and VandeWalle, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Holbrook, 2002)</ref>. In this paper, we consider a simpler setting by studying behavior in a dictator game. This avoids the complex factors often found in organizations. This simplified environment lets us examine how ethical feedback affects choices in a moral dilemma about allocating jointly-earned resources.</p><p>Related economic studies have focused on the reputational impact of feedback. We focus rather on how feedback affects managers' ethical decisions and their emotions. Our design excludes any possible indirect impact of ethical feedback on deciders. This is the main difference between our study and <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Pigors and Rockenbach (2016)</ref>. Their study has a similar design but it shows feedback to consumers. This feedback includes information like wages paid and worker satisfaction. Consumers then decide whether to buy the firm's goods. In our experiment, we do not consider the impact of feedback on consumer demand. The workers' feedback is only shown to managers. This allows us to abstract from the market-mediated impact of feedback. Other related economic studies have considered the role of rewards and punishments in repeated public good games <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Andreoni et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b82">Sefton et al., 2007)</ref>. Punishment can be seen as a form of feedback, and has been shown to help maintain cooperation, although at a cost. Unlike this literature, we focus here on explicit feedback with no monetary consequence. We also do not let participants meet again so the prospect of a continuing relationship does not come into play.</p><p>Psychological studies have shown the relation between feeling moral emotions such as shame and guilt and ethical behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Gaudine and Thorne, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Chebat and Slusarczyk, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b89">Valdesolo and DeSteno, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Bracht and Regner, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">Onwezen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Coricelli et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b92">Xie et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">Saintives and Lunardo, 2016)</ref>. Few however consider the full cycle from ethical feedback to emotions to behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Jacobs et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b93">Zada et al., 2022)</ref>. We consider this full cycle in this paper but do not measure emotions like shame and guilt directly. This is because these emotions are complex and can be difficult to quantify or interpret in a consistent and objective manner. The Valence-Arousal-Dominance model provides a more standardized and comprehensive framework for assessing emotional states by focusing on broader dimensions of emotion rather than specific emotions. Arousal represents the intensity of an emotional response, ranging from low arousal (calmness) to high arousal (excitement or alertness). Valence refers to the positive or negative quality of an emotion, ranging from positive (e.g., happiness, joy) to negative (e.g., sadness, anger). Dominance refers to the degree of control or influence an individual feels in a situation, ranging from low dominance (feeling submissive, controlled, or powerless) to high dominance (feeling in control, powerful, or influential).</p><p>Finally, unlike most of the psychological literature, we give financial incentives. Deciders in our experiment share money they earn by performing work. Whatever is paid to the worker does not go to the manager. Deciders in our experiment must therefore balance ethical and profit motives, which induces emotional conflict. How deciders manage such a conflict is interesting as a robustness test for theories of emotions as a driver of behavior. Indeed, as <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Lerner et al. (2004)</ref> say, "it may be that emotions have little impact when real money is at stake".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Context and motivation</head><p>This paper investigates situations when a person has some leeway in deciding another's welfare. Social and ethical norms come into play when assessing those situations. We consider cases where the subordinated person can give feedback. This feedback can be private or public; that is, either told privately to the decider or visible to others. Feedback lets the decider improve decisions and lets the subordinate influence them. This yields informed decisions that are more likely to gain social approval. Yet, obtaining such a positive outcome requires interpersonal skills. This is because emotions are key in how people interpret and respond to feedback.</p><p>Feedback plays an important role in managing relations in organisations. Companies and teaching institutions often have feedback systems in place <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Fletcher, 2004)</ref>. Such feedback is usually kept private or aggregated. This makes both the giver and receiver anonymous. Those feedback systems aim to improve performance and monitor workers. Grading students by teachers is another, well-covered feedback system. Such systems, however, seldom have a moral component. Still, some religious groups and institutions hold meetings to discuss moral issues among their members. This may lead to exclusion (e.g., Quakers, Jehovah's Witnesses, Amish).</p><p>More public feedback systems are used in online labor markets like Amazon Turk and Upwork <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Gandini et al., 2016)</ref>. Some of those let employers rate workers, others let workers rate employers. For Amazon Turk, workers can leave feedback on employers outside the platform in communities like MTurk Crowd. Public feedback systems are also used for work outside of online marketplaces. Glassdoor for example lets workers rate their firms on a wide range of criteria. Many other online marketplaces use feedback systems to rate satisfaction with both parties in transactions. This is the case when selling goods, renting apartments, hiring service providers, or finding romantic partners <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Dellarocas, 2003)</ref>. Most research on public feedback systems has focused on their reputational aspects. They encourage good behavior. They provide info about potential transaction parties. This builds trust among members <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">(Tadelis, 2016)</ref>.</p><p>Beyond systems to aggregate feedback, organizations also publish info on businesses' ethics. This includes compliance with labor and environmental standards, tax laws, and levels of executive pay. It also covers corruption and ties to authoritarian regimes. New and forthcoming regulations mandate disclosure of corporate social and environmental policies. Those initiatives aim to promote corporate social responsibility and ethics.</p><p>We further the study of those feedback systems by adding a psychological view. We study how feedback affects decision-making by looking at its emotional impact on decision-makers. We focus in particular on feedback about behavior that has an ethical component, so the feedback is both about the behaviour and the person. The direct effect of ethical feedback on incentivized decisions is rarely studied. The psychological literature has explored other, nonincentivized tasks, while the economic literature has focused on the indirect, reputational impact of feedback <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Dellarocas, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b85">Tadelis, 2016)</ref>. Unlike most economic literature, we focus on feedback's emotional impact. This is because emotions that arise from interpersonal relations play a crucial role in decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Andrade and Ariely, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Lerner et al., 2015)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Research questions and literature</head><p>This paper has three main research questions. First, how does ethical feedback affect decisions? Second, how do emotions mediate this effect? Third, do private and public feedback have different impacts? We underline the literature on those three topics. This literature allows us to express hypotheses about the results of our research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">The effect of feedback on behavior</head><p>Most studies on feedback's effects have focused on top-down feedback and have not examined its emotional impact. In the workplace, attention has focused on monitoring workers' performance. The goal is to use this to give feedback and improve performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(London, 2014)</ref>. In education, the emphasis has been to enhance learning experiences <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">(Mulliner and Tucker, 2017)</ref>. The literature has stressed the need for feedback to focus on the situation (e.g. task issues) and not the person (i.e. avoid attacks) <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Anderson et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Schartel, 2012)</ref>. It also says to focus on the positives, not the negatives. This builds self-esteem and boosts motivation <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Brockner et al., 1987;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Deci and Cascio, 1972;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Hattie and Timperley, 2007)</ref>. Our study differs from this literature because we look at feedback about decisions with a moral component. Those decisions reflect a person's moral character, not their skills. Feedback in our setting is therefore more likely to be taken personally. We also differ in considering the effects of alternating negative and positive feedback on the same person. This lets us compare their effects. Finally, we look at feedback from the bottom-up, i.e., from subordinates to superiors, rather than top-down. Top-down feedback can seem like a power play. It lets some people shape others' behavior and performance. Bottom-up feedback gives power to the subordinate and can motivate managers and teachers to perform better -it is however as an instrument of power for those higher up in the hierarchy as it helps them monitor the performance of managers and teachers. The effect bottom-up ethical feedback has been studied only in correlational field studies. Those studies show that employees who can express their values, and speak up when they're violated, report less misconduct in their organization (cf. the obedience construct in <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">Tanner et al. (2019)</ref>).</p><p>There is little research on how feedback affects moral choices in economics. The issue has been studied in dictator and public good games <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">(Masclet et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Ellingsen and Johannesson, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b91">Xiao and Houser, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Goldfarb et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">Joffily et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">Lumeau et al., 2015)</ref>. Deciders in the dictator game and contributors in the public good game give more when they expect feedback from others. Those papers do not consider, however, the role of emotions. We mention in section 2.2 some literature that goes further by including the full cycle feedback-emotion-behavior, as we do.</p><p>Compared to treatments with no feedback, this literature suggests that disclosing the moral judgment of one's actions by those affected will lead to more ethical behavior (Hypothesis 5). This is because some people don't naturally consider how their actions affect others, or the moral standards others apply to them. Feedback may lead these individuals to align their actions to the moral norms made evident by that feedback.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">The role of emotions in behavior</head><p>Emotions shape behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Baumeister et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Lerner et al., 2023)</ref>. Moral emotions like shame, pride, and guilt drive moral behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Eisenberg, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Gaudine and Thorne, 2001)</ref>. Moral emotions affect consumer buying <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Arli et al., 2016)</ref>, charity <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Andreoni et al., 2017)</ref>, lying <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Greenberg et al., 2014)</ref> and pro-environmental behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">(Onwezen et al., 2013)</ref>. Anger can drive uncooperative behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">(Ning and Mahmud, 2022)</ref> and retaliation <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Ben-Shakhar et al., 2007)</ref>.</p><p>Various actors can deliver ethical feedback in different formats. This feedback can generate moral emotions, and the expectation of experiencing those emotions can play a role when making decisions. They enter the thought process that leads to ethical decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Lerner et al., 2023)</ref>. Most people want to avoid negative emotions and keep positive ones, although there are individual differences in both motivations <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Carver and White, 1994)</ref>. One driver of ethical behavior could thus be to avoid negative emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Lindebaum et al., 2017)</ref> and to foster positive ones <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Hartmann et al., 2017)</ref>. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Dulleck et al. (2016)</ref> show that strong emotions in an ethical choice lead to more ethical behavior. Indeed, <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">Pfister and Böhm (2008)</ref> argue that emotions help us commit to important moral and social decisions.</p><p>Some economic papers investigate those issues by inducing an emotional state and studying its impact on behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">(Lin et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">Martinez et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Drouvelis and Grosskopf, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bartke et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">Nguyen and Noussair, 2022)</ref>. However, this does not allow to consider the full cycle from behavior to feedback to emotions and back to behavior. This dynamic view of the role of emotions in mediating feedback and behavior is important however, as behavior may partly be driven by a desire to avoid bad feedback. This cycle is only studied in a few papers. <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">(Reuben and van Winden, 2010)</ref> show that proposers in a power to take game experience stronger shame and guilt when they feel they took too much, particularly when punished. This leads them to reduce their demands. <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Peloza et al. (2013)</ref> also consider the full trigger-emotion-behavior cycle in ethical consumption decisions. They show that highlighting a gap between one's actions and morals can induce shame. Anticipated shame drives consumers to buy products with better ethics. Joffily et al. (2014) measure arousal and valence in a public good game with punishment. They find that lower arousal and more positive valence lead to greater contributions. Punishment, a form of feedback to others, comes from high arousal and negative feelings. Punishment itself triggers higher arousal and negative valence, and this triggers higher contributions. Finally, <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Noussair et al. (2024)</ref> show that a desire to avoid regret may lower contributions in public good games. People fear having contributed more than others. This literature suggests that good feedback will create positive emotions. Conversely, bad feedback will not (Hypothesis 1). We expect deciders to avoid repeating negative feedback, as it creates negative emotions. They will therefore raise wages after negative feedback. They will also try to keep positive feedback as it generates good feelings. They will therefore maintain wages after positive feedback (Hypotheses 2 and H3). We will attempt to separate the effect of feedback from the effect of resulting emotions on wages (Hypothesis 4).</p><p>Yet, as <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Lerner et al. (2004)</ref> say, "it may be that emotions have little impact when real money is at stake". Feedback might be seen as just information about what a situation or person needs, the ethical norms in a setting, not a moral judgment of the person. Feedback may thus not stir emotions in some individuals, and yet trigger reactions due to its ethical component. For example, negative feedback about wages may be seen as just information that says "workers expect more". Then it not seen as a moral judgment about the decision maker's "goodness. " In our experiment, we inform deciders about workers' expectations. We vary those expectations across treatments. This lets us control for those expectations and get rid of the informational effect of feedback. We can then focus on how feedback affects emotions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">The difference between public and private feedback</head><p>We cited research that underlined the need to avoid personal attacks and to focus on the positive when giving feedback. Also, the literature recommends giving feedback in private. This is for various reasons. It elicits more honest feedback <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">(Singh and Reddy, 2021)</ref>, respects privacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">(Seevers et al., 2014)</ref>, and avoids crowding out intrinsic motivation <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Delavallade, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>In our study, we explore this wisdom by varying the publicity of feedback. We have a treatment with feedback that is only anticipated. No feedback is given, but deciders know that recipients will rate their behavior. In other treatments, the feedback can be either private (only the decider learns it) or public (all participants learn it).</p><p>We thus change how much others can observe, which affects moral emotions, like guilt and shame <ref type="bibr" target="#b86">(Tangney et al., 2007)</ref>. Our treatment with public disclosure highlight a difference with private disclosure. It is the difference between: 1) considering the impact of one's actions on others, and 2) thinking about how others will view the impact of one's actions.</p><p>We expect public disclosure to cause more shame and embarrassment. These feelings come in addition to the guilt from private disclosure. Private disclosure (from the affected person to the decider) relies on the personal ethics of the decider. Public disclosure should enhance awareness of how others judge the decider's action. This would raise emotions, which can change ethical conduct <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Dulleck et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Patil et al., 2014)</ref>. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">Patil et al. (2014)</ref>, a virtual reality test raised emotions. This made people more utilitarian in their decision-making. In the trolley problem, they chose to save more lives instead of avoiding responsibility by not acting. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Brocas et al. (2021)</ref>, participants in an experiment can be sanctioned for stealing by making it public. This reduces stealing and increases arousal in would-be thieves, compared to a no-disclosure treatment. Our experiment differs in that we also consider a treatment with private disclosure, in addition to public and no disclosure. Also, we will study the dynamics of such behavior. We will do this by repeating the decision-feedback-emotion cycle three times.</p><p>The literature thus outlines that public feedback might act as stronger deterrent for bad behavior. However, public feedback may also have negative effects by generating more resentment. We expect the deterrent effect to dominate. So, wages would be higher in treatments with public feedback than in those with private feedback (Hypothesis 5).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">The experiment</head><p>We follow the empirical shift in economic research by using the experimental method <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Hamermesh, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Angrist et al., 2017)</ref>. The experimental method in economics is to recreate real economic conditions in a stylized way in a lab's controlled environment. Participants are incentivized to maximize economic outcomes. Surveys present hypothetical scenarios. In a lab, decisions affect real people. They put participants in real situations with real consequences. Laboratory decisions, therefore, have some external validity.</p><p>We generate feedback and elicit emotions and subsequent behavior by running a framed economic experiment that is inspired by the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Pigors and Rockenbach (2016)</ref>. Our experiment aims to replicate a labor market. In it, managers hire workers, set their wages, and receive feedback about wages. Wage setting and feedback repeat over three periods. We observe how pay evolves based on received feedback and managers' displayed emotions. Instructions for both sides of the labor market are available in online appendix H.</p><p>The labor market has an ethical dimension. Wages reflect a moral choice on how to share the surplus from a productive activity among its participants. They are not a neutral outcome of supply and demand in the labor market.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">The labor market relation</head><p>We model the ethical situations by having two people work together to generate an economic surplus. One person, whom we called the "counter" ("zähler" in German) in the experiment, and whom we refer to as "worker" or "recipient" in this paper, counts the number of dots on a line on 5 successive occasions (e.g., seeing ………. they should report 10). All counting of dots was done by workers prior to being matched with managers.</p><p>A second person, whom we called the "calculator" ("rechner" in German) in the experiment, and whom we refer to as "manager" or "decider" in this paper, performed a simple arithmetic operation on the numbers counted by the worker (e.g. 10 -2 × 15/10 + 7).</p><p>If both did their job correctly, then a surplus of 7€ was generated. The joint task was completed successfully in 92.4% of all cases.</p><p>Manager determines surplus allocation before knowing if the joint task was performed successfully. The worker then gives feedback about the manager's decision.</p><p>Unlike the dictator game, the worker has the opportunity to react to the manager's decision. Unlike the ultimatum game, this reaction has no effect on payoffs. The game can be seen as a variation on the impunity game <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Bolton and Zwick, 1995)</ref>, i.e. an ultimatum game where a rejection (negative feedback) by the worker has no impact on payoffs. The game is also similar to the power-to-take game, as both agents earn their income rather than being endowed with it <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Bosman and van Winden, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Bosman et al., 2005)</ref>. However, the recipient cannot retaliate by destroying joint earnings.</p><p>We vary whether to relay the feedback to the manager. We also vary if a third party might see it. We avoid reputation issues as workers cannot avoid badly rated managers.</p><p>Participants payoffs are as follows:</p><p>• Managers (deciders) set wages w for their workers (recipients). They may receive feedback from recipients about the level of such wages. One period is chosen at random At the end of the experiment. Managers learn whether the joint task was performed successfully in that period. In case of success, managers receive the €7 surplus. In this case, the manager's profit is 7 -w in euros. In case of failure, the manager's profit is zero. In addition to this, managers received €5.</p><p>• If the joint task is performed successfully in the chosen period, the worker (recipient) receives the wage w set by the manager in that period. Workers know the total surplus generated (7€). We got feedback from workers on different wage levels before running the manager side of the experiment (see Section 3.2). We communicated either positive or negative feedback to the manager based on this elicitation and the wage paid by the manager. Workers learned of the joint task's success when they got paid after we ran the manager side of the experiment. They received €3 if they failed, and €3+w if they succeeded.</p><p>In each period workers are matched with a new manager, wages are set by managers and feedback is generated by worker. Feedback is transmitted to the respective managers. Managers do not see past feedback given by workers, and neither do workers see past feedback given to managers. By matching workers with a new manager each period, and not giving access to a feedback history, we minimize time-dependence in behavior. The only exception is the effect of feedback on managers in following periods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Feedback during the experiment</head><p>We asked for feedback on a pre-specified scale, rather than letting workers give free-form comments. Feedback was determined by using the strategy method <ref type="bibr" target="#b83">(Selten, 1967)</ref>. At the start of the experiment, workers rated different wages. They chose to give either positive or negative feedback for each integer between 0€ and 7€. Workers had to give feedback. They could not abstain. We used a pictorial representation of feedback as in treatment "face" in <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Pigors and Rockenbach (2016)</ref>. Good feedback is a thumbs up on a green background. Bad feedback is a thumbs down on a red background <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Good feedback</head><p>Bad feedback Preliminary elicitation of feedback from workers showed that 40% of workers gave good feedback when wage was 2€, 83% when wage was 3€, and 96% when wage was 4€. To simply explain to deciders what to expect, we distinguished between two worker types. Type "H" has high expectations. They give good feedback only if the wage is over 4€. Type "L" has low expectations. They give good feedback whenever the wage is over 2€.</p><p>During the experiment, managers met workers of types L and H in alternating sequences. We varied the order of the low and high expectation workers. Managers in the case "thresholds HLH" were matched with a worker of type H in round 1, with a worker of type L in round 2, and with a worker of type H again in round 3. In the case "thresholds LHL", managers were matched with a worker of type L in round 1, with a worker of type H in round 2, and with a worker of type H again in round 3.</p><p>We informed managers of the workers' expectations to align beliefs in all treatments. In the case "thresholds HLH", managers were told that most workers give positive feedback only if they receive 4€ or more. In the case "thresholds LHL", they were told that most workers give positive feedback as long as they receive more than €2. However, we did not inform them of the sequence of workers of different types in their treatment. We did so even in the treatments where feedback was not shown to managers. Managers had to answer a question about workers expectations correctly to take part in the experiment. Prior expectation of feedback is therefore controlled. This lets us focus on the emotional effect of feedback rather than on the information it gives managers about workers' expectations. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> shows the positive feedback rates for the treatments. As designed, the frequency of positive feedback is high when thresholds are low. The frequency of positive feedback is low when thresholds are high. Feedback received is therefore exogenous to a large extent. We will use the (exogenous) thresholds as an instrument for feedback to address the remaining endogeneity. The vertical axis shows the relative frequency of positive feedback that corresponds to the manager's wage. In the treatments with feedback, managers receive exactly this feedback. In the treatment without feedback, managers might anticipate such a feedback, but they don't see this feedback. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Measure of emotions</head><p>We elicit self-reported subjective emotions after each round of feedback in our experiment. This differs from more immediate measures of emotions. Self reports rely on beliefs about one's emotions. These beliefs are retrospective. They reflect the person's self-concept, as an ethical agent <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">(Robinson and Clore, 2002)</ref>. This method of measuring emotions has been used in economic research on well-being and happiness <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">(Reyniers and Bhalla, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Brandts et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Blanchflower and Oswald, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Alesina et al., 2004)</ref>.</p><p>We let deciders rate their emotions directly after receiving feedback on a three dimensions scale. The dimensions are valence (from sad to happy), arousal (from calm to excited) and dominance (from powerless to powerful).</p><p>We elicit those dimensions with the Self-Assessment Manikin (SAM). This is "a non-verbal pictorial assessment technique that directly measures the valence, arousal, and dominance associated with a person's affective reaction to a wide variety of stimuli" <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Bradley and Lang, 1994)</ref>.</p><p>Participants received instructions on the meaning of the pictorial representations for each dimension. Then, they reported their emotions using that tool. They clicked the button under the humanoid representation ("Manikin") that best matched their feelings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Public and private disclosure of feedback</head><p>We vary whether the feedback is not shown to the manager, shown privately to the manager, or shown publicly to both the manager and other participants.</p><p>We thus compare three treatments:</p><p>• Baseline "no disclosure": In the baseline treatment, deciders set wages but do not receive feedback by recipients (no disclosure).</p><p>• Treatment "private disclosure": In this treatment, deciders set wages and receive feedback during the experiment. The purpose of this treatment is to explore the role of internalized (private) social emotions such as shame and guilt in deciders' decisions.</p><p>• Treatment "public disclosure": In this treatment, feedback from recipients is communicated to deciders, as in the second treatment. However we told recipients that their feedback will be shown to other participants (workers and managers). The purpose of this treatment is to explore the role of more public social emotions such as embarrassment, in deciders' decisions. In each round, they were reminded the feedback would be seen by others. This was represented with a picture of an eye above the feedback they received. The feedback they received was shown to others alongside a randomly generated name we assigned to each manager at the start of the experiment. Those names were given to managers in every treatments. The names were made of random combinations of two basic sounds (such as AL, BU, SI, MO), leading to names such as SIRA, JOUL, or ORBU. The aim was to avoid names with possible cultural or emotional connotations, but still have names that can be pronounced.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5.">Post-experimental questionnaire</head><p>At the end of the experiment, we collected a number of control variables (Appendix G). The socio-demographic variables are age, gender, nationality, field of studies, living situation, financial situation, religiosity, and charitable activity. In addition to those, we also collected:</p><p>WVS A measure of economic values from the World Value Survey <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Haerpfer et al., 2022)</ref>, which contrasts collectivist and individualist attitudes.</p><p>GASP A measure of guilt and shame proneness <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Cohen et al., 2011)</ref>, which gives insights into how individuals differ in their emotional responses to situations involving moral or social transgressions.</p><p>Big5 A short measure of personality along the Big Five in 15 questions <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">(Rammstedt and John, 2007)</ref>.</p><p>HPRS A measure of reactance, as a determinant of how feedback is received <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Dillard and Shen, 2005)</ref>. The scale assesses various aspects of psychological reactance, such as feelings of resistance, anger, and opposition to perceived threats to one's freedom.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Hypotheses</head><p>Based on our literature review, we test hypotheses about the impact of feedback on emotions and the impact of emotions on wage setting. We also test differences across treatments. Our hypotheses were registered on the OSF registry at https://osf.io/q3bme. We changed the ordering of hypotheses compared to the pre-registration, and include headers for different sections of the hypotheses. Our main hypotheses are as follow:</p><p>Feedback, emotions and wages H1: Individuals will display positive affective reactions (+valence, +arousal, +dominance) in response to positive feedback, and negative affective reactions to negative feedback.</p><p>H1a: Intensity of affective reactions in response to feedback will be lower in the treatment with private disclosure than in the treatments with public disclosure.</p><p>H2: Negative affective reactions during the feedback stage will lead to higher wages in the next trial. Positive affective reactions during the feedback phase will lead to maintenance in wages.</p><p>H2a: Higher affective reactions lead to larger subsequent changes in wages.</p><p>H2b: Affective reactions and changes in wage will be more pronounced at the beginning of the experiment than at the end.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H3:</head><p>Positive feedback lead to stable or higher wages in the next trial. Negative feedback lead to higher wages in the next trial.</p><p>H4: Both feedback and affective reaction to feedback play a role in the change in wage in the subsequent period.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Treatment effects H5:</head><p>The wage w that is paid to workers will be higher in the treatment with private feedback than with no feedback, and again higher with public disclosure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H6:</head><p>The wage w that is paid to worker will be higher in the treatment with high wage expectations than in the treatment with low wage expectations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Data collection and sample characteristics</head><p>The experiment was conducted online between August 2021 and May 2022 based on oTree <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Chen et al., 2016)</ref>. We recruited from pools of participants at the laboratory of the School of Economics of the University of Jena (Germany), at the laboratory of the Competence Center for Experimental Research at the Vienna University of Economics and Business (Austria), at the Faculty of Psychology of the University of Vienna (Austria), and at the Institute of Psychology at the University of Erlangen-Nuremberg (Germany). Participants were recruited with ORSEE <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Greiner, 2015)</ref> in both Jena and at the Vienna University of Economics and Business, with Sona Systems (https://www.sona-systems.com/) at the University of Vienna, and by email in Erlangen-Nuremberg. We recruited 636 participants in the role of managers between August 2021 and February 2022, of which 35 participants in Erlangen Nurnberg, 433 participants in Jena and 168 participants in Vienna. 17 of the participants in the role of managers failed an attention check. Only the remaining 619 are used in the following analysis. Among those, we had 87 participants of Austrian nationality, 429 participants of German nationality and 103 participants of unknown nationality.</p><p>We recruited 643 participants in the role of workers between August 2021 and May 2022, of which 277 participants in Jena and 366 participants in Vienna. Some participants in the role of workers were recruited after the end of the manager side of the experiment to obtain equality in the number of participants on both sides. We are not interested in the behavior of the workers because they are only needed to generate feedback and social incentive for the managers. Each worker is allocated one manager and is paid depending on the wage set by that manager in a randomly chosen period. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows the distribution of participants by feedback treatments and threshold sequences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Results</head><p>In the following subsections we first investigate the link between feedback and emotions, and then how feedback and emotions affect wages. We finally estimate a mediation model to determine how far emotional response to wages drive wage, rather than feedback directly affecting wages through other pathways. We finally test treatment effects. In each section, we first present some descriptive statistics and then test our hypotheses with the help of formal models. We use R version 4.3.2 (2023-10-31 ucrt) (R Core Team, 2022) for the empirical analysis. We use runjags 2.2.2-1.1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Denwood, 2016)</ref> to interface with JAGS 4.3.1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">(Plummer, 2003)</ref>. The data and analytic code are available at https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/6HFGC.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">H1: Feedback and Emotions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.1.">Descriptives</head><p>According to H1 we expect that individuals react positively to positive feedback, and negatively to negative feedback. In our study we elicit valence (e.g. happiness), arousal (e.g. excitement) and dominance (e.g. feeling powerful). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 3</ref> shows how those emotion dimensions vary depending on the feedback each period.</p><p>While already the anticipation of feedback might have an effect in the "no feedback" treatment, this effect seems to be very small. This indicates that any effect of feedback in other treatments is not due to an internal process but rather relates to feedback received. We do see effects of good and bad feedback for valence in the private and in the public feedback treatments. Valence seems to react clearly and positively to good feedback. Smaller effects can be observed with arousal, which increases slightly with bad feedback, and dominance, which increases slightly with good feedback. 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3 The vertical axis shows changes in emotion dimensions conditional on the positive or negative feedback that corresponds to the manager's wage. In the treatments with feedback, managers receive exactly this feedback. In the treatment without feedback, managers might anticipate this feedback, but they don't see this feedback. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.2.">Model</head><p>In this section we use a formal model to better understand the relation between feedback F i,t and change in emotions ∆M i,m,t . The feedback F i,t is 0 in case of bad feedback, 1 in case of good feedback. M i,m,t takes values from 1 to 5. Participants are indexed by i, rounds are denoted with t, the emotion dimension is described as m. Since feedback F i,t for participant i in round t is endogenous, we use the (exogenous) threshold T i,t as an instrument for feedback F i,t . T i,t was either H or L depending on the period and the specific threshold sequence used (see 3.2). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> shows the relation between thresholds and feedback.</p><p>Our dependent variable is ∆M i,m,t , which is the change in reported emotion m for participant i between time t -1 and t. Emotions may also be affected by controls (see below), modelled as a row vector X i . We demean ∆M i,m,t , F i,t and X i and normalise their standard deviation.</p><p>Graphically, the stochastic process could be described as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">T i,t F i,t ∆M i,m,t X i θ γ F γ C</formula><p>The first stage equation we estimate is</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P(F i,t |T i,t ) = Φ(θ 0 + θ 1 T i,t )<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where Φ is the distribution function of the normal distribution. Since the feedback can only take two values, positive or negative, there are many equivalent specifications for the first stage equation. We model the effect of the instrumented feedbackF</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">i,t = P(F i,t |T i,t ) = Φ(θ 0 + θ 1 T i,t ) on ∆M i,m,t as follows: ∆M i,m,t ∼ Φ((1,F i,t )γ F + X i γ C + η ′ i,m , τ ′ m )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>γ F is a column vector. Its second component, γ F 2 , is the marginal effect of feedback on the emotion. η ′ i,m is the random effect for participant i. τ ′ m is the precision of the distribution. To demonstrate robustness, we compare two different specifications for X: Either no controls, or all available controls (see 3.5). In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4</ref> we show estimates for γ F 2 (plus 95% credible intervals). For regression coefficients we assume throughout the paper a normal prior with mean zero and precision 10 -4 . For precision parameters we assume as a prior a Gamma distribution with shape and rate of 10 -2 . Detailed results are provided in Appendix E. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of a good feedback on change in emotion</head><p>The graph shows estimates (and 95% credible intervals) for γ F 2 from Equation (2) for the different feedback conditions. Detailed results are shown in Section E in the online appendix. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.3.">Results</head><p>In the treatment with no feedback, participants could still anticipate feedback and react to their anticipation. We see however, that in treatments with no feedback, emotional reaction to possibly anticipated feedback is small. In the treatments with explicit feedback, the reaction to feedback is, for all emotions, substantially stronger. Valence, thus the feeling of happiness versus sadness, seems to be more affected by feedback than arousal (i.e., feeling excited) or dominance (i.e., feeling powerful). Odds for positive effect of positive feedback on change in emotion</p><p>The top part of the graph shows odds for γ F 2 from Equation (2) being larger in the condition with feedback than without. The bottom part of the graph shows odds for γ F 2 being larger in the condition with public feedback than with private feedback.   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 5</ref> shows odds for the comparison of treatments with feedback with treatments without. In the following, we adopt the terminology for effect sizes suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Kass and Raftery (1995)</ref>: odds ∈ [1 : 1, 2.72 : 1]: only anecdotal evidence, odds ∈ [2.72 : 1, 20.1 : 1]: positive evidence, odds ∈ [20.1 : 1, 148 : 1]: strong evidence, odds ∈ [148 : 1, ∞ : 1]: very strong evidence. We find "very strong" evidence that a good feedback has a positive effect on change of valence. We also find "very strong" evidence that a good feedback has a negative effect on change of arousal. Finally, we have "very strong" evidence that a good feedback has a positive effect on change of dominance.</p><p>Thus, after a positive feedback our participants feel happier, less excited and more powerful. Hypothesis H1 is therefore verified for valence and dominance, while a good feedback actually appears to lead to lower arousal.</p><p>In the bottom part of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 5</ref> we compare public with private feedback. For valence we find "very strong" evidence that good public feedback has a less positive effect on change of valence than good private feedback. For arousal we find "only anecdotal" evidence that good public feedback has a more positive effect on change of arousal than good private feedback. For dominance we find "strong" evidence that good public feedback has a more positive effect on change of dominance than good private feedback. Thus, positive feedback has a stronger positive effect on dominance when it is public, but a weaker positive effect on valence. Hypothesis H1a is therefore verified for dominance, while a good public feedback actually has a lower impact on valence than a good private feedback.</p><p>In other words, public feedback affects more one's "standing" (dominance). Private feedback affects more one's internal state (happy/sad). This may be due to dominance being more of a social component of emotions. It's linked to public social interactions and hierarchies. In contrast, happiness is a private, subjective emotional state. It's a personal experience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">H2: Emotions and wages</head><p>According to H2, changes in emotion dimensions when confronted with feedback lead to changes in wages, whereby negative changes lead to higher wages and positive changes lead to stable wages. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 6</ref> shows the change in wages W i,t+1 -W i,t as a function of the prior change in emotion M m,i,t -M m,i,t-1 . While changes in arousal and dominance seems to have only a small effect on wages, positive changes in valence seem to have a clear negative effect on wage.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.1.">Descriptives</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.2.">Model</head><p>To test H2 formally, we explain the change of the wage from one period to the next as a linear function of positive and negative changes in reported emotions over time.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">W i,t -W i,t-1 = β 0 + ⎛ ⎜ ⎝ ∑ m∈E β m+ max(0, (M i,m,t-1 -M i,m,t-2 ))+ +β m-min(0, (M i,m,t-1 -M i,m,t-2 )) ) + ϵ i,t<label>(3)</label></formula><p>In Equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">3</ref>, W i,t is the wage of participant i in round t, E is the set of emotions we measure {valence, arousal, dominance}, m ∈ E is the respective emotion. β m+ and β mmeasure the impact of positive respectively negative changes to emotions. Estimation results are shown in column OLS in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>Since emotions might be endogenous, <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref> also shows results of an IV regression where we instrument the (positive or negative) change in valence with the change in feedback.</p><p>Since we use only a single instrument, we cannot control for more than a single dimension of emotion in the IV estimations. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.3.">Results</head><p>In line with <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 6</ref>, we find that an increase in valence (valence+) has a negative impact on wages. This is significant for our OLS estimation. The effect is, however, no longer significant in the IV estimation. An increase in dominance has a positive effect on wages, and a decrease has a negative effect, but this effect is not significant. Overall, we do not find any significant influence of negative affective reactions after feedback. Thus, we find no support for H2. Indeed, decreases in valence lead to no change in wage in the next trial, and increases in valence during the feedback stage lead to a decrease in wage in the next trial.</p><p>This contradicts our original expectation that deciders would aim for maintaining positive changes in emotions by maintaining wages, and for repairing negative changes in emotions by increasing wages.</p><p>Online appendices A and B test H2b which relates to the decay in affective reactions and their effect on wages over successive rounds of the experiment. Arousal and dominance seem to vary less with time, while valence appears to vary more. We also find indications that the effect of affective reactions on wages decreases over rounds.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.">H3: Feedback and wages</head><p>In this section, we test H3 about the effect of feedback on wages. This section helps us move from the effect of feedback on emotions and of emotions on wages to consider the overall effect of feedback on wages. We will then test H4 with a mediation model. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">Figure 7</ref> shows the change in wages W i,t+1 -W i,t as a function of feedback F i,t . We find that good feedback appears to have a positive effect on wages while bad feedback has a negative effect.  Note: Jitter was added to avoid overlapping symbols.</p><p>We fit a simple linear regression model of wages as a function of feedback last period, and then an instrumental variable regression model where the instrumental variable is the threshold (H or L) in each round (see 3.2). This is to address potential endogeneity issues and obtain consistent parameter estimates.</p><p>The linear model confirms that bad feedback is associated with lower wages (negative intercept), while good feedback leads to more positive changes in wages. However, the effects are not significant in the model with instruments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4.">H4: How far do emotions mediate feedback?</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4.1.">Model</head><p>We test H4 about the combined effect of feedback, emotion and wages with the help of a formal model.</p><p>In our study, positive or negative feedback F i,t may have a direct effect on changes in wage ∆W i,t . Furthermore, feedback F i,t may have, through change in emotions ∆M i,m,t , an indirect effect on changes in wage ∆W i,t . In this section we attempt to disentangle the direct and the indirect effect of feedback on wages.</p><p>Graphically, the stochastic process could be described as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">T i,t F i,t ∆M i,t ∆W i,t X i θ 1 γ F β F β C γ C β M</formula><p>As in Equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">1</ref>, we again instrument feedback F i,t with the thresholds T i,t . We again follow Equation (2) to model how changes in emotions ∆M i,m,t react to feedback feedback F i,t . To demonstrate robustness, we compare two sets of control variables X i . Either we consider the case of all available controls, including GASP, HPRS, Big Five and several sociodemographic variables (see subsection 3.5), or we use a simple model where X i contains just the constant. We also model the direct effect of the instrumented feedback F i,t on the measurement of changes in wage, ∆W i,t , set by participant i at time t, as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">∆W i,t ∼ Φ((1,F i,t )β F + ∆M ⊤ i,t β M + X i β C + η i , τ D )<label>(4)</label></formula><p>β F is a column vector. Its second component, β F 2 , is the marginal effect of feedback on wage. ∆M ⊤ i,t is a row vector with one element for each mediator variable, following Equation (2). β M is a column vector, its components each denoting the marginal effect of an emotion on wage. The random effect for participant i is η i . The precision of the distribution is τ D . From Equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_2">2</ref>and (4), the average direct effect of feedback on wage is</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">ADE = β F 2 .<label>(5)</label></formula><p>The average causal mediated effects of feedback through mediator m on wage is</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">ACME m = γ F m β M m .<label>(6)</label></formula><p>The total effect of feedback on wage is then </p><formula xml:id="formula_8">TOT = ADE + ∑ m ACME m .<label>(7)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Effect of feedback</head><p>The graph shows for the different feedback conditions estimates for the parameters from Equations (5) - <ref type="formula" target="#formula_8">7</ref>and their 95% credible interval. Detailed results are shown in Section F in the online appendix.   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Figure 8</ref>, showing for the same estimation results the odds that feedback has a positive effect. Detailed results are provided in Appendix F.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4.2.">Results</head><p>We find that positive feedback has a modest positive average direct effect (ADE) on wage. Note this includes the effect of anticipated feedback. Indeed, in the "no feedback" condition, the ADE is larger.</p><p>We do find "strong" evidence that good feedback has through valence a negative effect on change of wages . Valence acts as a suppressor. In contrast, we find "only anecdotal" evidence that good feedback has through dominance a negative effect on change of wages . We also find "only anecdotal" evidence that good feedback has through arousal a negative effect on change of wages . The direct effect itself is only small. We find "only anecdotal" evidence that good feedback has a negative effect on change of wages . The direct (positive) effect of feedback and the suppression effect through valence seem to cancel each other out. As a result, the total effect of feedback on wage is rather small.</p><p>An exception to this is the "no feedback" treatment where the anticipated feedback effect seems to prevail. In treatments without feedback, the total effect of anticipated good feedback is positive because the direct effect of feedback is not reduced as in treatment with feedback by the emotion mediated reduction in wage when feedback is good.</p><p>The bottom part of of <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref> shows the odds that public feedback has a more positive effect on wages than private feedback. With the exception of dominance, the type of the feedback, public or private does not seem to have a strong influence. However, we find "strong" evidence that good public feedback has through dominance a more positive effect on change of wages than private feedback.</p><p>The results of the mediation analysis explain why the total effect of positive feedback on wages is not significantly different from zero (subsection 6.3), even though it increased valence, especially in the private feedback treatment, and dominance, especially in the public feedback treatment (subsection 6.1). This is because increases in valence are related to lower wages (subsection 6.2). We do confirm that as a result, the average causal mediated effect of valence is negative in both public and private treatment. We add to this that the average causal mediated effect of dominance is positive in the public treatment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.5.">H5: Wages and treatments</head><p>According to H5, we expect that wages will be lower in the treatment with no feedback, as workers can't reward generous employers. In the treatments with explicit feedback, workers can at least show their satisfaction or dissatisfaction with a wage. Anticipating this feedback, employers should set higher wages. Feedback is more visible in the case of public feedback. In this case wages should be higher than in the case of private feedback. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Round Average Wage (95% CI)</head><p>The graph shows for the different feedback conditions the average wage and their 95% credible interval over time.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref> shows means and 95% credible intervals for wages in the different rounds and for the different treatments. In all treatments wages tend to decrease over time. The differences in average levels of wages across treatments are apparent from the first period onward, meaning that they are not the result of how feedback affects wages over time.</p><p>We estimate a Bayesian linear mixed-effects model with fixed effects of the treatments and subject-specific random effects. We find that the odds that wages are smaller in the treatment with no feedback than in the treatments with feedback are 470:1. We have, hence, "very strong" evidence that average wages with private or public feedback are larger than those with no feedback.</p><p>More surprisingly, the odds that wages are larger in the treatment with private feedback than in the treatment with public feedback are 22.7:1.</p><p>We have, hence, "strong" evidence that average wages with private feedback are larger than those with public feedback.</p><p>We report our test of H6 in Appendix C. We find that as expected higher wage expectations are related to higher wages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Discussion</head><p>We found that wages were higher when feedback was given than when no feedback was given. Unlike expected, wages were higher with private than with public feedback.</p><p>We expected public feedback to boost wages more than private feedback. So, it was surprising that wages were higher with private feedback. Private negative feedback might "save face", while public feedback may humiliate and hurt one's ego, lowering the sense of dominance. Negative public feedback might be seen as a punishment. It may also be viewed as an attempt to limit freedom. This can cause reactance and lead to non-conformity to requests. Alternatively, once negative feedback is public, the damage may be done. The manager has "lost face. " This might make it seem useless to increase salaries.</p><p>We found that positive feedback was related to increases in valence and dominance and to reductions in arousal. Increases in valence were related to lower wages in the subsequent trial. The indirect, emotions mediated impact of positive feedback was thus negative. This was compensated by positive direct effects, so the total effect of positive feedback on wages was not significantly different from zero.</p><p>The finding that increases in valence were related to lower wages in the subsequent trial was unexpected. It contradicts for example <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Rind and Bordia (1995)</ref> whereby expression of gratitude led to increased payments of waiting staff. This finding may align with a study on negotiations. It showed that negotiators conceded more to an opponent who expressed anger than to one who expressed happiness <ref type="bibr" target="#b90">(van Kleef et al., 2004)</ref>. The authors suggest this may stem from negotiators tracking their opponents' limits through emotion perception. In the current study, deciders may have used feedback to do "limit tracking. " They may have tried to find the lowest wage that got positive feedback. They did this by lowering the wage until they got negative feedback. The results of the experiment could support a view linking emotions with cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Hanoch, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Muramatsu and Hanoch, 2005)</ref>. It is similar to an appraisal theory framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">(Scherer, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Moors et al., 2013)</ref>. An initial emotion would cause thought, which would lead to a decision, but the decision is not necessarily motivated by the emotion. The emotion would simply have signaled the need for additional attention <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Lerner et al., 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Another reason why deciders did not aim to maintain positive emotions is that those who set low wages knew it would likely get them bad feedback. Good feedback was a surprise. It created a strong, positive emotional response. This fits with neuroscientific studies investigating reward processing. These studies show that neural processing of reward is relative <ref type="bibr" target="#b88">(Tremblay and Schultz, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Isoda, 2021)</ref>. If the expectation is high but the reward lower than expected, this is considered negative. Neural responses change accordingly. Thus, the positive emotional reactions to good feedback may be mainly those of deciders whose intent was not to get good feedback. This could explain why those emotions did not translate in the expected way into decisions. We need to know more about how emotions affect the deciders' expectations and intentions. Then, we can investigate this possibility further.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.">Conclusion</head><p>We confirmed that feedback systems improve ethical behavior in an artificial labor market. Our experiment found that managers raised wages when they expected to receive feedback on them. However, public feedback had a less positive effect on wages than private feedback. We discussed that public feedback may seem harsher than private feedback. It might create less goodwill among decision-makers.</p><p>We confirmed that feedback does cause emotional reactions. Good feedback increased valence and dominance, as expected. It also decreased arousal, which was unexpected. We confirmed that emotions mediate some of the effect of feedback on decisions. Increases in dominance were related to increases in wages when feedback was public. Unexpectedly, increases in valence were linked to lower wages under both private and public feedback. This contradicted our belief. We expected deciders to want to maintain positive emotional states. They should have responded to good feedback by keeping wages unchanged.</p><p>We discussed if emotions affect decisions in other ways. In particular, emotional responses may generate subsequent strategic thoughts. Good feedback may have caused positive feelings. But, it may have also led to a reappraisal of wages if the decider did not expect or aim to get good feedback. The findings suggest that some participants aimed to maximize profits, not to feel good.</p><p>Further work could focus on the intentions and expectations of the decision-makers. This could help distinguish between expected and unexpected feedback. We also need to investigate further differences in the reaction to feedback depending on whether it is given publicly or in private. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Low and high expectations</head><p>According to H6, wages should be higher in treatments with high expectations (HLH) than in treatments with low expectations (LHL </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pay Treatment Average Wage (95% CI)</head><p>The graph shows for the different feedback conditions the average wage and their 95% credible interval for the two different wage expectations treatments.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 13</ref> shows means and 95% credible intervals for wages depending on wage expectations for the different treatments. Wages tend to be higher in the treatment with high expectations, except in the treatment with public feedback.</p><p>The odds that wages are lower in the treatment LHL than in the treatment HLH are 4.1:1.</p><p>We have, hence, "positive" evidence that average wages under high expectations are larger than those under low expectations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D. Reactance and proneness to guilt and shame</head><p>In our study we elicit a number of control variables, some of which might interact with the effects that we have discussed in the previous section. Here we look at the HPRS measure for reactance <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Dillard and Shen, 2005)</ref> and the GASP measure for guilt and shame proneness <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Cohen et al., 2011)</ref>.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 14</ref> shows the joint distribution of the two measures. To better understand whether these measures have an influence on the above results, we estimate a model where direct and indirect effects of feedback and of our mediator may interact with the measure.</p><p>Graphically, the stochastic process could be described as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">T i,t (1, F i,t ) X i ∆M i,m,t ∆W i,t θ 1 γ FX β MX β FX Here (1, F i,t )</formula><p>is a vector containing a constant and the feedback received by individual i in round t. Here we assume that valence plays the role of a mediator M i,m,t . Measures for GASP and HPRS of individual i are represented as a vector X i (including a constant). The matrix γ FX describes the interaction between feedback F i,t and measures for GASP and HPRS, X i , on the mediator ∆M i,m,t . The matrix β MX describes the interaction between the mediator ∆M i,m,t and the measures X i on the outcome ∆W i,t , i.e. on wage. The matrix β FX describes the interaction between the direct effect feedback F i,t and the measures X i on the outcome ∆W i,t .</p><p>More formally, we extend Equations (2) and (4) as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">∆M i,m,t ∼ Φ((1,F i,t )γ FX X i + η ′ i,m , τ ′ m )<label>(9)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_11">∆W i,t ∼ Φ((1,F i,t )β FX X i + ∆M ⊤ i,t β MX X i + η i , τ D )<label>(10)</label></formula><p>If the first component of X i is the constant, we can calculate the size of interaction i for the mediated effect as</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">ACMI i = (γ FX 2,i ) ⊤ β MX 1 + (γ FX 2,1 ) ⊤ β MX i .<label>(11)</label></formula><p>The size of interaction i for the direct effect is simply</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">ADE i = β FX 2,i .<label>(12)</label></formula><p>Estimation results for different measures as interaction terms are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 15</ref>.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>G.7. Opinion and personality survey</head><p>• WVS: Now we want you to give us your opinion on various topics. For each of the rows, 1 means you completely agree with the statement on the left; 4 means that you totally agree with the statement on the right. If your views fall somewhere in between, you can choose 2 if you more agree with the statement on the left, or 3 if you more agree with the statement on the right.</p><p>-Income differences must be greater for individual performance to be more rewarding. / Incomes differences should be lower.</p><p>-Companies should be more privately owned / Companies should be more stateowned.</p><p>-The state should take more responsibility to ensure that everyone is doing well / People should take more responsibility for themselves.</p><p>-With this question we want to test whether you are paying attention. / Please select answer option one.</p><p>-In the long run, hard work usually leads to a better life. / Hard work does not lead to success. Success is a matter of luck and connections.</p><p>-People only get rich at other people's expense. / Prosperity can grow so that there is enough for everyone.</p><p>-Competition is good. Competition stimulates people to work hard and develop new ideas. / Competition is harmful and leads to bad behavior</p><p>• GASP: This questionnaire describes situations that people might encounter in everyday life, followed by common reactions to these situations. As you read the scenarios, try to put yourself in that situation. Then indicate how likely it is that you would react in the way described. (1. Very unlikely, 2. Unlikely, 3. Probably, 4. Very likely)</p><p>-You have been given too much change and decide to keep it. How likely is it that you feel uncomfortable about this behavior?</p><p>-How likely are you to feel guilty about breaking the law?</p><p>-At a party, you cover up a red wine stain on a carpet without anyone noticing. How likely are you to be ashamed of your behavior?</p><p>-How likely would you feel bad about a lie that goes undetected? -Out of frustration, you secretly damage the copier at work. How likely are you to feel bad about it?</p><p>• HPRS: To what extent do the following statements correspond to your personality? (Choices: 1 to 4, from does not correspond at all to corresponds exactly)</p><p>-Regulations trigger resistance in me.</p><p>-I find it stimulating to contradict others.</p><p>-When something is prohibited, I usually think, "That's exactly what I'll do. "</p><p>-I consider advice from others as interference.</p><p>-I get frustrated when I am unable to make free and independent decisions.</p><p>-It irritates me when someone points out things that are obvious to me.</p><p>-I get angry when my freedom of choice is restricted.</p><p>-Advice and recommendations usually prompt me to do exactly the opposite.</p><p>-I resist attempts by others to influence me.</p><p>-It makes me angry when another person is held up as an example for me.</p><p>-When someone forces me to do something, I want to do the opposite.</p><p>• Big Five: What kind of personality are you? (Choices: 1 to 4, from does not correspond at all to corresponds exactly) -I am someone who works thoroughly.</p><p>-I am someone who is communicative, talkative.</p><p>-I am someone who is sometimes a bit rough with others.</p><p>-I am someone who is original, brings in new ideas.</p><p>-I am someone who often worries.</p><p>-I am someone who can forgive.</p><p>-I am someone who is rather lazy.</p><p>-I am someone who can come out of their shell, sociable.</p><p>-I am someone who appreciates artistic, aesthetic experiences.</p><p>-I am someone who effectively and efficiently completes tasks.</p><p>-I am someone who becomes easily nervous.</p><p>-I am someone who is reserved.</p><p>-I am someone who treats others considerately and kindly.</p><p>-I am someone who has a vivid imagination. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Welcome</head><p>Welcome and thank you for participating in this experiment! The purpose of the experiment is to collect your decisions and evaluate them scientifically. You will receive €3.00 for your participation. You will also receive an amount that depends on your skills and decisions. After the experiment, we will ask you a series of questions about you and the experiment. You will then be paid. Now click on the "Next" button.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Payment</head><p>We will pay you via PayPal as announced in our invitation email. If you don't have a PayPal account, you can create one now and return to the experiment later. Please enter the email address you registered with PayPal. Make sure it is correct! (email entry field) Please confirm that this email is correct. (Yes, this is the correct email, No, sorry, I will correct it now.)</p><p>If you have not received money within the next 30 days, you can contact us at (email). In order to pay you in this experiment, we need to store your decisions as well as the email address you registered with PayPal. No later than four weeks after we have paid you, we will replace your email address with a pseudonym. We will then store your decisions without any reference to you personally.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 1 of 10</head><p>Now we will give you instructions for the experiment. In this experiment there are two types of players, "calculators" and "counters". You are a calculator in this experiment. You work together with other people, whom we call "counters", on a task. The counters were recruited from the same pool of participants as you. Your goal is to work with other players to find hidden numbers that will unlock rewards of €7.00. We will first explain to you the function of the counters and the function of the calculators. Then do your work as a calculator 3 times, each times with a different person as counter. You also decide how much of the €7.00 you want to pay for each counter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 6 of 10</head><p>At the end of the experiment, one of your 3 calculations will be randomly selected. Your payment depends on whether you found the hidden number in that round and how much you wanted to pay the counter in that round. So make sure you do the math carefully every time! Also, make sure you carefully decide what you pay to the counter each time. This decision could be chosen!</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 7 of 10</head><p>We don't just ask you to make decisions! We also ask you how you feel about each of your decisions .To determine this, we use a "self-assessment manikin" that we call SAM. SAM stands for your feelings.</p><p>You use SAM to describe three different dimensions of your feelings:</p><p>• sad or happy</p><p>• calm or excited</p><p>• powerless or powerful.</p><p>We explain these three dimensions on the next pages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 8 of 10</head><p>The sad-happy dimension is the first type of emotion that SAM can represent.</p><p>At one extreme of the sad-happy scale you feel: happy, content, joyful, hopeful, enthusiastic. Then SAM looks like this:</p><p>At the other end of the scale you feel: sad, dissatisfied, melancholic, desperate, bored. Then SAM looks like this:</p><p>Finally, this is what SAM looks like when you feel completely neutral, neither really happy nor really sad:</p><p>Instructions, page 9 of 10</p><p>The Calm-Excited dimension is the second type of emotion that SAM can represent. At one extreme of the calm-excited scale you feel: excited, stimulated, frenetic, nervous, wide awake, aroused. Then SAM looks like this:</p><p>At the other end of the scale you feel: calm, relaxed, sluggish, dull, sleepy, unawakened. Then SAM looks like this:</p><p>Finally, this is what SAM looks like when you feel completely neutral, neither excited nor really calm:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 10 of 10</head><p>The last emotional scale you rate with SAM is the dimension 'Powerless-Powerful'. At one extreme of this powerless-powerful scale you feel: powerful, dominant, influential, in control, important, autonomous. Then SAM looks like this:</p><p>At the other end of the scale you feel: powerless, dominated, insignificant, controlled, unimportant, dependent. Then SAM looks like this:</p><p>Finally, this is what SAM looks like when you feel completely neutral, neither powerless nor truly powerful:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Understanding of the instructions</head><p>To check whether you have been paying attention, we will ask you 4 control questions before we begin. The experiment begins when you have answered all 4 questions correctly. (See subsection G.2)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions reminder</head><p>You are known in this experiment as PUCU. Please write down your ID on a piece of paper as you will need it later! We remind you that you are a calculator in this study. You meet a series of 3 counters that you work with to get €7.00. You decide each time how much of the €7.00 reward should be given to the counters in case of success. The rest is for you.</p><p>How much of the €7.00 reward do you intend to pay out to the counters if successful? Click on the blue bar to display the slider.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Expectations</head><p>The respondents were recruited from the same pool of participants as you. The counters have already done their part so that you as a calculator can do the second part of the work. If successful, counters will receive the amount you selected. We asked the counters what feedback they would like to give you, depending on what you pay them. Most counters you work with will only give positive feedback if you give them €4.00 or more (This is for treatment HLH, otherwise €2.00).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feedback</head><p>However, we will not show you feedback from counters about what you paid them. (This is for the treatment without feedback. In the treatment with feedback participants are told they will see feedback from workers. In the treatment with public feedback they are also told this feedback will be public.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>H.2. Recipients Welcome</head><p>Welcome and thank you for participating in this experiment! The purpose of the experiment is to collect your decisions and evaluate them scientifically. In any case, you will receive €3.00 for your participation. You will also receive an amount that depends on your skills and someone else's decisions. Now click on the "Next" button</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Payment</head><p>We will pay you via PayPal as announced in our invitation email. If you don't have a PayPal account, you can create one now and return to the experiment later. Please enter the email address you registered with PayPal. Make sure it is correct! (email entry field) Please confirm that this email is correct (Yes, this is the correct email,No, sorry, I will correct it now.)</p><p>If you have not received money within the next 30 days, you can contact us at (email).</p><p>In order to pay you in this experiment, we need to store your decisions as well as the email address you registered with PayPal. No later than four weeks after we have paid you, we will replace your email address with a pseudonym. We will then store your decisions without any reference to you personally.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 1 of 7</head><p>In this experiment there are two types of players, "calculators" and "counters". You are a counter in this experiment. They work together with other people, whom we call calculators, on a task. Your goal is to work with other players to find hidden numbers that will unlock rewards of €7.00. We will first explain to you the role of the counters and the role of the calculators. Then you will do your work as counter 3 times, each time with a different person as calculator. We will send the result of your work to the calculators. The calculators will then use the result for their work. If the total result was correct, the calculators decide how much of the €7.00 you will receive.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 2 of 7</head><p>Your task as a counter: You have to count the number of dots in a series of 5 dotted lines. You do this 3 times, once for each of the calculators you are working with.</p><p>Example: You see ……………. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>End of the experiment</head><p>Thank you for participating in the experiment. We will pay you €3.00 for your participation. We will also randomly select a calculator to determine your payout. If both of you have unlocked the reward, we will also send you the amount that this calculator paid you. If you have not received any money in the next 30 days, you can contact us at (email).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Pictorial representation of good and bad feedback</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Positive (real or anticipated) feedback over time.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Emotion dimensions and feedback over time.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Effect of a positive feedback on change of emotions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Odds for a positive impact of positive feedback on change of emotions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>shows the corresponding odds. The top part of</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Change in wage due to change in emotion.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Change in wage due to feedback last period.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 8 :Figure 9 :</head><label>89</label><figDesc>Direct and mediated effect of feedback for different parameters of the mediation model. Odds for a positive effect of feedback on different parameters of the mediation model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc>shows estimation results and 95% credible intervals. The top part ofFigure 9extends</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Figure 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Wages over time, by treatment</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head>Figure 12 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Decay (impact of lagged emotion on changes in wages).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head>Figure 13 :</head><label>13</label><figDesc>Wages depending on wage expectations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>Figure 14 :</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Joint distribution of GASP and HPRS.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>Figure 15 :</head><label>15</label><figDesc>Interactions of direct and valence mediated effects of feedback.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Frequency of observations for the different treatment combinations threshold sequence no feedback private feedback public feedback</figDesc><table><row><cell>thresholds HLH</cell><cell>98</cell><cell>106</cell><cell>102</cell></row><row><cell>thresholds LHL</cell><cell>106</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>107</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Changes in wage due to past changes in emotions (H2)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>OLS (3)</cell><cell>IV+</cell><cell>IV-</cell></row><row><cell>(Intercept)</cell><cell cols="3">-0.047 (0.042) -0.045 (0.043) -0.121 (0.045)**</cell></row><row><cell>arousal+</cell><cell>-0.044 (0.074)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>arousal-</cell><cell>0.028 (0.068)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">dominance+ 0.068 (0.078)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">dominance--0.113 (0.074)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>valence+</cell><cell cols="2">-0.138 (0.054)* -0.121 (0.100)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>valence-</cell><cell>0.023 (0.045)</cell><cell></cell><cell>-0.104 (0.087)</cell></row><row><cell>Num.Obs.</cell><cell>619</cell><cell>619</cell><cell>619</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">*  *  *  p &lt; 0.001,  *  *  p &lt; 0.01,  *  p &lt; 0.05</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Changes in wage due to feedback (H3)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>OLS</cell><cell>IV</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">(Intercept) -0.132 (0.024)*** -0.092 (0.136)</cell></row><row><cell>feedback</cell><cell cols="2">0.205 (0.040)*** 0.095 (0.365)</cell></row><row><cell>Num.Obs.</cell><cell>1238</cell><cell>1238</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">*  *  *  p &lt; 0.001,  *  *  p &lt; 0.01,  *  p &lt; 0.05</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Approximately how many experiments have you participated in before? (Choices: I have never participated in an experiment before, 1 to 5, More than 5)</figDesc><table><row><cell>• 4. Problems2: If yes, what difficulties? (Max 100 characters)</cell></row><row><cell>• 5. Experience: H. Instructions</cell></row><row><cell>H.1. Deciders</cell></row><row><cell>-I am someone who is relaxed, can cope well with stress</cell></row><row><cell>G.8. Feedback questionnaire</cell></row><row><cell>• 1. Demand: -What do you think the experiment was about?</cell></row><row><cell>• 2. Difficulty: -Was it difficult for you to understand what you had to do in this exper-</cell></row><row><cell>iment? -(Choices: Yes, No)</cell></row><row><cell>• 3. Problems: Did you have any difficulties during the experiment? (Choices: Yes, No)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The correct number of dots is 16 You see ……… The correct number of dots is 9 You see ……….. The correct number of dots is 11 You see …. The correct number of dots is 4 You see ……………… The correct number of dots is 18</figDesc><table><row><cell>0 euros •</cell><cell>•</cell></row><row><cell>1 euro •</cell><cell>•</cell></row><row><cell>2 euros •</cell><cell>•</cell></row><row><cell>3 euros •</cell><cell>•</cell></row><row><cell>4 euros •</cell><cell>•</cell></row><row><cell>5 euros •</cell><cell>•</cell></row><row><cell>6 euros •</cell><cell>•</cell></row><row><cell>7 euros •</cell><cell>•</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Decay of emotions and wages</head><p>According to H2b we expect emotions and changes in wage to be more pronounced at the beginning of the experiment than at the end. <ref type="figure">Figure 11</ref> provides an overview. arousal dominance valence wage 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3 2 3 0.2 0.4</p><p>The vertical axis shows for emotion dimensions the change in emotion |M i,m,t -M i,m,t-1 | and for the wage the change in the wage |W i,t -W i,t-1 |. Since we elicit emotions four times during the experiment, we can report three changes. Since wages are paid only three times, we report only for two rounds changes of the wage. Indeed, changes in arousal and dominance seem to decrease during the experiment. Changes in valence and wage seem to increase over time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Time: Decay of emotions and wages</head><p>According to H2b we also expect the effect of early emotions to be maintained over time (low decay rate). To investigate this hypothesis, we estimate the effect of emotions in the first and in the second round both on changes in wages in the third round. We estimate</p><p>where the emotion m of participant i at time t is M i,m,t and the lag l ∈ {1, 2} (i.e. one or two period lag). We use both OLS and an IV estimator with feedback as an instrument for the regressor. <ref type="figure">Figure 12</ref> shows estimation results.</p><p>Valence is the only emotion which shows a significant effect from the second round to wages in the third round. We do find an impact of valence on decay. The effect from the first round to wages in the third round is clearly smaller. <ref type="formula">2</ref>An overview of these results is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. Odds are provided in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. An overview of these results is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref>. Odds are provided in <ref type="figure">Figure 9</ref>. • Assuming you unlocked the reward and paid the counter €2, how much will you get? (€7, €5, €3)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E. Estimation results for Equation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E.1. No controls</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>F.1. No controls</head><p>• Assuming you unlocked the reward and paid the counter €4, how much will you get? (€7, €5, €3)</p><p>• Which of the 3 times you have done calculations will be taken into account? (One, randomly selected, All, The first time)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>G.3. Control questions 2</head><p>• What is your ID in this experiment? Please write in uppercase letters. If you are unsure of your ID, write it down as best you can. If it is not correct, we will then remind you of your actual ID. • Choose the correct option: (Choices: Most counters are already satisfied with 2€ or more, Most counters are only satisfied with 4€ or more)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>G.4. Decisions in each period</head><p>• Pay: (Currency) What the participant pays counters, shown as a slider from 0 to 7 with no preset, in steps of 0.1. Instructions, page 2 of 10</p><p>The task of the counters: Counters must count the number of dots in a series of 5 dotted lines. They do this 3 times, once for each of the calculators they are working with. Example:</p><p>• You see ……………. The correct number of dots is 16</p><p>• You see ……… The correct number of dots is 9</p><p>• You see ……….. The correct number of dots is 11</p><p>• You see …. The correct number of dots is 4</p><p>• You see …….. The correct number of dots is 8</p><p>The counters have already done their part so that you as a calculator can do the second part of the work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 3 of 10</head><p>Your task as a calculator: You use the numbers reported by counters to perform a calculation. This calculation includes addition (+), subtraction (-), multiplication (*) and division (/). You do this 3 times, once for each of the counters you are working with.</p><p>Example: The counter reports 10, 2, 15, 10, 7. You may then need to perform a calculation such as 10-2*15/10+7 or similar calculations with these numbers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 4 of 10</head><p>If neither you nor the counter make a mistake, you will find the hidden number and the €7.00 reward will be unlocked. The €7.00 will be paid to you. You then decide what portion of the €7.00 reward you want to pay to the counter. If you don't find the hidden number, the reward will not be unlocked and neither you nor the counter will get paid. This happens when the counter does not count the number of dots correctly or you do not do the calculation correctly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 5 of 10</head><p>Example 1: Suppose the counter says 10, 2, 15, 10, 8. Your calculation is then 10-2*15/10+7. The correct answer is 14, the hidden number. However, if you report 13, neither of you will get anything. This is the case even though the counter reported the numbers correctly to you.</p><p>Example 2: Suppose the correct numbers are 10, 2, 15, 10, 8. However, the counter reports 9, 2, 15, 10, 8. You calculate 9-2*15/10+7 and report 13. Your calculation is correct, but this is not the hidden number (14), so neither of you gets anything. This happens even though you have done your calculation correctly, because you have received the wrong numbers from the counter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Control questions</head><p>We will now ask you 4 control questions to check if you have been paying attention before we begin. The experiment begins when you have answered all 4 questions correctly. (See subsection G.3)</p><p>We come to the actual experiment</p><p>We now come to the part of the experiment where you do calculations and decide how much you want to pay each counter. Before we do this, we want to know how you feel right now using SAM.</p><p>How sad or happy do you feel?</p><p>How calm or excited do you feel?</p><p>How powerless or powerful do you feel?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Your decision</head><p>Counter 1 counted the following numbers: 9, 3, 7, 5, 6. Based on these numbers, please perform the following calculation: 9 * 3 -(7 + 5) / 6 Result: (number inputs)</p><p>Hint: The answer is an integer. How much would you like to pay Counter 1 if successful? Click on the blue bar to display the slider.</p><p>Reminder: You are known as PUCU in this experiment. Most counters only give positive feedback if you give them€4.00 or more. We will not show you any feedback from Counter 1 about what you paid them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>You are known as PUCU in this experiment. You have decided to pay Counter 1 €4.90 (This is for the treatment without feedback. In treatment with feedback they see the feedback (thumb up or down) and in the treatment without feedback they are reminded this feedback will be made public).</p><p>How do you feel about this? (Same elicitation of emotions as before.) (Those two steps of decision and result are repeated over three rounds.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feedback</head><p>You have now made all your payment decisions. Finally, we would like to know how you judge your behavior in this experiment from a moral point of view (See subsection G.5).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Questionnaire, page 1 of 8</head><p>Now that the experiment is over, we will ask you a series of questions about yourself. You will then be paid. These questions are divided into 8 pages, with 5 to 10 questions on each page. For participating in this survey you will receive an additional €2.00. Please do your best to answer each question carefully and truthfully. The answers to these questions are important to evaluate the results of this experiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Questionnaire, page 2 of 8</head><p>On this page we want to learn about you (See subsection G.6).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Questionnaire, pages 3 to 7 of 8</head><p>(See subsection G.7).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Questionnaire, page 8 of 8</head><p>(See subsection G.8).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>End of the experiment</head><p>The experiment is now over. Thank you for your participation! Your decision in Round 1 was randomly selected for payment. In this round, your answer was wrong. You calculated 18, but the hidden number was 25. Therefore, you will not receive the €7.00 reward. You will only receive €3.00 + €2.00 = €5.00 as compensation for participating in this experiment. You can contact us at (email) if you have not received this payout within the next 30 days.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 3 of 7</head><p>The task of calculators: Calculators use the numbers you provide to perform a calculation. This calculation includes addition (+), subtraction (-), multiplication (*) and division (/). Calculators do this 3 times, once for each of the counters they are working with.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Example:</head><p>You report counting 10, 2, 15, 10 and 7 dots. The calculator may then need to perform a calculation such as 10-2*15/10+7 or similar calculations on these numbers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 4 of 7</head><p>If neither you nor the calculator make a mistake, the calculator will find the hidden number and the reward €7.00 will be unlocked. The €7.00 is paid to the calculator. The calculator then decides what share of the €7.00 you will receive. If the calculator does not find the hidden number, the reward will not be unlocked and neither you nor the calculator will be paid. This happens when you do not count the number of dots correctly or the calculator does not perform the calculation correctly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 5 of 7</head><p>Example 1: Suppose you report 10, 2, 15, 10, 8 and the calculator has to calculate 10-2*15/10+7. The correct answer is 14, the hidden number. However, if the calculator says 13, neither of you will get anything. This happens even though you entered the numbers correctly.</p><p>Example 2: Suppose the correct numbers are 10, 2, 15, 10, 8, but you report 9, 2, 15, 10, 8. The calculator calculates 9-2*15/10+7 and reports 13. However, this is not the hidden number (14), so neither of you gets anything. This happens even though the calculator performed the calculation correctly, because you reported the wrong numbers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 6 of 7</head><p>At the end of the experiment, one of the 3 calculators you worked with will be randomly selected. Your payment depends on whether the hidden number was found in this round and how much the calculator pays you in this round. Any of the 3 calculators you are working with can be selected. Therefore, count the dots carefully each time!</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Instructions, page 7 of 7</head><p>To check whether you have been paying attention, we will ask you 4 control questions before we begin. The experiment begins when you have answered all 4 questions correctly.</p><p>What is your job? (I have to count dots on 5 lines, I have to calculate with 5 numbers) Suppose you unlocked the reward and the calculator pays you €2, how much does the calculator get? (7€, 5€, 3€)</p><p>Suppose you unlocked the reward and the calculator pays you €4, how much does the calculator get? (7€, 5€, 3€)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Count 1</head><p>We now ask you to count for calculator 1: 1) ……… How many dots does row 1 have? 2) … How many dots does row 2 have? 3) ……. How many dots does row 3 have? 4) ….. How many dots does row 4 have? 5) …… How many dots does row 5 have? (This is presented three times)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feedback</head><p>Now tell us what feedback we should give the calculators based on how much they pay you. Depending on what they pay you and your feedback decision, the calculators will either receive: -a positive feedback (green signal with a thumb up): or -a negative feedback (red signal with a thumb down):</p><p>We think it makes sense to give positive feedback as long as the calculator pays you something. This is because some of them may decide not to pay you anything. Therefore, it makes sense to give good feedback to those who pay something.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inequality and happiness: are Europeans and Americans different</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Alesina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Tella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Macculloch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2009" to="2042" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Giving negative feedback to Millennials: How can managers criticize the &quot;most praised&quot; generation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Buchko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Buchko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Research Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="692" to="705" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The enduring impact of transient emotions on decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Andrade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior And Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Carrot or the Stick: Rewards, Punishments, and Cooperation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Andreoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Harbaugh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Vesterlund</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="893" to="902" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Avoiding the Ask: A Field Experiment on Altruism, Empathy, and Charitable Giving</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Andreoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Trachtman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Political Economy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="625" to="653" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic Research Evolves: Fields and Styles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Angrist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Azoulay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ellison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="297" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating the impact of guilt and shame proneness on consumer ethics: A cross national study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Arli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Leo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tjiptono</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Consumer Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motives and comprehension in a public goods game with induced emotions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bartke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bosworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Snower</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Chierchia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Theory and Decision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="238" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Emotion Shapes Behavior: Feedback, Anticipation, and Reflection, Rather Than Direct Causation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Baumeister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Vohs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Nathan Dewall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="203" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reciprocity and emotions in bargaining using physiological and self-report measures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ben-Shakhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Bornstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hopfensitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Van Winden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="314" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Well-being over time in Britain and the USA</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Blanchflower</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oswald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7-8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1359" to="1386" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anonymity versus Punishment in Ultimatum Bargaining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Bolton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Zwick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Games and Economic Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="121" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of real effort and emotions in the power-to-take game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bosman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sutter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Van Winden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="407" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotional Hazard in a Power-to-Take Experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bosman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Van Winden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Economic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">476</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="169" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moral emotions and partnership</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bracht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Regner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="326" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring emotion: The self-assessment manikin and the semantic differential</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bradley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavior Therapy and Experimental Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="59" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competitive rivalry, social disposition, and subjective well-being: An experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brandts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Van Winden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1158" to="1167" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shaming as an incentive mechanism against stealing: Behavioral and physiological evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Brocas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Carrillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">194</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">104351</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-esteem and reactions to negative feedback: Toward greater generalizability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brockner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Derr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Laing</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research in Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="318" to="333" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavioral inhibition, behavioral activation, and affective responses to impending reward and punishment: The BIS/BAS Scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Carver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="333" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How emotions mediate the effects of perceived justice on loyalty in service recovery situations: An empirical study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-C</forename><surname>Chebat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Slusarczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="664" to="673" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">oTree-An open-source platform for laboratory, online, and field experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schonger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wickens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="88" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introducing the GASP scale: A new measure of guilt and shame proneness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wolf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Panter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Insko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="947" to="966" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tax evasion and emotions: An empirical test of re-integrative shaming theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Coricelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Rusconi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Villeval</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="61" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Changes in Intrinsic Motivation as a Function of Negative Feedback and Threats. Presented at the Eastern Psychological Association Meeting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Deci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cascio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://eric.ed.gov/?id=ED063558" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972-04" />
			<pubPlace>Boston, Mass</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motivating teams: Private feedback and public recognition at work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Delavallade</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">197</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">104405</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The digitization of word of mouth: Promise and challenges of online feedback mechanisms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dellarocas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1407" to="1424" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">runjags: An R package providing interface utilities, model templates, parallel computing methods and additional distributions for MCMC models in JAGS</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Denwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the Nature of Reactance and its Role in Persuasive Health Communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dillard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communication Monographs</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="144" to="168" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of induced emotions on pro-social behaviour</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Drouvelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Grosskopf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">134</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tax compliance and psychic costs: Behavioral experimental evidence using a physiological marker</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Dulleck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fooken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Newton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ristl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schaffner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Torgler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Public Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">134</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion, Regulation, and Moral Development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Eisenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="665" to="697" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anticipated verbal feedback induces altruistic behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ellingsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Johannesson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Evolution and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="100" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Appraisal and Feedback: Making Performance Review Work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fletcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>CIPD Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reputation and trust on online labour markets: the reputation economy of Elance. Work Organisation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gandini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Pais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Beraldo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Labour &amp; Globalisation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="43" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion and Ethical Decision-Making in Organizations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gaudine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Thorne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business Ethics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavioral models of managerial decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Goldfarb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T.-H</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Amaldoss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Galasso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hossain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="405" to="421" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lying, Guilt, and Shame</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Greenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Smeets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhurakhovska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.aeaweb.org/conference/2015/retrieve.php?pdfid=1669&amp;tk=sNTAR9Tk" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Presented at the 2015 ASSA Annual Meeting</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subject pool recruitment procedures: organizing experiments with ORSEE</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Greiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Economic Science Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="114" to="125" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">World Values Survey Wave 7 (2017-2022) cross-national data-set</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Haerpfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Inglehart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moreno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Welzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kizilova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Diez-Medrano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lagos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Norris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ponarin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Puranen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Version: 4.0.0. World Values Survey Association</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Six Decades of Top Economics Publishing: Who and How</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Hamermesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Literature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="162" to="172" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neither an angel nor an ant&quot;: Emotion as an aid to bounded rationality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hanoch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Warm glow vs. altruistic values: How important is intrinsic emotional reward in proenvironmental behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hartmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eisend</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Apaolaza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Souza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Environmental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The power of feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hattie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Timperley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review of Educational Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="112" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Performance Appraisal Procedural Justice: The Role of a Manager&apos;s Implicit Person Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Heslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Vandewalle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1694" to="1718" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contact points and flash points: Conceptualizing the use of justice mechanisms in the performance appraisal interview</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Holbrook</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Resource Management Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Socially relative reward valuation in the primate brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Isoda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Neurobiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Un)Ethical Behavior and Performance Appraisal: The Role of Affect, Support, and Organizational Justice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Jacobs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Belschak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Hartog</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business Ethics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">121</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="76" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotions, Sanctions, and Cooperation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Joffily</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Masclet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Noussair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Villeval</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Southern Economic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1002" to="1027" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayes factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">430</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="773" to="795" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How Do Emotions Affect Decision Making?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lerner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dorison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Klusowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/xbsza</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/xbsza" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
			<publisher>PsyArXiv Preprints</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion and decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lerner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Valdesolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kassam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review Of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="799" to="823" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heart strings and purse strings: Carryover effects of emotions on economic decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lerner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Small</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="341" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of emotions in the endowment effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C.-H</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-C</forename><surname>Chuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Kao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C.-Y</forename><surname>Kung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="589" to="597" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moral Emotions and Ethics in Organisations: Introduction to the Special Issue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lindebaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Geddes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Gabriel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Business Ethics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">141</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="645" to="656" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Power of Feedback: Giving, Seeking, and Using Feedback for Performance Improvement. Routledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>London</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reputation and social (dis)approval in feedback mechanisms: An experimental study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lumeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Masclet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pénard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regret, disappointment and the endowment effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Martinez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zeelenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rijsman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="962" to="968" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Monetary and Nonmonetary Punishment in the Voluntary Contributions Mechanism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Masclet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Noussair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-C</forename><surname>Villeval</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="366" to="380" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Appraisal theories of emotion: State of the art and future development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moors</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ellsworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Scherer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Frijda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="124" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feedback on feedback practice: Perceptions of students and academics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mulliner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Assessment &amp; Evaluation in Higher Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="266" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotions as a mechanism for boundedly rational agents: The fast and frugal way</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Muramatsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hanoch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="221" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incidental Emotions and Cooperation in a Public Goods Game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Noussair</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">800701</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Does Emotion Relate To Cooperation In Social Dilemmas? A Review Of Literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Ning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Mahmud</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Positive School Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3449" to="3467" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of emotions in public goods games with and without punishment opportunities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Noussair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Breaban</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">217</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="631" to="646" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Norm Activation Model: An exploration of the functions of anticipated pride and guilt in pro-environmental behaviour</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Onwezen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Antonides</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bartels</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="153" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affective basis of judgment-behavior discrepancy in virtual experiences of moral dilemmas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Patil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cogoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Zangrando</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Chittaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Silani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="94" to="107" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Good and Guilt-Free: The Role of Self-Accountability in Influencing Preferences for Products with Ethical Attributes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Peloza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="119" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The multiplicity of emotions: A framework of emotional functions in decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H.-R</forename><surname>Pfister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Böhm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consumer Social Responsibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pigors</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rockenbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3123" to="3137" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jags: A program for analysis of bayesian graphical models using Gibbs sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Plummer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">3rd International Workshop on Distributed Statistical Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Vienna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">124</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Austria</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Vienna, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring personality in one minute or less: A 10-item short version of the Big Five Inventory in English and German</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rammstedt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research in Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="212" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fairness perceptions and prosocial emotions in the power to take</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Reuben</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Van Winden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="908" to="922" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reluctant altruism and peer pressure in charitable giving</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reyniers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bhalla</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of server&apos;s &quot;thank you&quot; and personalization on restaurant tipping</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rind</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bordia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="745" to="751" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Belief and feeling: Evidence for an accessibility model of emotional self-report</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Clore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="934" to="960" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How guilt affects consumption intention: The role of rumination, emotional support and shame</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Saintives</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Lunardo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Marketing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="51" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Giving feedback -An integral part of education</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schartel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Best Practice &amp; Research Clinical Anaesthesiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="87" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">editor, Handbook of cognition and emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Scherer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Dalgleish, T. &amp; Power, M. J.,</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="637" to="663" />
			<pubPlace>Chichester, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Appraisal theory</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Praise in Public, Criticize in Private? An Assessment of Performance Feedback Transparency in a Classroom Setting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Seevers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Rowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Skinner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing Education Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="100" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Effect of Rewards and Sanctions in Provision of Public Goods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sefton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shupp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Economic Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="671" to="690" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Die Strategiemethode zur Erforschung des Eingeschränkt rationalen Verhaltens im Rahmen eines Oligopolexperiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Selten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Beiträge zur experimentellen Wirtschaftsforschung</title>
		<editor>J.C.B. Mohr</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Paul Siebeck</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="136" to="168" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Public Versus Private Feedback: Who Gains From Anonymity? SSRN</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Reddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.3958814</idno>
		<ptr target="https://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3958814" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reputation and Feedback Systems in Online Platform Markets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tadelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="340" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Moral Emotions and Moral Behavior. Annual review of psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Tangney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Stuewig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mashek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="372" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The German Ethical Culture Scale (GECS): Development and First Construct Testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tanner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Gangl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Witt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1667</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relative reward preference in primate orbitofrontal cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Tremblay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">398</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6729</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="704" to="708" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Manipulations of Emotional Context Shape Moral Judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Valdesolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Desteno</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="476" to="477" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The interpersonal effects of anger and happiness in negotiations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Van Kleef</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K W</forename><surname>De Dreu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S R</forename><surname>Manstead</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="76" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Avoiding the sharp tongue: Anticipated written messages promote fair economic exchange</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Houser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="393" to="404" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of moral emotions and individual differences in consumer responses to corporate green and non-green actions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bagozzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Grønhaug</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="356" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shame: Does It Fit in the Workplace? Examining Supervisor Negative Feedback Effect on Task Performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Khan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Saeed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohamed</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology Research and Behavior Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2461" to="2475" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
