<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Universal Problem Solver: Viewing the Mind as a Difference Engine</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Millroth</surname></persName>
							<email>philip.millroth@psyk.uu.se</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Uppsala University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SE">Sweden</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">August</forename><surname>Collsiöö</surname></persName>
							<email>august.collsioo@psyk.uu.se</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Uppsala University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SE">Sweden</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Universal Problem Solver: Viewing the Mind as a Difference Engine</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:00+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>decision making</term>
					<term>cognitive strategies</term>
					<term>theory integration</term>
					<term>ecological validity</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Research on Artificial Intelligence and Psychology has traditionally been heavily intertwined. Thus, it is surprising that the ideas of Marvin Minsky (1927-2016) have not gained more interest among researchers in Psychology. One specific idea that persisted over decades in Minsky&apos;s work was that of the mind as a differenceengine. The idea posits that as soon as there is a goal, the mind works to reduce or eliminate the important differences between the current state and some desired goal. Several aspects of this idea precedes Minsky and has already proved fruitful for psychological researchers, yet there are aspects that deserve further work.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Many would agree that psychological science will have reached its goal when a set of principles (i.e., computational theories: <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Marr, 1982)</ref> that are responsible for producing human intelligence have been uncovered. Traditionally, the pursuit of identifying such principles have been rooted in solid preconceptions about how a "rational" agent should, in general, behave <ref type="bibr">(McCarthy, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Millroth et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Minsky, 2007)</ref>. While this approach has undoubtedly been fruitful (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Anderson, 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Chase et al., 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Marr, 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chater &amp; Oaksford, 1999)</ref>, it has been repeatedly argued that the understanding of human behavior is still meager because not enough effort has gone into studying the actual problems and goals of individuals, leading to premature assumptions about normative theory that can be used to guide research at the computational level of analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Millroth et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Minsky, 1974;</ref>. How, then, could we aid our understanding of where computational models come from, especially when human behaviors do not seem to converge with the typical normative theory of the specific research area? For this pursuit, we propose that the cognitive sciences would benefit from incorporating a central tenet in the works of the late Marvin <ref type="bibr">Minsky (1927</ref><ref type="bibr">Minsky ( -2016</ref>: the idea that the mind can be viewed as a difference engine. Influenced by <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Newell-and Simon's (1961;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">1972)</ref> work on the General Problem Solver (GPS), the almost over-simplistic and familiar idea holds that the mind constantly works to reduce or eliminate the critical differences between the current state and some desired goal state.</p><p>We will briefly review the basic mechanisms of the proposed difference engine, note to what extent that we believe the cognitive sciences have not embraced the idea, and finally we end with pointing out how embracing this idea invites new research directions. We also note that the idea involves conceptual similarities with other theories highlighting that cognitive systems constantly transition between different states (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Behrens et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Buss et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Decker et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Friston, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Laird et al., 1987;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Whiteson, 2010)</ref>. However, here we purposively do not wish to constrain the idea to a mathematical framework because we believe the difference engine's conceptual parts must be fully developed first.</p><p>The difference engine starts when a description of a sufficiently positive or negative possible future situation is evoked (e.g., "It would be fun to go to the concert next week" / "I'll be evicted if I don't pay the rent next week"). From here, the current state (e.g., "I am broke") and the goal state (e.g., being at the concert / paying the rent on time) are compared. After that, methods are applied to reduce those particular kinds of differences (e.g., going to the pawnshop and selling a valuable watch). While the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Newell and Simon (1961;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">1972</ref>; see also <ref type="bibr">Newell, 1992)</ref> was generally applied to a narrow set of problem-solving contexts, <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Minsky (1988;</ref> hypothesized that, inside each human brain, many such processes all run at once, at various levels in various realms. These range from automatic systems that work all the time-like those that maintain our temperatures (and these are so opaque to reflection that we don't recognize them as goals at all)-to those highest cognitive levels (e.g., language, social relationships, problem-solving).</p><p>To <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Minsky's (2007)</ref> grievance, cognitive scientists after Newell and Simon seemed to lose interest in the pursuit of understanding human intelligence through the lens of a difference engine <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Minsky, 2007)</ref>. In a sense, this concern echoes that raised in the seminal work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Miller, Galanter, Pribram (1960)</ref>: while it is true that the full complexity of human behavior cannot be captured by stimulus-response modeling, it is also true that cognitive psychologists at times tend to get pre-occupied by describing the execution of a stepwise plan that occur between the stimuli presentation and the response. What are the intentions and values triggering the execution of specific plans?</p><p>This is not to say that the concepts of current states and goal states are lacking. Cognitive researchers have, from various perspectives, stressed the importance of the goal state for understanding human behavior (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Anderson, 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Chase et al., 1998</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Marr, 1982)</ref>. The field has also stressed that an individual's current state is essential (e.g., rich and poor people may have different utility functions: e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979)</ref>. In an even broader sense, theories of motivation-among the most influential in Psychology -deal with current and goal states (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Festinger, 1957;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Locke &amp; Latham, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Maslow, 1962;</ref><ref type="bibr">Zimmermann, 2000)</ref>. However, in our opinion (and arguably also <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Minsky's, 1974;</ref>, it is often the case that goal states are beforehand assumed by researchers, derived by a priori conceptions of different rationality accounts (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Millroth et al., 2021)</ref>, rather than by scrutiny of the current state and its interaction with the environment. For example, the field of decision-making under risk has generally been concerned with creating theories and models that can be used to describe and predict behavior at the aggregate level, assuming that individual differences (e.g., of current states) are normally distributed (e.g., Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1992 -but for recent exceptions, see <ref type="bibr">Brooks &amp; Sokol-Hessner, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr">Mishra et al., 2017)</ref>.</p><p>The Minskyian alternative is to thoroughly scrutinize the current state before making assumptions about the goal state and to allow a heterogeneity of goals. Erroneous or sparse specification of the current state can lead to premature assumptions about the goal state. In the prolonging, such hasty assumptions about what differences the engine is currently trying to eradicate will also bring a misleading understanding of the applied cognitive strategies involved. Even more seriously, it may lead researchers to disqualify a set of strategies before considering them.</p><p>Admittedly, this pursuit is immense. Not least because the current state could theoretically incorporate all the knowledge and experience, the individual has acquired so far in life -a practically inconvenient definition for research purposes. A first task would thus be to work out a pragmatic framework for what current states entail and how to study their functions in the difference engine. Perhaps it can be constrained to involve previous experience with identical or similar situations, volatile real-time factors relevant to the situation (e.g., level of hunger), and stable biological and cognitive factors pertinent to the situation. A second task would be to conduct a humble pursuit towards mapping the different goals evoked as a function of how different environments interact with the current state (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Simon, 1956)</ref>. Thus, even before starting to research the different types of methods that people use to close the difference between the current state and goal state (e.g., decision-making strategies) -we would require an extensive mapping, more in the spirit of Linnaeus's taxonomy in Zoology than the Newtonian ideals of laws <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Millroth et al., 2021)</ref>. Recent neuroscience efforts that have tried to provide "cognitive atlases" for mapping brain functions with experimental tasks offer valuable inspiration (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Poldrack &amp; Yarkoni, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Varoquaux et al., 2018)</ref>. Finally, in the mission of identifying the methods (e.g., decision-making strategies) that people use, researchers will need to consider not only how current states influence method selection but also the notion of how and when the difference engine may switch goals if the methods used are unsuccessful for the initial transition between the current state and the goal state (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Monsell, 2003)</ref>. Similarly, how does the difference engine proceed if goals conflict with each other <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Mansouri et al., 2017</ref>)?</p><p>Minsky's difference engine is a wide-reaching conceptual umbrella and could be argued to be overly flexible. Even so, if applied as a theoretical lens -not a set theorywe believe it can serve as a guiding compass to cognitive researchers by forcing them to understand what goes into a behavior even before the actual behavior (e.g., applying a decision-making strategy) is triggered. In other words, the idea of the difference engine could serve as a compass in the pursuit of mapping the wide variety of computational theories that may ultimately be necessary to understand human cognition fully.</p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The architecture of cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What is a cognitive map? Organizing knowledge for flexible behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Behrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Whittington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Baram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stachenfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kurth-Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="490" to="509" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Z.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dimensional attention as a mechanism of executive function: Integrating flexibility, selectivity, and stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Buss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kerr-German</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">192</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Chase</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Visions of rationality. Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="214" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ten years of the rational analysis of cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Oaksford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From creatures of habit to goal-directed learners: Tracking the developmental emergence of model-based reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Decker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Otto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hartley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="848" to="858" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Festinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">A theory of cognitive dissonance</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Stanford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1957" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The free-energy principle: a unified brain theory?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Friston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospect theory: An analysis of decisions under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">278</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Soar: An architecture for general intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Laird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Rosenbloom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Artificial intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New directions in goal-setting theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Locke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Latham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="268" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing competing goals-a key role for the frontopolar cortex</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mansouri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Koechlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="645" to="657" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Vision: A computational investigation into the human representation and processing of visual information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Marr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Toward a psychology of being</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Maslow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1962" />
			<publisher>General Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From here to human-level AI</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mccharthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">171</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1174" to="1182" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Plans and the structure of behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Galanter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Pribram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
			<publisher>Henry Holt and Company</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitiva Speciebus: Towards a Linnaean Approach to Cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Millroth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Collsiöö</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Juslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="176" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A framework for representing knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Minsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>MIT Artificial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Artificial Intelligence Memo No. 36</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Society of mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Minsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>Simon and Schuster</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The emotion machine: Commonsense thinking, artificial intelligence, and the future of the human mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Minsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>Simon and Schuster</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Task switching</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Monsell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="140" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">GPS -a program that simulates human problemsolving</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of a conference in learning automata</title>
		<meeting>a conference in learning automata<address><addrLine>Munich</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
			<biblScope unit="page">49</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Human problem solving</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<publisher>Prentice-Hall</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From brain maps to cognitive ontologies: informatics and the search for mental structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Poldrack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Yarkoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="587" to="612" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rational choice and the structure of the environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Atlases of cognition with large-scale human brain mapping</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Varoquaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Poldrack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Gauthier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bzdok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Poline</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Thirion</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1006565</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Whiteson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Adaptive representations for reinforcement learning</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">291</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attaining self-regulation: A social cognitive perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Zimmerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of self-regulation</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="39" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
