<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Reward Sensitivity and Noise Contribute to Negative Affective Bias: a Learning Signal Detection Theory Approach in Decision-Making</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isabel</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Lütkenherm</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Cognitive Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shannon</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Locke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Département d&apos;Études Cognitives</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire des Systèmes Perceptifs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">École Normale Supérieure</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">PSL University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">CNRS</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Paris</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oliver</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Cognitive Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Reward Sensitivity and Noise Contribute to Negative Affective Bias: a Learning Signal Detection Theory Approach in Decision-Making</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:01+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Negative Affective Bias</term>
					<term>Signal Detection Theory</term>
					<term>Mood Disorders</term>
					<term>Reward Sensitivity</term>
					<term>Reinforcement Learning</term>
					<term>Prospect Theory</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>In patients with mood disorders, negative affective biases-systematically prioritising and interpreting information negatively-are common. A translational cognitive task testing this bias has shown that depressed patients have a reduced preference for a high reward under ambiguous decision-making conditions. The precise mechanisms underscoring this bias are, however, not yet understood. We therefore developed a set of measures to probe the underlying source of the behavioural bias by testing its relationship to a participant&apos;s reward sensitivity, value sensitivity and reward learning rate. One-hundred-forty-eight participants completed three online behavioural tasks: the original ambiguous-cue decision-making task probing negative affective bias, a probabilistic reward learning task probing reward sensitivity and reward learning rate, and a gambling task probing value sensitivity. We modelled the learning task through a dynamic signal detection theory model and the gambling task through an expectation-maximisation prospect theory model. Reward sensitivity from the probabilistic reward task (ß = 0.131, p=0.024) and setting noise from the probabilistic reward task (ß=-0.187, p = 0.028) both predicted the affective bias score in a logistic regression. Increased negative affective bias in depression, at least on this specific task, may therefore be driven in part by a combination of reduced sensitivity to rewards and more variable responses.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Negative affective biases, the tendency to prioritise negative over positive information, are a core feature of mood disorders <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Everaert et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Roiser et al., 2012)</ref> and are found, for instance, in emotional perceptual processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Park et al., 2016)</ref> as well as decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Aylward et al., 2020)</ref>. Targeting these negativity biases is the goal of many current treatment options, but many mood disorder patients fail to recover with our current treatments. Therefore, understanding the precise mechanisms of negative affective biases is crucial to a better understanding of mood disorders and how to treat them.</p><p>To study negative affective biases, a translational decision-making paradigm has been developed. Negative affective bias on this task is measured as a decision-making bias on ambiguous trials away from highreward responses, i.e., interpreting an ambiguous trial as having a low-reward outcome. Within this paradigm, negative bias was higher in depressed human clinical groups <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Aylward et al., 2020</ref>), a rodent model of depression <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Hales et al., 2016)</ref> and is related to individual differences in depression scores in the general population <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Daniel-Watanabe et al., 2022)</ref>.</p><p>Using a signal detection theory (SDT) model, a reanalysis of the data of the original ambiguous-cue decision-making task testing negative affective bias in a human clinical population <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Aylward et al., 2020)</ref> linked mood disorders to decision conservatism <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Locke &amp; Robinson, 2021)</ref>. Within the SDT framework conservatism is a particular type of sub-optimal behaviour, where the criterion is placed close to the neutral location showing an absence of a strong preference for one choice over the other. In an unequal reward context, an increased propensity to consider the low-reward option, in effect treating unequal reward options as more equal, is both a conservative shift in criterion placement and a bias away from the higher reward i.e., a negative affective bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Locke &amp; Robinson, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>However, this observed conservatism/negativity bias may be driven by a host of underlying processes. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Locke and Robinson (2021)</ref> identified multiple possible mechanisms: incorrect beliefs about prior probabilities and performance, undervaluing rewards, learning sub-optimally in rewarding contexts and a preference for accurate responding. In this study, we test whether sub-optimal reward-learning or diminished subjective value representations underly the original measure of negative affective bias.</p><p>In depression, sub-optimal reward learning has been linked to both decreased reward sensitivity (i.e., depressed individuals are less interested in a given reward) and decreased reward learning rates (i.e., depressed individuals are slower to update their behaviour in response to rewards) <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Halahakoon et al., 2020)</ref>. Specifically, depression was linked to a decrease in reward sensitivity in a probabilistic reward task, in which depressed participants showed task conservatism <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Huys et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Pizzagalli et al., 2008</ref>) and a simulation meta-analytic study showed that depressed individuals had lower reward learning rates during reinforcement learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Pike &amp; Robinson, 2022)</ref>. Together these findings stress the importance of considering dynamic reward contexts when studying the origin of biases away from high rewards. We, therefore, predict that a conservative shift away from the high-reward option on the ambiguous-cue decision-making task should be underscored by a reduced sensitivity to reward during learning and/or a suboptimal reward learning rate.</p><p>Depression is, however, also linked to undervaluing rewards in static contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Halahakoon et al., 2020)</ref>. Value sensitivity is distinct from reward sensitivity in that value sensitivity refers to the subjective evaluation of the magnitude of a potential future reward outcome, whereas reward sensitivity refers to how received reward outcomes shape subsequent behaviour and beliefs. The link between depression and subjective value sensitivity has been shown through option valuation tasks, in which probabilities, reward and cost outcomes are explicitly known (unlike in reward learning tasks) and choices should be influenced by subjective value representations. Diminished subjective value representations are linked to conservative responding as modelled under SDT <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Ackermann &amp; Landy, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Locke &amp; Robinson, 2021)</ref>.When maximising reward, the criterion placement shift depends on maximising the expected gain of subjective reward values. When the expected gain of values does not differ between high and low objective reward values, in effect the two unequal reward options are treated as equal, the criterion is shifted towards the neutral position and results in a conservative behavioural response. Therefore, we expect diminished subjective value representations of rewards to lead to more negative affective bias on the ambiguous-cue decision-making task.</p><p>In sum, depression is linked to negative affective biases and a reduced sensitivity to the subjective value and the objective outcome of rewards in static and dynamic contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Halahakoon et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Pike &amp; Robinson, 2022)</ref>. We therefore related multiple aspects of reward processing in our study, namely a general, subjective loss of representing the accurate value of reward magnitude and a loss of reward sensitivity in dynamic contexts, to the negative affective bias signature of the original decision-making task. We replicated the online version of the original ambiguous-cue decision-making task <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Daniel-Watanabe et al., 2022)</ref> to obtain the original negative affective bias measure. We adapted Norton et al. (2019) task to a probabilistic reward learning task to probe the relationship between our negative affective bias signature, reward sensitivity and learning rate. We chose to adapt this design, as it allowed us to model conservative reward processing and learning rate separately in a dynamic SDT model. Further, dynamic SDT models can unify learning mechanisms with SDT decision-making and therein model a respondents' degree of conservatism in a dynamic learning context. We predicted that conservative behaviour on the learning task due to diminished sensitivity to reward would be associated with more negative affective bias. Participants also completed a gambling task, and we modelled their risk aversion, loss aversion and inverse temperature parameter through a Prospect Theory model. We predicted that diminished representations of the subjective value of rewards, as modelled by our risk aversion parameter, would be associated with more negative affective bias on the ambiguous-cue decision-making task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Participants</head><p>We recruited 150 participants (98 women, mean age 39 years) online through Prolific (www.prolific.co) using the following selection criteria: 18 years or older, spoke English fluently, and had no cognitive impairment, neurological impairment, or prior head injuries. The data of two participants was not complete, leaving a final sample of 148 participants who completed all three tasks. A sample size of 105 participants is required to achieve 90 % power in a two-tailed correlation (at p= 0.05, for effect size d = 0.3 for the correlation between two tasks). We increased our sample size as the difficulty of the dynamic SDT task was predicted to have high sensitivity analysis exclusion rates based on pilot data. The study was approved by the University College London Research Ethics Committee (protocol number: 15253/001). All participants received details of the experimental procedures and provided consent via an online form prior to participation in the experiment. Participants were reimbursed at a rate of £7.50/hour with the chance to win a £1 bonus depending on task performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Experimental Design</head><p>The experiment was conducted on the Gorilla platform (www.gorilla.sc) where each participant completed three online, computerised tasks: 1) a dynamic reward task, 2) a replication of the original affective bias task, and 3) a classic gambling task, in this order. Participants completed the dynamic reward task first, as pilot testing revealed a risk of non-engagement with this task. Participants failing comprehension (N=88) and attention checks (N=2) for the dynamic reward task were redirected out of the study and were not part of our final N=148. Each experimental session lasted approximately 45 minutes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Affective Bias Task : the Ambiguous-Cue Decision-Making Task</head><p>Adapting the experimental paradigm of Daniel-Watanabe et al. <ref type="formula">2022</ref>, participants completed an ambiguous-cue decision-making task consisting of 20 learning trials and 120 test trials.</p><p>In the learning phase, participants saw a thick black line tilted either 45° left or right of vertical. The line was presented for 1000 ms, followed by a fixation cross of 750 ms. Participants were instructed to respond with "z" or "m" and learnt the correct association for reward (left-tilt requiring a "z" response and right-tilt a "m" response) through trial and error. Upon a correct response, positive feedback was given for 750 ms ("Correct, win £4" or "Correct, win £1"). Incorrect or late trials incurred an experimental pause of 3250 ms with feedback reading "incorrect!" or "too late, timeout!" before proceeding to the subsequent trial. Both stimuli were equally likely to be presented, but their reward structure was unequal: counterbalancing the stimulus-reward associations, one stimulus-response pair was awarded a virtual £1, and the other £4 ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure  1</ref>). In the learning phase (20 trials), participants learned associations between stimuli (left-and right-tilted lines), responses ("z" or "m" respectively) and reward outcomes (counter-balanced across participants) through trial-and-error. Here we depicted one counterbalanced rewardcontingency condition. Participants who pressed "z" when seeing a left-slanted line received 1 virtual pound. When seeing a rightslanted line, an "m" response received 4 virtual pounds. B) The testing phase consisted of three equally likely appearing stimuli: the left-slanted line, the right-slanted line, and a horizontal line. The horizontal line is called "ambiguous stimulus" due to its intermediate representation and was used to calculate the affective bias score. C) A schematic representation of ambiguous trials and rewards. On half of the trials, the ambiguous stimuli belonged to the left-tilt category, and the other half to the right-tilt category, unbeknownst to the participant. If participants responded with the correct category-response association, they received the reward associated with that category.</p><p>In the testing phase, participants saw the same task setup as in the learning phase. However, an intermediate stimulus, a horizontal line (0°), was added. The three potential stimuli were again presented equally often (i.e., 33% of trials). Unbeknownst to the participant, the horizontal stimulus of a given trial randomly belonged to either the "left-tilt" or "right-tilt" category. If the correct response was given according to this random assignment, the reward on those trials mirrored the response-reward associations of the randomly allocated stimulus category.</p><p>As per Daniel-Watanabe et al. <ref type="formula">2022</ref>, we measured negative bias as the proportion of high reward choices on ambiguous stimuli. That is, we quantified how often an individual participant selected the response associated with the £4 rewarded category when they saw the horizontal stimuli and did not time-out, giving us the dependent variable p(mid as high). Given the task contingencies, p(mid as high) = 1 is the ideal strategy to maximise rewards. Random responding would correspond to p(mid as high) = 0.5. Negative affective bias is inversely proportional to p(mid as high).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Dynamic Reward Task : the Learning Task</head><p>The purpose of this task was to characterise how reward affects participants' behaviour in a changing environment. To achieve this, we adapted Norton et al. <ref type="formula">2019</ref>'s overt criterion placement task designed to study perceptual decision-making in an environment with dynamic rewards. On each trial, participants saw a blue arrow on the screen with a randomised starting position. Participants were instructed to move the arrow between -45 and 45 degrees of vertical via an onscreen slider using their mouse or trackpad, with the final position of the slider recorded as the behavioural response. After letting go of the slider, a second coloured arrow was superimposed ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>). With equal probability, this arrow was either purple (category P), or orange (category O). The orientation of this second arrow was sampled from the corresponding Gaussian distribution for that category (purple µ = -15 °, orange µ = 15 °, s = 20 °). Sampling was conducted for each trial independently. Correct categorisation was given the feedback "Correct", and incorrect categorisation "Incorrect", for 200 ms before the start of the next trial. Trials were counted as correctly categorised if the orange arrow was titled more rightward than blue arrow, or the purple arrow was tilted more leftward of the blue arrow. On some trials, correct categorisation would lead to a virtual reward. Such trials additionally displayed the feedback "+1 point!" and a point was added to a tally of the participant's total score. After the first 5 trials and then every 9 trials, participants are asked the question: "Which arrow is currently rewarded more often?" and they responded either "purple" or "orange". Participants were randomised to six pseudo-randomised reward-contingency structures, which ensured that the order was counterbalanced with regard to the reward probabilities of the colour categories. Each rewardcontingency structure had a total of 194 trials, divided into 5 reward-contingency epochs, each lasting between 38-45 trials. Epochs were defined by yoked category-reward contingency ratios (50:50%, 20:80%, 80:20%, 35:65%, 65:35%). The first epoch always rewarded both categories (orange and purple) equally. Thereafter, reward contingencies of the two categories were unpredictable and unequal but yoked. This reward structure requires the participant to adjust their response bias (i.e., the orientation of the blue arrow) differently across time to maximise rewards.</p><p>For each trial, we recorded the participant's slider end orientation position as their response, which divided the decision space into "orange category" and "purple category" choices. Combined with the random sample from the category distribution, this determined the correctness of their choice. We used this information in our SDT modelling as our trial-by-trial empirical criterion placement (c) (see 2.4.1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.1">Modelling for the dynamic reward task</head><p>To model the dynamic reward task, in which participants had to continuously learn reward changes and map their decisions, we fit a dynamic signal detection theory model with four free parameters. We computed a gain parameter G, (-¥ £ G £ ¥), interpreted as reward sensitivity, with 1 &lt; G &lt; ¥ corresponding to liberal and 0 &lt; G &lt; 1 corresponding to conservative responding. That is, a liberal participant would have a disproportionately strong response to reward, whereas a conservative participant would have a diminished sensitivity to reward and instead bias their responses towards a prior which treats rewards as equal. Note that -1 &lt; G &lt; 0 reflects incorrect mapping of conservatism and -¥ &lt; G &lt; -1 reflects incorrect mapping of liberal responses. We also computed the learning rate, a (0 £ a £ 1) of the participant interpreted as a participant's sensitivity to new information, with higher a implying greater sensitivity; a bias parameter, b (-¥ £ b £¥), capturing general shifts in sub-optimal responding; and a setting noise parameter (s) reflecting the accuracy of mapping the decision to an actual response, with larger numbers corresponding to greater inaccuracies. A dynamic SDT model differs from a static SDT model, in that it has a standard signal detection theory component and a learning component. The learning component step of our model describes how the belief about reward probabilities is formed over time given reward feedback. We here used a learning process that was adapted from a similar dynamic decision-making task (Norton et al., 2019):</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">!(#) = a * (#%&amp;) + (1 − a) ' ("#$) * !(#%&amp;) .</formula><p>Where !(#) is the estimation of the reward probability for the orange category on the current trial, (#%&amp;) is the reward value in the previous trial, (#%&amp;) is the correctness of the previous response (i.e., either 1 if the stimulus was correctly categorised, or 0 otherwise), a is the fitted learning rate parameter, and !(#%&amp;) is the estimation of the reward of the orange category on the previous trial. Note that this formulation only updates the reward-probability beliefs following correct trials, as no information about reward probability can follow an incorrect trial.</p><p>The standard SDT modelling step describes how a participant's belief e.g., about a reward, is translated into a criterion placement i.e., a decision-making threshold <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Locke &amp; Robinson, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Macmillan, 1991)</ref>. In our model we considered how the criterion placement of the observer (c), deviated from the optimal, by fitting a magnitude scaling parameter (G) and a shifting parameter (b) to the criterion placement of the optimal observer with identical reward-probability beliefs:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">= * ()# + .</formula><p>To model the actual response, we used a likelihood function given the model predictions and the setting noise(s):</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">*+,)(-,+ ~ ( , s).</formula><p>More details about the modelling can be found in the supplementary file 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Gambling Task : the Prospect Theory Task</head><p>In this task, participants chose between a card showing a safe choice, or a 50/50 gamble <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Figure 3</ref>) by either clicking on the image or using the left and right arrow buttons on their keyboards. Participants received no feedback on their choices. There were 100 trials in total, with an equal number of mixed-gambles ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure  3A)</ref>, where the safe bet was 0 and the gamble could incur a gain or a loss, and gain-gamble trials ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure  3B</ref>), in which the safe bet was a gain, and the gamble either gave no gain but also no loss or a gain, which was potentially higher than the gain from the safe bet. The gamble pay-off structures can be found in the supplementary file 2. The presentation order was randomised. We used a prospect theory model to extract three parameters per participant from their gamble choices: risk aversion (r), loss aversion (d), and inverse temperature (t) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979)</ref>. For details regarding the parameter values and the model fitting procedure see the appendix and <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Huys et al. (2011)</ref>. . They could be presented with either with a mixed-gamble (A) or a gain-gamble (B). Each safe bet, gamble combination was shown twice. Participants did not receive feedback. A) When safe bets gave 0 points, participants could either gain or lose a reward on the gamble. Here, there was a 50 % chance to win £50 or loose £20. B) When safe bets gave a reward, the gamble consisted of winning nothing 50 % of the time or winning a reward 50 % of the time, here £60.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.6">Statistical Analysis</head><p>To understand the relationship between our measure of negative affective bias, p(mid as high), and reward and value processing in dynamic and static contexts, a logistic regression was run in Python (version 2.7). We used all parameters obtained through the modelling of the tasks, as well as age and sex as predictors (total nine predictors) for the affective bias score. The natural logarithm of |G| was taken to make the regression more interpretable. Thereafter, G = |0.5| and G=|2|, a doubling or halving of the response gain respectively, were equally spaced. Two participants' data was not included, due to task non-completion, resulting in a final sample size of 148. All parameters included in the regression except for sex were normalised, to facilitate effect-size comparison.</p><p>Many participants had a high noise parameter. This could indicate a high choice variability or misunderstanding of the task. Therefore, as a sensitivity test, a logistic regression in a strict, reduced sample with low noise parameters was also performed (N=45). For exclusion criteria see supplementary file 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.7">Preregistration and Data Availability</head><p>The data, pre-registration and learning model code for this study can be found at https://osf.io/ewn23/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Descriptive Statistics</head><p>The descriptive statistics of the affective bias score and the predictors of the logistic regression can be found in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.   <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: The descriptive statistics of the affective bias score and the nine parameters used in the logistic regression model to predict the affective bias score. The outcome of the logistic regression, p(mid as high) represents the affective bias sore. The demographic predictor variables included were age and sex. The predictor variables from the dynamic SDT model were the learning rate (a), the reward sensitivity (i.e., gain, ln|G|), the bias parameter (b), and the setting noise parameter (s). The predictor variables from the prospect theory model were the subjective value of reward (i.e., risk aversion, r), loss aversion (d) and inverse temperature (t).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Affective Bias Measure:</head><p>The median p(mid as high) of 148 participants is 0.55 (0.45-0.7). The minimum value is 0 and the maximum value is 1. We thus see that most participants behave sub optimally (i.e., have p(mid as high) &lt;1) ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 4</ref>). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Logistic Regression:</head><p>3.3.1 Full sample (N=148) P(mid as high) was significantly predicted by s (setting noise, b = -0.187, p = 0.028) and ln(|G|) (reward sensitivity i.e., gain, b = 0.131, p = 0.024) only ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 5</ref>). The relationship between reward sensitivity and the affective bias score is in line with predictions; when participants have a low reward sensitivity, their p(mid as high) is lower. In a sample that includes all participants, we can infer that both choice variability and conservatism bear a relationship with response biases on the affective bias task. Average p(mid as high)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.1">Contextualising the significant reward sensitivity result</head><p>A simple Pearson correlation between the raw p(mid as high) and reward sensitivity parameter values (i.e., gain, ln|G|) shows that those who are less negatively biased in the affective bias task are also more sensitive to reward in the learning task (r=0.149; <ref type="figure">Figure 6A</ref>). Further, there is a trend that those who are more sensitive to reward in the learning task are also more sensitive to value in the gambling task (r=0.159; <ref type="figure">Figure 6B</ref>). <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>. Pairwise linear correlations between reward sensitivity, affective bias and subjective value sensitivity A) The raw correlation between the affective bias score and reward sensitivity. There is a weak positive, non-significant relationship. The dashed horizontal line indicates no preference between the low and high reward. The dashed vertical line represents a neutral gain parameter, which neither inflates nor shrinks optimal criterion estimates. Turquoise shaded region indicates participants are conservative, the yellow shaded region shows that participants are liberal on the learning task. B) The raw correlation between reward sensitivity and subjective value sensitivity. The dotted horizontal and vertical lines indicate no bias. The yellow shaded area encompasses participants who are liberal in their criterion placements and risk seeking. The upper green shaded background indicates conservatism in the gain parameter but risk seeking behaviour in the gambling task. The right hand green shaded area indicates risk aversion but inflation of reward. The turquoise shaded region indicates conservatism on both the risk aversion and gain parameter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.3">Contextualising the significant setting noise result</head><p>We also performed a logistic regression restricted to participants who did not fail stringent data quality checks (N=45). In this regression, p(mid as high) was significantly predicted by s only (b = -0.436, p= 0.019) although the effect of the ln(|G|) (b = 0.249, p=0.183) was in the same direction as predicted and found in the full sample.</p><p>In line with the logistic regression analysis, participants with a higher noise parameter had a lower affective bias score (i.e., they were more negatively biased) on a Pearson correlation between s and p(mid as high) (full sample: r = -0.209, p = 0.011; reduced sample: r = -0.261, p = 0.083; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 7A</ref>-B). The significant correlation of the full sample shows that most participants with the highest noise parameters respond conservatively on the affective bias task (p(mid as high) around 0.5), instead of with a true negative bias preferring the low reward option (p(mid as high) &lt; 0.5). This might indicate that people who are noisier on the learning task, are also more inconsistent in their responses on the horizontal trials of the ambiguous-cue decision-making task. Interestingly, setting noise from the learning task and inverse temperature from the gambling task are not correlated (r=0.094, p=0.254; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 7C</ref>). This relationship holds when transforming inverse temperature into a log space and across the sensitivity exclusion. Thus, we show no relationship between setting noise and inverse temperature even though they both represent inconsistent task-responding, indicating that these two parameters correspond to different noise sources. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussion:</head><p>In the present study, we investigated reward sensitivity, subjective value sensitivity, learning rate and noise as possible mechanisms underscoring a replicated measure of negative affective bias, which previously revealed that people with depression choose high-reward responses less frequently than healthy controls <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Aylward et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Daniel-Watanabe et al., 2022)</ref> and are more conservative in their criterion placing than healthy controls <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Locke &amp; Robinson, 2021)</ref>. Our results reveal a significant association between reward sensitivity (i.e., gain, ln|G|) and affective bias; the less sensitive a participant is to reward in a probabilistic learning task, the more negatively biased they are in the ambiguous-cue decision-making task. We failed to find an association between reward learning rate and negative affective bias. We further failed to find an association between subjective value sensitivity (i.e., risk aversion, r) and affective bias. This indicates that reward sensitivity and not value sensitivity, that is detecting the chance of reward rather than accurately gauging the magnitude of a reward, might underscore task conservatism on our metric of negative affective bias. Additionally, we found an association between affective bias and noise. This indicates that choice variability might play a role in determining the affective bias score. We predicted conservative choices on our affective bias task, indicative of a larger negative affective bias propensity, would be linked to a reduced sensitivity to reward during learning. We found some support for this prediction. Specifically, we found a relationship between our gain parameter in the learning task and our negative affective bias score in the full sample: when participants have a low absolute gain parameter, their probability of choosing a high reward option on ambiguous trials is lower. A smaller absolute gain parameter shrinks the criterion placement estimate and therein biases participants towards conservative responding i.e., participants behave as if the two reward probabilities are more similar than they are. As the criterion placement is dependent on a transformation of the reward-probability estimate, this indicates the participants' sub-optimality is due to a reduced response to reward. This result is in line with the results of the to date most extensive probabilistic reward task learning set in depressed participants, which showed depressed participants had a conservative bias and specifically reduced reward sensitivity rather than abnormal learning per se <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Admon &amp; Pizzagalli, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Huys et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Pizzagalli et al., 2008)</ref>.</p><p>We also predicted that a diminished subjective sensitivity to value would drive a bias away from high rewards on our affective bias task. While rewards refer to the objective value received after an outcome, value refers to an individual's subjective evaluation of the desirability of a potential outcome, i.e., their subjective representation of the reward <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Kahneman &amp; Tversky, 1979)</ref>. Contrary to our hypothesis, we did not find a positive association between subjective value sensitivity and the affective bias score. This prediction was made as a small subjective value sensitivity parameter shrinks the expected gain of subjective values and results in a conservative criterion placement shift <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Ackermann &amp; Landy, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Ulehla, 1966)</ref>. Therefore, in our sample, decreased subjective value sensitivity does not seem to be the source of task conservatism. This indicates a diminishment of valuing reward does not incur a weaker preference for a high-reward response association on ambiguous cues on the affective bias task. Combining this with the significant reward sensitivity effect above shows that not choosing high reward options in uncertain contexts is not related to an a priori disregard of the value of reward on the affective bias task but to a difference in experiencing the presence or absence of rewards. In our affective bias task, participants were not given explicit response instructions, but learnt reward contingencies through trial and error. Therefore, it makes conceptual sense, that a reduced sensitivity to positive feedback does not incur a bias toward high-reward response choices on this task.</p><p>In our study, setting noise also significantly predicted the affective bias score. A higher noise parameter in the dynamic reward task was related to a tendency to not choose the high reward option on ambiguous trials in the affective bias task. The setting noise parameter signifies how accurately the criterion placement decision is mapped to the actual response in the learning task. This result was robust to exclusions for excessive noisiness. When looking at the significant simple correlation between the setting noise parameter and the affective bias score, the relationship is not driven by true negative affective bias scores (p(mid as high) &lt; 0.5) but instead by conservative responses (p(mid as high) ~ 0.5) (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 7A</ref>-B). However, it is important to note that the setting noise parameter can be influenced by a variety of participant behaviours, attributable to task-specific dimensions (e.g., divergent exploration strategies, misunderstanding of the task) or non-specific task dimensions (e.g., executive function, intelligence, attention, concentration).</p><p>In the full sample, it is plausible the relationship between setting noise and p(mid as high) was driven by a misunderstanding of the task or a lack of concentration. This sample included participants who failed to correctly respond to questions probing explicit knowledge of the more frequently rewarded category in the learning task and further included respondents who gave incorrect answers to unambiguous trials of the affective bias task. Considering depression is associated with executive-function processing difficulties <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Varghese et al., 2022)</ref>, particularly attentive difficulties <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Keller et al., 2019)</ref>, an affective bias score of 0.5 could represent stochastic noise in a forced two-choice task. However, our stringent sample allows us to indirectly differentiate between possible sources of setting noise. Despite being underpowered, the significant association between noise and affective bias remains after the exclusion of participants whose data indicates their lack of concentration or task understanding. Therefore, the association is likely not just linked to random responses. Instead, an elevated setting noise parameter value could also be the result of divergent decision-making behaviour and strategies. As participants need to learn the probabilistic response associations on the affective bias task, a conservative affective bias score might represent over-exploration and within-task strategy switching, while a higher p(mid as high) score might be representative of a more stable exploitation strategy. A recent meta-analysis of reinforcement learning tasks concurs with this insight and showed that depressed patients had a lower inverse temperature i.e., their task choices were less consistent than healthy controls <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Pike &amp; Robinson, 2022)</ref>. Further, choice variability on a probabilistic learning task has been associated with anhedonia symptoms in a large clinical sample <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Huys et al., 2013)</ref>. This could be equivalent to an under-exploitation of rewards or an over-exploration of task strategy. Thus, the affective bias score could plausibly be underscored by alternative task engagement, task variability, or indecisiveness.</p><p>The ambiguous-cue decision-making task we used to probe negative affective bias is a simple behavioural task, which showed reliable associations with depression in a general and clinical population in humans as well as a mouse model of depression <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Aylward et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Daniel-Watanabe et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hales et al., 2016)</ref>. The task therefore seemed promising for translational research of treatments and mechanisms. Our study suggests the affective bias score is driven by a multitude of processing biases and decision-making strategies and might therefore not be cleanest approach for future translational research. Our result can also inform pharmacological and non-pharmacological trials aiming to improve mood disorder treatment. Common pharmacological anti-depressants are thought to act therapeutically by changing bottom-up negative affective biases, inducing more positive associations reinforced through social interactions, and therein leading to mood improvements <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Godlewska &amp; Harmer, 2021)</ref>. However, not everyone benefits from common antidepressants therapeutically <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Roiser et al., 2012)</ref>. There is thus a need to understand the mechanisms behind negative affective biases and to develop more targeted pharmacological approaches as well as psychological treatments. Our result highlights the importance of targeting reward pathways in depression treatment. Yet, some evidence suggests improving positive affect through behavioural and pharmacological interventions is less successful than reducing negative affect <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Dunn et al., 2020)</ref>. That it is worthwhile to trial new treatments targeting reward hyposensitivity specifically has recently been shown in a randomised clinical trial, which showed treatment focusing on positive affect was superior to treatment focusing on negative affect and the improvements on reward anticipation-motivation and responses to reward attainment in the positive affect arm correlated with improvements of metrics of positive affect, anhedonia and depression and anxiety <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Craske et al., 2023)</ref>.</p><p>Our study had several benefits. In SDT, conservatism is a behaviour that deviates from the optimal strategy, where an individual places their decision criterion close to the neutral location, indicating no strong preference for either choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Green &amp; Swets, 1966)</ref>. A previous study linked our metric of negative affective bias to a conservative shift in criterion placement <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Locke &amp; Robinson, 2021)</ref>. Depression is linked to reduced responses to gains in static and dynamic contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Halahakoon et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Pike &amp; Robinson, 2022)</ref> which exemplifies the importance of precisely testing reward/value-related sub-processes which lead to biases on cognitive tasks such as the affective bias signature on the ambiguous-cue decision-making task. A strength of our approach was therefore that we were able to test two underlying constructs as possible sources of task conservatism <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Locke &amp; Robinson, 2021)</ref>. Our experiment approached this by studying how reward feedback influenced the conservatism of criterion placements and through the risk aversion parameter of a gambling task. This let us tackle a conceptual difficulty in the depression literature distinguishing an individual's response to positive feedback in the reward outcome phase, from disrupted appraisal processes of value in the decision-phase <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Chung et al., 2017)</ref>. Therein, we were able to test whether disrupted value representations or reward-feedback processes drove task conservatism. Collectively, our analysis indicates that most respondents were conservative in subjective value sensitivity and reward sensitivity measures <ref type="figure">(Figure 6b</ref>). Further, participants who were conservative in their option valuation were also conservative in their reward sensitivity, although the relationship did not reach statistical significance. Thus, conservatism on the affective bias task is driven not by an overall diminishment of valuing reward, but probably at least in part by experiencing the reward feedback differently.</p><p>The SDT framework is also a useful approach when studying biases, as it relates behavioural observations to distinct cognitive processes: sensitivity and bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Green &amp; Swets, 1966)</ref>. We exploited this approach and developed a novel probabilistic reward task. This allowed us to integrate optimality into our model, which is an improvement over previous SDT modelling of probabilistic reward tasks studying biases in depression. Further, our new task is a probabilistic reward learning task during which participants need to make overt criterion decisions. This approach yields a richer dataset of explicit criterion choices. By requiring participants to indicate a criterion placement on every trial, we had a trial-by-trial continuous estimate of participants' perceived optimal cut-off points, which we let our model estimate. An overt criterion task also increases confidence in attributing the source of response conservatism to conservatism tendencies. Meanwhile, two-forced choice covert criterion tasks can lead to behavioural conservatism due to decisionmaking strategies which smooth binary observer responses (e.g., probability matching) or increased task uncertainty due to implicit feedback leading to a stronger reliance on priors (Norton et al., 2019).</p><p>Our study also has several limitations. For the current study, participants were sampled from the general population, and we did not measure their psychopathology profiles. Instead, we rely on the previously shown association between mood disorders and affective biases to interpret our findings. To understand the relationship more confidently between mood disorders, our affective bias measure, and the sources of conservatism, the study should be replicated within a clinical sample and include clinical questionnaires. Further, future studies should try and understand the source of choice variability. The task we used is sensitive to depression, and depression is related to both altered hot cognition and cold cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Roiser &amp; Sahakian, 2013)</ref>. To understand if choice variability is driven by inattention, exploration-exploitation trade-offs or general choice inconsistency, more testing is required. Further, the affective bias task could be made perceptually harder. Perceptual ambiguity could be added by using circle area instead of line tilt as the feature discriminating dimension. This could rule out lack of attention as a driver of conservatism, as participants with very low perceptual sensitivity would likely not be paying attention. Moreover, from an SDT perspective, this would be beneficial as it would more clearly separates biases: for tasks in which perceptual sensitivity is high, the optimal criterion point is closer to neutral than for tasks in which perceptual sensitivity is lower (e.g., d'=1) <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Locke &amp; Robinson, 2021)</ref>. Tasks testing executive functioning, exploration-exploitation trade-off as well as an IQ test could be added to the task-battery.</p><p>To conclude, understanding the mechanisms underlying negative affective bias is crucial for our understanding of mood disorder symptomatology and treatments. Our results show reward sensitivity, but not subjective value sensitivity probably drives task conservatism on this affective bias task. The present study has also shown that the affective bias score is most probably not driven by one underlying mechanism. Both reward sensitivity and noise (and hence unmodelled decision-making strategies) seem to drive the response bias on the affective bias task.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Schematic representation of the affective bias task set up and scoring procedure. A)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>A schematic of the scoring of correctness of the dynamic reward task. A) Participants moved a blue arrow using a slider. This corresponded to their task response. Once they let go of the slider, a second arrow was superimposed. B) On half of the trials, the second arrow is from category purple (P). The tip of the purple arrow must fall left of the blue arrow tip to be scored as correct. C) On trials with superimposed category orange (O) arrows, the tip of the orange arrow must fall right of the blue tip to be scored as correct. Not all correct trials are rewarded. Instead, category reward was yoked and changed throughout the experiment, necessitating a continuous adjusting of response bias to gain maximal rewards.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>An example of a mixed-gamble and a gain-gamble trial. For 100 trials, participants made a choice between two cards, showing a safe bet (left option) or a 50/50 gamble (right option)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Box plot of the affective bias score with a density distribution plot and individual data points. The plot represents the affective bias data of the full sample of 148 participants.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>The logistic regression predicting p(mid as high) performed on the full sample (N=148). The predictor variables were sex, age, d = loss aversion, r = risk aversion conceptualising subjective value sensitivity, t = inverse temperature, b=bias, s = setting noise, ln(|G|) = gain parameter conceptualising reward sensitivity, a = learning rate.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Pairwise linear correlations between setting noise, affective bias and inverse temperature A) showing the raw correlation between setting noise and the affective bias score in the full sample. B) showing the raw correlation between setting noise and the affective bias score in the reduced sample C) showing the raw correlation between setting noise and inverse temperature in the full sample</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>Study design: IKL, SML, OJR; study set-up: IKL; data collection: IKL; learning model: IKL, SML; prospect theory model: a special thanks to Anahita Talwar for providing her modelling code and helping IKL fit the data; data analysis: IKL with supervision from SML, OJR; first written draft: IKL; draft revisions: IKL, SML, OJR.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competing Interests</head><p>OJR's MRC senior fellowship is partially in collaboration with Cambridge Cognition (who plan to provide in-kind contribution), and he is running an investigator-initiated trial with medication donated by Lundbeck (escitalopram and placebo, no financial contribution); he holds an MRC Proximity to Discovery Award with Roche (who provide in-kind contributions and sponsor travel) regarding work on heart rate variability and anxiety; and he has completed consultancy work on affective-bias modification for Peak and on online cognitive behavioral therapy for IESO Digital Health. The other authors disclose no competing interests.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Suboptimal decision criteria are predicted by subjectively weighted probabilities and rewards. Attention, Perception, &amp; Psychophysics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Ackermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13414-014-0779-z</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13414-014-0779-z" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="638" to="658" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dysfunctional Reward Processing in Depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Admon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pizzagalli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.copsyc.2014.12.011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.copsyc.2014.12.011" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr Opin Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="114" to="118" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Translating a rodent measure of negative bias into humans: the impact of induced anxiety and unmedicated mood and anxiety disorders</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Aylward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/s0033291718004117</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/s0033291718004117" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="246" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valuation in major depression is intact and stable in a non-learning environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kadlec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Aimone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mccurry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>King-Casas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/srep44374</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/srep44374" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">44374</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Positive affect treatment targets reward sensitivity: A randomized controlled trial</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Craske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Meuret</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Echiverri-Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rosenfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ritz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/ccp0000805</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/ccp0000805" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Consult Clin Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="350" to="366" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Association Between a Directly Translated Cognitive Measure of Negative Bias and Self-reported Psychiatric Symptoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Daniel-Watanabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mclaughlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gormley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.bpsc.2020.02.010</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bpsc.2020.02.010" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Biological Psychiatry: Cognitive Neuroscience and Neuroimaging</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="209" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Changes in Positive and Negative Affect During Pharmacological Treatment and Cognitive Therapy for Major Depressive Disorder: A Secondary Analysis of Two Randomized Controlled Trials</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>German</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Khazanov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hollon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Derubeis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/2167702619863427</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/2167702619863427" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clinical Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="51" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comprehensive meta-analysis of interpretation biases in depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Everaert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Podina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H W</forename><surname>Koster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cpr.2017.09.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2017.09.005" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clinical Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive neuropsychological theory of antidepressant action: a modern-day approach to depression and its treatment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Godlewska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Harmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s00213-019-05448-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00213-019-05448-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychopharmacology (Berl)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">238</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1265" to="1278" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Signal detection theory and psychophysics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Swets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
			<publisher>John Wiley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward-Processing Behavior in Depressed Participants Relative to Healthy Volunteers: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Halahakoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kieslich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>O'driscoll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Roiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.2139</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.2139" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JAMA Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1286" to="1295" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion Modelling Reveals the Decision Making Processes Underlying Negative Judgement Bias in Rats</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Houghton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0152592</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0152592" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disentangling the Roles of Approach, Activation and Valence in Instrumental and Pavlovian Responding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">J M</forename><surname>Huys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cools</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gölzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Friedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heinz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1002028</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1002028" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mapping anhedonia onto reinforcement learning: a behavioural meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">J M</forename><surname>Huys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pizzagalli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bogdan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1186/2045-5380-3-12</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1186/2045-5380-3-12" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biology of Mood &amp; Anxiety Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospect Theory: An Analysis of Decision under Risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/1914185</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/1914185" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Econometrica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="291" />
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paying attention to attention in depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Leikauf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Holt-Gosselin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Staveland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41398-019-0616-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41398-019-0616-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transl Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">279</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affective Bias Through the Lens of Signal Detection Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Locke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5334/cpsy.58</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.5334/cpsy.58" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput Psychiatr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human online adaptation to changes in prior probability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A C C D</forename><surname>Macmillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Norton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Acerbi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1006681</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1006681" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Detection theory : a user&apos;s guide</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trait Anxiety Is Associated with Negative Interpretations When Resolving Valence Ambiguity of Surprised Faces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Vasey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Thayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2016.01164</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2016.01164" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Original Research]. Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reinforcement Learning in Patients With Mood and Anxiety Disorders vs Control Individuals: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Pike</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.0051</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.0051" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JAMA Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="322" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reduced hedonic capacity in major depressive disorder: evidence from a probabilistic reward task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pizzagalli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Iosifescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hallett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ratner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2008.03.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2008.03.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Psychiatr Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="76" to="87" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive mechanisms of treatment in depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Roiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Elliott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sahakian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/npp.2011.183</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/npp.2011.183" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychopharmacology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hot and cold cognition in depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Roiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sahakian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S1092852913000072</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1092852913000072" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CNS Spectrums</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimality of perceptual decision criteria</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ulehla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0023007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0023007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Exp Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="564" to="569" />
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Functional and cognitive impairment in the first episode of depression: A systematic review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Varghese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Frey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Kapczinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>De Azevedo Cardoso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/acps.13385</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/acps.13385" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Psychiatr Scand</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">145</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="185" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
