<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:01+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> <ref type="table">Table 2</ref><p>. Similarity shapes trait-based generalization across ten novel contexts . <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. Similarity shapes the spontaneous generalization of trait knowledge ...</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ix</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ABSTRACT</head><p>People robustly and rapidly infer traits from the social behavior of others. These trait impressions support predictions about future behavior. How do people use this learning flexibly in novel social situations? We propose people use maps of social knowledge (representing similarity between traits) to generalize trait impressions and predict behavior in new domains and contexts, a prediction we test across three experiments. First, in a pilot study, we demonstrate that conceptual similarity between traits predicts situation-specific inferences of trait relevance. In Experiment 1, participants learned about targets (described either as humans or non-human slot machines) whose behavior in a task revealed sociability, and later, made choices about which partners to choose in decision making tasks relevant to other traits. Trait similarity (i.e., between the original context and novel contexts) shaped partner choice, but critically, this relationship was socially specific: participants generalized social learning based on trait similarity when interacting with other humans but not with slot machines. In Experiment 2, participants were given explicit trait labels describing potential partners. Here, we observed that trait similarity continued to influence generalization across an expanded set of traits and task contexts, above and beyond the mere valence similarity of traits. While Exps. 1-2 demonstrate trait-based generalization in decision-making, Experiment 3 demonstrated that trait-based generalization occurs with relative spontaneity. Here, in a false recognition task, perceived similarity between lure and target traits was associated with falsely remembering lure traits. Overall, our results demonstrate the social specificity of traitbased generalization and provide a foundation for future work exploring this process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>Imagine that it is your first day working at an automobile design firm and your boss is fielding pitches for the latest version of a client's flagship model. You offer up your best ideas, but when your boss lists their favorites, they attribute your suggestions to the person sitting next to you. Your colleague quickly pipes up and clarifies that you, in fact, were the source of said brillianceperhaps revealing something about their trustworthiness. This initial impression may facilitate predictions about whether your colleague will be trustworthy in the future. Yet, beyond that, it also provides affordances for inferring whether your colleague might be sociable at a post-work hangout, or if they'll be decisive about where to order lunch from, or if they themselves have any good car ideas.</p><p>Indeed, theories of social cognition assert that social impressions are functionally adaptive: they allow us to predict others' behavior. For example, if your car broke down, you might choose to reach out for help from a friend you know to be reliable, as opposed to a friend who is disorganized. These impressions allow you to predict how each friend will likely respond in this emergency; all things being equal, the reliable friend is probably more likely to come to your aid. Moreover, these impressions are context-specific. For example, even if the reliable friend was awkward and shy, while the disorganized friend was a life-of-the-party extravert, in this situation, you'd likely still prefer to phone the former rather than the latter.</p><p>A key implicationthough one that is not always testedis that this functionality should be flexible, and in particular, generalizable to situations beyond those specific to one's initial impressions of a person <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Hackel et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Son et al., 2021)</ref>. In other words, for our impressions to be broadly functional, we also need to be able to generalize them to new contexts. We cannot gain experience with others in every type of situation that can arise, so we use what information we do know to predict likely behavior in other situations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Generalization and Dimensional Models of Person Perception</head><p>The ability to generalize individual bits of social knowledge into predictions about how others will behave in novel contexts is crucial for effective social navigation. That said, a mechanistic understanding of exactly how people accomplish such generalization is still in development. One possible way people could manage the problem of generalization arises from classic research in social cognition, which has produced models attempting to describe the multidimensional trait structure of these social representations. For example, one such model suggests that we represent other people along the orthogonal dimensions of warmth (e.g., are this person's intentions good or bad?) and competence (e.g., can this person successfully act on their intentions?; <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Fiske et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Fiske, Cuddy, &amp; Glick, 2007)</ref>. Indeed, similar two-dimensional models of person perception have been a mainstay of modern social psychology for decades <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abele &amp; Wojciszke, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Eagly &amp; Steffen, 1984;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Oosterhof &amp; Todorov, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Rosenberg, Nelson, &amp; Vivekananthan, 1968;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b93">Wojciszke, 2005)</ref> and contemporary research has continued to refine these models <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Brambilla, Sacchi, Rusconi, &amp; Goodwin, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">Ray, Mende-Siedlecki, Gantman, &amp; Van</ref> Bavel, 2021)-in some cases expanding them with additional dimensions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Brambilla, Rusconi, Sacchi, &amp; Cherubini, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">Sutherland, Oldmeadow, Santos, Towler, Burt, &amp; Young, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">Tamir &amp; Thornton, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>While work in this vein has typically sought to establish overarching trait dimensions governing global impressions, this research has also laid a foundation for examining how specific impressions regarding a particular trait, context, or individual might be generalized to other cases. For example, the "halo effect" phenomenonwhere evaluations in one trait domain (e.g., warmth) bleed over to shape evaluations in a separate domain (e.g., competence)-has been well-documented in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Nisbett &amp; Wilson, 1977;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">Rosenberg et al., 1968;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">Thorndike, 1920;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b95">Wyer, 1974)</ref>. At times, the halo effect has been characterized as a form of cognitive bias: having learned that an individual possesses a particular positive trait, assessments of their (ambiguous) behavior in another trait domain are, accordingly, positively skewed. However, another interpretation of this phenomenon would be a form of valence-based generalization. From this perspective, someone who is socially warm might also be judged to be competent because the similar valence of these traits produces an association between the two. Thus, having one piece of trait knowledge about a person affords the possibility of inferences to other traits that share similar valence.</p><p>At the same time, these generalizations might be context-sensitive, such that there are situations in which typically-linked traits do not imply each other (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Kervyn et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Kervyn, Bergsieker, &amp; Fiske, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Holoien &amp; Fiske, 2016</ref>)-for example, when evaluations are being made in a comparative context (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Judd et al., 2005;</ref>. More broadly, there are surely cases where mere valence similarity between traits would not be a good basis for extrapolation. Being funny and being morally upright are both positive traits, but learning that someone is a successful comedian would not necessarily promote an inference of virtuousness. Thus, the halo effect seems unlikely to fully explain the nature of our ability to generalize trait impressions across domains.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Generalization Based on Perceptual Similarity</head><p>At the other end of the spectrum, social knowledge can be generalized from known to novel cases based on perceptual similarity. For example, in tasks where perceivers learn to associate sets of faces with valenced behavioral descriptions (e.g., "he stole money and jewelry from the relatives he was living with"), they generalize these social impressions to novel faces on the basis of perceptual similarity <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">(Verosky &amp; Todorov, 2010)</ref>. Despite perceiving these novel faces ("morphs" containing small percentages of faces from the originally learned sets) as different individuals, those who resembled faces paired with positive behaviors were rated as being more trustworthy than those who resembled faces paired with negative behaviors. This appearance-based generalization is also spontaneous and robust, persisting under cognitive load and even when novel faces were, themselves, paired with relevant behavioral information <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">(Verosky &amp; Todorov, 2013)</ref>. While these initial demonstrations used a passive learning approach in which faces were simply paired with valenced behaviors, other work in this vein reveals similar effects in the context of direct interpersonal exchange <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(FeldmanHall, Dunsmoor, Tompary, Hunter, Todorov, &amp; Phelps, 2018)</ref>. Here, participants who learned players' tendencies to reciprocate in an iterative trust game showed preferences to play with novel players in a future trust game that scaled parametrically with perceptual similarity. Specifically, participants preferred to select future partners who resembled the initially trustworthy player and avoided future partners who resembled the initially untrustworthy player, and these tendencies magnified as perceptual similarity increased. Thus, across this work, perceptual similarities between individual faces supports the flexible generalization of social knowledge from one person to another. How, then, might we generalize within one person from one situation to another?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cognitive Maps Support Generalization in Social and Non-Social Contexts</head><p>While the perceptual generalization described above is quite literally rooted in the structural similarities between pairs of faces, a more general capacity to identify and exploit meaningful cognitive structures of knowledge has been well-studied in social and nonsocial domains alike <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Honig &amp; Urcuioli, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">Shepard, 1987;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">Tenenbaum et al., 2011)</ref>.</p><p>From this perspective, we can use cognitive maps <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Behrens et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Garvert et al., 2023</ref>) that characterize spatial (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Morgan, MacEvoy, Aguirre, &amp; Epstein, 2011)</ref>, temporal (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">Schapiro, Turk-Browne, Norman, &amp; Botvinick, 2016)</ref>, contextual (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">Schuck, Cai, Wilson, &amp; Niv, 2016)</ref>, or conceptual relationships (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Constantinescu, O'Reilly, &amp; Behrens, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Garvert, Dolan, &amp; Behrens, 2017)</ref> in the environment to make flexible predictions and plan our actions accordingly; for example, actions that yield rewards in a given context should produce similar results in related contexts. Indeed, considerable work in the reinforcement learning literature suggests that people generalize reward value based not only on stimulus similarity but also relational structure <ref type="bibr" target="#b89">(Wimmer, Daw, &amp; Shohamy, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Gershman &amp; Daw, 2017)</ref>. How, then, might we make these kinds of flexible inferences about other people?</p><p>When learning about other people, humans do not merely generalize based on the reward values associated with individual actors and their actions. Instead, our acquired knowledge of the structure of trait space provides its own form of cognitive map for making sense of and predicting people's behavior. Notably, trait knowledge is comparatively abstract and is more heavily weighted in social partner choice when compared against the kinds of reward feedback typically studied in reinforcement learning models <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Hackel et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hackel et al., , 2020</ref>. In principle, this knowledge structure describes the linkages between different traits in terms of their conceptual similarity or likelihood of co-occurrence. For example, having learned that a person is generous, we may be likely to infer that they are also sociable to the extent that we see those two trait concepts as overlapping. At the same time, we may have little basis for making a strong inference regarding less related traits like impulsivity. Thus, we might predict that this person would thrive in a social setting like a large gathering, but we might not be able to predict how this person would behave while shopping.</p><p>This conceptual understanding of the correlations between individual trait concepts may ultimately be more critical for characterizing adaptive social cognition than the overarching dimensions that divide trait space. Indeed, recent work demonstrates how conceptual associations between traits shape social inferences and perceptions across a wide array of contexts, including face-based impressions, familiar person knowledge, and group stereotypes <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Stolier et al., 2020)</ref>. In other words, to the extent that a perceiver sees "friendly" and "cooperative" as being similar to one another, they tend to show greater correspondence between evaluations of those traits when making impressions of novel faces, when considering the personalities of familiar individuals, and when evaluating social groups. Critically, these conceptual associations are idiosyncratic, in that they vary across perceivers, and dynamic, in that they are shaped by real-world experience. In particular, <ref type="bibr">Stolier and colleagues (2020)</ref> observed that the actual structure of observed correlations between Neuroticism-Extraversion-Openness Personality Inventory (NEOPI) traits explained considerable variance in perceivers' conceptual representations of social trait space. Thus, these relationships are inherently bidirectional: our social knowledge structures both influence and are influenced by social perception (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">Oh, Walker, &amp; Freeman, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Oh, Martin, &amp; Freeman, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b96">Xie et al., 2019)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Recent Work: Social Knowledge Structures</head><p>More recent work has begun to investigate how these social knowledge structures support adaptive social behavior. For example, in work by van Baar and colleagues (2021), social motives served as a structure that, if deduced, could promote more optimal social decision-making. Participants learned about the behavior of people who played across four economic games that varied in their payoff structures, meaning that a player with a given motive (i.e., risk aversion) might behave differently in different games (i.e., cooperating in one where mutual defection is particularly disadvantageous and defecting in another where unilateral cooperation is most risky; van <ref type="bibr">Baar, Nassar, Deng, &amp; FeldmanHall, 2021)</ref>.</p><p>Results revealed that participants were indeed able to glean these players' latent motives (independent of specific task details) and successfully use them to predict players' future behavior in novel contexts. Notably, basic reinforcement learning models could not capture the acquisition and generalization of this structure, but a feature-based reinforcement learning model designed to account for these unobservable drivers of players' behavior.</p><p>Other work from Frolichs and colleagues (2022) directly tested how a conceptual map of trait space might facilitate dynamic social learning. Here, participants rated a series of unknown targets on the basis of multiple social trait items (e.g., individual items associated with the Big Five personality factors; <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Frolichs, Rosenblau, &amp; Korn, 2022)</ref>. After each rating, participants received feedback about how that target had rated themselves on the item in question (in four of the five studies, these were real individuals and the feedback was genuine). The authors used a series of computational models to examine the contributions of various strategies for making these predictions-in particular, reference points (i.e., expectations regarding where the average person falls on the traits in question) and granularity (i.e., a representation of the interrelationships between individual traits).</p><p>Granularity was operationalized in two ways: coarse granularity (i.e., where feedback regarding a particular trait could only update a summary value regarding the corresponding Big Five factor [e.g., extraversion]) and fine granularity (i.e., where feedback regarding a particular trait could update values for all traits, as a function of pairwise similarity to the trait in question). Fine granularity was modeled in terms of actual relationships between individual traits in independent samples of participants. While results revealed that participants' usage of reference points, coarse granularity, and fine granularity varied across targets and context, the most consistent influence on updating was fine granularity information. In other words, these data illustrate that fine-grained social knowledge structures may play a more direct role in guiding trait generalization, compared to broad dimension-based categories.</p><p>Beyond supporting our ability to learn about and predict the behavior of others, social knowledge structures can be applied to our understanding of the self as well. Elder and colleagues (2023) constructed a trait dependency model based on independent raters' subjective assessments of the extent to which certain traits depended on other traits. When participants were given feedback indicating they were high in one trait (e.g., generous), they generalized this feedback based on how it related to or depended on other traits. In other words, to the extent that people believed being generous depends on another trait (e.g., cooperative), they also updated their (self-)impression of cooperation in response to feedback regarding generosity. In sum, this work provides evidence that people are aware of the semantic linkages between traits, and further, that this knowledge influences how we preserve and generalize our self-concept.</p><p>Finally, our own recent work demonstrates how people can generalize contextdependent trait impressions formed via interactive feedback as a function of similarity between contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Hackel, Mende-Siedlecki, Loken, &amp; Amodio, 2022)</ref>. For example, having learned instrumentally that a target was competent in a math context (i.e., they scored highly on Math GRE questions), participants generalized this knowledge to similar novel contexts. Specifically, they were more likely to choose to "hire" such individuals to answer questions in the domains of Science and Pattern Recognition. Conversely, participants were also more likely to choose individuals who they learned were competent in a verbal context (i.e., the Verbal GRE) in the verbal-related domains of History and Arts.</p><p>Critically, participants did not generalize based on domain-irrelevant knowledge: similarity between the novel and verbal domains did not influence reliance on math competence and similarity between the novel and math domains did not influence reliance on verbal competence. In other words, participants flexibly and selectively applied trait-based learning to make social choices in novel domains as a function of perceived contextual similarity. By contrast, reward-based learning-which was manipulated orthogonally to trait competence-demonstrated both significantly weaker context-sensitivity and generalization.</p><p>While these results focus on the generalization of one specific trait (i.e., competence) to contexts varying in their expression of that trait (e.g., math vs. science), one final piece of evidence from this work suggests that the generalization phenomenon extends more broadly. In their final study, Hackel and colleagues asked participants to evaluate the targets they'd encountered in the instrumental learning task in terms of how likely they'd be to turn to them for help in three social scenarios: one involving interpersonal empathy (which might prioritize verbal abilities), one involving planning and logistics (which might prioritize math abilities), and one involving a social problemsolving situation (which might involve both abilities). Indeed, results revealed the flexible generalization of learned trait information to these completely novel contexts. When determining whom to seek for support, verbal ability was prioritized for the empathy and social problem-solving scenarios, while math ability was prioritized for the planning scenario.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Gaps in the Current Literature</head><p>This recent research collectively extends our understanding of how social knowledge structures support dynamic social cognition, but several gaps still exist. For</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overview of the Current Studies</head><p>We propose that people use maps of social knowledge to generalize trait feedback, transcending the specifics of a particular encounter to choose partners in novel situations requiring different trait dispositions. By applying trait-based learning-potentially rooted in semantic memory systems rather than instrumental reward systems-people may be able to leverage abstract knowledge about traits to assign value to social partners, enabling flexible choices. Here, we tested this concept across three experiments to illuminate how conceptual maps support trait generalization and its implications on decision-making. We further hypothesized that trait generalization is a socially specific process, cannot be attributed to valence alone, and occurs spontaneously at encoding.</p><p>Informed by the results of our pilot study, we conducted Experiment 1, where we tested how trait generalization based on inferences made in one social domain guides decision-making in novel social contexts that rely on various other traits. Participants learned about two targets in a learning game (that revealed sociability about each target), and then chose which target to hire in other social games that relied on different traits. We predicted that participants' decisions would be explained by perceived similarity between traits, such that participants would be more likely to choose the sociable target in a new game whose trait profile is more similar to that of the learning game. Since it's possible that such generalization might reflect associations between the games themselves (rather than perceived similarity between the traits they require), we also tested our hypothesis that trait generalization is a socially specific process in Experiment 1. Specifically, we randomly assigned participants to one of two versions of our experiment where the targets were either described as a) previous participants from a prior study or b) slot machines.</p><p>This manipulation helped us establish whether trait generalization is predominantly deployed in social contexts (i.e., where underlying trait dispositions are more likely to support predictions about behavior).</p><p>Next, Experiment 2 tested the robustness of trait generalization by implementing multiple new game contexts. Each new game relied on a new trait that was not included in Experiment 1. Participants followed a similar procedure as described in Experiment 1 with one crucial difference: rather than having participants learn and infer traits through a learning task, we explicitly labeled each target with a single, unique trait. This allowed us greater experimental control as the learning task introduced a potential confound in that participants learned multiple traits about each target. We also aimed to elucidate the factors that contributed to trait generalization, such as consensus, idiosyncratic, and valence ratings between traits. Participants rated similarity between trait pairs and valence values for individual traits after the main task was completed. We predicted that traits generalization could not be explained through valence ratings alone, such that "sociable" would not generalize to "intelligent" just because both traits are perceived as positive.</p><p>Finally, Experiment 3 tested our final hypothesis that trait generalization occurs spontaneously at encoding of a trait impression. Participants completed a false recognition paradigm; participants read sentences about a trait paired with random faces, and then later were asked if a certain trait was used to describe a shown face. We predicted that the more similar traits were to one another, the more likely participants were to falsely remember a trait describing a certain face. In sum, these three studies further our understanding of social learning, inference, and decision-making, and suggest that trait-based conceptual maps guide the human ability to generalize traits across multiple domains.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chapter PILOT STUDY: CHARACTERIZING TASK CONTEXTS AND</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RELATIONSHIPS BETWEEN TRAITS</head><p>We first conducted a pilot study to validate and measure our initial behavioral games and trait pairs. Specifically, we obtained sets of subjective ratings that allowed us to determine 1) the trait profiles associated with each game (i.e., "Task-trait" task), 2) the extent to which behavior in a given game might be predicted from a hypothetical target's behavior in a different game (i.e., "Task-task" task), and 3) the perceived similarity between all possible pairs of traits in the set we selected (i.e., "Trait-trait" task). This was achieved by randomly assigning participants to one of three tasks, respectively. Once collected, these ratings were used in analyses throughout the rest of the experiments collected in this manuscript.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We recruited 119 participants from Prolific (Mage = 30.37, SD = 10.63). 54 identified as female, 62 identified as male, and 3 identified as non-binary/third gender. 68 identified as White/Caucasian, 24 identified as East Asian, 8 identified as African American, 5 identified as South Asian, 9 identified as multiracial, 1 identified as American Indian or Alaska Native, 1 identified as Pacific Islander, and 3 preferred to self-identify their race/ethnicity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Participants were randomly assigned to one of three tasks. Two of these tasks (the "Task-trait" task and the "Task-task" task) involved learning about a series of six games that could conceivably be psychological paradigms and evaluating hypothetical participants' behavior in these games. These games were described as follows:</p><p>In the "Gambling Game," a player is given two options to choose between. Option #1 affords them some chance of winning a sum of money and some chance of losing a different sum of money. Option #2 guarantees that they will win a sum of money that's smaller than what they could win if they chose Option #1. Thus, this game essentially resembles a two-armed bandit task (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Dayan &amp; Daw, 2008)</ref> where one option offers a certain payout but a lower expected value than the other. Behavior in this game should facilitate judgments of the degree to which a player is cautious or prone to taking risks.</p><p>In the "Giving Game," there are two players, a Giver and a Receiver. The Giver is given a sum of money that they can choose to distribute between themself and the Receiver.</p><p>They can decide how much to keep for themselves (which could be all of the money), and how much to send to the Receiver (which could also be all of the money). Thus, the game is formulated like a typical Dictator game <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Kahneman, Knetsch, and Thaler 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Forsythe et al. 1994)</ref>; behavior in the game should facilitate judgments of the Giver's generosity.</p><p>In the "Photo Game," there are two players, a Director and a Viewer. The Director is given a set of images ranging in emotional content from very negative (e.g., upsetting images of bodily injuries, disgusting scenes, frightening snakes and spiders, etc.; similar to images from the International Affective Pictures System [IAPS]; <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bradley &amp; Lang, 2007)</ref> to neutral (e.g., images of household objects) to very positive (e.g., cute images of baby animals, beautiful nature scenes, happy people, etc.). They are given the task of choosing 10 images to give to the Viewer to see and rate. Thus, behavior in the game should facilitate judgments of how prosocial or anti-social the Director is.</p><p>In "Rock-Paper-Scissors," there are two players. Each player chooses one of three hand signals to "throw" on a given turn --rock, paper, or scissors. The typical rules applied: rock beats scissors, scissors beats paper, paper beats rock. Since victory in the game requires making predictions about what the other player will throw, in an iterative context, behavior in the game should facilitate judgments of how strategic a player is.</p><p>In the "Delay Game," there are two players, a Decider and a Recipient. The Decider is given the choice between two options; whichever option they choose will be given to the Recipient. In Option #1, the Recipient will receive a certain amount of money immediately.</p><p>In Option #2, the Recipient will receive a larger sum of money after a delay of at least a day. Thus, the game takes the form of a dyadic delay discounting paradigm (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Becker, DeGroot &amp; Marschak, 1964;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Myerson &amp; Green, 1995)</ref>, where the Decider's choices should facilitate judgments of how patient or impulsive they are.</p><p>In the "Learning Game," there are two players, a Listener and a Speaker. The Listener gets to decide whether they want to get to know another person (the Speaker) or to learn random facts, based on what they are more interested in. Each trial, this choice is revealed to the Speaker. Depending on what the Listener chose, the Speaker either sends information about themselves (specifically, Yes or No answers to biographical and personal preference questions that they're posed with-for example, "Yes" in response to "Do you prefer coffee over tea?") or chooses whether or not to send a particular random fact (specifically, these were either facts about animals or geography-for example, "Otters have favorite rocks"). This paradigm was adapted from work on the rewarding nature of self-disclosure <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">(Tamir &amp; Mitchell, 2012)</ref> and should facilitate judgments of how sociable the Listener is.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task-Trait Task</head><p>63 participants were randomly assigned to the Task-trait task. They read brief descriptions of each of the six games listed above, accompanied by descriptions of how specific hypothetical players behaved in each game. After these descriptions, participants saw a list of fourteen trait adjectives and rated the degree to which they felt they could infer each trait from the hypothetical player's in-game behavior (-3 to +3 scale; -3 = "They definitely don't have this trait," 0 = "Unclear as to whether or not they have this trait," +3 = "They definitely have this trait"). We noted explicitly that each scenario concerned a different player; in other words, participants were not rating the same individual in each scenario.</p><p>For example, participants might read about the Gambling Game and hear about a hypothetical player who, when faced with the choice between 1) a 90% chance of winning $5 and a 10% chance of losing $1.50, or 2) a certainty of winning $1, chose Option 2 (a certain $1). Based on this information, they then rated the extent to which they could infer that this player was cautious, cheerful, cooperative, friendly, generous, impulsive, intellectual, patient, reliable, self-disciplined, smart, sociable, strategic, and trustworthy.</p><p>Since our goal was ultimately to determine the sensitivity of these inferences to a player's behavior, we varied the hypothetical players' behavior across two versions of the task. In one version (N = 30), these individuals were cautious in the Gambling Game, generous in the Giving Game, friendly in the Photo Game, not strategic in Rock-Paper-Scissors, impatient in the Delay Game, and not sociable in the Learning Game. These behavioral profiles were reversed in the other version (N = 33).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task-Task Task</head><p>29 participants were randomly assigned to the Task-task task. This task began with a description of each of the six games explained above. Next, participants read about a hypothetical player's behavior in each game and then judged how likely it was that they would behave in a particular way in each of the other games (1 to 7 scale; 1 = not at all likely, 7 = extremely likely). Once again, participants were instructed that they were not rating the same individual in each scenario.</p><p>For example, they might read a prompt about a hypothetical player who, when playing the Giving Game in the role of the Giver, is given $10 to share with the Receiver.</p><p>The Giver chooses to split the money equally and send the Receiver $5. (The participant is told to imagine that they are the Receiver.) Based on this information, the participant is asked a series of questions-specifically, how likely it is that this hypothetical individual will a) take a sure $1 over a 90% chance of winning $5 with a 10% chance of losing $1.50 in the Gambling Game, b) send 8 positive and 2 neutral photos to the Viewer in the Photo Game, c) win 9 out of 10 rounds of Rock-Paper-Scissors, d) take $6 in two weeks over $5 tomorrow in the Delay Game, and e) request 8 personal details and 2 random facts in the Learning Game. (The same behavioral profiles were used for each Task-task item-both prompts and questions.)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trait-Trait Task</head><p>26 participants were randomly assigned to the Trait-trait task. This task was unconnected to any of the six tasks described above. Participants read 91 pairs of traits (taken from the list of fourteen trait adjectives described above) and rated how similar each pair of traits was to each other (1 to 7 scale, 1 = "not at all similar" and 7= "extremely similar"). For example, participants might see the pair "sociable-strategic," and would simply have to report the similarity of these two trait concepts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses</head><p>Our examination of the data from Pilot Study 1 breaks down into two sets of analyses: those geared to provide an initial test of hypotheses regarding conceptual similarity and those specifically designed to characterize the games for use in future studies.</p><p>We first asked how conceptual similarity of traits related to the array of trait inferences people made based on each game. In our pilot study, one sample of participants in the Task-Trait task rated the extent to which they would infer 14 different traits for targets who made each possible choice in each game we described. For instance, they rated the extent to which a Dictator Game player who shared $1 or one who shared $5 is cooperative, trustworthy, patient, self-disciplined, and so on. These ratings indicated the constellation of traits that participants inferred for targets who enacted these behaviors. A second sample of pilot subjects in the Trait-Trait task rated the conceptual similarity of these trait terms-for instance, rating the similarity of "cooperative" and "trustworthy."</p><p>Past research indicates that the conceptual similarity of traits shapes the extent to which they are perceived together in others <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Stolier et al., 2020)</ref>. We similarly asked whether the conceptual similarity of traits predicted the extent to which traits were perceived together in the games. That is, if "cooperative" and "trustworthy" are seen as conceptually similar traits, are they likely to be jointly inferred to a similar degree when seeing another person's behavior? For each game, we first calculated how much each trait was inferred from each game. Specifically, we calculated a difference score comparing the trait ratings for one target (e.g., the player who shares $5) versus the other (e.g., the player who shares $1), indicating the extent to which behavior in this game impacts perception of each trait. We next calculated whether pairs of traits were likely to be inferred in tandem in response to the games. Specifically, we computed the absolute difference for each pair of traits within each game (e.g., in the Dictator Game, how far apart were scores for "cooperative" and "trustworthy"). Finally, we asked whether conceptually similar traits were more likely to be inferred in tandem. Specifically, we conducted a mixed effects linear regression predicting these distance scores as a function of conceptual trait similarity (reverse coded as dissimilarity, given that the outcome variable was distance). Random effects for each game were included.</p><p>In addition, to validate that the games did evoke the intended trait inferences, we sought to determine which trait was most strongly inferred from behavior in each game.</p><p>Thus, we computed average ratings of each trait within both versions of the Task-trait task and conducted paired-samples t-tests to examine which trait showed the largest difference in ratings between the two versions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conceptual Similarity of Traits Predicts Constellation of Trait Inferences</head><p>Aligned with past research <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">(Stolier et al., 2020)</ref>, we found that the conceptual similarity of two traits predicted whether those two traits tended to be perceived in tandem, b = .44, SE = .07, t = 5.95, p &lt; .001. That is, if "cooperative" and "trustworthiness" were seen as similar by one group of subjects, then another group of subjects was more likely to perceive "cooperativeness" and "trustworthiness" as similarly present (or absent) in each game. This finding links conceptual similarity of traits to the constellation of trait impressions participants had of each target based on each game, tying conceptual trait knowledge to patterns of inferences in these specific games. In the experiments that follow, we built on this observation to test whether those trait constellations supported generalization in decision-making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Traits Revealed by Each Game</head><p>The Gambling Game most strongly revealed the trait cautious, as this trait produced the largest difference in evaluations across the two versions of the <ref type="table">Task</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>This pilot study allowed us to fully characterize our stimuli (i.e., in terms of which games were most strongly associated with which traits, as well as the perceived relationships between trait concepts) and to obtain initial evidence for conceptual similarity shaping trait inference. Moving forward, we leveraged these findings to guide our subsequent experiments' design and analyses. In other words, apart from establishing proofs of concept for the behavioral games and trait profiles, we used this pilot study as a means of operationalizing perceived similarities between traits, so that we could test how similarity guides generalization and social decision-making across Experiments 1-3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chapter 3 EXPERIMENT 1: ESTABLISHING SIMILARITY-BASED TRAIT</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>GENERALIZATION AND ITS SOCIAL SPECIFICITY</head><p>In Experiment 1, we investigated whether conceptual maps based on trait similarity guide the generalization of social knowledge in decision-making. Previous work demonstrates that context-dependent impressions support our ability to flexibly apply our impressions of others to determine who to interact with in novel contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Hackel et al., 2022)</ref>. Moreover, social knowledge structures regarding the relationships between traits guide learning about the self <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Elder et al., 2023)</ref> and others <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Frolichs et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">van Baar et al., 2021)</ref>. Here, we integrate across this work to test how perceived similarity facilitates trait-based generalization in service of social decision-making.</p><p>Participants in Experiment 1 learned about two different targets who previously played a Learning Game, which revealed information regarding the sociability of each target. One target behaved sociably by asking participants questions about themselves, while the other was less sociable and instead preferred to ask for general knowledge facts.</p><p>We then tested how inferences of sociability influenced participants' decisions to choose either target in new game contexts that relied on other traits varying in similarity to sociability (e.g., a Delay Game revealing patience). We hypothesized that the more similar two traits are perceived to be, the more likely the traits are perceived to be in tandem. As such, we predicted that when making choices in new game contexts that relied on different traits, people would be more likely to choose the sociable target in a new context to the extent that the trait profile of the original context was similar to the trait profile of the new context.</p><p>Critically, we also included a test of whether this generalization process is domaingeneral or is socially specific. While people can use conceptual maps or inferences about causal structure in any domain, trait knowledge offers rich conceptual knowledge that may be specifically useful for generalization in social contexts. To address this question, we manipulated the descriptions of the two targets encountered in the learning phase between subjects. Specifically, we varied whether these targets were described as human (e.g., previous MTurk workers) or non-human slot machines. We expected that trait generalization would be observed in social contexts (i.e., for human targets), but would not exist in non-social situations where traits-and thus relationships between traits-would be less applicable (i.e., for slot targets).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preregistration</head><p>The predictions, measures, sample size, and analytic strategy associated with Experiment 1 were preregistered (https://aspredicted.org/XRS_SGM).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>One hundred seventy-one participants completed Experiment 1 on the platform CloudResearch (then called TurkPrime) in exchange for payment (76 female, 94 male, 1 nonbinary; Mage = 39, SDage = 11, range = 18-71). A power analysis reported in prior work <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hackel et al., 2020)</ref> suggested a sample of 40 participants per cell would be sufficient for 90% power in a comparison of trait-based choices for human versus slot machines. However, to account for the likelihood that the generalization effect size could be weaker and for any potential subject exclusions, we aimed for a sample size of 85 per cell. One additional MTurk worker completed the study without submitting their response for payment.</p><p>Participants were excluded based on two preregistered exclusion rules. First, participants were asked, at the end of the study, which target had been associated with more "self-disclosure" questions (indicating a sensitivity to the sociable target) during the initial learning task, and data were excluded from participants who answered incorrectly. Second, participants were excluded if they did not respond in time on more than 20% of trials in the Test Phase. Using these preregistered exclusion criteria, which resulted in data from 26 subjects being excluded, leaving 145 participants for analysis. The study was approved by the USC Office for Protection of Human Subjects and informed consent was collected from all participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimuli</head><p>Participants viewed two distinct fractal images that they were told represented either 1) two previous participants (in the social condition) or 2) two computerized slot machines (in the non-social condition). We used fractal images to represent targets instead of face images so that the same images could be used in both conditions, and further, to avoid activating any specific stereotypes (e.g., race, gender, age, etc.) that might lead to biased learning or choice. For each participant, each fractal target was randomly assigned to one of two task roles in the learning phase, ensuring that any features of the images (e.g., pleasantness) were randomly distributed across player types and would not influence effects of interest.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Learning Phase</head><p>For the learning phase of the task <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">(Figure 1A)</ref>, participants were told that they would play the "Learning Game." Critically, we manipulated (between subjects) whether participants were assigned to a social condition or a non-social condition.</p><p>The mechanics of the Learning Game were consistent with those described in Pilot Study 1. In the social condition, participants were told that previous participants had played a "Listener" role and that they themselves would now be playing in the role of "Speaker."</p><p>They were told that Listeners made a series of choices about whether they wanted to learn about other MTurk workers or to learn facts about animals and geography. Participants were told that they would complete whichever task the Listener chose on each round. If the Listener wanted to get to know them, they would be asked a personal Yes-or-No question (specifically, whether or not a particular statement described them), and their answer would be sent to the Listener in a follow-up session. If the Listener instead wanted to learn a fact, the participant would see an animal or geography fact and could choose to accept it or reject it. If they accepted the fact, it would be sent to the Listener in the follow-up session;</p><p>if they rejected the fact, then a random fact from the other category would be sent instead.</p><p>The "self" and "fact" questions thus involved similar timing and effort. This game was created based on prior work indicating that people generally find self-disclosure rewarding, relative to discussing facts <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">(Tamir &amp; Mitchell, 2012)</ref>, meaning that participants might infer the trait sociability about these targets, while, in addition, potentially finding one more rewarding than the other.</p><p>In the non-social condition, the Learning Game operated exactly the same with one important change: participants were told that they were learning about computerized "slot machines" that would assign them "self" or "fact" questions on each trial, and further, that any self-disclosures or facts would be sent to a "Listener" who would participate on a future occasion. Similar instructions have been used to manipulate social or non-social framings in past work <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Hackel et al., 2020)</ref>.</p><p>Participants completed 36 trials of the learning phase. At the start of each trial, participants viewed the two fractal targets representing prior participants and were tasked with picking one. Each target was equally likely to appear on each side of the screen.</p><p>During a choice epoch, participants indicated which target they preferred to engage with by pressing one of two response keys. Next, for 3 seconds, feedback was displayed on screen indicating the task selected by the target. After seeing this feedback, participants completed the assigned task. On "self-disclosure" trials, they were presented with a statement that could describe someone (e.g., "is a talented cook") and were asked to indicate whether the statement described them or not. On "fact" trials, they were presented with a statement describing a fact about animals or geography (e.g., "Seahorses are monogamous and mate for life") and were asked to indicate whether they accept or reject the fact. No response window was placed on decisions, since trials involved reading and responding to statements, which required longer and varied amounts of time. One target requested self-disclosures 85% of the time (the "sociable" target) and one target requested self-disclosures 15% of the time (the non-sociable target).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Test Phase</head><p>In the test phase, participants were once again told that they would play five new games with the same targets (either human or slot, depending on condition) and received instructions for each ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 1B)</ref>. Specifically, we described the five games detailed above in Pilot Study 1: the Photo Game, the Gambling Game, the Delay Game, Rock-Paper-Scissors, and the Giveaway Game (identical to the "Giving Game" in Pilot Study 1). These games were designed to prompt inferences primarily about friendliness, cautiousness, patience, strategy, and generosity, respectively. The instructions were directly adapted from the materials used in the original pilot. For participants in the non-social condition, we made clear that the selections made in each game context were still assigned by slot machines.</p><p>For the Photo Game, we explicitly stated that a) the targets they learned about in the Learning Game had chosen ten images for future participants to view and rate and that b) they (the participants) would have to view and rate the images assigned to them by their selected target. For the Gambling Game, we specified that when playing this game, these targets could choose between two options: (1) a 90% chance of winning $5 and a 10% chance of losing $1.50 or (2) a 100% chance of winning $1. Additionally, participants were told that they could now earn whatever those targets earned. The instructions emphasized that over several trials, Option 1 would offer higher payouts, and it would therefore be beneficial to select the target who gives the riskier option.</p><p>For the Giveaway Game, we specified that these targets had $10 available and could share $5 or $1 with a receiver. For the Delay Game, we specified that targets could choose to send the participant $5 immediately or $6 in two weeks. In both of these cases, we stated that participants' bonuses would depend on choices that their selected target had made.</p><p>Finally, for the Rock-Paper-Scissors game, we stated that targets played against other human opponents, and further, that participants would win money each time their chosen target won a game.</p><p>Our analyses required us to identify which target was perceived as more valuable in each game (described below). Therefore, before beginning the test phase, we asked participants to a) indicate which of the specified options they preferred in the Delay Game and b) whether they would prefer a partner in the Photo Game who sent many pleasant images or many unpleasant images, given that these two games involve subjective preferences. For the other games, participants were asked to indicate which target they thought would bring them a larger payoff in the long run. In the case of Rock-Paper-Scissors, we asked participants to choose between someone who won their round and someone who lost their round. In the learning phase, participants made choices to interact with two targets described as humans or computerized slot machines. Feedback indicated whether another person was interested in learning about them versus facts (human condition) or whether a slot machine had assigned them to send information about themselves or a fact to another person (slot machine condition). After feedback, participants either answered a self-disclosure question or decided to send or reject a potential fact to another person. (b) In the test phase, participants chose between the same targets in five new games that varied in the traits they require, such as a "Giveaway Game" in which a target can share money or a "Gambling Game" in which a target offers either a risky high-payoff option or a safe low-payoff option.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Post-Task Ratings</head><p>After the task, participants were asked which target had offered more "selfdisclosure" questions during learning as an attention check. For exploratory purposes, participants were probed for suspicion using two questions (i.e., an open-ended question ["Do you have any other thoughts on the {people or slot machines depending on condition} you learned about today?"] and a multiple-choice question ["Which of the following statements about today's task would you say is ultimately most accurate?"]) described in prior work <ref type="bibr">(Hackel, Mende-Siedlecki, &amp; Amodio, 2020, Supplemental Materials)</ref>.</p><p>Participants also completed a multiple-choice question asking which of the following options best described the targets they learned about: "previous students who participated previously," "other students participating simultaneously as you," "computer-controlled "slot machines"," "randomly generated responses," or something else (which was accompanied by a free response box). We did not preregister any exclusions associated with responses to this question.</p><p>Next, participants indicated whether they had preferred self-disclosure or fact questions during the learning game. Participants in the human condition then rated each target on the 14 traits used in Pilot Study 1 for exploratory purposes. Finally, participants completed demographic questions regarding their age, gender, and racial identity, and were then debriefed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses</head><p>To examine how trait inferences during the learning phase influenced decisionmaking in new games, we fit test phase behavior to a mixed effect logistic regression. This regression predicted the log odds of choosing the target associated with more "selfdisclosure" questions in the learning phase (arbitrarily chosen; 1 = yes, 0 = no). Our primary predictor was the similarity of trait profiles for this target and a hypothetical valuable target in each of the five new games, as rated by the independent sample. (The calculation of this predictor is described below.) In addition, we also included predictors for framing condition (1 = social, -1 = non-social) and the interaction of framing condition with similarity.</p><p>For each new game, we computed a difference score indicating the trait profile that distinguishes the "valuable target" from the "less valuable target" in each game. For instance, in games in which one target had a clear economic benefit (e.g., the Giveaway Game), the valuable target was defined as the one with higher expected return (i.e., the generous as opposed to stingy giver). For games in which preferences were subjective (e.g., the Delay Game), the valuable target was defined using the participant's self-reported preferences. Using trait ratings from the pilot study, we subtracted ratings for the nonvaluable target from ratings for the valuable target in each game. We computed a similar difference score for the Learning Game, indicating the trait profile distinguishing the sociable and non-sociable target. Finally, we correlated the trait profiles from each new game with the trait profile from the Learning Game <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>.</p><p>This procedure yielded five correlations, indicating the extent to which a valuable (versus non-valuable) target in a given new game context has a similar or different constellations of traits when compared to the "sociable" (versus non-sociable) target in the Learning Game <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>. These correlations (Fisher r-to-z transformed and meancentered within-subject) were therefore used to predict, trial-by-trial, whether participants chose the sociable target in the test phase. In other words, this predictor tests whether participants were more likely to choose the "sociable" target in a new game when the trait profile of a valuable target in the new game grew more similar to the trait profile of the sociable target. All random variances were included. This analysis was preregistered (https://aspredicted.org/XRS_SGM).  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Defining the similarity regressor. Using data from Pilot Study 1, we took the difference scores characterizing the "trait profile" of each game and calculated the resulting correlation (r) between each game and the Learning Game. Positive values reflect greater similarity in terms of the traits perceived to be revealed by two pairs of games. For example, the Learning Game (which revealed sociability) was seen as relatively similar to the Photo Game (which revealed friendliness), but relatively dissimilar to Rock-Paper-Scissors (which revealed how strategic a player was).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Generalization of Trait Knowledge for Social Versus Non-Social Choices</head><p>We hypothesized that participants would generalize based on trait knowledge for humans but not slot machines. Consistent with trait generalization, we found a main effect of Trait Similarity in the test phase, b = .73, SE = .13, z = 5.62, p &lt; .001, such that participants were more likely to choose the "sociable" target when that target's traits were Here, we show that trait similarity serves as a guiding mechanism underlying generalization. For instance, after learning that someone preferred learning about them over learning about facts (suggesting the trait "sociable"), participants were more likely to choose this person to play for them in a Dictator Game (where sharing suggests the trait "generous") but not in Rock-Paper-Scissors (where winning suggests the trait "strategic")-consistent with our pilot data demonstrating that people judge "generous" as more conceptually similar to "sociable" than to "strategic." More broadly, these findings accord with the idea that trait knowledge offers a conceptual map that guides social learning and decision-making across trait domains.</p><p>Critically, Experiment 1 also demonstrated the social specificity of trait-based generalization. Participants generalized their learning based on trait similarity when told they were playing with other humans, however, this generalization effect was not observed when participants thought they were playing with slot machines. In other words, when it made sense to infer trait-like dispositions from (human) targets, perceived relationships between trait concepts shaped partner choice in new contexts. However, since trait concepts are comparatively less applicable to slot machines, trait-like behavior in the learning phase domain was seen as much less predictive of behavior in the test phase domains. Thus, the conceptual map afforded by our trait knowledge may be specifically applied in social interactions to guide our predictions about other people's behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2. Trait-based choices in novel contexts varied by condition.</head><p>The y-axis indicates the proportion of times participants chose the target that had been more "sociable" during the learning phase (i.e., the target who asked more self-disclosure questions). Contexts are ordered, from left to right, to indicate whether a valuable player in each new context was seen as similar or dissimilar relative to the sociable target in the learning phase (as rated by an independent sample). When participants were told they were playing with other humans, they were more likely to choose the sociable target when the new context required a partner with a more similar trait profile. When participants were told they were playing with computerized "slot machines," choices did not vary as a function of trait similarity. Error bars show SEM, adjusted for withinsubject comparisons <ref type="bibr">(Morey, 2008)</ref>. Dashed line indicates chance performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chapter 4</head><p>EXPERIMENT 2: DEMONSTRATING THE ROBUSTNESS AND</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>GENERALIZABILITY OF SIMILARITY-BASED TRAIT GENERALIZATION</head><p>While Experiment 1 establishes that perceived trait similarity guides generalization to support social decision-making in novel contexts, several limitations leave open questions. First, Experiment 1 relied only on one inferred trait-sociability-as the basis for generalization to a relatively limited set of novel game contexts. Thus, the generalizability of this generalization process remains untested. Relatedly, it's possible that rather than generalizing their initial impressions of sociability, the learning context we chose led participants to make a host of social inferences at once. Indeed, our pilot data suggest that the Learning Game (i.e., the basis for participants' initial impressions in Experiment 2) reveals not only the trait sociable, but also cooperative, friendly, generous, and reliablealbeit to lesser degrees. In addition, it's unclear whether participants were generalizing social knowledge on the basis of genuine conceptual similarity (e.g., "sociable people also tend to be friendly and generous") or mere valence (e.g., "sociability, friendliness, and generosity are all positive traits"). Finally, our perceived similarity measure in Experiment 1 was based on consensus ratings, preventing the possibility of testing the extent to which participants' own conceptual maps guided their choices, over and above the general consensus. Experience or acculturation might lead an individual to perceive two traits as more strongly (or more weakly) linked relative to consensus, and presumably, that difference should be reflected in generalization. Thus, focusing only on consensus perceptions of similarity would likely yield a limited view of the possible scope of trait generalization.</p><p>Experiment 2 aimed to address these limitations. First, we expanded the traits used as the basis for generalization and the set of game contexts in which participants made their choices. Moreover, we randomly assigned specific trait labels to targets, rather than relying on participants to infer traits via instrumental learning. As such, we focused participants' initial inferences on one explicitly-referenced trait concept. We also introduced four new game contexts, in addition to the six already used in Experiment 1.</p><p>We predicted that we would continue to observe evidence of trait-based generalization across the new trait profiles and game contexts. In addition, we tested whether participant-specific trait similarity ratings would guide generalization over and above both consensus similarity ratings and mere valence similarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preregistration</head><p>The predictions, measures, sample size, and analytic strategy associated with Experiment 2 were initially preregistered on AsPredicted.org (https://aspredicted.org/D2M_N7K). An addendum to this preregistration concerning our exclusion criteria and sample size was subsequently posted on AsPredicted.org (https://aspredicted.org/59D_XJR).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>217 undergraduate students at the University of Delaware were recruited from the PSYC100 SONA pool in exchange for research participation credit. Preregistered exclusion criteria stated that participants who failed to correctly answer a suspicion question at the end of the survey would be excluded from data analysis. Specifically, participants had to select the multiple-choice option "You learned about people who participated previously in a separate study, who completed a diagnostic personality test" in response to the question "Which of the following statements about today's task do you think is most accurate?". However, as the study progressed, only slightly more than half of the participants were answering the correct statement. (The majority of wrong answers occurred when participants selected "You learned about people participating simultaneously as you, who self-reported their favorite personality characteristics."</p><p>Relatively few participants selected "You learned about computer-controlled slot machines" or "You learned about randomly generated responses," or answered "Something else" and filled in the free-response box provided.)</p><p>While it was unclear why participants were inferring that the targets they learned about were participating simultaneously, we also reasoned that our predictions would still likely hold even if participants made this (incorrect) inference, though not the inferences regarding slot machines or randomly generated responses. We filed an amendment to the initial preregistration, which established the following changes to our exclusion procedures and analyses. We decided that a) we would include participants who selected the second most chosen response (e.g., "You learned about people participating simultaneously as you"), but b) we would also conduct and report analyses limited to participants who selected the initially-preregistered correct answer to ensure that our results were robust.</p><p>Further, we stated that while we initially preregistered a sample of 100 participants given the effect size in a conceptually similar previous study, we would now continue to recruit until we reach 100 people who provided the originally-intended answer to the question described above or until the end of the 2023 Spring semester, whichever came first.</p><p>After exclusions, 175 participants were used for data analysis (Mage = 18.67, SDage = 0.78). 127 participants identified as women, 45 as men, 2 as non-binary, and 1 participant chose to self-describe. 134 participants identified as White, 3 as Black, 1 as Indigenous, 1</p><p>as East Asian, 4 as Hispanic or Latinx, 3 as Middle Eastern, 25 as multiracial or another racial/ethnic category, and 4 chose not to disclose. This study was approved by the Institutional Review Board at the University of Delaware, and informed consent was collected from all participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stimuli</head><p>Throughout the main task, participants were shown images of AI-generated abstract paintings (generated at deepai.org/) and were told that these represented previous participants in the experiment. These images were randomly assigned to trait description and game context. As with the fractal targets used in Experiment 1, these images were used instead of faces to avoid activation of any sociodemographic-related stereotypes and thus, any potential bias (see examples in Appendix).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Main Task</head><p>Participants were told that they would be learning about people who participated previously in a separate study in which they completed a diagnostic personality test, which characterized them in terms of stable aspects of their personality. This diagnostic test was described as having been developed specifically to predict behavior in a series of games.</p><p>Further, participants were told that they would learn about those games, and that for each game, they would make choices about which of these previous participants they wanted to be paired with.</p><p>Ultimately, participants read about and responded to questions concerning ten different games, which were encountered in a random order. For each game, participants first read a description of the game's rules and saw an image depicting the game (see Appendix). Then, participants were presented with two diametrically-opposed descriptions of behavior in the game (e.g., someone who kept clicking long enough in the Thermometer Game to get to 100 F on 2 out of 10 rounds versus someone who kept clicking long enough in the Thermometer Game to get to 100 F on 8 out of 10 rounds), and asked to identify which type of person they would prefer to select to play for them in that particular game. We used these responses to account for participants' personal preferences in our data analysis. (For example, some participants may have preferred targets who behaved compassionately but netted small bonuses in the Tradeoff Game, while others preferred targets who were callous but netted large bonuses.)</p><p>After learning about each game and completing the preference question, participants were introduced to four previous participants., each represented by an AIgenerated abstract painting and a trait description (e.g., "This person was characterized by our diagnostic test as being [TRAIT]"). These traits were randomly assigned to three of the participants within each game, with the fourth being hard-coded as the main trait association identified in our pilot study (for example, "sociable" for the Learning Game).</p><p>These trials serve as a manipulation check and are referred to throughout as "intended trait" trials. The abstract images signifying each target were randomly assigned to traits and game contexts. Moreover, targets were encountered in a random order within each game context.</p><p>Participants then responded to the question "Would you like to select this person to play with in the <ref type="bibr">[GAME]</ref>?" on a four-point scale from 1 ("Strong No") to 4 ("Strong Yes";</p><p>Figure 3). We informed participants that these ratings would be used to select individuals to advance to a future study where other participants would actually play against them. After learning the rules of a given game and reporting their preferences for partners' behavior in that game, participants encountered four targets per game, each described with a single trait adjective. Participants gave responses on a four-point scale that indicated the extent to which they wanted to select each target to play for them in that particular game. All in all, participants encountered 40 unique game-trait combinations (e.g., an individual described as "dominant" in a Learning Game indexing sociability) varying in terms of the similarity between their explicit trait description and the "intended trait" associated with the game. 10 of these traits were the "intended" trait. The other 30 traits were selected to vary broadly in valence and representativeness of classic "domains" of person perception (e.g., morality, warmth/sociability, ability/competence).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trait Pairs Task</head><p>Similar to the trait pairs task in our previous pilot studies, participants also were presented with 30 trait pairs to rate on a 7-point scale from "very dissimilar" to "very similar." (The midpoint of the scale was anchored with "neither dissimilar nor similar.")</p><p>However, the trait pairs presented in this study were tailored to the targets that participants saw previously in the main task of the experiment. Specifically, participants rated how similar each of the three traits encountered within a given game was to the "intended trait" associated with that game. For example, if a participant learned about ambitious, empathetic, and selfish targets in the Tradeoff Game, they would now rate the similarity of each of those traits to compassionate in the trait pairs task.</p><p>These trait pairs were presented in a random order for each participant. In our preregistration, we stated that this task would be used to create a participant-specific measure of perceived similarity to be used in exploratory analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Valence Ratings Task</head><p>Finally, participants rated the valence of all 40 traits they encountered in the main task. These ratings were made on a scale from -3 ("very negative") to +3 ("very positive"), with the midpoint 0 anchored with "neither negative nor positive." In our preregistration, we stated that this task would be used to create an additional valence similarity predictor that we would control for in exploratory analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Post-Task Ratings</head><p>As mentioned above (see "Participants"), after completing the main task, the trait pairs task, and the valence ratings task, participants were probed for suspicion.</p><p>Specifically, we asked to select the answer that most accurately described the targets they had just learned about. During this section, participants were also able to provide feedback and any additional thoughts they might have about the tasks they completed or the people they learned about. Finally, in a demographics section, participants were asked their age, gender identity, and racial/ethnic identity. Participants were then debriefed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses</head><p>We analyzed participants' selections in the main task using mixed effects regression. Specifically, we used the perceived similarity between the referenced trait associated with each target and the "intended trait" associated with the game as a predictor of choice (e.g., participants' ratings of each target on the four-point scale). This predictor was Fisher r-to-z transformed and mean-centered within-subject. In our preregistration, we stated that a random intercept and random slope would initially be included in the model; if the model did not converge, we would iteratively remove the smallest random effect until it converged <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Barr et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>To construct the similarity predictor, we first confirmed the "intended trait" in each game context. In a separate pilot study (N = 97) directly adapted from Pilot Study 1, previous participants again rated hypothetical individuals on a series of traits. These individuals varied in their behavior across two versions of each game (manipulated between subjects; e.g., a person who made an even split in the Dictator game vs. a person who kept $9 out of $10 for themself). For each game, we identified the trait whose ratings varied the most across the two task versions (e.g., "generous" in the Dictator Game).</p><p>Pilot participants also rated the similarity of pairs of traits, composed from a larger set of traits including all 40 of the traits appearing in the main task of the present experiment. These ratings were made the same 1-to-7 scale used in the trait pairs task described above. Thus, for each game-target combination, we could determine a consensus judgment of how similar the referenced trait is to the "intended trait" associated with that particular game context.</p><p>As noted above, since participants could vary in terms of the outcomes they preferred in a given game, we collected participants' preferences for each game. While each game was associated with a typical preference, in instances where participants preferred the atypical option (for example, fewer personal questions and more fact-based questions in the Learning Game), we reverse-scored participants' ratings of how much they wanted to select each target. Thus, higher values would still reflect a greater desire to select partners who exhibited subjectively more valuable traits.</p><p>Finally, as detailed in our preregistration, we assessed whether our results were robust to participants' performance on the post-task question indexing their understanding of the targets they learned about. Specifically, we tested to see whether the relationship between similarity and choice varied based on whether participants correctly indicated that the targets they learned about were "people who participated previously in a separate study, who completed a diagnostic personality test."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exploratory Analyses</head><p>As noted above, our preregistration indicated that exploratory analyses would a)</p><p>compare consensus versus idiosyncratic judgments of perceived similarity as a predictor of choice and b) confirm if our primary results held when controlling for valence. For the former, we pit the consensus perceived similarity predictor (derived from ratings collected in a separate pilot study) against the participant-specific similarity predictor (derived from ratings in the trait pairs task).</p><p>For the latter, we re-ran each model with a measure of valence similarity included as a separate predictor. This predictor represents the extent to which the referenced trait for each target was judged to be similarly positive, neutral, or negative to the "intended trait" associated with the game context it appeared in. We simply subtracted the referenced trait's valence rating from the intended trait's valence rating, took the absolute value of the difference, and reverse-scored the result so that higher numbers would reflect greater similarity on a scale from 1 to 7. Our goal here was to confirm that our results were not merely driven by low-level connections between traits. From the perspective of our predictions, while frugal is likely more similar in valence to sociable than nosy is, we would predict that participants who value sociability would be more likely to select a nosy target in the Learning Game than a frugal target. If perceived similarity remains a significant predictor of choice even when controlling for valence similarity, this suggests that conceptual resemblance between traits, over and above mere valence, guides trait generalization.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Generalization of Trait Knowledge for Social Versus Non-Social Choices</head><p>Consistent with our findings in Experiment 1, consensus judgments of trait similarity were significantly associated with participants' ratings of their potential partners across the ten game contexts, b = 0.24, 95% CI [0.21, 0.26], t(5141) = 16.89, SE = 0.01, p &lt; .001 <ref type="table">(Table 2A)</ref>. When we added a) participant-specific judgments of trait similarity and b) a measure of mere valence similarity to the model, all three predictors were significantly associated with partner ratings (consensus similarity:  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. Similarity shapes trait-based generalization across ten novel contexts. A) Consensus judgments of similarity between presented traits and the traits "intended" to be associated with each game context positively predicted partner choice across ten games. B) Moreover, this relationship held when controlling for idiosyncratic (i.e., participantspecific) judgments of trait similarity and mere valence similarity between presented and intended traits. (Both of these competing predictors were, themselves, positively and significantly associated with partner choice.)</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">b = 0.</formula><p>These results remained consistent when the model was run including only participants who passed our initial preregistered exclusion criteria (consensus similarity: b </p><formula xml:id="formula_1">=</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Experiment 2 illustrated that trait-based generalization persists across a wide variety of other traits and contexts, beyond the ones deployed in Experiment 1. Moreover, these data help rule out the possibility that participants' test phase choices in those experiments were merely based on other trait inferences afforded by the Learning Game.</p><p>Here, we explicitly supplied participants with individual trait labels describing each of the potential partners they considered, and we still observed evidence of trait-based generalization. We also demonstrate that participant-specific ratings of trait similarity predicted partner choice over and above consensus ratings, while both measures of similarity remained significant predictors of choice when controlling for valence. These data suggest that individual differences in our conceptual maps of trait space explain meaningful variance in generalization beyond the "average" map, and further, that links between traits are not reflective of shared valence alone.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preregistration</head><p>The predictions, measures, sample size, and analytic strategy associated with Experiment 3 were initially preregistered on AsPredicted.org (https://aspredicted.org/G67_PSF).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>In accordance with our preregistration, we recruited 125 undergraduate students at the University of Delaware from the PSYC100 SONA pool in exchange for research participation credit. Preregistered exclusion criteria stated that participants who a) failed to rate traits in the Related condition as more similar to the explicitly stated target traits, compared to traits in the Unrelated condition and b) who did not respond on 20% or more of the Test Phase trials would be excluded would be excluded from data analysis.</p><p>We chose to recruit 125 participants to ensure at least 100 passing these exclusion criteria. An a priori power analysis (https://koumurayama.shinyapps.io/summary_statistics_based_power/) suggested that 100 participants would give us greater than 90% power to detect the predicted effect based on the results observed in our pilot study (i.e., a t-statistic of 1.63 with a sample size of 24).</p><p>After exclusions, 117 participants were included in data analysis (Mage = 18.44, SDage = 0.72). 103 participants identified as women, 11 identified as men, 2 identified as non-binary and 1 identified as transgender. 104 participants identified as White, 7</p><p>identified as Black, 3 identified as South Asian, 1 identified as East Asian, and 2 identified as multiracial. This study was approved by the Institutional Review Board at the University of Delaware, and informed consent was collected from all participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>Participants completed a false recognition task adapted from previous work on spontaneous trait inference <ref type="bibr" target="#b90">(Winter &amp; Uleman, 1984;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b91">Winter, Uleman, &amp; Cunniff, 1985;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Todorov &amp; Uleman, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">2003)</ref>. In a Learning Phase, participants read 39 statements randomly paired with full-color face stimuli (see below for details). Each statement contained an explicit reference to a specific trait adjective (e.g., "She was honest with the cashier and told him he'd given her too much change"; italics for emphasis here; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure   4A</ref>). Prior to completing the Learning Phase, participants read thorough instructions, which contained two sample trials.</p><p>After a short break, participants viewed all 39 faces once again in a Test Phase, each one paired with a trait adjective ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4B)</ref>. A third (i.e., 13) of these adjectives were the same trait adjective that originally appeared in the sentence paired with the face in question during the Learning Phase ("Exact" targets). The other two conditions represented two different types of lure trials. Another third of these adjectives were related to the originally presented trait word, but ultimately distinct ("Related" targets). For example, a  participants completed a false recognition task adapted from prior work (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Todorov &amp; Uleman, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">2003)</ref>. After reading the instructions and completing two practice tasks, participants saw 39 full-color faces randomly paired with behavioral descriptions, each explicitly referencing a specific trait. After a short break, participants moved on to the (b) Test Phase where all 39 faces were presented individually with a single trait word. 13 of these words were initially seen paired with the face in question during the Learning Phase, 13 were related to the originally presented trait, and 13 were unrelated to the originally presented trait. (In this case, "patient" is related to the originally presented trait "easygoing.") Participants indicated whether the trait on screen had appeared in the sentence initially learned about the face during the previous task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Face Stimuli</head><p>Faces were taken from the Chicago Face Database (CFD; <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Ma, Correll, &amp; Wittenbrink, 2015)</ref>. We made an effort to select relatively average faces (i.e., in terms of attractiveness, trustworthiness, dominance, and unusualness). In order to demonstrate the generalizability of spontaneous trait generalization across target gender appearance, we randomly assigned each participant to see only male-or female-appearing faces. (Thus, target gender is technically manipulated between-subjects, though we did not conduct any formal comparisons based on this factor.) Similarly, the selected faces also varied in race/ethnicity. Specifically, within either gender condition, we selected 10 Asianidentified, 10 Black-identified, 10 Latine-identified, and 10 White-identified faces, for a total of 40 faces. The inclusion of a diversity of racial identities within both the male and female-appearing faces was an attempt to increase the generalizability of this work by better capturing everyday social perception (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Hester &amp; Gray, 2020)</ref>. These faces were then randomly assigned to sentences in the Learning Phase, meaning that one of the 40 faces was always left out of the set of targets each participant learned about. Examples of the selected stimuli from the CFD can be found in the Appendix.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Behavioral Stimuli</head><p>Target sentences were created by first adapting a collection behavior-implying sentences <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">(Uleman, 1987)</ref> that have been used in previous work in the STI literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">Todorov &amp; Uleman, 2003)</ref>. To supplement this set, we also adapted similar sentence stimuli from our own collection <ref type="bibr">(Mende-Siedlecki &amp; Havlicek, in prep)</ref>, which were previously piloted in terms of trustworthiness, sociability, moral character, and various other social traits. Finally, where necessary, we created new sentence stimuli to fill in any remaining gaps in our set.</p><p>When developing these stimuli, we purposefully attempted to select equivalent numbers of positive and negative traits. Moreover, while the same 39 sentences were shown to each participant, we divided these stimuli into three subsets of 13 sentences, which counterbalanced the condition that each subset was ultimately associated with across three versions of the task. For example, the sentence "He was a compassionate listener who reached out to friends when they were going through hard times" was associated with the trait compassionate (Exact condition) in one version, generous (Related condition) in the second version, and smart (unrelated) in the third version. Across these three versions, each trait appeared in each condition once. To ensure that the effect of similarity was not confounded with valence, we endeavored to select Unrelated lures that were still of the same valence as the originally presented traits. To offset the handful of cases where this was not possible, we attempted to include some Related lures that crossed a valence boundary (i.e., dominant-selfish; adventurous-impulsive).</p><p>Norming data on the selected traits (collected in a separate pilot study; N = 97)</p><p>suggested that overall, Related traits were much more similar to the originally presented </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses</head><p>While we originally operationalized similarity in a categorical fashion (i.e., Related versus Unrelated lures), a previous pilot investigation demonstrated considerable variability in participants' perceptions of similarity, both between participants and between individual traits. As such, our preregistered primary analysis collapses across the Related and Unrelated conditions to capitalize on this variability and operationalizes similarity continuously rather than categorically.</p><p>We analyzed participants' responses to the false recognition task using generalized mixed effects logistic regression. We used the participants' responses to the false recognition task ("Yes" responses [indicating that the participant mistakenly thought the lure in question had appeared in the Learning Phase] were coded as 1, "No" responses were coded as a 0) as our DV. Perceived similarity between the originally presented trait and the lure trait (collected from each participant after the Test Phase; rated on a 1-to-7 scale from very dissimilar to very similar) as a predictor of choice.</p><p>For the primary analysis, the similarity predictor was calculated across participants (consensus perceived similarity) and mean-centered. Our pre-registration stated that a random intercept and random slope would be included, and if the model did not converge, then we would iteratively remove the smallest random effect until it converged. Similarly, we conducted another preregistered analysis with idiosyncratic (i.e., subject-level) judgments of perceived trait similarity as the predictor, rather than the consensus values used in the primary analysis.</p><p>In our preregistration, we indicated that a somewhat simpler test of the same hypothesis would be to simply examine whether participants gave more "Yes" responses to Related lures versus Unrelated lures, independent of similarity judgments. To conduct this test, we conducted a one-way ANOVA on the proportion of "Yes" responses across the Exact, Related, and Unrelated conditions. (In addition to the prediction regarding Related versus Unrelated lures, we also expected that participants would give more "Yes" responses in the Exact condition as compared to Related and Unrelated trials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exploratory Measures</head><p>We also collected data on a variety of individual difference variables (i.e., region of the US identified with, the Big Five, self-construal scale, perceived social status, morning vs. night preference, religiosity, etc.). We plan to use these measures for exploratory analyses that will guide future work on group differences in trait maps.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assessing Similarity as a Continuous Predictor</head><p>We predicted that perceived trait similarity would be positively associated with "Yes" responses in the Test Phase. Our results were consistent with this hypothesis; we found a statistically significant and positive relationship between consensus judgments of trait similarity and participants' responses in the Test Phase (b = 0.08, 95% CI [0.007, 0.15], z = 2.15, SE = 0.04, p = 0.032; <ref type="table">Table 3A</ref>). A similar relationship was also observed when using idiosyncratic similarity ratings as the primary predictor (b = 0.05, 95% CI [0.005, 0.09], z = 2.10, SE = 0.02, p = 0.035; <ref type="table">Table 3B</ref>). In both cases, participants were more likely to falsely remember traits as having been explicitly referred to in the Learning Phase when trait similarity (both consensus and idiosyncratic) between the lure and target trait was greater. Interestingly, when consensus and participant-specific judgments were pit against each other in the same model, neither consensus nor participant-specific similarity ratings were significantly associated with "Yes" responses (i.e., false recognition reflecting trait generalization) in the Test Phase (both ps &gt; .276; <ref type="table">Table 3B</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assessing the Effect of Similarity Categorically</head><p>As described above, an alternative approach would have been to collapse across these individual differences in perceived similarity and simply compare the proportion of 'Yes' responses as a function of whether participants were evaluating an Exact, Related, or Unrelated trait. Indeed, a one-way ANOVA revealed a positive, significant main effect of trait condition(F(2,232) = 49.24, p &lt; .001, p 2 = .30; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5)</ref>  In the false recognition paradigm, participants were most likely to correctly recall "exact" traits as having appeared during the Learning Phase, but critically, were also more likely to incorrectly recall related (vs. unrelated) traits as having appeared.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>While Experiments 1 and 2 provide evidence for the robustness and socialspecificity of similarity-based trait generalization, they left open the question of when this generalization occurs. Building on this work, Experiment 3 demonstrated that trait generalization can occur spontaneously at encoding. Specifically, participants completing a false recognition paradigm were more likely to show false memory for traits to the extent that they were more conceptually similar to the originally learned target traits. We take this as evidence that upon encoding, participants' initial impressions regarding a particular trait can spread and activate other related trait concepts. Moreover, we found evidence of generalization when operationalizing similarity through both consensus and idiosyncratic (i.e., participant-level) judgments. In addition, our use of a wide variety of traits and behavioral contexts in Experiment 3 offers further evidence for the generalizability of the trait generalization phenomenon demonstrated in Experiments 1 and 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>GENERAL DISCUSSION</head><p>Research on person perception frequently argues that our social impressions of other people should allow us to predict their future behavioreven in new situations that differ from those in which those impressions were originally formed <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Hackel et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">Son et al., 2021)</ref>. Here, we explored how people generalize initial impressions by using conceptual maps of social knowledge that allow them to make flexible predictions about others' behavior across various novel contexts. Across three experiments, we find evidence that perceived similarity between traits (both on a consensus and idiosyncratic level) guides such generalization.</p><p>Experiment 1 provides initial evidence for this phenomenon. Here, we observed that the conceptual similarity between the traits associated with different social game contexts guided decision-making from one context to the next. Specifically, to the extent that participants valued traits like friendliness or generosity, they were more likely to choose a sociable partner in novel contexts (i.e., a Photo Game revealing friendliness, a Giveaway Game revealing generosity, etc.) to the extent that those contexts required similar traits to the initial learning context. Critically, this effect was observed when participants thought they were making social choices about other humans, but not when they were playing with non-human slot machines, suggesting that trait-based generalization occurs in social, but not non-social, contexts. This indicates that trait knowledge is particularly useful and prevalent in guiding social interactions, where behavioral instances would presumably be more likely to reflect a latent dispositional structure characterizing one's personality <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Gershman, Norman, &amp; Niv, 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Experiment 2 extends these findings by illustrating this generalization phenomenon across a wider set of traits and contexts-and notably, when learning is reduced to associating a single trait word with a given social target. In other words, here we demonstrate the generalizability of trait-based generalization, confirming that its relevance is not constrained to the particular traits and social scenarios deployed in Experiment 1.</p><p>We further corroborated that generalization is not merely a function of commonalities in valence across traits: conceptual similarity between traits continued to predict choice even when valence was accounted for in our model, distinguishing this phenomenon from typical conceptualizations of the halo effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">(Nisbett &amp; Wilson, 1977)</ref>. Additionally, we found that both consensus and idiosyncratic (i.e., participant-specific) similarity ratings predict partner choice in the social games. This suggests that individual differences in conceptual maps play a significant role in individual decision-making.</p><p>Finally, we turned our attention to the spontaneity of this generalization phenomenon in Experiment 3. Prior work illustrates that traits are spontaneously and effortlessly inferred from behavior, supporting the formation of lasting social impressions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">Todorov &amp; Uleman, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">2003)</ref>. Here we tested whether a similar process supports generalization. Using a false recognition task, Experiment 3 provides evidence that indeed, trait generalization occurs spontaneously at encoding. Specifically, we found evidence that perceived similarity predicted participants' false memories for traits in a recall task: they were more likely to say that a lure trait was used to describe a particular face to the extent that it was seen as more similar to the originally presented trait.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Connections to Prior Work</head><p>Beyond the overarching dimensions that our social impressions can be plotted along (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abele &amp; Wojciszke, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Fiske, Cuddy, &amp; Glick, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">Oosterhof &amp; Todorov, 2008)</ref>, more recent data suggests that conceptual relationships between trait concepts provide a critical scaffolding for social cognition and perception (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">Stolier et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">Oh, Martin, &amp; Freeman, 2022)</ref>. Using this framework as a foundation, the present work sought to test how those conceptual linkages might facilitate our ability to flexibly predict behavior based on socially interactions that were limited to a particular context. In so doing, we directly expanded on several programs of contemporary research.</p><p>For example, <ref type="bibr">Frolichs and colleagues (2022)</ref> recently demonstrated evidence of trait generalization based on self-reported traits; perceivers anticipated that individuals who described themselves as possessing a given trait would also possess related traits too, as a function of real-world co-occurrences between those traits. Here, we conceptually replicate this phenomenon, but critically, extend it to traits that have been gleaned directly through instrumental learning, advancing our knowledge of when and how trait generalization occurs. Across this work, similarity-based trait generalization facilitated social decisionmaking across a diversity of novel contexts expanding on prior work that provided more constrained tests of generalization (e.g., the same motive across different contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">[van Baar et al. 2021]</ref> or different expressions of the same core trait [math versus verbal competence in <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Hackel et al., 2022]</ref>). Further, our results also dovetail with recent data suggesting that network similarity between traits serves as a guiding mechanism for self-referential judgments <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Elder et al. 2023)</ref>. Finally, this work (particularly Experiment 1)</p><p>provides important evidence demonstrating that trait generalization is a socially specific process, adding to a growing body of literature aiming to characterize domain-specific versus domain-general mechanisms supporting dynamic social cognition (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Hackel, Mende-Siedlecki, &amp; Amodio, 2020)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations and Future Directions</head><p>While this work provides important insights into our ability to flexibly generalize existing trait impressions, some limitations are worth consideration. When constructing these studies, we aimed to be programmatic; each study attempted to address flaws or fill gaps left by the previous. For example, Experiment 1 was limited by a small range of domains and traits and a focus on a consensus-based operationalization of perceived similarity. Moreover, our design was such that it was possible that the Learning Game afforded inferences about other traits beyond sociability. While these issues directly influenced our design and goals for Experiment 2, they are still important to point out.</p><p>Similarly, both Experiments 1 and 2 represented targets with images (i.e., fractals in Exp.</p><p>1, AI-generated art in Exp. 2) to avoid biases and stereotypes associated with specific racial and gender identities. Consequently, these studies have clear limitations in terms of ecological validity. By limiting the inferences that participants could draw about these targets to their in-game behavior (Exp. 1) or personality test results (Exp. 2), these stimuli are devoid of the social cognitive richness that people actually encounter in daily life.</p><p>While we addressed this to some extent in Experiment 3, we encourage future work to continue to push the boundaries of ecological validity, through even more diverse sets of stimuli.</p><p>By the same token, we would also welcome tests of trait generalization that employ more realistic, direct social interactions. In Experiments 1 and 2, participants' social decision-making amounted to selecting which targets to "hire" based on their instrumentally (Exp. 1) or passively learned (Exp. 2) trait dispositions. Secondly, these games likely do not perfectly replicate social decisions and interactions in the real world; most people don't hire someone to play Rock-Paper-Scissors for them on a daily basis, however we applaud anyone who does. How, then, does trait generalization unfold (or perhaps differ) in more direct social interactions between two individuals? Future research could operationalize learning in terms of more naturalistic stimuli <ref type="bibr">(Jolly et al., 2023)</ref> or structured interactions (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Ames &amp; Fiske, 2013)</ref> to create more authentic contexts for learning and generalization, or even behavioral vignettes or resumes that more closely approximate real-world instances of these phenomena. Consequently, despite our efforts in Experiments 2 and 3, there is still an ocean of more traits and social contexts that could be included in future follow-up work.</p><p>Another limitation concerns our test of "spontaneous" trait generalization in Experiment 3. It could be argued that our false recognition paradigm (adapted from work on spontaneous trait inference <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">[Todorov &amp; Uleman, 2002]</ref>) does not provide a conservative test of the automaticity of generalization; while we have demonstrated that generalization is occurring at without prompting or planning, the present work was not designed to assess the efficiency of this process at encoding. Other work provides useful suggestions for study designs that could be used to extend our understanding of the social cognitive processes involved in trait generalization. For example, across three follow-up experiments, <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">Todorov and Uleman (2003)</ref> manipulated time pressure, depth of processing, and cognitive load, reasoning that if similar patterns were observed when participants' attentional resources were taxed or diverted, this would provide stronger evidence for the efficiency of spontaneous trait inference. The same logic could be applied here. For example, one might manipulate whether participants are under cognitive load during the Learning Phase of the task. If similar differences between "Yes" responses to related and unrelated traits were observed even under load, this would suggest that generalization depends, at least in part, on relatively automatic processing of trait informationand not solely on controlled processes.</p><p>Further, though we did use both male-and female-appearing stimuli with varying racial identities in Experiment 3, as of yet, this work has not looked into how trait generalization and conceptual maps might differ as a function of target identity. Groupbased stereotypes regarding gender, race, class, age, or ideology might all provide important influences on the affordances from one trait to another. For example, how might the links between assertive and competent vary when considering a man versus a woman, or between dominant and untrustworthy when considering a Black person versus a White person? In turn, how are these conceptual maps trained up on the perceiver side of things through experience and socialization? One might imagine that liberals and conservatives, city-dwellers and rural-dwellers, and religious and nonreligious people might learn to ascribe different meanings to trait words like patriotic, nosy, or pious, with consequences for the paths that wind through their conceptual maps of trait space, and in turn, generalization itself. As such, future work should devote time to investigating both target and perceiver identity as key moderators of this phenomenon.</p><p>Finally, there is room for future work to consider a broader spectrum of "nonsocial" targets. Our primary manipulation in Experiment 1 revolved around defining the targets as previous participants or computerized slot machines. While our results suggested that similarity-based trait generalization only occurred for human targets (and not the slots), contemporary increases in AI prevalence, usage, and capability hint at intriguing questions regarding how perceivers might treat a more advanced non-human agent. If an AI-based target were perceived to fall somewhere in the middle between human and non-human, it would be interesting to test the extent to which inferences about its dispositions might be generalized to novel contexts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusions</head><p>Humans form impressions of others by inferring stable traits from instances of social behavior, allowing us to predict how others will likely behave in the future. These predictions, in turn, shape our social decision-making and attitudes towards others. Our findings suggest that this ability is flexibly achieved through trait generalization, which itself is guided by conceptual maps of trait-based similarity. Moreover, we provide evidence that trait generalization is socially specific, cannot be solely explained by valence, and can occur spontaneously during the encoding process. Taken together, this work illuminates a core mechanism that helps humans navigate complex social environments through a social cognitive lens.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTSI</head><label></label><figDesc>would first like to thank my advisor, Peter Mende-Siedlecki, for his unwavering guidance, support, and encouragement to both this project and to me as a researcher. I am beyond grateful for your presence and mentorship throughout this chapter of my life. To my collaborator Leor Hackel, thank you for your invaluable advice, especially with regards to data analysis and statistics. I would also like to thank my committee members, Lisa Jaremka and Jas Cloutier, for playing a pivotal role in my academic and professional development, along with their advice on this project. I also give my heartfelt thank you to my lab mates, Yanzi Huang and Sam Haas, along with the rest of my amazing lab and department. To my mother Gail Mullin, late father Rob Mullin, and sister Hollie Mullin: thank you for your endless love and faith in my ambitions and dreams. This extends to my step, immediate, and extended family members all the same. Notably, this includes my fianc Matt Cavender and our two boisterous cats Gizmo and Lennie. You three are a constant source of my joy, resilience, and passion. Your presence is forever appreciated, and I could not have done this without you by my side. While I could (and would) write a hundred more pages thanking each individual friend, family member, and mentor who has been a part of my life-frankly my hands and brain are tired. I love you all and am so glad to have been surrounded by such fantastic people throughout my life! LIST OF FIGURES Figure 1. Schematic of learning and choice tasks in Experiment ......................</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Trait-based choices in novel contexts varied by condition ...................</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Main task schematic for Experiment 2 ..................................................</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Main task schematic for Experiment 3 ..................................................</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Mean proportion of "Yes" responses as a function of trial type ........... viii LIST OF TABLES Table 1. Defining the similarity regressor ...........................................................</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>-Trait task(MD =   3.48, t(46.174)  = 11.65, p &lt; .001, d = 2.85) 1 . Smaller but statistically significant differences were observed for the traits impulsive (MD = -2.66, t(61) = -7.29, p &lt; .001, d = -1.84), selfdisciplined (MD = 1.61, t(60) = 5.37, p &lt; .001, d = 1.37), patient (MD = 0.94, t(61) = 2.56, p = .013, d = 0.65), and cheerful (MD = 0.49, t(59.343) = 2.33, p = .023, d = 0.58).The Giving Game most strongly revealed the trait generous(MD = 4.66, t(61) =   16.53, p &lt; .001, d = 4.17). Smaller but statistically significant differences were observed for the traits cooperative(MD = 3.85, t(49.521)  = 12.43, p &lt; .001, d = 3.05), friendly (MD= 3.26, t(61) = 11.57, p &lt; .001, d = 2.92), reliable (MD = 2.87, t(60) = 8.68, p &lt; .001, d = 2.21), sociable (MD = 2.81, t(53.492) = 9.52, p &lt; .001, d = 2.35), trustworthy (MD = 3.18, t(61) = 9.46, p &lt; .001 , d = 2.39), patient (MD = 1.53, t(61) = 6.04, p &lt; .001, d = 1.52), selfdisciplined (MD = 1.99, t(60) = 5.48, p &lt; .001, d = 1.40), impulsive (MD = -1.38, t(61) = -4.00, p &lt; .001, d = -1.01), intellectual (MD = 1.03, t(61) = 3.60, p &lt; .001, d = 0.91), and smart (MD = 0.71, t(61) = 2.04, p = .045, d = 0.52). The Photo Game most strongly revealed the trait friendly (MD = 3.70, t(61) = 13.86, p &lt; .001, d = 3.50). Smaller but statistically significant differences were observed for the traits cheerful (MD = 3.09, t(61) = 10.52, p &lt; .001, d = 2.65), generous (MD = 3.20, t(61) = 11.94, p &lt; .001, d = 2.28), cooperative (MD = 2.77, t(61) = 9.02, p &lt; .001, d = 2.28), sociable (MD = 2.71, trustworthy (MD = 2.67, t(61) = 8.26, p &lt; .001, d = 2.08), t(61) = 8.17, p &lt; .001, d = 2.06), cautious (MD = 1.86, t(61) = 6.70, p &lt; .001, d = 1.69), reliable 1 Variances within either group were compared using Levene's test. For cases where equal variances could not be assumed (p &lt; .05), Welch's t-test was used, resulting in noninteger degrees of freedom. (MD = 1.82, t(61) = 6.16, p &lt; .001, d = 1.55), patient (MD = 0.93, t(61) = 4.15, p &lt; .001, d = 1.05), smart (MD = 1.09, t(61) = 3.84, p &lt; .001, d = 0.97), impulsive (MD = 1.08, t(61) = 3.50, p &lt; .001, d = 0.89), and intellectual (MD = 0.81, t(61) = 3.53, p &lt; .001, d = 0.89). and The Delay Game most strongly revealed the trait patient (MD = 2.85, t(61) = 7.90, p &lt; .001, d = 1.99). Smaller but statistically significant differences were observed for the traits impulsive (MD = -1.81, t(61) = -5.68, p &lt; .001, d = -1.43), self-disciplined (MD = 1.64, t(61) = 5.10, p &lt; .001, d = 1.29), intellectual (MD = 0.89, t(61) = 2.98, p = .004, d = 0.75), strategic (MD = 1.17, t(61) = 2.94, p = .005, d = 0.74), and smart (MD = 0.72, t(61) = 2.32, p = .024, d = 0.58). The Learning Game most strongly revealed the trait sociable (MD = 1.64, t(61) = 5.07, p &lt; .001, d = 1.28). Smaller but statistically significant differences were observed for the traits friendly (MD = 1.27, t(60) = 3.97, p &lt; .001, d = 1.01), reliable (MD = 0.73, t(61) = 3.24, p = 0.02, d = 0.82), cooperative (MD = 0.70, t(61) = 2.52, p = 0.15, d = 0.63), and generous (MD = 0.38, t(55.735) = 2.18, p = .033, d = 0.54).Rock-Paper-Scissors most strongly revealed the trait strategic (MD = 2.81, t(61) = 9.18, p &lt; .001, d = 2.32). Smaller but statistically significant differences were observed for the traits smart (MD = 1.98, t(61) = 8.18, p &lt; .001, d = 2.06), intellectual (MD = 1.40, t(54.579) = 5.67, p &lt; .001, d = 1.42), self-disciplined (MD = 0.96, t(61) = 3.45, p = .001, d = 0.87), cautious (MD = 0.82, t(61) = 2.70, p = .009, d = 0.68), reliable (MD = 0.70, t(61) = 2.56, p = .013, d = 0.65), and impulsive (MD = -0.91, t(61) = -2.52, p = .014, d = -0.64).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Schematic of learning and choice tasks in Experiment 1. (a)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>more similar to the trait profile of a valuable target in a new game. Critically, as hypothesized, we found a Trait Similarity x Condition interaction, b = .76, SE = .13, z = 5.87, p &lt; .001 indicating that the effect of Trait Similarity depended on Condition (Figure 2). Specifically, simple effects analysis revealed that Trait Similarity strongly predicted choices in the social condition, b = 1.49, SE = .20, z = 7.63, p &lt; .001, but did not predict choices at all in the non-social condition, b = -.03, SE = .17, z = -.20, p = .84. Within the human condition, participants preferred the sociable target when Trait Similarity was high (1 SD above the mean), b = .89, SE = .17, z = 5.37, p &lt; .001, but avoided the sociable target when Trait Similarity was low (1 SD below the mean), b = -.36, SE = .16, z = -2.26, p = .02. These findings indicate that participants generalized value in new contexts based on trait inferences specifically in social, but not non-social, interactions. Discussion Experiment 1 demonstrated evidence of trait-based generalization to novel social domains. This finding directly expands on our prior work showing that people generalize context-specific impressions of competence to make flexible decisions in social dilemmas.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Main task schematic for Experiment 2.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Related target described as anxious in the Learning Phase might be paired with insecure in the Test Phase. A final third of these adjectives were unrelated to the originally presented trait word ("Unrelated" targets). For example, an Unrelated target described as funny in the Learning Phase might be paired with patient in the Test Phase. Related or unrelated trait adjectives were categorized on the basis of trait similarity, determined in a separate pilot study (N = 97).For each target appearing during the Test Phase, participants were asked if the adjective presented on screen had appeared in the sentence that participants initially learned about the face in question during the Learning Phase. Participants provided a binary Yes/No response. Prior to beginning the Test Phase, participants again read thorough instructions, which contained two sample trials referring back to the sample targets encountered in the Learning Phase instructions..</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Main task schematic for Experiment 3. (a) In the Learning Phase,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>traits they were paired with (M = 5.12; SD = 0.36), compared to the Unrelated traits (M = 3.93; SD = 0.22; t(38) = 16.77, p &lt; .001, d = 2.69). This difference was maintained in each of the three subsets of sentences we arrived at (Related Ms ranged from 5.08 to 5.18; Unrelated Ms ranged from 3.92 to 3.95; all ps &lt; .001). This expected difference was conserved in the present sample, where participants rated Related traits as much more similar (M = 5.06, SD = 0.85) to the originally presented target traits, related to Unrelated traits (M = 3.37, SD = 0.91; t(116) = 25.23, p &lt; .001, d = 2.33).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>.</head><label></label><figDesc>Unsurprisingly, the highest percentage of 'Yes' responses was observed in the Exact condition (M = .590, SD = .163). Dovetailing with the multilevel model results above, participants also gave more 'Yes' responses for Related traits (M = .443, SD = .150) than for Unrelated traits (M = .406, SD = .163). This difference between Related and the Unrelated conditions was statistically significant (t(116) = 2.17, p = .032, d = .200).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Mean proportion of "Yes" responses as a function of trial type.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Specifically, participants learned about the six games used in Experiment 1 (e.g., the Gambling Game, Giving Game [as originally named in Pilot Study 1], Delay Game, Rock-Paper-Scissors Game, Photo Game, and Learning Game) as well as four new games that we characterized in a separate</figDesc><table><row><cell>pilot study directly adapted from Pilot Study 1 (N = 97). These included a Tradeoff Game</cell></row><row><cell>(where targets could either choose to receive a financial bonus or forego that bonus to</cell></row><row><cell>prevent a Receiver from experiencing physical pain [adapted from FeldmanHall et al.,</cell></row><row><cell>2012], revealing information about the trait compassionate), a Preferences Game (where</cell></row><row><cell>targets answered questions about simple binary preferences and received a bonus based on</cell></row><row><cell>how fast they responded, revealing information about the trait decisive), a Thermometer</cell></row><row><cell>Game (where targets tried to increase a thermometer's temperature with probabilistically-</cell></row><row><cell>effective mouse clicks and received a bonus if they reached 100 F within 30 seconds,</cell></row><row><cell>revealing information about their persistence [akin to the motivation measure in Ames &amp;</cell></row><row><cell>Fiske, 2015]), and Testing Game (where targets answered Math and Verbal GRE questions</cell></row><row><cell>and received a bonus for correct answers, revealing information about the trait smart [as in</cell></row><row><cell>Hackel, Mende-Siedlecki, Loken, &amp; Amodio, 2022]).</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">instance,Frolichs and colleagues (2022)  illustrated how people generalize impressions based on self-reported traits, but did not examine generalization in the context of observationally or instrumentally learned traits, which are likely more reflective of realworld social learning. Further, it will be crucial to test how this generalization process supports and informs subsequent social decision-making. Related, while van Baar colleagues (2021) demonstrate how inferences about social motives can be generalizedeven when they're associated with different patterns of behavior-across different contexts, this work was placed less emphasis on the generalization of this learning to related goals, nor did it explicitly test perceived similarity as a guiding mechanism. To this point, Elder and colleagues (2023) did show how network similarity between traits shaped evaluations, but this work focused on self-referential judgments, rather than the judgment of others.Moreover, while Hackel and colleagues (2022) laid the groundwork by providing evidence for generalization on a relatively proximal level (how competence in one context [e.g., math] generalized to another [e.g., science]), it is critical to test this generalization process across more distal and distinct trait concepts and social contexts. Finally, as discussed previously, there is an extensive literature illustrating similarity-based generalization in non-social contexts. At the same time, recent work illustrates that social cognitive mechanisms may meaningfully distinguish between social and non-social learning. For example, in a task where participants learned about targets varying orthogonally in trait generosity and reward value, they prioritized learning about generosity information when these targets were described as other humans (i.e., a social context), but prioritized reward when the targets were described as non-social slot machines. Thus, it will be critical to test the social specificity of trait generalization. Taken together, the studies collected in this manuscript will directly address these gaps in knowledge.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>.. D EXAMPLE OF EXPERIMENT 3 CHICAGO FACE DATABASE IMAGES81</head><p>Chapter 5</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EXPERIMENT 3: CAN SIMILARITY-BASED TRAIT GENERALIZATION OCCUR SPONTANEOUSLY AT ENCODING</head><p>While Experiments 1 and 2 demonstrate how similarity-based maps of social knowledge support trait generalization, they leave unanswered the question of when such generalization occursduring the initial encoding of a trait impression, or later, when that impression is retrieved prior to decision making? To test this, we used a classic false recognition paradigm adapted from the spontaneous trait inference literature, which has previously provided evidence that we spontaneously infer traits implied by behavior during encoding <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">(Todorov &amp; Uleman, 2002)</ref>.</p><p>Participants in Experiment 3 viewed sentences explicitly describing behavior in trait terms, each randomly paired with a face. Later, participants viewed the same faces along with a single trait word and asked if that trait was previously used to describe the individual in question. We hypothesized that trait similarity would be predictive of falsely remembering traits, such that the greater the similarity between the target and lure trait, the more likely a participant would falsely remember that trait. Thus, this would support the process that generalization occurs spontaneously at encoding.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. Similarity shapes the spontaneous generalization of trait knowledge. Both consensus (3A) and participant-specific judgments (3B) of similarity between lures and original trait adjectives were positively and significantly associated with "Yes" responses (i.e., false recognition) in the spontaneous trait generalization paradigm. That said, when pit against each other, neither predictor remained significant (3C). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Multilevel model predicting false recognition based on consensus similarity judgments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Agency and communion from the perspective of self versus others</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Abele</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wojciszke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.93.5.751</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.93.5.751" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="751" to="763" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Outcome dependency alters the neural substrates of impression formation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ames</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="599" to="608" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceived intent motivates people to magnify observed harms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ames</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3599" to="3605" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring utility by a singleresponse sequential method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Degroot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Marschak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bs.3830090304</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="226" to="232" />
			<date type="published" when="1964" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bs.3830090304</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/bs.3830090304" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Random effects structure for confirmatory hypothesis testing: Keep it maximal</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Barr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Scheepers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tily</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jml.2012.11.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jml.2012.11.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of memory and language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What Is a Cognitive Map? Organizing Knowledge for Flexible Behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E J</forename><surname>Behrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C R</forename><surname>Whittington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Baram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stachenfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kurth-Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2018.10.002</idno>
		<ptr target="htts://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2018.10.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="490" to="509" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Z.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The International Affective Picture System (IAPS) in the Study of Emotion and Attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bradley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/oso/9780195169157.003.0003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/oso/9780195169157.003.0003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Emotion Elicitation and Assessment (p. 0)</title>
		<editor>J. A. Coan &amp; J. J. B. Allen</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Looking for honesty: The primary role of morality (vs. sociability and competence) in information gathering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brambilla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rusconi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sacchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Cherubini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/ejsp.744</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="143" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/ejsp.744</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/ejsp.744" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The primacy of morality in impression development: Theory, research, and future directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brambilla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sacchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rusconi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Goodwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In Advances in Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="262" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<publisher>Elsevier Academic Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organizing Conceptual Knowledge in Humans with a Grid-like Code</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Constantinescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>O'reilly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E J</forename><surname>Behrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.aaf0941</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaf0941" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">352</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6292</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1464" to="1468" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Decision theory, reinforcement learning, and the brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/CABN.8.4.429</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="429" to="453" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/CABN.8.4.429</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/CABN.8.4.429" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gender stereotypes stem from the distribution of women and men into social roles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Eagly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Steffen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.46.4.735</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.46.4.735" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="735" to="754" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mapping the self: A network approach for understanding psychological and neural representations of selfconcept structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Elder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/pspa0000315</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/pspa0000315" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stimulus generalization as a mechanism for learning to trust</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Feldmanhall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Dunsmoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tompary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hunter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1715227115</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1715227115" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1690" to="1697" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What we say and what we do: The relationship between real and hypothetical moral choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Feldmanhall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mobbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hiscox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Navrady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Dalgleish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2012.02.001</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="441" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2012.02.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2012.02.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Universal dimensions of social cognition: Warmth and competence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J C</forename><surname>Cuddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Glick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2006.11.005</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2006.11.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2006.11.005" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model of (often mixed) stereotype content: Competence and warmth respectively follow from perceived status and competition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J C</forename><surname>Cuddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Glick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.82.6.878</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.82.6.878" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="878" to="902" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fairness in Simple Bargaining Experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Forsythe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Horowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Savin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sefton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1006/game.1994.1021</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Games and Economic Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="369" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1006/game.1994.1021</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1006/game.1994.1021" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating social knowledge structures into computational models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M M</forename><surname>Frolichs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Rosenblau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Korn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41467-022-33418-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-022-33418-2" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6205</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A map of abstract relational knowledge in the human hippocampal-entorhinal cortex. eLife, 6, e17086</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Garvert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Behrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.17086</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.17086" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Garvert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Saanum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Schuck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Doeller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hippocampal spatio-predictive cognitive maps adaptively guide reward generalization</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41593-023-01283-x</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="615" to="626" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41593-023-01283-x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-023-01283-x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discovering latent causes in reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Niv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">https://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1016/j.cobeha.2015.07.007</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Behavioral Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="50" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cobeha.2015.07.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cobeha.2015.07.007" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reinforcement learning and episodic memory in humans and animals: An integrative framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev-psych-122414-033625</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-psych-122414-033625" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Instrumental learning of traits versus rewards: Dissociable neural correlates and effects on choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hackel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Doll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Amodio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.4080</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4080" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1233" to="1235" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reinforcement learning in social interaction: The distinguishing role of trait inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hackel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mende-Siedlecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Amodio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2019.103948</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2019.103948" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextdependent learning in social interaction: Trait impressions support flexible social choices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hackel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mende-Siedlecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Loken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Amodio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/pspa0000296</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="655" to="675" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/pspa0000296</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/pspa0000296" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The moral psychology of raceless, genderless strangers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Hester</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691619885840</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="216" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691619885840</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691619885840" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Downplaying Positive Impressions: Compensation Between Warmth and Competence in Impression Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Holoien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2012.09.001</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2012.09.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2012.09.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twenty-five years of research on stimulus generalization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Honig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Urcuioli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1901/jeab.1981.36-405</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The legacy of Guttman and Kalish</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="405" to="445" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1901/jeab.1981.36-405</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1901/jeab.1981.36-405" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">People are represented and remembered through their relationships with others</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Jolly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sadhukha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Iqbal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Molani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Walsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>under review. psyarxiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fundamental dimensions of social judgment: Understanding the relations between judgments of competence and warmth</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Judd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>James-Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Yzerbyt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kashima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.89.6.899</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.89.6.899" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="899" to="913" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fairness as a Constraint on Profit Seeking: Entitlements in the Market</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Knetsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thaler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="728" to="741" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The innuendo effect: Hearing the positive but inferring the negative</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kervyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Bergsieker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Fiske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2011.08.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2011.08.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Competence and warmth in context: The compensatory nature of stereotypic views of national groups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kervyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Yzerbyt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Demoulin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Judd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/ejsp.526</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1175" to="1183" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/ejsp.526</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/ejsp.526" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A question of compensation: The social life of the fundamental dimensions of social perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kervyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Yzerbyt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Judd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nunes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0013320</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="828" to="842" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0013320</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0013320" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Chicago face database: A free stimulus set of faces and norming data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Correll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wittenbrink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-014-0532-5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-014-0532-5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1122" to="1135" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distances between real-world locations are represented in the human hippocampus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Macevoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Aguirre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Epstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4667-10.2011</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1238" to="1245" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4667-10.2011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4667-10.2011" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mende-Siedlecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Havlicek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in prep</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discounting of delayed rewards: Models of individual choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Myerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1901/jeab.1995.64-263</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="276" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1901/jeab.1995.64-263</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1901/jeab.1995.64-263" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The halo effect: Evidence for unconscious alteration of judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nisbett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.35.4.250</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.35.4.250" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="250" to="256" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality Across World Regions Predicts Variability in the Structure of Face Impressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/09567976211072814</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/09567976211072814" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1240" to="1256" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Person knowledge shapes face identity perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2021.104889</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2021.104889" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">217</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The functional basis of face evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Oosterhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.0805664105</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0805664105" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11087" to="11092" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of morality in social cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mende-Siedlecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gantman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Bavel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The neural basis of mentalizing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="555" to="566" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Springer Nature Switzerland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-51890-5_28</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-51890-5_28" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A multidimensional approach to the structure of personality impressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rosenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Vivekananthan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0026086</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0026086" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="294" />
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Schapiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Turk-Browne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Statistical learning of temporal community structure in the hippocampus</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/hipo.22523</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/hipo.22523" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Hippocampus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human Orbitofrontal Cortex Represents a Cognitive Map of State Space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Schuck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Niv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2016.08.019</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1402" to="1412" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2016.08.019</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.08.019" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a universal law of generalization for psychological science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shepard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.3629243</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.3629243" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">237</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4820</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1317" to="1323" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive maps of social features enable flexible inference in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-Y</forename><surname>Son</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bhandari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Feldmanhall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.2021699118</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2021699118" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trait knowledge forms a common structure across social cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Stolier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hehman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-019-0800-6</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="361" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-019-0800-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-019-0800-6" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social inferences from faces: Ambient images generate a three-dimensional model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A M</forename><surname>Sutherland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Oldmeadow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Towler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Burt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2012.12.001</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="118" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2012.12.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2012.12.001" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disclosing information about the self is intrinsically rewarding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Tamir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1202129109</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1202129109" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8038" to="8043" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling the predictive social mind</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Tamir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Thornton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2017.12.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2017.12.005" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="212" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to Grow a Mind: Statistics, Structure, and Abstraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kemp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1192788</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">331</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6022</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1279" to="1285" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1192788</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1192788" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A constant error in psychological ratings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Thorndike</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0071663</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0071663" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="1920" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spontaneous trait inferences are bound to actors&apos; faces: Evidence from a false recognition paradigm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Uleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.83.5.1051</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.83.5.1051" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1051" to="1065" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The efficiency of binding spontaneous trait inferences to actors&apos; faces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Uleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0022-1031(03)00059-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-1031(03" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consciousness and control: The case of spontaneous trait inferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Uleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167287133004</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167287133004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0146167287133004" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intolerance of uncertainty modulates brain-to-brain synchrony during politically polarized perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Van Baar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Halpern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Feldmanhall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.2022491118</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2022491118" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalization of affective learning about faces to perceptually similar faces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Verosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797610371965</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="779" to="785" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797610371965</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797610371965" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When physical similarity matters: Mechanisms underlying affective learning generalization to the evaluation of novel faces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Verosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2013.02.004</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="661" to="669" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2013.02.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2013.02.004" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalization of value in reinforcement learning by humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Wimmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1460-9568.2012.08017.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1460-9568.2012.08017.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1092" to="1104" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When are social judgments made? Evidence for the spontaneousness of trait inferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Winter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Uleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.47.2.237</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.47.2.237" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How automatic are social judgments?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Winter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Uleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cunniff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.49.4.904</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="904" to="917" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0022-3514.49.4.904</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-3514.49.4.904" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Morality and competence in person-and self-perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wojciszke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/10463280500229619</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Review of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b94">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/10463280500229619</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/10463280500229619" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b95">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cognitive organization and change: An information processing approach (pp. x, 502)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Wyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b96">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceiver and target characteristics contribute to impression formation differently across race and gender</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Flake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hehman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/pspi0000160</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="364" to="385" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b97">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/pspi0000160</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/pspi0000160" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b98">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compensation versus halo: The unique relations between the fundamental dimensions of social judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Yzerbyt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kervyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Judd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167208318602</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1110" to="1123" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b99">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167208318602</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0146167208318602" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
