<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Multi-tiered systems of educator professional development: A systematic literature review of responsive, tiered professional development models</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bradley</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bloomfield</surname></persName>
							<email>brad.bloomfield@monash.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Monash University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Melbourne</settlement>
									<region>Victoria</region>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Monash University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>19 Ancora Imparo Way, Clayton VIC 3800</addrLine>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russell</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Monash University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Melbourne</settlement>
									<region>Victoria</region>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erin</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Leif</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Monash University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Melbourne</settlement>
									<region>Victoria</region>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Multi-tiered systems of educator professional development: A systematic literature review of responsive, tiered professional development models</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Teachers and clinicians report feeling underprepared to implement evidence-based behavior supports. As such, effective models of professional development that lead to improved outcomes for all individuals are required. Critical components of high-quality professional development include explicit instruction, modeling, practice, direct feedback, and, potentially, individual coaching. However, delivering all components may be time-and resource-intensive. Professional development approaches that extend the tiered logic of multi-tiered systems of support to adult learning may address these challenges. In such models, universal professional development is provided to whole-staff groups on specific skills using explicit instruction, modeling, practice, and feedback. Data are then collected and used to inform targeted, individualized supports. The current systematic literature review addressed a gap in the literature by identifying, summarizing, and appraising 20 published studies that examined tiered, responsive professional development models. While consistent practices were identified (e.g., group didactic training at Tier 1 and coaching at Tiers 2 and 3), the form and shape of specific interventions at each tier differed across studies. The same was observed in the data-based decision-making processes employed to determine the need for additional trainee support. Practical implications to inform the ongoing examination of tiered responsive professional development models are discussed. 2 A systematic literature review of responsive tiered training models for professional development In-service professional development (IPD) is a vital component to ensure that staff have the requisite skills to fulfill the requirements of their job. Effective IPD is particularly important in school contexts to build the capacity of staff (Waitoller &amp; Artiles, 2013) to meet the academic, social, and behavioral needs of their students, support the staff&apos;s wellbeing, and ensure staff retention. School contexts can include mainstream classrooms as well as early childhood settings, alternative schools, and specialist programs for students with disability. In these contexts, professional development has been defined as &quot;…structured professional learning that results in changes to teacher knowledge and practices…&quot; and results in improved outcomes for students (Darling-Hammond et al., 2017, p. 2). Darling-Hammond and colleagues (2017) conceptualized IPD as being both embedded learning activities within a professional&apos;s role and school, as well as externally provided to staff through didactic and workshop-based learning activities. Multiple examinations of IPD have been undertaken with the aim of understanding the components of professional development programs that lead to improved student outcomes (Darling-Hammond et al., 2017; Flynn et al., 2016; Sims et al., 2022). The importance of extended duration of training, an explicit focus on content, active learning opportunities including modeling and opportunities to practice, delivery of performance feedback, as well as coaching and ongoing expert support were noted as important components of training across several studies (Darling-Hammond et al., 2017, Flynn et al., 2016; Sims et al., 2022). Some studies have assessed the impact of such IPD on student outcomes. For example, Flynn et al. (2016) found that school staff who engaged in group workshops and individual coaching significantly decreased behavior incidents and school suspensions. In this study, following the initial skill instruction, school staff received direct coaching which consisted of an 3 expert coach observing the staff member implement the target skill with performance feedback. These findings are consistent with Fallon et al.&apos;s (2018) systematic review examining the effects of direct training, in which 45% of the included studies reported cases in which strong or moderate effects of direct training were observed. Taken together, these studies emphasize the importance of IPD that includes direct instruction of the target skill followed by more training components that include modeling, skill rehearsal, and performance feedback (e.g., behavioral skills training [BST]; Lerman et al., 2015). Challenges with In-Service Teacher Professional Development Ensuring that IPD is designed with the critical components described above and achieves the desired outcomes is a significant challenge. For example, while Fallon et al. (2018) described overall positive effects of IPD programs that included components identified as critical to effective teacher learning, there were still multiple studies within the systematic review that did not achieve the desired outcomes. When considering the barriers to successful implementation of practices, multiple barriers exist that relate directly to the context of implementation (e.g., time, resourcing, alignment with existing practices; McIntosh et al., 2014; Sanetti &amp; Collier-Meek, 2019), as well as to the practitioner (e.g., staff buy-in and disagreements about the practices; McIntosh et al., 2014). This aligns with findings presented by Zhang et al. (2021), who reported that teacher motivation can influence the effectiveness of IPD. Studies have shown that teacher motivation might vary based on personal factors (such as the perceived value of IPD or alignment with teachers&apos; personal choices and interest; Zhang et al., 2021), school level factors (such as workload, time, and support from colleagues; Fox et al., 2021), and systems level factors (such as whether IPD is mandatory or optional, or whether IPD occurs during or outside of working hours; McMillan et al., 2016).</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4</head><p>The challenge of delivering IPD that incorporates the components of effective PD programs, and builds motivation, within complex and dynamic school settings is significant.</p><p>Coaching supports have been recognized as a critical mechanism for building teacher fluency to effectively implement EBPs in context <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Freeman et al., 2017)</ref>. However, the resource demands of such coaching supports are significant and come with no guarantee of success <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bastable et al., 2020)</ref>. Furthermore, once trained, teachers require sufficient time to prepare and implement new EPBs as many require additional material resources. As a result, schools and school systems need efficient, effective, and resource efficient approaches to improving the ability of teachers to implement evidence-based behavior supports that lead to positive outcomes for all learners.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Responsive Tiered Training Frameworks</head><p>The need to provide thorough training to staff so that they can implement the trained skills with fluency must be balanced with the persistent resource constraints that have been identified across sectors (i.e., time, expertise, and money; <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bastable et al., 2020)</ref>. A tiered approach to staff training may be an effective means to support performance development in ways that are more cost-and time-efficient <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Brock, 2022)</ref>. This approach allows implementers to build on the positive outcomes of high-quality universal IPD with individualized supports for those staff that need them. In doing so, limitations in the generality or sustainability of effects of IPD models for some staff may be addressed (described above). Further, this approach may also reduce some of the costs -including hidden costs -of delivering individualized coaching to all staff in the first instance <ref type="bibr">(Pas et al., 2020)</ref>. Finally, the provision of more individualized supports may allow implementers to identify and address motivational factors that may be hindering participation of some teachers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5</head><p>A tiered system of support such as multitiered systems of supports (MTSS) is often employed to support student behavior and academic performance <ref type="bibr">(McIntosh &amp; Goodman, 2016)</ref>.</p><p>In schools, this may be called positive behavioral interventions and supports (PBIS) or response to intervention (RTI) for behavior and academics, respectively. This is a framework defined as supporting all learners, which includes staff as well as students <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Reddy et al., 2016)</ref>. Following a similar framework as traditionally applied to students, staff development can be approached in a multitiered manner to adapt staff professional development supports to best align with staff needs <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Simonsen et al., 2014)</ref>. This proposed multitiered framework uses data-based decision making of staff behavior in a problem-solving framework where staff have opportunities to receive more frequent feedback with less latency between the behavior and the specific feedback.</p><p>Responsive tiered training frameworks use a tiered logic of support provision and in many cases are underpinned by theoretical frameworks consistent with the response to intervention, positive behavioral interventions and supports (PBIS), and integrated multi-tiered systems of support (MTSS) frameworks. For example, responsive tiered frameworks are designed to organize the prevention-focused practices, systems, and data-based processes along a continuum that allows for increasingly intensive and individualized supports to be provided (e.g., universal behavioral expectations at Tier-1 PBIS, functional behavior assessment for individual students at Tier-3; <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">Simonsen &amp; Sugai, 2019)</ref> In addition, behavioral theory (i.e., radical behaviorism) and the principles of behavior derived from applied behavior analysis (ABA; e.g., reinforcement, punishment, and stimulus control) underpin the practices and systems, as well as the implementation processes across all Tiers <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Simonsen &amp; Sugai, 2019)</ref>. Consistent with this logic, tiered responsive training frameworks are structured to provide all staff with high-quality group training at Tier 1 (e.g., incorporating the components of BST or effective group 6 professional development outlined above). There is an expectation that this level of training and support will support most staff to effectively implement the practices with integrity. Within this multitiered framework, Tier 1 monitoring practices focus on routine progress monitoring of all teachers. Staff who are unable to effectively implement the practices as intended after Tier 1 training receive additional, more intensive, and increasingly individualized support practices.</p><p>Tier 2 supports staff members at risk for struggling to fluently implement instructional or behavior management practices with fidelity. Tier 2 training may include explicit individualized instruction, the provision of the rehearsal and feedback components of BST, self-monitoring or self-assessment procedures, and or other direct coaching methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Myers et al., 2020)</ref>. Many of the monitoring strategies are similar to Tier one; however, these are often individualized and more frequently used. Staff members who do not respond to these Tier 2 supports receive the highest level of intensive, individualized training support. Tier 3 supports are consistently based on observations of the staff members practice in context. Tier 3 assessments and supports reflect an increase in intensity and duration of procedures to build staff skills and address motivation <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Myers et al., 2020)</ref>. This is typically accomplished through intensive coaching both in-vivo and after observation <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Reddy et al., 2016)</ref>.</p><p>The increased focus on using tiered training models to deliver IPD for staff that leads to effective implementation in context has led to an increase in the published research examining the effectiveness, efficacy, and social validity of this approach. To this point, there has been no systematic review of these studies. Such a review of this emerging approach is relevant and required as to this point as there are no clear definitions of tiered training and little unanimity in descriptions or definitions of the evidence-based training practices that may be selected and implemented at each tier.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>7</head><p>The purpose of this systematic review was to: a) Identify, summarize, and appraise the extant literature examining the efficacy of tiered training models. b) Identify the training practices used at each tier across all studies c) Summarize how each tier has been defined across studies d) Describe the decision-making processes to determine the provision of additional support.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method Inclusion/Exclusion Criteria</head><p>To be included in this review, articles needed to be empirical in nature published in the English language. Articles published in peer reviewed journals as well as dissertations and theses were included. To be included, articles must have evaluated a tiered responsive training program.</p><p>We defined tiered training as a model of professional development wherein all trainees receive training in evidence-based behavior support practices with smaller groups of trainees receiving more intensified and individualized implementation supports. Responsive means that data (e.g., frequency or rate of trainee skill use, student outcome data) are used to inform the need for, and type of, more individualized or intensified support for some trainees. In other words, additional levels of support are provided to trainees based on their response to earlier professional learning opportunities. Tiered responsive training is different from models that provide cascading training (e.g., train the trainer, pyramidal training) that do not use data to inform the design of more individualized or intensified training from some members of the group.</p><p>Studies were excluded if they were published in a language other than English or did not report an experimental design. Additionally, conference proceedings or non-peer reviewed outlets (e.g., newsletters) were not included in this review. Articles that only reported learner 8 outcomes, rather than the trainee outcomes were excluded as well; given the focus on the training procedures, outcome data must be reported on the training itself. As the tiered responsive training must be responsive to data (e.g., using data-based decision making), included articles must report outcome data on the trainee. Any studies that deliver training not using a tiered training model were excluded, such as pyramidal training or sequentially offered training components outside of a responsive structure; some of these training models may have been labeled as tiered but did not meet our definition of a tiered responsive training model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Search Procedures</head><p>This review was conducted following the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines. Searches were undertaken to identify seminal or frequently cited peer-reviewed tiered training articles. The authors collated the following key words for the search: tiered, training, professional development, coaching, and professional learning. To comprehensively gather related articles, the specific search terms were as follows: "tier* training" OR "tier* professional development" OR "tier* professional learning" OR "tier* coaching" OR "tier* implementation support*".</p><p>The authors used those exact search terms across the following databases: EBSCOhost, OVID, and ProQuest on February 21, 2023. Both the first and second author conducted this initial search independently to verify that both authors identified the same articles. Records were limited to English-language publications and no date restrictions were put in place. We used Covidence (2022) to conduct this review. A total of 121 articles were found with 39 duplicates removed. This resulted in 82 unique results screened for inclusion or exclusion in this review.</p><p>The first and second author independently conducted a review of titles and abstracts for the 82 articles resulting in an agreement of 97.56% (Cohen's Kappa = 0.94). For the two articles 9 that resulted in disagreement, the authors met and discussed until a consensus was reached. As a result, 58 articles were coded as irrelevant resulting in a pool of 24 articles to be included at fulltext review to assess for eligibility.</p><p>Both the first and second author read the full-text 24 articles independently to determine if they met the inclusion criteria stipulated above. Eleven articles met inclusion criteria, and 13 articles were excluded for presenting the wrong intervention; the excluded articles did not present a tiered training that was responsive in nature. The first and second author had 100% agreement of the articles that met inclusion criteria for this systematic review (Cohen's Kappa = 1.0). Due to researcher error, one of the included articles was excluded at the article coding stage due to further reading indicating that the intervention does not meet the inclusive of responsive <ref type="bibr">(Hoston, 2022)</ref>. Thus, the forward and backward searches will be based on the 11 included at this stage of analysis; however, only 10 articles from the initial search are included in the results.</p><p>Upon identifying the final articles from the initial search, the first and second author conducted a forward and backward search to determine if there were further articles that are relevant to this review but were not captured in the original search. As this research area is emerging this step was deemed necessary to capture any articles that have been published but not yet indexed in the databases used in the initial search. For the backward search, the authors reviewed the articles cited in the included 11 studies. There were 515 articles cited in the included studies; 30 articles were then included for further review with 98.44% agreement between the first two authors (Cohen's Kappa = 0.85). All articles with disagreements were included for further review. Twelve articles were excluded for being duplicates of articles already included resulting in 18 articles for full text review. Twelve articles were excluded upon 10 full-text review for not meeting the definition of a tiered responsive training resulting in six additional articles included in this systematic review.</p><p>The first author conducted a forward article review using Google Scholar on March 10 th , 2023; the first author searched each of the original 11 included articles on google scholar and developed a list of other articles that cited each of those articles (n = 151). The first and second author then independently reviewed all articles based on title and authors to identify those articles that met criteria for further review. Using this method, 18 additional articles were included for further review, with 99.34% agreement (Cohen's Kappa = 0.97). Ten articles were excluded for being duplicates with the previous searches and one article was excluded for not being data-based. One article was excluded for not meeting the definition of tiered responsive training. This resulted in an additional six articles for inclusion in the systematic review.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Article Coding</head><p>A total of 22 articles were included in the systematic review including 15 peer reviewed publications and seven dissertations. Two dissertations were also subsequently published in a peer review journal, so they were removed from the final analysis. We developed a coding sheet to permit the extraction of data from each included study on the following characteristics: (a) study information; (b) trainee participant characteristics; (c) learner participant characteristics; </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participant Characteristics</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trainee</head><p>Most trainees were White, female staff in schools (See <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>). Five studies did not report race/ethnicity data of their trainees (i.e., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Artman-Meeker et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Brock et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Reed, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Simonsen et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Tekverk, 2010)</ref>. Of those who reported demographic variables, 76.4% of trainees identified as White and 14.7% of trainees identified as Black. The remaining trainees identified as Hispanic (n = 3), Asian/Native Hawaiian/Pacific Islander (n = 1), other (n = 1), and did not respond (n = 1). Two studies did not report gender identity of their trainees <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Artman-Meeker et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Reed, 2014)</ref>. Of the remaining studies which reported demographic data, 87.1% of trainees identified as female with the remaining participants identifying as male. Fifteen of the 20 studies report the participants were teachers with most remaining participants serving as a teaching assistant or paraprofessional role (n = 3). The remaining two studies used graduate students (LaBrot et al., 2021) and day treatment program staff <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">(Tekverk, 2010)</ref> as trainees.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Learner</head><p>Nine of the 20 studies used individual children as the learner to measure training outcomes whereas the remaining were school-based and measured the impact of training on the class as a group <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>. The learners ranged in age from birth to 18 years old, yet six studies did not report learner age characteristics <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Gage, MacSuga-Gage, et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Grasley-Boy et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Myers et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sanetti &amp; Collier-Meek, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Simonsen et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Tekverk, 2010</ref>).</p><p>Tekverk (2010) did not report any other learner demographics. There was varied reporting of race/ethnicity across the included studies with 45% not reporting this for their included learner participants. For the studies that included information about the gender identity of their learner participants, 79.17% were reported to be male with 20.83% were reported to be female; 14 of the studies did not report gender demographics. For studies that provided a description of the special education status of the included participants, all studies included at least some students with a disability in their learner sample.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trainer</head><p>Limited information was provided about the trainer for many of the included studies <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>. In most cases, the trainer was the primary researcher of the study (n = 9) or a graduate student (n = 7); based on the article reporting, it is unclear if the graduate students were also the primary researchers in the studies. <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Thompson et al. (2012)</ref> used a coach and program specialist at the participating school district as the primary trainer in their work. Similarly, Johnson <ref type="formula">2021</ref>had a school-based instructional coach as the trainer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Setting Characteristics</head><p>Across most of the included studies, the trainers supported educators in school-based settings; this included early childhood classrooms (n = 6), elementary (n = 6), middle (n = 2), and secondary school classrooms (n = 2; <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Brock et al. (2021)</ref> conducted their study in a public school across students in primary and secondary classrooms. Sinclair <ref type="formula">2019</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dependent Variables</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trainee variables</head><p>For the trainees, there were two primary outcome variables measured across all studies: fidelity of implementation and the implementation of behavior specific praise (BSP; See <ref type="table">Table   13</ref> 2). Seven studies measured the fidelity of implementation where they evaluated the impact of responsive training on the percent of steps implemented as planned. Twelve studies evaluated the trainee's implementation of BSP using either a count or rate per minute. One study used the Teaching Pyramid Observation Tool (TPOT; <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Fox et al., 2014)</ref> to measure impact of tiered training on trainee practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Artman-Meeker et al., 2022)</ref>. Additionally, some studies included other outcome variables such as choice and precorrection <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Ennis et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Freeman et al., 2018)</ref>, opportunities to respond (OTR; <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Freeman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Johnson, 2021</ref><ref type="bibr">), reprimands (LaBrot et al., 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Lown, 2020)</ref>, positive to negative interaction ratio <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Myers et al., 2011)</ref>, as well as social prompts <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Freeman et al., 2018)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Learner variables</head><p>In comparison to outcome measures of the trainee, studies were less likely to report information about the learner outcomes <ref type="table">(Table 2)</ref>. When studies reported information about the learner, they often reported the learner's percent on-task behavior (n = 9). Some studies also reported on the level of disruptive behavior displayed by the learner (n = 7). Other outcomes for the learners include percent of correct responses <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Brock et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Sinclair, 2019)</ref> or number of mands <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Rispoli et al., 2021)</ref>. The remaining studies did not provide information about the learner outcome variables.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Responsive Tiered Training</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Tier 1</head><p>Didactic Training. All 20 of the included studies included some form of didactic training at Tier 1 ( <ref type="table">Table 2)</ref>. The most used Tier 1 training approach was group didactic training (n = 14). This form of training was provided to groups of varying sizes, ranging from three trainees (LaBrot et al., 2021) through to a whole-of-staff cohort from a large middle school (enrolment of 14 1050; <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Myers et al., 2011)</ref>. Duration of Tier 1 didactic training ranged from <ref type="bibr">30-minutes (or approximately;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Freeman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gage, MacSuga-Gage, et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Grasley-Boy et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Johnson, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Rispoli et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Thompson et al., 2012)</ref> through to 210-minutes across the school year <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Ennis et al., 2020)</ref>. Six studies used delivered Tier 1 training to individuals using <ref type="bibr">BST (LaBrot et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Rispoli et al., 2021)</ref>, one-on-one direct training <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Sanetti &amp; Collier-Meek, 2015)</ref>, brief individual training <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Simonsen et al., 2014)</ref>, individual professional development <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Freeman et al., 2018)</ref>, and individual didactic training <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Reed, 2014)</ref>. These approaches, while delivered to individuals, were universal in nature in multiple studies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Freeman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">LaBrot et al., 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Reed, 2014)</ref>. In studies conducted by <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sanetti &amp; Collier-Meek (2015)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Rispoli et al. (2021)</ref> the focus of the training was tailored to match specific content foci of teachers.</p><p>Forty-five percent of studies (n = 9) included all components of a BST approach (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Lerman et al., 2015)</ref>. The most used training practice was an oral description of the practice (n = 18). A written description of the target skill as well as opportunities for the trainee to rehearse skills were identified in 10 of the included studies. Direct observations (n = 9) and performance feedback (n = 10) were the least frequently identifiable training practices coded. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Tier 2</head><p>Coaching. Coaching (n = 14) was the most described Tier 2 support practice <ref type="table">(Table 2)</ref>.</p><p>While coaching was frequently used at Tier-2, there was considerable variability in both the duration of coaching and the specific practices described across the included studies. (2019) coached trainees at Tier 2 using real-time remote bug-in-ear coaching (i.e., the delivery of immediate performance feedback to a trainee within their work setting using in-ear communication devices). The use of remote coaching at Tier 2 was specifically identified, with trainees coached using teleconsultation platforms such as Zoom or GoReact <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Johnson, 2021)</ref>, as well as by email <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Freeman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ennis et al., 2020)</ref>.</p><p>Performance Feedback. Performance feedback (n = 7) was also a commonly used Tier 2 support for trainees. Performance feedback was frequently used in combination with other training practices such as coaching, self-monitoring, and prompting (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gage, MacSuga-Gage, et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Grasley-Boy et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">LaBrot et al., 2022)</ref>. Digital performance feedback was used in six studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Freeman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gage, MacSuga-Gage, et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Grasley-Boy et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Johnson, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">LaBrot et al., 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">LaBrot et al., , 2021</ref>, with this feedback provided by email <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Freeman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gage, MacSuga-Gage, et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Johnson, 2021</ref>), text message <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(LaBrot et al., 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(LaBrot et al., , 2021</ref>, both email and text message <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Grasley-Boy et al., 2023)</ref>, and or in GoReact <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Johnson et al., 2021)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Myers et al. (2011)</ref> provided written feedback.</p><p>Other supports. Self-monitoring or prompting procedures were used in 9 studies at Tier 2. Self-monitoring supports included the use of golf counters and recording of rate of delivery of the target skill <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Freeman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gage, MacSuga-Gage, et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Simonsen et al., 2014)</ref>, as well as trainees watching recordings of their practice in context and assessing their own fidelity against a performance checklist <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Owens et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Thompson et al., 2012)</ref>. Reed Prompts for trainees included the use of a tactile prompting aide for trainees (e.g., a MotivAider Ò ; Lown, 2020), as well as written prompts <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Reed, 2014)</ref>, and antecedent prompts sent weekly via email <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Simonsen et al., 2014)</ref>, and daily in person <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(LaBrot et al., 2022)</ref>. Goal setting was identified as a specific intervention in one study <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(LaBrot et al., 2022)</ref>. Finally, video models of the target skills were provided to trainees in three studies to supplement Tier 2 supports <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(LaBrot et al., 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(LaBrot et al., , 2021</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Sinclair, 2019)</ref>. It is important to note that while Reed (2014) and <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Simonsen et al. (2014)</ref> planned Tier 2 interventions, none were required.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Tier 3</head><p>Of the 20 studies included in the current review, 11 studies implemented Tier 3 training support for trainees <ref type="table">(Table 2)</ref>. Six studies did not include a third tier of support for trainees, while two studies included Tier 3 supports that were not required <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Johnson, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Reed, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Grasley-Boy et al. (2023) did not describe Tier 3 supports but indicated that they would have been provided if necessary. In total, 21 participants across all studies received Tier 3 training, representing 21% of all participants. Of the 11 studies that delivered Tier 3 training supports, seven explicitly described maintaining existing Tier 2 trainee interventions while additional supports were added (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Freeman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">LaBrot et al., 2021)</ref>. For example, in their studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ennis et al. (2020)</ref> and LaBrot et al. (2021) maintained email coaching and digital performance feedback respectively, while tactile prompts were added. LaBrot et al. <ref type="formula">(2022) added</ref>visual performance feedback to participants' goal setting and their delivery of daily prompts.</p><p>Coaching. Coaching remained the most common Tier 3 intervention. LaBrot et al. <ref type="formula">2021</ref>and <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Thompson et al. (2012)</ref> included coaching at Tier 3, while <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sanetti and Collier-Meek (2015)</ref> provided modeling and coaching within the trainees' classrooms. Artman-Meeker et al. <ref type="formula">2022</ref>moved participants from group coaching to individual coaching supports in which their practice was observed, and performance feedback delivered. Similarly, Owens et al. (2020) provided bugin-ear coaching for staff to allow for real-time feedback in context. In addition, Myers et al.</p><p>(2011) increased the frequency of coaching sessions from weekly to following each session, increasing the frequency of written and verbal performance feedback to the same schedule.</p><p>Coaching supports at Tier 3 were repeatedly supplemented with tactile prompting devices (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ennis et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">LaBrot et al., 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">LaBrot et al., , 2021</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Lown, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Thompson et al., 2012)</ref>. When provided with a choice of Tier 3 supports, participants in LaBrot et al.'s (2020) study chose tactile prompting over bug-in-ear coaching. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ennis et al. (2020)</ref> supplemented their coaching supports with a trainee self-monitoring procedure using a task-analyzed performance checklist.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Decision-making Processes for Increased Supports</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>18</head><p>Nineteen of the included studies described an a priori decision-making process to determine the provision of additional support to trainees <ref type="table">(Table 2)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Freeman et al. (2018)</ref> presented a study that provided increased and individualized support based on teacher response to training. However, they did not explicitly articulate the specific a priori criterion by which this decision was made. While all studies focused on a specific percentage of implementation fidelity or expected rate of target skill use, the performance criteria differed across studies. For example, while <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Brock et al. (2021)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Owens et al. (2020)</ref> both assessed implementation fidelity by measuring percentage correct of required steps, increased supports were provided by <ref type="bibr">Brock et al.</ref> if the trainee did not reach at least 85% implementation fidelity, whereas <ref type="bibr">Owens et al. provided</ref> Tier 2 supports if the trainee implemented less than 50% of the steps correctly. In addition, variability was observed in the number of observations required to demonstrate performance below the predetermined criterion. For example, LaBrot et al. (2020) required trainees to perform below the criterion for five consecutive observations, while <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sanetti and Collier-Meek (2015)</ref> required two days or trainee performance at criterion within a week. <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Thompson et al. (2012)</ref> made decisions about increasing support by assessing changes in performance relative to baseline. In their study, Artman-Meeker et al., (2022) made decisions for increased support provision based on fidelity of implementation of key Pyramid Model practices, as well as the presence of "red flag" practices that are inconsistent with implementation of the Pyramid Model, and or high-levels challenging or disruptive behavior. Multiple studies included a decisionmaking process for maintaining or fading existing supports, or for moving trainees into a maintenance phase (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Johnson, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Lown, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Rispoli et al., 2020)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study Quality</head><p>Study variables, including study design, measurement of treatment integrity, social validity assessment type and respondents, and whether the What Works Clearinghouse (2020) standards were met, are reported in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Research Design</head><p>Nineteen of the 20 included studies used a single-case research design with all but Lown (2020) using a variation of a multiple baseline or multiple probe design (See table 3); Lown (2020) proposed a multiple baseline design but resulted in an ABC design due to researcher error. Three studies used a multiple probe design whereas 15 studies used a multiple baseline design. Of those designs, most were across participants (n = 16) with <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Simonsen et al. (2014)</ref> using a multiple baseline design across settings and Reed <ref type="formula">2014</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Treatment Integrity</head><p>All but two studies reported the measure of treatment integrity of the training intervention using a fidelity checklist developed by the researchers. <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Simonsen et al. (2014)</ref> and Tekverk (2010) did not report any measure of treatment integrity within their studies. <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Thompson et al., (2012)</ref> also reported the use of permanent product data collection in the form of video recordings and email records as a measure of treatment integrity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Social Validity</head><p>Most studies measured some form of social validity. In many cases, the study used a researcher-developed intervention acceptability questionnaire (n = 5). Alternatively, studies used 20 the Intervention Rating Profile-15 <ref type="bibr">(IRP-15;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Freeman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gage, MacSuga-Gage, et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Grasely-Boy et al., 2023)</ref>, Usage Rating Profile -Intervention Revised <ref type="bibr">(URP-IR;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">LaBrot et al., 2021</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">LaBrot et al., , 2022</ref>; Lown, 2020), Behavior Intervention Rating Scale <ref type="bibr">(BIRS;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">LaBrot et al., 2020)</ref>, Targeted Professional Development Acceptability Questionnaire <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Freeman et al., 2018)</ref>, and Consultation Acceptability and Satisfaction Scale <ref type="bibr">(CASS;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">LaBrot et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Lown, 2020)</ref>. One additional measure used was the Desired Teacher Behavior Acceptability Questionnaire <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Myers et al., 2011)</ref>. When measuring social validity, most studies asked the trainee themselves (n = 13). Additionally, <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Johnson (2021)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Owens et al. (2020)</ref> asked the student learners about their acceptability of the intervention developed as well as the trainees and instructional coaches. As <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Brock et al. (2021)</ref> trained teachers to deliver the training to paraprofessional staff, they measured social validity of the teachers and the paraprofessionals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>What Works Clearinghouse Design Standards</head><p>Of the 20 studies included in this systematic review, nine studies met What Works Clearinghouse (WWC) standards without reservations <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Freeman et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gage, MacSuga-Gage, et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Grasley-Boy et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">LaBrot et al., 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">LaBrot et al., , 2021</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">LaBrot et al., , 2022</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Rispoli et al., 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sanetti &amp; Collier-Meek, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Simonsen et al., 2014</ref>; see table 3). Six studies met standards with reservations. Four studies did not meet WWC single-case design standards <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Johnson, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Lown, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Reed, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Sinclair, 2019)</ref>; all four of these studies were dissertations. They did not meet standards due to design constraints such as insufficient participants (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Johnson, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Reed 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Sinclair, 2019)</ref> or research design error that ensured insufficient points of experimental manipulation (e.g., Lown, 2020). One study did not meet WWC design standards as it did not randomize group assignment <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Artman-Meeker et al., 2022)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>21</head><p>Multitiered systems of support (MTSS) was originally designed to support educators to select and adopt evidence-based academic and behavioral supports and interventions to meet the needs of learners of all ages and abilities <ref type="bibr">(McIntosh &amp; Goodman, 2016)</ref>. This same tiered logic has increasingly been used to support the professional development needs of staff through the delivery of effective pre-and in-service training using formative data to guide the implementation of specific professional development activities that promote improved outcomes for staff <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Reddy et al., 2015)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Reddy et al. (2016)</ref> proposed that this process could be used to improve staff outcomes, focusing on collecting data to enhance staff performance (i.e., formative assessment) rather than evaluate their abilities (summative assessment). The current study evaluated the extant literature within the scope of this framework.</p><p>In this systematic review, 20 unique studies met the inclusion criteria for a multitiered, responsive professional development program. Across these studies, a wide array of professional development activities supported the training of staff in schools, clinics, and a day treatment program across three tiers of support. While most studies did explicitly include evidence-based, comprehensive training components (e.g., BST), variability was observed in the delivery of more specific, intensive, and individualized supports. This resulted in a high degree of overlap across different tiers of supports between studies with some studies using a complete and individualized BST training model at Tier 1 (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Rispoli et al., 2021)</ref>, whereas others did not include those individualized components until Tier 3 (e.g., coaching; LaBrot et al., 2021). In addition, the use of more intensive coaching supports varied across studies as well. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">Sinclair (2019)</ref> delivered bug-in-ear coaching to trainees at Tier 2, whilst <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Owens et al. (2020)</ref> used the same intervention at Tier 3. Importantly, even with the variability of duration, modality (e.g., face-toface or remote), as well as Tier of use, a consistent increase in the frequency, duration, or 22 intensity of coaching interventions was noted across studies at Tiers 2 and 3. In addition, there were examples in which the individualized supports were increasingly contextualized to the specific workspaces of the trainees' (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sanetti &amp; Collier-Meek, 2015)</ref>. For example, by assessing an individual trainee's barriers to implementation within their context and developing strategies to directly address these barriers. Conceptually, this aligns with the tiered logic of MTSS frameworks for students and ensures that supports are provided to match the level of individual need <ref type="bibr">(McIntosh &amp; Goodman, 2016)</ref>. In doing this, responsive tiered training models may allow for efficient allocation of the costliest resources (e.g., coaching), while minimizing the impact on time poor teachers <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Fox et al., 2021)</ref>.</p><p>There was also notable variability in the use of prompting (including tactile), selfmonitoring, and the delivery of performance feedback (in-person and remotely) across all three tiers of responsive training. For example, Lown (2020) utilized a tactile prompt at Tier 2, while other studies implement tactile prompts at Tier 3 (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ennis et al., 2020)</ref>. The studies that delivered these additional supports at Tier 3 all provided some form of performance feedback and or self-monitoring interventions at Tier 2, while Lown incorporated performance feedback at Tier 3. Taken together, this may indicate that tiered responsive training models incorporated both antecedent (e.g., tactile prompting) and consequence-based (e.g., performance feedback delivered at the end of the week) interventions to support staff. While an assessment of the logic or effectiveness of decisions to select specific antecedent or consequence-based supports was beyond the scope of this current research, it may represent a meaningful area for future research.</p><p>The decision-making procedures trainers used to assess when an increased level of support is required for trainees, as well as what interventions and supports are best matched to trainee needs are critical components of responsive tiered training programs. As acknowledged in the student-focused MTSS literature, there can be a variety of choices of interventions that may be relevant at various tiers of instruction (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Jimerson et al., 2016)</ref>; it is not a one-sizefits-all approach. This is paralleled in the tiered responsive training literature where components such as workshops (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ennis et al., 2020)</ref>, individual training (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Rispoli et al., 2021)</ref>, selfmonitoring (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Gage, MacSuga-Gage, et al., 2017)</ref>, tactile prompting (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">LaBrot et al., 2021)</ref>, and graphic feedback (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">LaBrot et al., 2020)</ref> were used at different Tiers across different studies. In addition, trainees were offered choices in which supports they would like to receive as part of their increased training intervention (e.g., bug-in-ear coaching or tactile prompting; LaBrot et al., 2020). In future, researchers and implementers may consider providing choice to trainees when delivering increasingly individualized and intensive supports.</p><p>In the included studies, the decisions about when additional supports were required were predominantly focused on the trainee performance. For example, participants received additional support when their performance dropped below a specific rate (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Myers et al., 2011)</ref> or fidelity percentage (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Owens et al., 2020)</ref> over multiple observations or days. Each of the included studies described an a priori determination of the performance criteria at each Tier. As noted by , data-based decision making about professional supports are required to ensure that evidence-based practices are implemented effectively in ways that are acceptable to trainees and learners. Ensuring that additional supports were matched to the skill and provided in a timely fashion (i.e., not leaving trainees implementing ineffectively for extended periods) may be critical to ensure effective and acceptable implementation of evidencebased practices using tiered training frameworks. It will remain an empirical question as to when increased support should be provided. Given that this model of professional development can be used flexibly across settings and skills, it becomes important to consider how to measure success for each skill. For example, opportunities to respond (OTR) and behavior specific praise (BSP) lend themselves to rate or frequency of use (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">LaBrot et al., 2020</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">LaBrot et al., , 2021</ref>. In contrast, other more specific skills for a unique setting may require a measure of percentage accuracy using a fidelity checklist (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Owens et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">Rispoli et al., 2021)</ref>. The learner's behavior of interest may vary as well, yet similar considerations are worth noting. These studies all measured an observable student behavior that may be susceptible to change over time such as rate of disruptive behavior or percent of time academically engaged. When conducting further evaluation of a responsive training model, individualized change sensitive metrics are effective for student behavior change; however, they must relate to the expected behavior change in the corresponding trainee.</p><p>In this review, we used the language of trainer, trainee, and learner to refer to the person conducting the training, the person receiving the training, and the person with whom the trainee works, respectively. This was to refer to the different settings in which a responsive training model can be implemented. This framework can be applied to any setting where staff are in need of professional development; however, most of the included studies were conducted in a PK-12 school setting. Thus, the trainee and learner were most often a teacher or paraprofessional, and student, respectively. Further study is needed in other environments such as clinic training programs (e.g., LaBrot et al. 2021), hospitals and day treatment programs (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">Tekverk, 2010)</ref>, or other alternative settings for learning (e.g., afterschool programs, clinics, juvenile justice centers). Staff across all these contexts participate in and would benefit from further training to support the learners with whom they work. Additional evaluation in these contexts would better support the effectiveness of training modalities for settings outside of the school environment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>25</head><p>Each of the included studies focused on developing or expanding trainees' repertoires of evidence-based practice implementation, as well as the interventions that supported these changes. As <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Noell and Gansle (2009)</ref> noted, trainee behavior will be strongly influenced by the environments within which they work (i.e., the contingencies of reinforcement or punishment for implementation within their context), as well as their existing evidence-based practice repertoires. As such, by focusing on the development of repertoires and the interventions that support the effective development of trainees' skills, there is the potential to underemphasize the impact of the implementation environment. Importantly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sanetti and Collier-Meek (2015)</ref> included assessments of potential implementation barriers and the development of plans to overcome these barriers as part of their coaching model. Future assessments of tiered training models may also consider the impact of variables that have been associated with successful and sustained implementation of PBIS (e.g., impact of leadership, teaming, and staff buy-in; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">McIntosh et al., 2014</ref>).</p><p>While we reviewed the various training components included, we were not intending to do any form of component analysis of the training components. Thus, this systematic review cannot be used to discuss the differential effectiveness of training components. Future research should examine the effective and relevant components of this training model. We suggest that this be undertaken with a clear description of contextual needs and variables to assess the impact of components of tiered training within specific learning or work environments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Limitations</head><p>With such flexibility in the decision making model, and various settings in which it has been applied, there are possibly missing studies that were not found in this search. While we intended to use a broad search to capture all relevant studies -including dissertations and theses 26 as recommended by <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Gage, Cook, et al. (2017)</ref> -some may still have been missed. Further, many of the studies are recent publications which were not captured in the initial database searches; they may not have been indexed within the included databases. We conducted a forward and backward ancestral search to try and capture as much of this as possible; however, due to various labels for the training programs, some may not have been included. Future research should consider the terms in which they label their training models to easily link to previous studies in the field. Terms such as multi-tiered support frameworks (MTS; <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Simonsen et al., 2014)</ref>, multitiered implementation supports (MTIS; <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sanetti &amp; Collier-Meek, 2015)</ref>, along with descriptions such as multitiered systems of support for teachers <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Ennis et al., 2020)</ref> have been used. We propose the title responsive tiered training to differentiate these training models from multitiered systems of support for students, establishing an independent title that reflects a conceptually systematic, tiered approach to professional learning.</p><p>When extracting the procedures of the included studies, each study labeled their procedures in different ways. With various labels to define the specific components of training and decision making, or gaps in reporting details of their training, some studies may have included more than reported in this study. This conservative approach to data extraction may undersell what was done. In the future, we encourage researchers to describe their procedures using consistent terms. By unifying the terms to describe the training and decision-making procedures, the consistency and clarity of the procedures conducted can be increased. This may enhance efforts to conduct direct and systematic replication of studies.</p><p>In the evaluation of the design quality, we used the WWC design standards for single case design (2020). WWC design standards do not align nicely with responsive tiered training with multiple phases. As most included studies used a multiple baseline design, WWC design 27 standards evaluate three or more replications with consecutive phases demonstrating sufficient measurement. In a responsive tiered training model, trainees might be participating in additional, sequential training components as they progress through added tiers of intervention. That may result in additional phases of intervention (e.g., ABCD design) to represent baseline, Tier 1, Tier 2, and Tier 3 intervention. Thus, in our evaluation of the WWC design standards, all assessment was based on the initial baseline and first intervention phase presented due to the overlapping baseline, and systematic introduction of subsequent intervention phases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>Twenty studies were included in this systematic review of the emerging research literature examining the impact of tiered responsive training models on trainee and learner performance. While each model was unique, consistent features were identified across studies.</p><p>Didactic training that included some or all components of BST was consistently used at Tier 1.</p><p>In some studies, these didactic supports were supplemented with performance feedback, prompts, or self-monitoring interventions. As with other tiered frameworks, the supports provided to staff at Tiers 2 and 3 increased in frequency and were increasingly individualized for trainees. This was achieved by coaching, delivery of performance feedback, and the addition of self-monitoring interventions. It is apparent that the form and shape of specific interventions at each Tier differed across studies, reflecting the need for such tiered responsive training programs to be tailored to both the target training behaviors and the specific settings in which training and supports are to be delivered. Overall, the importance of data to inform decision-making is clear.</p><p>If educators are to receive training that is truly responsive to the needs of their learners, their own needs, and that matches the challenges and constraints of their work, then decision-making that is informed by direct behavioral data will be critical.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(d) trainer characteristics; (e) independent variables; (f) dependent variables; (g) treatment integrity; (h) social validity; (i) design quality and characteristics. The first and second author coded the articles independently; they assessed interrater agreement five of the 22 articles representing 22.73% of the studies. Their agreement across all variables was 96.60%. The first and second author reviewed the coding disagreements and came to consensus.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>evaluated the responsive training program in a day treatment program whereas LaBrot et al. (2021) evaluated a responsive training approach with graduate students in an outpatient clinic setting. LaBrot et al. (2022) conducted their study in a university child development and teacher training center.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Additional Tier 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Practices. Six of the included studies supplemented Tier 1 training with some form of self-monitoring, prompt, or performance feedback. For example, Freeman et al. (2018), Gage, MacSuga-Gage, et al. (2017), and Simonsen et al. (2014) incorporated selfmonitoring in Tier 1 training (i.e., using a golf counter). Sinclair (2019) supplemented Tier 1 training with performance feedback provided remotely, while Johnson (2021) delivered email prompts to trainees. Artman-Meeker et al. (2022) provided self-coaching resources (i.e., 15 individual action plan, practice checklists, and self-observation and reflection sheets), as well as opportunities to check-in with a coach monthly.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>For example, Artman-Meeker et al. (2022) provided coaching in a group format at Tier-2, while Owens et al. (2020) described a single 30-40-minute session delivered to trainees using BST. Similarly, Grasley-Boy et al. (2023) provided participants with a brief training session using BST (i.e., approximately 20 min), following this with performance feedback delivered via email and text message. Brock et al. (2021) reported trainees receiving two 15-minute coaching sessions that used a video recording of trainee practice to deliver corrective and positive feedback relating to the target skill. Myers et al. (2011) reported 10-minute weekly coaching meetings in which graphed trainee performance data were reviewed and feedback delivered to trainees, while Rispoli et al. (2021) provided weekly 20-minute sessions. In addition, Sinclair</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>2014) and Artman-Meeker et al. (2022) provided staff with a cue-sheet and self-reflection form to allow trainees to monitor their own performance.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>using a multiple baseline across groups design. Artman-Meeker et al. (2022) measured the impact of their tiered training framework using statistical analyses of teachers' TPOT scores taken at three timepoints (i.e., pretest, midpoint, and post-test), as well as results of a teacher survey that measured preferences for professional development, self-efficacy in discipline, amongst other variables.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Note. * = school or center-wide data. No study-specific data were reported for those variables; ^ = variables were reported for part of sample. reporting incomplete; NR = Not Reported; Race/Ethnicity: W = White, B = Black, H = Hispanic/Latino, A = Asian; Gender: M = Male, F = Female; SES: F/RL = Free/Reduced Lunch </p><p>Group didactic training provided over 3x 50-min sessions (one school had 2x 25-min as a replacement).</p><p>Two 15-minute, special education teacher delivered on-to-one coaching sessions</p><p>Following Tier-1 group training, if the paraeducator did not reach &gt;85% implementation fidelity when delivering either simultaneous prompts or least-to-most prompts for either specified student goals in two consecutive sessions during the maintenance condition, they received Tier-2 coaching.</p><p>% fidelity for prompting steps (either simultaneous prompting, least-to-most prompting).</p><p>% of correct student responses.</p><p>Ennis, et al.</p><p>Group didactic training (2-hr start of school year, 1-hr booster training in fall, and 30-min in spring).</p><p>Coaching provided via individualized emails.</p><p>Vibratory prompt (MotivAider) and ongoing email coaching.</p><p>Tier-1 to Tier-2: Educator delivery of BSP, choice, and or precorrection below predetermined goal rates (12-15 BSP statements, 3 -5 choices and or precorrects within a 15minute observation). Tier-2 to Tier-3: If an educator did not meet their goal for &gt;5 consecutive days or displayed inconsistent performance at low levels at least three coaching emails, they received Tier-3 supports. Tactile prompt (MotivAider) and inperson performance feedback meetings (no longer than 5-minutes).</p><p>Tier-2 supports were provided if &lt; .5 BSP statements per minute were made. Tier-3 supports were provided if &lt; .5 BSP statements per minute were made for the "most recent" three data points. If teacher did not meet criterion after 10 sessions of Tier-3 intervention was concluded. If teachers delivered &gt; .5 BSP statements per minute for three consecutive data points, their support was reduced to the next Tier down (maintenance from Tier-1). Weekly consultation and performance feedback (verbal and written).</p><p>Consultation and performance feedback (verbal and written) following each observation.</p><p>Teachers were moved into a maintenance phase if they delivered 6 BSP statements and maintained a 4:1 of positive to negative interactions within a 15-minute observation period. If one of the two criteria was acheived, participants remained in Tier-2 intervention. If neither was achieved, Tier-3 supports were provided.</p><p>Rate BSP + Positive:negative interactions % AET + DB Owens et al.</p><p>Group didactic training (60minute).</p><p>Individual coaching session (40 -45-minute).</p><p>In situ bug-in-ear coaching session <ref type="bibr">(30minute)</ref>. Post in situ coaching if required.</p><p>Teachers received individual coaching if &lt; 50% of implementation checklist steps were implemented. Tier-3 supports were provided If &lt; 20 (of 25) steps in the implementation checklist were implemented in 3 consecutive sessions at Tier-3. At Tier-3, post in situ coaching was provided in addition to bug-in-ear coaching if &lt; 20 steps were implemented during bug-in-ear coaching session. % steps % on-task <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Reed (2014)</ref> One-on-one didactic training (approx. 1-hr).</p><p>Re-teaching of skill, written prompts, and self-reflection.</p><p>Re-teaching of skill and daily written performance feedback.</p><p>Tier-2 supports were provided for teachers who did not show an increase in BSP or who showed a contratherapeutic trend for 3 consecutive data points. Tier-3 supports were provided if no increase in BSP and a contratherapeutic trend was observed for 3 consecutive data points was observed during Tier-2 training. Rate BSP % on-task</p><p>Rispoli et al.</p><p>One-on-one behavioral skills training (approx. 30-minutes) Practice-based coaching</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Practice-based coaching with selfmonitoring</head><p>Teachers received the next Tier of support if they demonstrated stable pattern of fidelity with zero to negative trend and with fidelity below the mastery criterion (3 consecutive observations with 100% fidelity). If student challenging behaviour was eliminated and student communication was at or above 10 mands per session an increase in support was not provided. % steps % DB, # Mands Sanetti and Collier-One-on-one direct training.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Implementation planning Participant modelling</head><p>Increased support was provided if &lt; 80% adherence to intervention plan was observed for 2 days in a week. % steps #DB</p><p>Meek <ref type="formula">2015</ref>When high levels of adherence &gt; 80% were observed for 10 data points following direct training, or 5 data points following more intensive support, a treatment evaluation interview was conducted, report written, and a determination about further support needed was made. Tier-2 supports were implemented if BSP rate increased less than 50% from baseline. Tier-3 intervention was provided if, during Tier-2, teacher use of BSP fell below a 50% increase from Tier-1 for two or more data points. Tier-3 supports were reduced if frequency of BSP use was equal to or greater than 50% of Tier-2 rate. If this dropped below a 50% increase on Tier-2, the coach reintroduced video self-monitoring and increased visits until frequnecy was greater than or equal to 50% increase on Tier-2. Rate BSP % on-task</p><p>Note. NR = not reported    <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">Thompson et al. (2012)</ref> X X Note. *All training components conducted individually</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Iterative design and pilot implementation of a tiered coaching model to support socioemotional teaching practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>*artman-Meeker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fettig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Cunningham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H.-C</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Harbin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/02711214211050122</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/02711214211050122" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Topics in Early Childhood Special Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of team members&apos; perceptions of coaching activities related to tier 1 SWPBIS implementation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bastable</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Massar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mcintosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1098300719861566</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1098300719861566" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Positive Behavior Interventions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="61" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A tiered approach for training paraeducators to use evidence-based practices for students with significant disabilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Brock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/00400599211006745</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/00400599211006745" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TEACHING Exceptional Children</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="224" to="233" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficacy of tiered training on paraeducator implementation of systematic instructional practices for students With severe disabilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Brock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Barczak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bordner-Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Exceptional Children</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="235" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0014402920947641</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0014402920947641" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Effective teacher professional development. Learning Policy Institute</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Darling-Hammond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hyler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gardener</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.54300/122.311</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.54300/122.311" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using a tiered approach to support early childhood educators&apos; use of behavioral strategies. Education and Treatment of Children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Ennis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Flemming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s43494-020-00027-x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s43494-020-00027-x" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="277" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Professional development for teachers plus coaching related to school-wide suspensions for a large 29 urban school system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Lissy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Alicea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Tazartes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mckay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Children and Youth Services Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="39" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.childyouth.2016.01.015</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.childyouth.2016.01.015" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Teaching pyramid observation tool for preschool classrooms (TPOT</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hemmeter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Snyder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>Paul H. Brookes</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Research ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Not Enough Time&apos;: Identifying Victorian Teachers&apos; Perceptions of the Facilitators and Barriers to Supporting Improved Student Behaviour</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Leif</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stocker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/jsi.2021.6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/jsi.2021.6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Australasian Journal of Special and Inclusive Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kowitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Simonsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Dooley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Maddock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A high school replication of tiered professional development for classroom management</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Remedial and Special Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="144" to="157" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0741932517719547</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0741932517719547" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sugai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Simonsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Everett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">MTSS coaching: Bridging knowing to doing. Theory Into Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="37" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/00405841.2016.1241946</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/00405841.2016.1241946" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Publication Bias in Special Education Meta-Analyses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Reichow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Exceptional Children</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="428" to="445" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0014402917691016</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0014402917691016" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Increasing teachers&apos; use of behaviorspecific praise using a multitiered system for professional development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Macsuga-Gage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Crews</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Positive Behavior Interventions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="251" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1098300717693568</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1098300717693568" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Conceptual Replication of Targeted Professional Development to Increase Teachers&apos; Behavior-Specific Praise</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">*</forename><surname>Grasley-Boy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Reichow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Macsuga-Gage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">School Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="86" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/2372966X.2020.1853486</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/2372966X.2020.1853486" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">From response to intervention to multi-tiered systems of support: Advances in the science and practice of assessment and intervention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Jimerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Burns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Vanderheyden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-4899-7568-3_1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4899-7568-3_1" />
		<editor>S. R. Jimerson, M. K. Burns, &amp; A. M. VanDerHeyden</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>Springer US</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Handbook of Response to Intervention: The Science and Practice of Multi-Tiered Systems of Support</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Effects of multilevel coaching on teachers&apos; implementation of opportunities to respond and student academic engagement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">N N</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>D.Ed., The University of North Carolina at Charlotte</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Examination of a tiered training model to increase school psychology graduate students&apos; behavior specific praise</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Labrot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Defouw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eldridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s43494-021-00048-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s43494-021-00048-0" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Targeted and intensive consultation for increasing Head Start and elementary teachers&apos; behaviorspecific praise</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Labrot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Dufrene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Whipple</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mccargo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Pasqua</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="717" to="740" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10864-019-09342-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10864-019-09342-9" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Labrot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Weaver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Peak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Maxime</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Butt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Pigg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Multitiered Consultation to Promote Preservice Teachers&apos; Delivery of Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
			<biblScope unit="page">31</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Specific Praise in Early Childhood Education Classrooms</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10864-022-09502-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10864-022-09502-4" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Education</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence-Based Application of Staff and Caregiver Training Procedures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Leblanc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Valentino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/B978-0-12-420249-8.00014-9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-420249-8.00014-9" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Clinical and Organizational Applications of Applied Behavior Analysis</title>
		<editor>H. S. Roane, J. L. Ringdahl, &amp; T. S. Falcomata</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="351" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multi-tiered systems of support for Head Start teachers behavior specific praise</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>*lown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://aquila.usm.edu/dissertations/1802" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Continuing professional development-why bother? Perceptions and motivations of teachers in Ireland</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mcmillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mcconnell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="150" to="167" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Professional development in education</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mcintosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Predy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Upreti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hume</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Turri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mathews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceptions of contextual features related to implementation and sustainability of schoolwide positive behavior support</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Positive Behavior Interventions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="43" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1098300712470723</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1098300712470723" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Implementing classwide PBIS: A guide to supporting teachers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Simonsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<publisher>Guilford Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Increasing teachers&apos; use of praise with a response-to-intervention approach. Education and Treatment of Children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Simonsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sugai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1353/etc.2011.0004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1353/etc.2011.0004" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="59" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moving from good ideas in educational systems change to sustainable program implementation: Coming to terms with some of the realities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Noell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gansle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/pits.20355</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/pits.20355" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology in the Schools</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using tiered coaching and bug-in-ear technology to promote teacher implementation fidelity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Owens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0022466919852706</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0022466919852706" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Special Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring teacher self-report on classroom practices: Construct validity and reliability of the Classroom Strategies Scale -Teacher Form</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Reddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dudek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fabiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">School Psychology Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="513" to="533" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/spq0000110</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/spq0000110" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Teacher formative assessment: The missing link in response to intervention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Reddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dudek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Shernoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>S. R. Jimerson, M. K. Burns, &amp; A. M</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Handbook of Response to Intervention: The Science and Practice of Multi-Tiered Systems of Support</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Vanderheyden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="607" to="623" />
			<pubPlace>US</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-4899-7568-3_34</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4899-7568-3_34" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The effects of a tiered-training intervention on teachers&apos; use of behavior specific praise during the reading instruction of elementary students with emotional disabilities. Communication Disorders &amp; Special Education Theses &amp; Dissertations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.25777/zepp-x595</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.25777/zepp-x595" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of multilevel supports on special education preschool teacher implementation of function-based interventions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rispoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gregori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mason</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lory</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10864-021-09461-2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10864-021-09461-2" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Increasing implementation science literacy to address the research-to-practice gap in school psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M H</forename><surname>Sanetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Collier-Meek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jsp.2019.07.008</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsp.2019.07.008" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of School Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="47" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Data-driven delivery of implementation supports in a multi-tiered framework: A pilot study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M H</forename><surname>Sanetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Collier-Meek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/pits.21861</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/pits.21861" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology in the Schools</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="815" to="828" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using data to support educators&apos; implementation of positive classroom behavior support (PCBS) practices. Education and Treatment of</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Simonsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Swain-Bradway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Putnam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sprague</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hershfeldt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1353/etc.2019.0013</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1353/etc.2019.0013" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Children</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="289" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">School-wide positive behavioral interventions and supports: A systems-level application of behavioral principles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Simonsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sugai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0000126-000</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0000126-000" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Behavioral interventions in schools: Evidence-based positive strategies</title>
		<editor>S. G. Little &amp; A. Akin-Little</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>American Psychological Association</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multitiered support framework for teachers&apos; classroom-management practices: Overview and case study of building the triangle for teachers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Simonsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Macsuga-Gage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Briere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sugai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Positive Behavior Interventions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="190" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1098300713484062</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1098300713484062" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Effective teacher professional development: New theory and a meta-analytic test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sims</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fletcher-Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>O'mara-Eves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cottingham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Stansfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Herwegen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Anders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://edworkingpapers.com/ai22-507" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Annenberg Institute at Brown University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The effect of targeted professional development on paraprofessional fidelity to an evidence-based reading intervention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Sinclair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Ph.D., Vanderbilt University</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A prescriptive model of multi-tier professional development to increase treatment integrity for staff in a day treatment setting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tekverk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Southern Maine</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Psy.D.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Effects of tiered training on general educators&apos; use of specific praise. Education and Treatment of Children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marchant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Prater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gibb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1353/etc.2012.0032</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1353/etc.2012.0032" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="521" to="546" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A decade of professional development research for inclusive education: A critical review and notes for a research program</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Waitoller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Artiles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3102/0034654313483905</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3102/0034654313483905" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review of educational research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="356" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What Works Clearinghouse standards handbook (Version 4.1). National Center for Education Evaluation and Regional Assistance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>What Works Clearinghouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Institute of Education Sciences, U.S. Department of Education</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teachers&apos; motivation to participate in continuous professional development: relationship with factors at the personal and school level</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Admiraal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Saab</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Education for Teaching</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="714" to="731" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
