<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:12+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bayesian Inference for the A/B Test: Example Applications with JASP</head><p>Most popular in clinical studies, but also the latest trend in business, A/B testing is a procedure to compare the success frequencies of two alternatives, such as two treatment arms or two website versions. With the present paper, we advocate for using a Bayesian approach to A/B testing. We demonstrate how Bayesian A/B tests allow practitioners to address various questions concerning a difference between two proportions. With the proposed analyses, practitioners can monitor and quantify their uncertainty as data accumulate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>When to Use This Procedure</head><p>Experimentation is omnipresent in medical studies. It is used, for example, to compare the treatment success of a new pharmacological drug to a placebo. In recent years, there has been a growing interest in a similar kind of experimentation in the web development context as it allows establishing an evidence-based approach to business. In general, the number of visitors that take action on a website is a key indicator of success.</p><p>The more traffic a website has, i.e., the more people visit and navigate through a website, the more chances there are for the acquisition of new customers and the promotion of customer loyalty. However, the traffic on a website is only profitable for a company if it translates into meaningful customer actions such as signing up for a newsletter or buying something. In technical jargon, the number of website visitors that take a desired action is called conversion. The goal of online marketers is to have the highest possible conversion rate which denotes the conversion count divided by the total number of unique visitors. To lure customers into clicking, signing up or buying, online marketers have to equip a website with a compelling design <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Gudigantala, Bicen, et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Saleh &amp; Shukairy, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>Experimentation allows them to test whether their assumptions on effective website design translate into the desired conversion rates.</p><p>In online marketing, an experiment may proceed as follows: Two versions of the same webpage are shown to different selections of website visitors and the number of visitors who take the desired action (e.g., the click rate) is monitored in a nominal dichotomous manner. The two website versions only differ in one aspect (e.g., the colour of a call-to-action button). Changing only one aspect ensures being able to identify what had an effect on website visitors' behaviour. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> illustrates the procedure. Eventually companies want to test which webpage version has the highest conversion rate. To make this judgment, the company needs to determine whether and to what extent the observed sample difference in proportions translates to the population; in other words, the company needs to conduct a statistical analysis. While data-driven decision-making sounds compelling to many businesses, it needs to be carried out correctly to yield the desired monetary pay-off. In the next section, we will introduce different statistical approaches that practitioners can adopt.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Different Statistical Approaches to A/B testing</head><p>The difference between the two sample proportions can be analyzed with an A/B test <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Little, 1989)</ref>. Ideally this test should meet three general desiderata <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Gronau et al., 2019)</ref>: evidence can be obtained in favor of the null hypothesis, evidence can be monitored as the data accumulate, and expert knowledge can be taken into account. In general, practitioners can chose between the frequentist and the Bayesian framework. With the desiderata in mind, we can evaluate the qualities of these two statistical approaches to the A/B test analysis. The content and meaning of the desiderata will become more explicit in the subsequent paragraphs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Frequentist Statistics</head><p>As it is the case for many other analyses in various fields, online marketers predominantly utilize the p-value based null hypothesis significance testing (NHST). The NHST approach however does not satisfy the three desiderata. Firstly, the results do not distinguish between absence of evidence and evidence of absence. While evidence of absence denotes that an effect truly does not exist (e.g., two website versions do not differ in conversion rates), absence of evidence means that one cannot know whether there is an effect or not (i.e., the data are inconclusive) <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Altman &amp; Bland, 1995)</ref>. Secondly, the data cannot be tested sequentially. In practice, sellers need to know as quickly as possible which online campaign creates the highest conversion rate because many offers are bound to specific events such as Christmas shopping offers. To be time-efficient, many A/B test applicants repeatedly 'peek' at the results and call the testing quits as soon as the p-value is smaller than some predefined α-level <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Goodson, 2014)</ref>. However, repeatedly monitoring the uncorrected p-value and stopping the analysis when significant results are achieved invalidates a NHST analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Wagenmakers, 2007)</ref>: With an increasing number of tests, the probability that at least one of the tests is significant also increases, leading to an inflated type I error rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Jennison, Turnbull, et al., 1990)</ref>. A third disadvantage of p-value based A/B testing is that it does not allow incorporating expert knowledge. Among conversion rate optimization professionals it is widely known that online advertising campaigns often yield minuscule conversion increases (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Johnson et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Patel, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Enriching statistical models with such expert knowledge leads to more informed statistical analyses <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Lindley, 1993)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bayesian Statistics</head><p>The limitations of frequentist statistics can be overcome by adopting a Bayesian data analysis approach (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Deng, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Kamalbasha &amp; Eugster, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Stucchio, 2015)</ref>. In Bayesian statistics, probability expresses a degree of reasonable belief <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Jeffreys, 1961)</ref> and in principle Bayesian statistics fulfill all three desiderata (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wagenmakers et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>In recent years, some practitioners have discovered the benefits that Bayesian statistics bring for A/B testing (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Deng, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Kamalbasha &amp; Eugster, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Stucchio, 2015)</ref>. In the next section we introduce two approaches to Bayesian A/B testing. The two approaches make different assumptions, ask different questions, and therefore provide different answers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">The 'Common Approach'</head><p>Let n A denote the total number of observations and y A denote the number of successes for version A. Let n B denote the total number of observations and y B denote the number of successes for version B. The commonly used Bayesian A/B testing model is specified as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">y A ∼ Binomial(n A , θ A ) y B ∼ Binomial(n B , θ B )</formula><p>This model assumes that y A and y B follow independent binomial distributions with success probabilities θ A and θ B . These success probabilities are assigned independent beta(α, β) distributions that encode the relative prior plausibility of the values for θ A and θ B . In a beta distribution, the α values can be interpreted as counts of hypothetical "prior successes" and the β values can be interpreted as counts of hypothetical "prior failures" <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lee &amp; Wagenmakers, 2013)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">θ A ∼ Beta(α A , β A ) θ B ∼ Beta(α B , β B )</formula><p>With the data coming in from the A/B testing experiment, the two independent prior distributions are updated to two independent posterior distributions. This is achieved by Bayes' rule:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">p(θ A | y A , n A ) = p(θ A ) × p(y A , n A | θ A ) p(y A , n A ) p(θ B | y B , n B ) = p(θ B ) × p(y B , n B | θ B ) p(y B , n B )</formula><p>where p(θ A ) and p(θ B ) are the prior probabilities and p(y A , n</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">A | θ A ) and p(y B , n B | θ B ) are</formula><p>the likelihoods of the data given the respective parameter. Hence, the reallocation of probability from prior to posterior is brought about by the data: the probability of parameters that predict the data well increases while the probability of parameter values that predict the data poorly decreases <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kruschke, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">van Doorn et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Wagenmakers et al., 2016)</ref>. Note that whenever a beta prior is used and the observed data has a binomial distribution, the resulting posterior distribution is also a beta distribution.</p><p>In fact, if the data contains s successes and f failures, the resulting posterior beta distribution equals beta(α + s, β + f ) <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Gelman et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">van Doorn et al., 2020)</ref>. 1</p><p>Eventually, practitioners are most often interested in the difference δ = θ A − θ B between the success rates of the two website versions. That is because this difference indicates whether the implemented changes on the website had the desired effect. In the next section, we will introduce an open source software implementation of the 'common approach.'</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Software Implementation of the 'Common Approach': The bayesAB Package</head><p>The 'common approach' is implemented in the bayesAB <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Portman, 2017)</ref> package in R (R Core Team, 2020). Consider the following fictitious example. A company wishes to improve the click rate on their landing page. Therefore, they test two versions of this page -the original page and a modified version. Before setting up the A/B test and collecting the data, the prior distributions have to be specified so that they represent the relative plausibility of the parameter values. For the present example we specify two uninformed beta(1,1) priors -a popular choice <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bondarenko &amp; Kravchenko, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Singh, 2019)</ref>. Each version is visited by N = 100 people. In version A -the original website -35 people click, and in version B -the modified website -50 people click. After running the A/B test procedure, the priors are updated with the obtained data. The R file for the fabrication of the data for this fictitious example can be found in the OSF repository associated with this manuscript (https://osf.io/anvg2/).</p><p>With bayesAB the calculation of the posterior distributions is done by feeding both the priors and the data to the bayesTest function:</p><p>R&gt; library(bayesAB)</p><p>R&gt; data &lt;-read.csv2("example_data1.csv") R&gt; AB1 &lt;-bayesTest(data$y1, + data$y2, + priors = c('alpha' = 1, 'beta' = 1),</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">+ n_samples = 1e5, + distribution = 'bernoulli')</formula><p>The results can be obtained and visualized:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">R&gt; summary(AB1)</formula><p>R&gt; plot(AB1) <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 2</ref> shows the two independent posterior distributions that plot(AB1) returns.</p><p>To plot these posterior distributions, bayesTest makes use of the rbeta function that draws random numbers from a given beta distribution. To obtain each posterior distribution the package first exploits conjugacy: the number of successes s are added to the α values of either version's prior distribution and the number of failures f are added to</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2</head><p>Independent posterior beta distributions of the success probabilities for version A and B.</p><p>The plot is produced by the bayesAB package with the fictitious data. The analysis used two independent beta(1, 1) priors.</p><p>the respective β values. Thus, the posterior distribution for θ A is beta(α</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">A + s A , β A + f A ) and that for θ B is beta(α B + s B , β B + f B ).</formula><p>The rbeta function draws random samples from each posterior distribution and the density of these values is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 2</ref>. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We can see that version B's posterior distribution for the success probability assigns more mass to higher values of θ. This suggests that the success probability of the modified website version is higher and the alterations had a positive impact on the click rate.</p><p>The bayesAB package also returns a posterior distribution (see <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>) which 10 indicates the conversion rate uplift. The uplift is calculated as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">(θ B −θ A ) θ A</formula><p>; that is, it is the difference between the success rates (i.e., θ B − θ A ) expressed as a proportion of θ A . This posterior distribution is computed from the random samples obtained for the two beta posteriors shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 2</ref>.</p><p>The posterior distribution for the uplift peaks at around 0.4, indicating that the most likely conversion increase equals 40%. Also, most posterior mass (i.e., 98.4% of the samples) is above zero, indicating that we can be 98.4% certain that version B is better than version A. Note that this statement assumes that it is equally likely that the alterations in versions B had a positive or negative effect on the conversion rate!</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 3</head><p>Histogram of the conversion rate uplift from version A to version B. The uplift is calculated by dividing the difference in conversion by the conversion in A. The plot is produced by the bayesAB package.</p><p>The posterior probability for θ B &gt; θ A can also be calculated analytically <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Schmidt &amp; Mørup, 2019)</ref>. The formula is not implemented in the bayesAB package; our R implementation can be found in the OSF repository. For the above example, p(θ B &gt; θ A | data) = 0.984. As far as the posterior distribution for the difference between the two independent beta distributions is concerned, it can be calculated analytically as well <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Pham-Gia et al., 1993)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_30">Figure 4a</ref> shows the posterior density of the difference between the two independent beta posteriors from the above example. Unfortunately, the analytic calculation fails for values of α and β above ∼ 50, which occur with strong advance knowledge or high sample sizes. In this case, one can instead employ a normal approximation, the result of which is shown in the right panel of <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. 3 Note however that this is only a crude approximation of δ. For a detailed explanation and an alternative approximation see Appendix B.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 4</head><p>Posterior density distributions of the difference θ B − θ A for the fictitious example data. An advantage of the Bayesian approach is that the data can also be added to the analysis in a sequential manner. This means that the evidence can be assessed continually as the data arrives and the analyses can be stopped as soon as the evidence is judged to be compelling <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Deng et al., 2016)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 5</ref> plots the posterior mean of the difference between θ A and θ B as well as the 95% highest density interval (HDI) of the difference in a sequential manner. With increasing sample size, the HDI becomes more narrow. This indicates that the range of likely values for δ becomes smaller. After some initial fluctuation, the posterior mean difference between θ A and θ B settles between 0.1 and 0.2. To create this plot, we used the abtest package in R which will be introduced in a later section.</p><p>Appendix B contains the R code for the sequential computation. In sum, the common approach allows practitioners to judge the size and direction of an effect, that is, the difference between the two success probabilities. It is important, however, to recognise the assumptions that are made under this approach. In the next section, we will elaborate on these assumptions and their consequences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assumptions of the 'Common Approach'</head><p>The 'common approach' makes two important assumptions. The first assumption is that the two success probabilities are independent: learning about the success rate of one version does not affect our knowledge about the success rate of the other version <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Howard, 1998)</ref>. In practice, this assumption is rarely valid. If we know the conversion rate under version A relatively precisely, we anticipate that the conversation rate under version B is relatively close.</p><p>The second assumption of the common approach is that an effect is always present;</p><p>that is, a new version may increase conversation rates or decrease conversion rates; it is never the case that the new version is completely ineffective. This assumption is a consequence of the fact that a continuous prior assigns zero probability to a specific point value such as zero <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Jeffreys, 1939;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Williams et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Wrinch &amp; Jeffreys, 1921)</ref>. Thus, using the common approach practitioners can only test whether website alterations yield a positive or negative effect. Obtaining evidence in favor of the null hypothesis -which was one of the desiderata listed by Gronau et al. (2019) -is not possible with this approach.</p><p>Hence, 'the common approach' does not represent a testing effort, but an estimation effort <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Jeffreys, 1939)</ref>. To allow for both hypothesis testing and parameter estimation a Bayesian</p><p>A/B testing model has to be able to assign prior mass to the possibility that the difference between the two versions is exactly zero. Next, we will introduce such an approach.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The 'Odds Ratio Approach'</head><p>An A/B test model that assigns prior mass to the null hypothesis of no effect was introduced by <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kass and Vaidyanathan (1992)</ref> and implemented by <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Gronau et al. (2019)</ref>. In contrast to the 'common approach', this model assigns a prior distribution to the log odds ratio, thereby accounting for the dependency between the success probabilities of the two website versions. The odds are the ratio of an event occurring to an event not occurring and the odds ratio quantifies the odds of an event occurring in one group compared to another (see <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). The 'odds ratio approach' is specified as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">y A ∼ Binomial(n A , θ A ) y B ∼ Binomial(n B , θ B ) log θ A 1 − θ A = γ − ψ/2 log θ B 1 − θ B = γ + ψ/2</formula><p>As before, this model assumes that y A and y B follow binomial distributions with success probabilities θ A and θ B . However, the success probabilities are a function of two parameters, γ and ψ. Parameter γ indicates the grand mean of the log odds, while ψ denotes the distance between the two conditions (i.e., the log odds ratio). The hypothesis that there is no difference between the two versions can be formulated as a null hypothesis:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">H 0 : ψ = 0.</formula><p>Under the alternative hypothesis H 1 , ψ is assumed to be nonzero. By default, both parameters are assigned normal priors:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">γ ∼ N (µ γ , σ 2 γ ) ψ ∼ N (µ ψ , σ 2 ψ )</formula><p>While the choice of a prior for γ is relatively inconsequential for the comparison between H 0 and H 1 , the choice of a prior for ψ is far-reaching: it determines the predictions of H 1 concerning the difference between versions A and B. For this reason, ψ is the test-relevant parameter.</p><p>We consider four hypotheses that may be of interest to online marketers:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">H 0 : θ A = θ B ;</formula><p>The success probabilities θ A and θ B are identical.</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">H 1 : θ A = θ B ;</formula><p>The success probabilities θ A and θ B are not identical.</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">H + : θ B &gt; θ A ;</formula><p>The success probability θ B is larger than the success probability θ A .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 6</head><p>Illustration of the odds and the odds ratio.</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">H − : θ A &gt; θ B ;</formula><p>The success probability θ A is larger than the success probability θ B .</p><p>By comparing these hypotheses online marketers may answer the following questions: <ref type="formula">1</ref> Does version B yield more successes than version A, or does version A yield more successes than version B? This is the question addressed by the 'common approach' discussed earlier, and it requires a comparison between H + and H − .</p><p>To compare the evidence that the observed data provide for and against the hypotheses we quantify and compare the models' predictive performance. 4 For two models, say H 0 and H + , the comparison of their likelihoods for the observed data is known as the Bayes factor <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Jeffreys, 1939;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Kass &amp; Raftery, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Wagenmakers et al., 2018)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">BF +0 = p(data | H + ) p(data | H 0 ) ,</formula><p>where BF +0 indicates the extent to which H + outpredicts H 0 .</p><p>The evidence from the data is expressed in the Bayes factor, but to compare two hypotheses in their entirety, the a priori plausibility of the hypotheses needs to be considered as well. Bayes' rule describes how we can use the Bayes factor to update the relative plausibility of the two competing models after having seen the data <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Kass &amp; Raftery, 1995)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">p(H + | data) p(H 0 | data) posterior odds = p(H + ) p(H 0 ) prior odds × p(data | H + ) p(data | H 0 ) BF +0 .</formula><p>The prior odds quantify the plausibility of the hypotheses before seeing the data, while the posterior odds quantify the plausibility of the two hypotheses after taking the data into account <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Wagenmakers et al., 2018)</ref>. The Bayes factor is the evidence -the change from prior to posterior plausibility brought about by the data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Software Implementation of the 'Odds Ratio Approach': The abtest Package</head><p>To demonstrate the analyses with the 'odds ratio approach' we can use the abtest package <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Gronau, 2019)</ref> in R (R Core Team, 2020). It is important that a hypothesis is specified before setting up the A/B test <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(McFarland, 2012)</ref>. For the previous example, it can be assumed that the alterations implemented on website version B were designed with the express purpose to lead to more clicks. Hence, from a Bayesian perspective, we may want to compare the directional hypothesis H + that website visitors in version B generate more clicks (not fewer clicks) against the null hypothesis H 0 that there is no difference in the click rate between version A and B. The prior distribution for the log odds ratio under H + has to be specified before the data collection, too, as it quantifies how large the difference between the two success probabilities is expected to be. For the present example, we assume that there is little prior knowledge, which is why we use an uninformed parameter prior. For the log odds ratio the normal distribution with µ = 0 and σ 2 = 1 can be employed. Within the abtest package, the prior is specified using the elicit_prior function: The function then returns the Bayes factors and the prior and posterior probabilities of the hypotheses. The Bayes factor BF +0 equals 4.7, meaning that the data are approximately 5 times more likely to occur under the alternative hypothesis H + than under the null hypothesis H 0 . A Bayes factor of ∼ 5 corresponds to moderate evidence (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Jeffreys, 1939;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lee &amp; Wagenmakers, 2013)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">R&gt;</formula><p>The robustness of this conclusion can be explored by changing the prior distribution on ψ (i.e., by varying the mean and standard deviation of the normal prior distribution) and observing the effect on the Bayes factor. <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> visualizes the robustness of the Bayes factor for changes across a range of values for µ ψ and σ ψ . The Bayes factor is highest for low σ ψ values and µ ψ ∼ 0.6. From looking at the heatmap we can deduce that our conclusion regarding the evidence for H + over H 0 is relatively consistent. The plot can be produced with:</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">Figure 7</formula><p>Bayes factor robustness plot. The highest Bayes factor is reached for a prior on psi with µ ψ ∼ 0.6 for the small example data set. Overall, the conclusion that there is moderate evidence for H + over H 0 seems robust across a large range of values for µ ψ and σ ψ . shows that after some initial fluctuations, and a tie after about 40 observations, the last 160 observations cause the probability for the alternative hypothesis to increase substantially.</p><p>The sequential analysis as well as the probability wheel can be plotted as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">Figure 8</formula><p>Posterior probabilities of the hypotheses. The green area visualizes the posterior probability of the alternative hypothesis. The grey area visualizes the posterior probability of the null hypothesis. Both hypotheses were assigned a probability of 0.5 before testing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>R&gt; prob_wheel(AB2)</head><p>R&gt; plot_sequential(AB2)</p><p>Having collected some evidence for a difference in effectiveness between the two versions, one might wish to then quantify this difference. To do so, estimation is required.</p><p>We can again use Bayes' rule as described for the 'common approach' above. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref> shows the prior and posterior distribution for the log odds ratio under the two-sided model H 1 , as produced via the plot_posterior function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">R&gt; plot_posterior(AB2, what = 'logor')</formula><p>The dotted line in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref> displays the prior distribution, the solid line displays the posterior distribution (with 95% central credible interval), and the posterior median and 95% central credible interval (CI) are displayed on top. For our fictional example, the plot indicates that, given that the log odds ratio is not exactly zero, it is 95% probable to lie between 0.027 and 1.124, where the posterior median is 0.576.</p><p>The posterior distributions for the two success probabilities can be inspected with:</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">R&gt; plot_posterior(AB2, what = 'p1p2')</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 9</head><p>The flow of posterior probability for H 0 and H + as a function of the number of observations across both fictional website versions. To showcase the different approaches to Bayesian A/B testing we carried out the analyses with two data sets. The first data set is a real data set that has been collected on an online learning platform. The second data set is fictitious. It serves the purpose to demonstrate the analyses with a data set that is very similar to data sets that result from conversion rate optimization efforts. We first report on the results that we acquired with the real data set. Afterwards, we will describe the analyses that we carried out with the second data set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Example 1: The Rekentuin Data Set Preregistration</head><p>The data has already been collected by Abe Hofman and colleagues on the Rekentuin website (data property of Oefenweb.nl) in 2019. To preregister our analyses we created data, carried out all analyses before receiving the real data, and stored the analysis scripts on our repository at the Open Science Framework (OSF). All preregistration   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 12</ref>). With the coins, the children can buy virtual awards and add them to their trophy cabinet. The better a given student performs, the more trophies can be collected. The prospect of earning trophies motivates the children to perform better at the different math problems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 11</head><p>Example of the Rekentuin landing page. The figure shows that the child has earned three crowns for the category 'optellen' (Dutch for 'summation').</p><p>In 2019, the developers of Rekentuin were facing the challenge that many children would repeatedly solve math problems they were already performing well on. To incentivise the children to improve other skills (i.e., play other games), the developers implemented a crown for the games that the children had already mastered <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 11</ref>). More precisely, the crowns were created with the ulterior motive to prompt the children to collect crowns on as many games as possible. The players could gain up to a maximum of three crowns for each game. Thus, to obtain a crown for every game category the children had to engage more frequently with games they played less often. However, the crowns did not have the desired effect -instead of decreasing the playtime on crown games, the playtime on these crown games increased.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 12</head><p>Example of a game in the Rekentuin web environment. The coins are displayed on the bottom right corner.</p><p>To induce the children to play other games, the developers constructed a less subtle manipulation: to take away the virtual reward (i.e., the coins) from the crown games. To test the effectiveness of this manipulation the Rekentuin developers designed an A/B test.</p><p>One-half of the children continued playing on an unchanged website (version A), whereas the other half could no longer earn coins for crown games (version B). The children playing version B were not notified of the change but had to discover the changes for themselves.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>We applied the two Bayesian A/B testing approaches outlined above to the Rekentuin data set. In doing so we followed the general procedures discussed above.</p><p>However, we used JASP for the 'odds ratio approach' analysis (JASP Team, 2020 As a dependent variable, we chose the last game the children played during the time of testing. We did so because we assumed that it will only become apparent after some time whether the children moved on to playing non-crown games. They might have only realized after some games that they do not receive any more coins for crown games.</p><p>Additionally, they might have hoped that the coins would reappear and therefore did not abandon their favourite game immediately. Thus, to obtain a binary variable, we noted for each player whether or not the last game played was a crown game.</p><p>We excluded players from the analyses according to two criteria. Firstly, players who did not play at least one crown game during the time of testing were excluded because they could not have experienced the experimental manipulation in version B. There were 8573 players in the data set who did not play at least one crown game during the testing interval. Secondly, we excluded 350 players who only played one crown game and it was their last game, because for these players we can not observe the potential influence of the manipulation on their playing behavior. In sum, we excluded 8923 players.</p><p>The question that needs to be answered is whether changing the incentive structure for crown games (i.e., removing the coins) had the desired effect. From a Bayesian perspective, we want to compare the directional hypothesis H + that children in version B</p><p>played more non-crown games against the null hypothesis H 0 that there is no difference in the amount of non-crown games between the two versions. For the 'common approach' we employed two uninformed beta distributions for the success probabilities of version A and B. For the 'odds ratio approach' we employed a truncated normal distribution with µ = 0 and σ 2 = 1 under the alternative hypothesis as there is a range of parameter values that seem plausible (see, for example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cameron et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Tang &amp; Hall, 1995)</ref>. Having the strong manipulation in mind that was implemented on the Rekentuin website it seems unlikely to us that the children in the experimental condition B played less non-crown games. We think that the data was encoded incorrectly and that the real nature of the data is reversed. We assume that either the dependent variable or the conditions are interchanged in the data set. For our analyses we therefore switched the conditions: players that were originally indicated to be in the control condition A are now treated as if they are in the experimental condition B and vice versa.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Descriptives</head><p>The 'Common Approach' <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 13</ref> displays the two independent posterior distributions. From <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 13</ref> we can see that version B's posterior distribution for the success probability assigns all mass to higher values of θ as compared to version A. This suggests that the success probability of the modified Rekentuin version is higher and that taking the coins away from the crown games had a positive impact on the amount of non-crown games that were being played. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 14</ref> indicates the conversion rate uplift. The distribution peaks at around 0.12, indicating that the most likely conversion increase equals 12%. Also, all posterior mass (i.e., 100% of the samples) is above zero. In other words, we can be 100% certain that version B is better than version A. Note that this statement assumes that it is equally</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 13</head><p>Independent posterior beta distributions of the success probabilities of playing a non-crown game. Version A corresponds to the unchanged Rekentuin website. Version B denotes the Rekentuin version where the players could not earn coins for crown games. The plot is produced by the bayesAB package. The analysis used two independent beta(1, 1) priors.</p><p>likely that the alterations in versions B had a positive or negative effect on the rate at which the children played non-crown games!</p><p>In addition to the bayesAB package output, we computed the posterior probability of the event θ non-crown B &gt; θ non-crown A using the formula reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Schmidt and Mørup (2019)</ref>. For the Rekentuin data P (θ B &gt; θ A ) = 1. The analytic calculation of the posterior distribution for the difference δ = θ non-crown B − θ non-crown A between the two independent beta distributions fails for this data set because the data set is too large. We did not use the normal approximation of the difference as it is imprecise. Instead, we calculated the posterior samples of the absolute risk under H 1 . <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 15</ref> plots the entire probability   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The 'Odds Ratio Approach'</head><p>The observed sample proportions of 0.806 for version B and 0.715 for version A suggest that the children in version B played more non-crown games as compared to version A. The Bayes factor BF +0 that assesses the evidence in favor of our hypothesis that the children in version B played more non-crown games equals 7.944e+14. This means that the data are several billion times more likely to occur under the alternative hypothesis H + than under the null hypothesis H 0 . In sum, the Bayes factor indicates extreme evidence for the alternative hypothesis (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Jeffreys, 1939;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lee &amp; Wagenmakers, 2013)</ref>.    Bayes factor robustness plot for the Rekentuin data.</p><p>hypothesis H 0 has correspondingly decreased from 0.5 to 0.000.</p><p>In sum, there is extreme evidence in favor of the alternative hypothesis. To complete the picture, we quantified the difference between the two Rekentuin versions by estimating the size of the log odds ratio. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 19</ref> shows the prior and posterior distribution for the log odds ratio under the two-sided model H 1 . The dotted line displays the prior distribution and the solid line displays the posterior distribution (with 95% central credible interval). The plot indicates that, given that the log odds ratio is not exactly zero, it is 95% probable to lie between 0.386 and 0.622, where the posterior median is 0.504.</p><p>It is important to remember, however, that these results only show because we reversed the assignment of the conditions in the data set. It remains open to investigate why the original data set has such an unexpected pattern. We think that there are two possibilities. As mentioned before the data could have been coded incorrectly; either the conditions or the dependent variable could have been switched. At the same time, we should not ignore the possibility that there are no errors in the data and that this is indeed the true nature of the data. It might be that the children actually enjoyed playing their</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 18</head><p>The flow of posterior probability for H 0 and H + as a function of the number of observations across both Rekentuin versions. The prior and posterior probabilities of the hypotheses are displayed on top.</p><p>favorite game without experiencing pressure (i.e., having to earn as much coins as possible).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional Analyses</head><p>We ran two independent Bayesian t-tests on the data set. The first t-test examined whether the children reallocated their time amongst the games. 6 Specifically, we compared the proportion of playtime that the children spent on playing crown games across the two versions. We hypothesized that the manipulation in version B would lead to a decrease in the amount of playtime spent on crown games per child. This analysis allows us to compare the A/B test analysis with an analysis of the same question that uses a different dependent variable and a different statistical procedure. The independent Bayesian t-test</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 19</head><p>Prior and posterior distribution of the log odds ratio under H 1 for the Rekentuin data set.</p><p>The median and the 95% credible interval of the posterior density for the Rekentuin data are shown in the top right corner.</p><p>comes to a similar conclusion as the A/B test analysis: The children in version B spent on average a smaller proportion of their playing time on crown games as compared to the children in version A (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref>). The data are 2.326e+11 times more likely under the alternative hypothesis H − . A Bayes factor of this size indicates extreme evidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lee &amp; Wagenmakers, 2013)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 20</ref> shows that the posterior distribution of the effect size under H 1 is concentrated near zero but has all mass below zero. The posterior median is -0.191 and the 95% CI ranges from -0.240 to -0.142. We can conclude that the children in   meaning that there is moderate evidence for the null hypothesis <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lee &amp; Wagenmakers, 2013)</ref>. We can see that the effect size is narrowly concentrated at zero in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 21</ref>. All told, the results of this t-test present moderate evidence for the claim that the manipulation in version B did not lead to a reduction in overall playing time.</p><p>In sum, there is strong evidence that removing the coins from crown games led children in version B to spent less time on crown games. Fortunately, this change in their playing behavior was not accompanied by a reduction in overall playing time. Note however that this pattern also only showed because we changed the allocation of the conditions.  purposes implement much subtler manipulations. In this section we describe an A/B test analysis with a more customary data set.</p><p>Consider the following fictitious scenario: an online marketing team wants to improve the click rate on a call-to-action button on their website's landing page. Therefore, they devise an A/B test. Half of the website visitors read "Try out our new product."</p><p>(further denoted as version A), and the other half reads "Test out our new product."</p><p>(further denoted as version B) when visiting the website. 7 The success of the website versions is measured by the rate at which website visitors click on the call-to-action button.</p><p>To demonstrate the analyses we use synthetic data. The R code for the data creation and the data as well as the analysis files can be found at https://osf.io/anvg2/. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 3</ref> depicts the number of clicks in either group. The conversion rate in version A From a Bayesian perspective, the company wants to assess the evidence in the data for H + that users in version B clicked more often as compared to H 0 that there is no difference between the two versions.</p><p>We will first present the results of the 'common approach' analysis and later contrast them with the results of the 'odds ratio approach.' The dependent variable of both analyses is the click rate, i.e. whether or not a given website visitor clicked on the call-to-action button (1 = click, 0 = no click).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The 'Common Approach'</head><p>We again used the bayesAB package in R to analyse the data according to the 'common approach' <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Portman, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">R Core Team, 2020)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 22a</ref> illustrates the two independent posterior distributions. We can see that version B's posterior distribution for the success probability assigns more mass to higher values of θ. This suggests that the success probability of the modified website version is higher and the alterations had a positive impact on the click rate. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 22b</ref> depicts the conversion rate uplift. The posterior distribution for the uplift peaks at around 0.125, indicating that the most likely conversion increase equals 12.5%. Also, most posterior mass (i.e., 99.9% of the samples) is above zero, indicating that we can be 99.9% certain that version B is better than version A.</p><p>The analytically calculated posterior probability of the event θ B &gt; θ A amounts to 0.999 <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Schmidt &amp; Mørup, 2019)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 23</ref> shows the posterior difference distribution δ.</p><p>The distribution peaks at about 0.02. A difference of this size is quite large for a conversion rate optimization endeavor. We calculated δ for this data set with the approach described in Appendix B. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 24</ref> plots the posterior mean of the difference between θ A and θ B as well as the 95% highest density interval (HDI) of the difference in a sequential manner. With increasing sample size, the HDI becomes more narrow. This indicates that the range of likely values for δ becomes smaller. We can see in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 24b</ref> that after some initial fluctuation, the posterior mean difference between the two success probabilities θ A and θ B settles between 0 and 0.05. The 'Odds Ratio Approach'</p><p>Before the data can be analysed according to the 'odds ratio approach', a prior distribution for the log odds ratio has to be specified. For this purpose it is important to note that the subtle manipulations of common A/B tests lead to very small effect sizes.</p><p>The effect size of website changes, i.e., the difference in conversion rates between the baseline version and its modification, is typically as small as 0.5% and less <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Berman et al., 2018)</ref>. This means that the analysis of such data requires an exceptionally narrow prior distribution that peaks at a value close to 0 as the shape of the prior distribution has to map the relative plausibility of parameter values.</p><p>For the present example we can compare the influence of different prior distributions on the analysis. Suppose that the online marketing team specifies three prior</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 23</head><p>The difference δ (i.e., θ B − θ A ) between the two independent beta distributions for the fictitious webshop example.</p><p>distributions: Most team members are inexperienced with conversion rate optimization.</p><p>Therefore they are indifferent about plausible values of the log odds ratio and prefer to use the commonly employed uninformed normal prior. The prior is however truncated as they expect a positive effect (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 25a</ref>). The team members with prior knowledge on A/B testing specify more narrow distributions that center around a value above zero. One team member is quite optimistic about the conversion rate increase in version B. He thinks that the odds ratio will be around 1.2 (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 25c</ref>). Another team member thinks this is too extreme. Her more conservative estimate is an odds ratio of 1.05 (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 25b</ref>). In sum, the data will be analysed with three priors: the indifferent prior with µ ψ = 0 and σ ψ = 1, the optimistic prior with µ ψ = 0.18 and σ ψ = 0.005, the conservative prior with µ ψ = 0.05 and σ ψ = 0.03.  We used the abtest package <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Gronau, 2019)</ref> in R (R Core Team, 2020) and JASP for the present analysis. Before estimating the effect, we evaluate the evidence presented by the data that there is indeed a difference between version A and B. Overall the data support the hypothesis that users in version B clicked more often as compared to users in version A. The data are approximately 11 times more likely under the alternative hypothesis H + than under the null hypothesis H 0 for the indifferent prior. They are ∼ 27 times more likely under the alternative hypothesis for the conservative prior, and ∼ 80 times more likely under H + for the optimistic prior. The influence of the prior on the Bayes factor can be explored more broadly with the Bayes factor robustness plot. This illustrates the risk of applying an uninformed prior distribution that assigns probability to unreasonable parameter values. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 26</ref> shows that the evidence is robust if the prior distribution utilizes reasonable µ ψ and σ ψ values. Hence, it should be reflected in the prior distribution if an effect can be anticipated to be very small.  prior to posterior is largest for the optimistic prior which is displayed in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 27c</ref>. For all three prior distributions the alternative hypothesis H + has a much higher posterior probability (&gt; 0.9) as compared to the null hypothesis. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 28</ref> plots the evidential trajectory for the three prior distributions. The evidence fluctuates a good deal for the first 10,000 observations for the analysis with the standard normal prior -in phases the data provide more evidence for H + and then again for H 0 . After a tie at 10,000 observation H + triumphs and the posterior probability of H + </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 25</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 26</head><p>Bayes factor robustness plot for the fictitious webshop data. Overall, the conclusion that there is strong evidence for H 1 over H 0 seems robust across a range of reasonable values for µ ψ and σ ψ . The evidence is not compelling if the analysis utilizes a very wide prior <ref type="bibr">(i.e.,</ref> for high values for σ ψ )</p><p>rises substantially while the posterior probability of H 0 decreases accordingly. By contrast, the sequential analysis with the conservative prior is unambiguous (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 28b</ref>). The posterior probability of H + dominates throughout all observations. The analysis with the optimistic prior produces a similar picture as the analysis with the standard normal prior (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 28c</ref>). The probability of H + increases sharply after some initial fluctuation and a tie at about 10,000 observations.</p><p>In sum, the data present strong to very strong evidence for the claim that the conversion rate is higher in version B <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lee &amp; Wagenmakers, 2013)</ref>. Knowing this, the online marketing team wants to assess the size of the effect.  indicates that the posterior median of the log odds ratio is 0.135 with a 95% credible interval (CI) ranging from 0.050 to 0.220 when using the standard normal prior. The middle panel of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 29</ref> displays the posterior distribution for the log odds ratio when using the conservative prior. The posterior distribution indicates that the effect is slightly bigger than expected under this prior. The distribution peaks at 0.072 and the 95% CI ranges from 0.029 to 0.116. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure 29c</ref> indicates that given the log odds ratio is not exactly zero, the posterior median is 0.179 when using the optimistic prior. The 95% CI ranges from 0.168 to 0.190. In fact, the optimistic prior is very similar to its corresponding posterior distribution of the log odds ratio.</p><p>Lastly, to compare the predictive performance of the three different models, the company calculates Bayes factors with the resulting marginal likelihoods. The comparison clarifies that the three models are very similar. The data are 1.5 times more likely under the conservative model than under the indifferent model. They are 4.5 times more likely under the optimistic than under the indifferent model. And the data are 2.9 times more likely under the optimistic than under the conservative model. In verbal terms, these Bayes factors correspond to 'anecdotal' or 'moderate' evidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lee &amp; Wagenmakers, 2013)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Concluding Comments</head><p>Data are an important resource for modern companies. The race is on in any market where lots of data is available and whoever learns fastest from their data will triumph <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Domingos, 2015)</ref>. However too many decision are made with a limited understanding of the statistical analysis in use. By knowing what a particular test does, businesses can be sure to understand the information they receive from their data and eventually to optimize what they care about.</p><p>With lots of data to go with it, Bayesian A/B testing is a tool that transforms data into knowledge. We showed that the Bayesian approach to A/B testing allows applicants to answer a wide array of questions that are relevant in the web development domain.</p><p>With our demonstrations we hope to inspire companies to use the Bayesian approach and</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 28</head><p>The flow of posterior probability for H 0 and H + as a function of the number of observations across both fictitious website versions.  to inform them on how to use it to their competitive advantage.</p><p>Especially the 'odds ratio approach' fulfills the general desiderata that an A/B test should meet: The approach allows practitioners to obtain evidence in favor of the null hypothesis, to monitor the evidence as the data accumulate, and to take prior/expert knowledge into account. The benefits of a test that fulfills these three desiderata are manifold. For a start it affords companies with economicalness. That is because the sequential analysis prevents a waste of resources -the testing can be stopped as soon as the evidence is compelling. This also means that the company can make decisions much quicker since they do not have to stick to some predefined sampling plan. Another advantage is that the 'odds ratio approach' allows practitioners to test the influence of different priors and examine how well those predict the data. In the long run, companies can build a database of prior distributions where they incorporate what was learned from previous data; paying tribute to Lindley's axiom "today's posterior is tomorrow's prior" <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Lindley, 1972)</ref>. Lastly, being able to obtain evidence in favor of the null hypothesis enables practitioners to ascertain that there is truly no difference between two website versions. This comes in handy whenever practitioners want to ensure that, for example, technical changes on a website did not hamper website visitor's experience. Moreover is it valuable to know if a certain implementation does not have the desired effect. Knowing for sure that there is no effect allows practitioners to stop the ongoing experiment in good conscience and thereby save money, time and other resources.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Formulae</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Schmidt and Mørup, 2019</head><p>Let T denote a 2 × 2 contingency table with fixed column total n 1 and n 2 ,</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">T =     y1 y2 n1 − y1 n2 − y2     .</formula><p>The posterior probability of the event P (θ 1 &gt; θ 2 |T ) is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">P (θ 1 &gt; θ 2 |T ) = Z(α 1 , β 1 , α 2 , β 2 ) B(α 1 , β 1 )B(α 2 , β 2 )</formula><p>where B(α, β) is the Beta function. The normalizing constant Z is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">Z(α 1 , β 1 , α 2 , β 2 ) = Γ(α 1 + α 2 )Γ(β 1 + β 2 ) β 1 α 2 Γ(α 1 + β 1 + α 2 + β 2 − 1) 3 F 2 1, 1 − α 1 , 1 − β 2 β 1 + 1, α 2 + 1 ; 1</formula><p>where 3 F 2 is the generalized hypergeometric function.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pham-Gia et al., 1993</head><p>Let p i ∼ beta(α i , β i ), i = 1, 2, be independent variables. Then p = p 1 − p 2 has the following density:</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">For 0 &lt; p ≤ 1, f (p) = B(α 2 , β 1 )p β 1 +β 2 −1 (1 − p) α 2 +β 1 −1 F 1 (β 1 , α 1 + β 1 + α 2 + β 2 − 2, 1 − α 1 ; β 1 + α 2 ;</formula><p>(1 − p), 1 − p 2 )/A, and for −1 ≤ p &lt; 0 f (p) = B(α 1 , β 2 )(−p) β 1 +β 2 −1 (1+p) α 1 +β 2 −1 F 1 (β 2 , 1−α 2 , α 1 +α 2 +β 1 +β 2 −2; α 1 +β 2 ; 1−p 2 , 1+p)/A, where A = B(α 1 , β 1 )B(α 2 , β 2 ).</p><p>Moreover, if α 1 + α 2 &gt; 1 and β 1 + β 2 &gt; 1 we have:</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">f (0) = B(α 1 + α 2 − 1, β 1 + β 2 − 1)/A BAYESIAN A/B TESTING 51</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Normal Approximation of Beta Difference</head><p>The Beta(α, β) function can be approximated by the Normal distribution when α and β are sufficiently large:</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">Beta(α, β)=Normal α α + β , αβ (α + β) 2 (α + β + 1)</formula><p>The distribution of the difference between two normally distributed variables</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">X ∼ N (µ X , σ 2 X ) and Y ∼ N (µ Y , σ 2 Y )</formula><p>is given by another Normal distribution</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">δ(X − Y ) ∼ N (µ X − µ Y , σ 2 X + σ 2 Y )</formula><p>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>On Calculating the Difference between Two Independent Beta Distributions</head><p>We considered three ways of inspecting the difference between the two versions:</p><p>analytically calculating it, approximating it with a normal distribution, or using the 'odds ratio approach.' We would suggest that the 'odds ratio approach' is most useful whenever practitioners are interested in testing and quantifying the difference between two versions.</p><p>However, in practice, the 'odds ratio approach' is virtually never used. It is therefore beneficial to review which of the remaining methods is most useful to quantify this difference. In addition to using the formula by <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Pham-Gia et al. (1993)</ref> or the normal approximation, there is another possibility to calculate P (δ &gt; 0): inspecting the posterior probability of H + when comparing H + and H − . While this is exactly what the 'common approach' does -gauging whether there is either a positive or a negative effect -we do not receive the posterior probability of the hypotheses when using the bayesAB package. This is because of the approach's strong focus on estimation. It is however easy to acquire the probability with the abtest package:</p><p>R&gt; plus.minus &lt;-c(0, 1/2, 1/2, 0) R&gt; names(plus.minus) &lt;-c("H1", "H+", "H-", "H0") R&gt; AB3 &lt;-ab_test(conversion, prior_prob = plus.minus) R&gt; AB3$post_prob <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure B1a</ref> now visualises the sequential analysis of P (δ &gt; 0) for the three different methods. While the analytic calculation of the difference is the most accurate, it fails for large values of α and β. For the present example, we cannot calculate P (δ &gt; 0) with the exact approach from n ≈ 100. This is unfortunate as websites are often visited by a large number of people.</p><p>As mentioned before, the normal approximation can be used as an alternative to the analytical solution. Specifically, the independent posterior beta distributions can be</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure B1</head><p>Sequential analysis of P(δ &gt; 0). approximated by two normal distributions for sufficiently large α and β values. Therefore, α and β are used to calculate the parameters µ and σ of the normal distributions, which then determine the distribution of δ (Appendix A).</p><p>However, both <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure B1a</ref> and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure B1b</ref> show that the approximation is rather crude. A better way to calculate δ is to inspect the posterior probability of the hypothesis that the difference is positive rather than negative, that is, compare H + versus H − . To examine the entire probability distribution of the difference we can use:</p><p>R&gt; AB4 &lt;-ab_test(conversion, prior_prob = plus.minus, + posterior = T, nsamples = 1000000)</p><p>R&gt; plot(density(AB4$post$Hplus$arisk))</p><p>The code plots the posterior samples of the absolute risk under H + (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure B2</ref>).</p><p>Comparing <ref type="figure" target="#fig_16">Figure B2</ref> and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_30">Figure 4a</ref> as well as <ref type="figure" target="#fig_21">Figure 4b</ref> confirms that this is a better method to calculate the exact difference as compared to the normal approximation.</p><p>As mentioned in the main text, it is also possible to monitor the difference over time with this technique. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 5</ref> plots the sequential analysis of the posterior mean of the absolute risk, that is, the difference in success probabilities θ B − θ A . The data points for the plot can be produced with the following code: Posterior distribution of the absolute risk under H + . The absolute risk can be used to inspect the difference between the success probabilities of the two website versions.</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">R&gt;</formula></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 A</head><label>1</label><figDesc>/B testing procedure for conversion rate optimization. Subdivisions of website visitors are redirected to either of two website versions. A variable of interest is measured and indicated as the conversion rate (number of conversions/total number of website visitors).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Normal approximation of the difference between two independent beta distributions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Sequential analysis of the difference between the success probabilities (i.e., θA − θ B ) of the two website versions. The orange line plots the posterior mean of the absolute risk. The grey area visualizes the width of the highest density interval as a function of sample size n.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>prior_par &lt;-elicit_prior(q = c(-1.95, 0, 1.95), + prob = c(.025, .5, .975), + what = 'logor') The observed success proportions of 35/100 for version A and 50/100 for version B suggest an enhanced click rate in version B as compared to version A. Whether this difference is statistically convincing needs to be assessed with a hypothesis test, for which we use the ab_test function. This function requires the data, parameter priors, and prior model probabilities. For the present example, we set the prior probabilities of H + and H 0 to 0.5: R&gt; library(abtest) R&gt; conversion &lt;-as.list(read.csv2("example_data2.csv")[-1,-1])R&gt; AB2 &lt;-ab_test(conversion, prior_par, prior_prob = c(0, 0.5, 0, 0.5))</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 8</head><label>8</label><figDesc>visualizes the posterior probabilities of the hypotheses as a probability wheel. The posterior probability of H + indicates that the data have increased the plausibility of the hypothesis from 0.5 to 0.823 while the posterior plausibility of H 0 has correspondingly decreased from 0.5 to 0.177.The sequential analysis tracks the evidence in chronological order.Figure 9plots the posterior probability of either hypothesis as a function of the number of observations. It</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 10</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Prior and posterior distribution of the log odds ratio under H 1 . The median and the 95% credible interval of the posterior density are shown in the top right corner. materials as well as the real data are available on the OSF repository at https://osf.io/anvg2/. Neither author of the present document has inspected the real data before the preregistration was finished. Conducting the analyses this way helped us avoid cognitive biases and other scientifically undesirable self-deception<ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Munafò et al., 2017)</ref>. In the next section, we describe the Rekentuin data set.The Rekentuin Data SetRekentuin is a tutoring website where children can playfully improve their mathematical skills with challenging online games. The children that are active on the Rekentuin website are Dutch elementary school children between the ages of 4 and 12. During the testing interval from the 22 nd of January 2019 to the 5 th of February 2019 15,322 children were active on Rekentuin.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 11</head><label>11</label><figDesc>shows a screenshot of the Rekentuin landing page. The basic principle is that by solving small math problems the children can earn coins (see the bottom right corner of</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 14</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Histogram of the conversion rate uplift from version A to version B of the Rekentuinwebsite. The conversion rate indicates the proportion of players that played a non-crown game. The uplift is calculated by dividing the difference in conversion by the conversion in A. The plot is produced by the bayesAB package. distribution of the difference δ. The distribution is very narrow and it peaks at around 0.1 which means that players in version B played more non-crown games as compared to players in version A.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 16</head><label>16</label><figDesc>plots the sequential analysis of the posterior mean of the difference between θ non-crown A and θ non-crown B as well as the 95% highest density interval (HDI) of the difference. After some initial fluctuation, the posterior mean difference between θ non-crown A and θ non-crown B settles at ∼ 0.1 while the HDI becomes more narrow with increasing sample size. The range of likely values for δ eventually spans from approximately 0.075 to 0.125.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 15</head><label>15</label><figDesc>Posterior distribution of the difference δ = θ non-crown B − θ non-crown A for the proportion of non-crown games between the two Rekentuin website versions. Children in version B -the modified website version -played more non-crown games as compared to children playing on the website version A.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 17</head><label>17</label><figDesc>visualizes the dependency of the Bayes factor on the prior distribution on</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Figure 16</head><label>16</label><figDesc>Sequential analysis of the difference between the success probabilities (i.e.,θ non-crown B − θ non-crown A ) of the two Rekentuin versions. The orange line plots the posterior mean of the absolute risk. The grey area visualizes the width of the highest density interval as a function of sample size n. ψ by varying the mean µ ψ and standard deviation σ ψ of the normal prior distribution.From looking at the heatmap we can conclude that the Bayes factor is robust. The data indicate extreme evidence across a range of different values for the prior distribution on ψ.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 18</head><label>18</label><figDesc>tracks the evidence for either hypothesis in a chronological order. It shows that the evidence for H + is overwhelming from 1000 observations on. The posterior probabilities of the hypotheses are also shown as a probability wheel on the top ofFigure 18. The green area visualizes the posterior probability of the alternative hypothesis.The grey area visualizes the posterior probability of the null hypothesis. The data have increased the plausibility of H + from 0.5 to 1 while the posterior plausibility of the null</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Figure 17</head><label>17</label><figDesc>Figure 17</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>version B -the modified Rekentuin version -spent less of their time on Rekentuin playing crown games as compared to the children in version A -the original Rekentuin version.The second t-test examined whether the reallocation of time was accompanied by a reduction of overall playing time. We hypothesized that the implemented manipulation may have had an unintended and undesirable effect: the children may have reallocated their time from crown games to non-crown games, but, as a consequence, they did not</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head>Example 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>The Fictional WebshopThe Rekentuin data is not the most representative example of an A/B test. That is because the manipulation that was implemented on the website targeted the children's underlying motivation to play the games. Common A/B tests for web development</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_17"><head>Figure 20</head><label>20</label><figDesc>Prior and posterior distribution of the effect size for the proportion of playtime spent on crown games under H 1 for the Rekentuin data. The median and the 95% credible interval of the posterior density are shown in the top right corner.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>Figure 21</head><label>21</label><figDesc>Prior and posterior distribution of the effect size for the summed up playing time under H 1 for the Rekentuin data. The median and the 95% credible interval of the posterior density are shown in the top right corner. equals 0.113 and 0.128 in version B. The company now wants to determine whether and to what extent the observed sample difference in proportions translates to the population.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head>Figure 22 ( a )</head><label>22a</label><figDesc>Independent posterior beta distributions of the success probabilities for version A and B. The plot is produced by the bayesAB package with the fictional webshop data. The analysis used two independent beta(1, 1) priors. (b) Histogram of the conversion rate uplift from version A to version B. The uplift is calculated by dividing the difference in conversion by the conversion in A. The plot is produced by the bayesAB package.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head>Figure 24</head><label>24</label><figDesc>Sequential analysis of the difference θ B − θA of the two fictitious webshop versions. The orange line plots the posterior mean of the absolute risk. The grey area visualizes the width of the highest density interval as a function of sample size n. (a) Sequential analysis of the difference. For a close-up seeFigure 24b</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_21"><head>( b )</head><label>b</label><figDesc>This plot shows the same as the plot on the left, but the limits of the y-axis are more narrow.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_22"><head>Figure 26</head><label>26</label><figDesc>plots the corresponding heatmap. Varying the standard deviation σ ψ of the prior distribution on ψ shows that the BF 10 changes from very strong to moderate evidence.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_23"><head>Figure 27</head><label>27</label><figDesc>plots the probability wheels of the hypotheses. The most left plot illustrates the probabilities of the hypotheses for the indifferent (standard normal) prior.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_24"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>27b shows the change of probability for the conservative prior. The change from</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_26"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 29displays the prior and posterior distribution for the log odds ratio using the three different priors. The prior distribution is plotted as a dotted line and the posterior distribution as a solid line (with 95% central credible interval). Under the assumption that the effect is non-zero,Figure 29a</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_27"><head>Figure 27</head><label>27</label><figDesc>Probabilities of the hypotheses after taking the fictitious webshop data into account. The green area visualizes the posterior probability of the alternative hypothesis. The grey area visualizes the posterior probability of the null hypothesis. Both hypotheses were assigned a probability of 0.5 before testing.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_28"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 29</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_29"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The conservative prior. (c) The optimistic prior.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_30"><head>( a )</head><label>a</label><figDesc>Sequential analysis of the probability that θ B is larger than θ A for N = 200. The striped line visualizes the exact difference. Note that the calculations break down for n ≈ 70 (b) Sequential analysis of P(δ &gt; 0) for a larger data set of N = 20000. The calculation of the exact difference quickly breaks down.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_31"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>library(HDInterval) R&gt; CI.upper &lt;-numeric(length(conversion$n1)) R&gt; CI.lower &lt;-numeric(length(conversion$n1)) R&gt; mean.ar &lt;-numeric(length(conversion$n1)) R&gt; for(i in 2:length(conversion$n1)){ + conversion1 &lt;-as.list(as.data.frame(conversion)[2:i,]) + plus.minus &lt;-c(0, 1/2, 1/2, 0) + names(plus.minus) &lt;-c("H1", "H+", "H-", "H0") + AB5 &lt;-ab_test(conversion1, prior_prob = plus.minus, + posterior = T, nsamples = 10000) + CI.upper[i] &lt;-as.numeric(hdi(AB5$post$H1$arisk)[1]) + CI.lower[i] &lt;-as.numeric(hdi(AB5$post$H1$arisk)[2]) + mean.ar[i] &lt;-mean(AB5$post$H1$arisk) } Figure B2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). JASP is an easy to use, free, open-source graphical program for statistical analysis. The program uses the abtest package in R as a back end. 5</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1 Table 1</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Descriptives of the original Rekentuin data. Apparently children in version A played morenon-crown games. The conditions (i.e. A and B) were switched for the statistical analyses as this data pattern seems unlikely.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Counts Total Proportion</cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell>2596 3221</cell><cell>0.806</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell>2272 3178</cell><cell>0.715</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">version A played more non-crown games.</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>is a 2 × 2 table of the Rekentuin data where A refers to the control condition and B to the experimental condition. The table indicates the proportion of children that played a non-crown game as their last game. It seems as if the children in</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Descriptives of the proportion of playtime that was spent on crown games and the summed up playing time (in seconds) in the two Rekentuin versions.</figDesc><table><row><cell>95% Credible Interval</cell></row></table><note>enjoy playing on the website as much as before and therefore spent less time on Rekentuin overall. To test this conjecture we compared how much time (in seconds) the children spent on Rekentuin altogether, i.e., summed up playtime duration, across the two versions.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>lists the descriptive statistics for this test. The Bayes factor BF 0− equals ∼ 4;</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fourfold table indicating the amount of clicks on each webshop version. We used synthetic data for this analysis.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Clicked on button</cell></row><row><cell>Condition</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>No</cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell cols="2">1131 8869</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell cols="2">1275 8725</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">The posterior distributions are available analytically, so at this point the rbeta function is not needed; it will become relevant once we start to investigate the posterior distribution for the difference between θ A and θ B .</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Appendix A contains the formulas from<ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Schmidt and Mørup (2019)</ref> and<ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Pham-Gia et al. (1993)</ref>, as well as the formulas for the normal approximation.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">We use the terms 'model' and 'hypothesis' interchangeably.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">For a detailed explanation on how to conduct the analyses in JASP read https://jasp-stats.org/2020/01/14/how-a-simple-bayesian-test-could-have-rescued-a-famous-clinical-trial/</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6">The time variable in the Rekentuin data set is only an approximation of the children's playing time. We calculated the playing time by subtracting the starting time for consecutive games. Calculated playing times above 600 seconds were changed to NA because we assumed that in that case the children had left the game to return another day.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">This example was inspired by a real conversion rate optimization project at https://blog.optimizely.com/2011/06/08/optimizely-increases-homepage-conversion-rate-by-29/</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A</head><p>Appendix B</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistics notes: Absence of evidence is not evidence of absence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Altman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BMJ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7003</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">485</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">P-hacking and false discovery in A/B testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Berman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Pekelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Van Den Bulte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://ssrn.com/abstract=3204791" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian approach to landing page testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bondarenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kravchenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Problems of Applied Mathematics and Mathematical Modeling</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pervasive negative effects of rewards on intrinsic motivation: The myth continues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cameron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Banko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Pierce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Behavior Analyst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="44" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Objective bayesian two sample hypothesis testing for online controlled experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW&apos;15 companion: Proceedings of the 24th international conference on world wide web</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Continuous monitoring of A/B tests without pain: Optional stopping in bayesian testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2016 IEEE international conference on data science and advanced analytics (DSAA)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The master algorithm: How the quest for the ultimate learning machine will remake our world</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Domingos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>Basic Books</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian data analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Carlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Dunson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vehtari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>CRC press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Most winning A/B test results are illusory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Goodson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://tinyurl.com/y9g3m9bq" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Whitepaper Qubit</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Abtest: Bayesian A/B testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Gronau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=abtest" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Gronau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Raj K N</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Informed Bayesian inference for the A/B test, arXiv 1905.02068</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An examination of antecedents of conversion rates of e-commerce retailers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Gudigantala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bicen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Research Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="114" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The 2×2 table: A discussion from a Bayesian viewpoint</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Howard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistical Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="367" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">JASP (Version 0.13)[Computer software</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Jasp Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://jasp-stats.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jeffreys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Theory of probability</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Oxford, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1939" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>1st ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jeffreys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Theory of probability</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Oxford, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3rd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical approaches to interim monitoring of medical trials: A review and commentary</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Jennison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Turnbull</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistical Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="317" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The online display ad effectiveness funnel &amp; carryover: Lessons from 432 field experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Nubbemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kamalbasha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J A</forename><surname>Eugster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>arXiv 2003.02769</idno>
		<title level="m">Bayesian A/B testing for business decisions</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayes factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Raftery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="773" to="795" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approximate Bayes factors and orthogonal parameters, with application to testing equality of two binomial proportions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Vaidyanathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Royal Statistical Society, Series B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="144" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian estimation supersedes the t test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kruschke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">142</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="573" to="603" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian cognitive modeling: A practical course</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian statistics, a review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lindley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<pubPlace>Philadelphia (PA), SIAM</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The analysis of experimental data: The appreciation of tea and wine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lindley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Teaching statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing the equality of two independent binomial proportions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Little</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Statistician</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Experiment!: Website conversion rate optimization with A/B and multivariate testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Mcfarland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<pubPlace>Berkeley, CA, New Riders</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A manifesto for reproducible science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Munafò</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nosek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Bishop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Button</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Sert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Simonsohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ware</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Ioannidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What is a good conversion rate? The answer might surprise you</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.crazyegg.com/blog/what-is-good-conversion-rate/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian analysis of the difference of two proportions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pham-Gia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Turkkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Eng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications in Statistics-Theory and Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1755" to="1771" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesab: Fast Bayesian methods for A/B testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Portman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/bayesAB/index.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.R-project.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<pubPlace>Vienna, Austria</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Conversion optimization: The art and science of converting prospects to customers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Saleh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shukairy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<pubPlace>Sebastopol (CA), O&apos;Reilly Media, Inc</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient computation for Bayesian comparison of two proportions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mørup</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Statistics &amp; Probability Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">145</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What is Bayesian statistics?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<publisher>VWO Knowledge Base</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian A/B testing at VWO. Whitepaper, Visual Website Optimizer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Stucchio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The overjustification effect: A meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-H</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="365" to="404" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An in-class demonstration of Bayesian inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Van Doorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Matzke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology Learning &amp; Teaching</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="45" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A practical solution to the pervasive problems of p values</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="779" to="804" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian inference for psychology. Part I: Theoretical advantages and practical ramifications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marsman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Jamil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Love</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Selker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Gronau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Šmıra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Epskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian benefits for the pragmatic researcher</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E.-J</forename><surname>Wagenmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Morey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Directions in Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="176" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Bayes factors to test hypotheses in developmental research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bååth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Philipp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Research in Human Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="337" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On certain fundamental principles of scientific inquiry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wrinch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jeffreys</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Magazine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="369" to="390" />
			<date type="published" when="1921" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
