<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Promoting erroneous divergent opinions increases the wisdom of crowds</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Federico</forename><surname>Barrera Lermarchand</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratorio de Neurociencia</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Torcuato Di Tella</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Buenos Aires</settlement>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">National Scientific and Technical Research Council (CONICET)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Buenos Aires</settlement>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Departamento de Física</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Buenos Aires</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pablo</forename><surname>Balenzuela</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">National Scientific and Technical Research Council (CONICET)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Buenos Aires</settlement>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Departamento de Física</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Buenos Aires</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bahador</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Department of General Psychology and Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Crowd Cognition Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ludwig Maximilian University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Royal Holloway University of London</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Centre for Adaptive Rationality</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Human Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ophelia</forename><surname>Deroy</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Munich Centre for Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ludwig Maximilian University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Institute of Philosophy</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Advanced Study</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of London</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff8">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Philosophy</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ludwig Maximilian University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joaquin</forename><surname>Navajas</surname></persName>
							<email>joaquin.navajas@utdt.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratorio de Neurociencia</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Torcuato Di Tella</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Buenos Aires</settlement>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">National Scientific and Technical Research Council (CONICET)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Buenos Aires</settlement>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff9">
								<orgName type="department">Escuela de Negocios</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Torcuato Di Tella</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Buenos Aires</settlement>
									<country key="AR">Argentina</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Promoting erroneous divergent opinions increases the wisdom of crowds</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:13+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>wisdom of crowds</term>
					<term>collective intelligence</term>
					<term>diversity</term>
					<term>anchoring</term>
					<term>extremization</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The aggregation of many lay judgements generates surprisingly accurate estimates. This phenomenon, called the &quot;wisdom of crowds&quot;, has been demonstrated in domains such as medical decision making and financial forecasting. Previous research identified two factors driving this effect: the accuracy of individual assessments and the diversity of opinions. Most available strategies to enhance the wisdom of crowds have focused on improving individual accuracy while neglecting the potential of increasing opinion diversity. Here, we study a complementary approach to reduce collective error by promoting erroneous divergent opinions. This strategy proposes to anchor half of the crowd to a small value and the other half to a large value before eliciting and averaging all estimates. Consistent with our mathematical modeling, four experiments (N=1362 adults) demonstrate that this method is effective for estimation and forecasting tasks. Beyond practical implications, these findings offer new theoretical insights into the epistemic value of collective decision making.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>The aggregation of many lay estimates often outperforms individual expert judgements <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(De Condorcet, 1785;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Galton, 1907)</ref>. This phenomenon, popularly known as the "wisdom of crowds" <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Surowiecki, 2005)</ref>, has been applied to a wide range of problems such as improving medical diagnoses <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Kurvers et al., 2016)</ref>, forecasting geopolitical events <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Mellers et al., 2014)</ref>, predicting financial markets <ref type="bibr">(Ray, 2010)</ref>, reverseengineering the smell of molecules <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Keller et al., 2017)</ref>, and fact-checking news <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Allen, 2021)</ref>, among many others. Given its practical relevance, understanding the conditions under which crowds produce accurate estimates has become a relevant issue in the psychological sciences <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Kameda, Toyokawa, &amp; Tindale, 2022;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Karachiwalla &amp; Pinkow, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Navajas et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kao &amp; Couzin, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>One important driver of collective accuracy is the diversity of opinions in the crowd <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Hong &amp; Page, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Page, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Becker, Porter &amp; Centola, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Shi et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Jönsson, Hahn &amp; Olsson, 2015)</ref>. A simple intuition underlies this claim: when crowds produce diverse estimates, it is likely that some individuals will underestimate the correct answer, while others will overestimate it. Therefore, the more diverse the crowd, the higher the chance that individual errors will cancel out in the aggregation process. More formally, the "Diversity Prediction Theorem" <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Page, 2007)</ref> states that the crowd's error (Ε) can be expressed as the mean individual error (ε) minus the crowd's predictive diversity (δ, also known as the population variance):</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">= − [1]</formula><p>One implication of this mathematical identity (proof can be found in Supplementary Information) is that, in principle, the crowd's accuracy could be increased either by reducing the individual error (ε) or, alternatively, by increasing the predictive diversity (δ). However, while these two strategies are equally valid in theory, most available studies aiming at increasing the wisdom of crowds have exclusively focused on reducing ε while neglecting the potential of increasing δ.</p><p>For example, previous studies have proposed aggregating information from "select" crowds composed by individuals who are more accurate across estimation problems <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Mannes, Soll &amp; Larrick, 2014)</ref>. Other studies have shown that individual error can be reduced by counteracting individual biases <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kao et al., 2018)</ref> or by exposing individuals to social information <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Jayles et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Frey &amp; Van de Rijt, 2021;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Madirolas &amp; de Polavieja, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Lorenz et al., 2011)</ref>. A notable exception to this tendency demonstrated that collective accuracy can be increased by enhancing cognitive-process diversity <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Keck and Tang, 2020)</ref>, a construct which is different from predictive diversity. However, even in that case, it remains unclear whether the method actually increased opinion diversity, reduced mean individual error, or both. A few other works have focused on diversity, but in less direct ways. For example, a previous paper performed secondary analyses to evaluate increases in diversity through the lens of Equation [1], but without directly manipulating diversity or individual accuracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Nobre &amp; Fontanari, 2020)</ref>. Similarly, the "crowd within"</p><p>phenomenon <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Vul &amp; Pashler, 2008)</ref>, where experimenters ask participants to produce more than one estimate, rely on the idea of increasing in diversity within individuals. However, whether and how this procedure increases population diversity remains unknown.</p><p>Showing that it is possible to decrease collective error merely by increasing predictive diversity is nontrivial for several reasons. First, it would demonstrate that there are processes that simultaneously increase individual error and collective accuracy. Second, from a practical standpoint, it would provide practitioners with a novel approach to increase collective estimation accuracy. Third, given that the wisdom of crowds has been previously interpreted as empirical evidence for the epistemic value of democratic judgements, this putative dissociation between individual and collective accuracy should mitigate concerns about the increase of misinformed voters in recent elections.</p><p>Put together, one converges to a counterintuitive, albeit somewhat uncomfortable possibility: if collective error is reduced by increasing diversity, this would imply that the wisdom of crowds may be enhanced by persuading individuals to adopt erroneous divergent opinions. In this paper, we present theoretical simulations and empirical evidence for this claim. We introduce a new approach to increase collective accuracy by boosting the crowd's predictive diversity at the expense of reducing individual accuracy, even when the truth is completely unknown and unavailable, including to the experimenters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Increasing the Wisdom of Crowds through Extremization</head><p>We propose to promote the adoption of extreme estimates, and therefore to increase diversity, by means of a cognitive bias known as the anchoring effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Tversky &amp; Kahneman, 1974)</ref>. The proposed method consists in anchoring one half of the crowd to a small value ("low anchor") and the other half to a large value ("high anchor"), and then averaging all estimates. We hypothesized that this technique should lead to an increase in the predictive diversity that surpasses the increase in mean individual error, thus leading to lower collective error. Using a simple mathematical model, we first demonstrated that this method is expected to enhance collective accuracy across a wide range of parameters. We then empirically tested the procedure across four different experiments and showed that it indeed leads to a substantial reduction of collective error.</p><p>Let us consider the scenario where someone needs to estimate a numerical variable that is unknown to them; for example, the height of the Eiffel Tower. Based on the wisdom-of-crowds effect, one could obtain an approximate value by asking a large number of individuals to provide an estimate. Then, to estimate the height of the Eiffel Tower, the person would aggregate these values, for example, by averaging them <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig.   1A)</ref>. In this work, we propose an alternative approach that consists in dividing the crowd into two halves and extremizing opinions in opposite directions <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 1B)</ref>. We suggest doing so by using the anchoring effect: before estimating the relevant variable, individuals are first asked to consider either an extremely low or high value. In the previous example, half of the individuals would be asked to consider if the height of the Eiffel Tower is greater or less than 10 meters (low anchor, ) and the other half, if it is greater or less than 1000 meters (high anchor, ). After providing a categorical answer to this initial question, all individuals would then be asked to provide their best-guess estimate. An extensive literature has shown that these estimates should then be consistently biased towards the initially considered values <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Furnham &amp; Boo, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Röseler et al., 2022)</ref>. Because these anchors are extreme in opposite directions, this procedure should extremize the estimates produced by the crowd as a whole, leading to an increase in predictive diversity. We therefore propose to average all numbers, across both halves of the crowd.</p><p>While this procedure requires pre-defining two extreme values that will be used as anchors, the strategy does not require knowing the correct answer. However, reasonably, its accuracy will depend on the specific choice of anchors. Therefore, to understand better the conditions under which the proposed approach is expected to increase collective accuracy, we developed a simple mathematical model of the anchoring effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model</head><p>We consider a set of individuals who, being asked to estimate the variable , produce a distribution of values with mean . The model assumes that, when those individuals are anchored to a low value , they produce a set of estimates with a different mean</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">= + (1 − ) ,<label>[2]</label></formula><p>where 0 ≤ ≤ 1 is an anchoring weight reflecting the strength of the anchoring procedure given by the anchor . Similarly, a population anchored to a high value would produce a distribution of estimates given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">= + (1 − ) ,<label>[3]</label></formula><p>where 0 ≤ ≤ 1 is the corresponding anchoring weight given by anchor . diversity. However, the increase in individual error (left panel) is smaller than the increase in predictive diversity (right panel), resulting in an overall reduction in collective error ("c" represents the control group, and "x" the extremized crowd).</p><p>Eq.</p><p>[2] and [3] imply that the anchored mean (either low or high) is a weighted average of the anchor and the mean of the original distribution of values µ. Following a variety of empirical findings linking the anchoring effect to the plausibility of the anchor <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Mussweiler &amp; Strack, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">Wegener et al., 2001)</ref>, we</p><p>propose that the weights are given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">= 0 − | − | [4]</formula><p>where indicates whether the weight corresponds to the low or high anchor ( or , respectively) and</p><p>0 is a parameter reflecting the anchoring weight when individuals are anchored to the correct value .</p><p>The parameter is an "inverse temperature" encoding the sensitivity of the individuals to the distance between the anchor and . Thus, the value of modulates the strength of the "anchoring extremeness effect" <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Röseler et al., 2022)</ref>.</p><p>In this work, we propose averaging estimates from two populations of individuals, each of which is anchored to either a low or a high value ( or ). Assuming both populations are equally sized, we can estimate the mean estimates from both populations as</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">= + 2 [5]</formula><p>Simulations (for a set of parameters, with =324, =250, =10, =1000, 0 =1, and β=0.0017) show that this model is expected to produce a reduction in collective error <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 1C)</ref>. This increase in collective accuracy is due to an increase in diversity that surpassed the observed reduction in individual accuracy <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 1D)</ref>. The combination of increased diversity accompanied by a reduction in individual accuracy is a general tradeoff appearing under different model specifications <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. S1)</ref>.</p><p>The method implicitly assumes that it is possible to select anchors in a way in which the correct value will be underestimated by the low anchor and overestimated by the high anchor. However, meeting this condition is neither sufficient nor necessary. For example, the method should also work when both anchors have the opposite bias than the non-anchored responses. Therefore, to understand the conditions under which the method is expected to work, we performed a fine-grained model-based analysis.</p><p>Analytically, we found that the key variable determining the success of the approach is the mid-point of the anchors, defined as ̅ = + 2</p><p>. Following a simple mathematical procedure (for details, see</p><p>Supplementary Information), we found that the range (∆) of ̅ values where the method outperforms the wisdom of crowds is</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">∆= 4| − | + [6]</formula><p>The expression derived in Eq.</p><p>[6] implies that the range of values where the method outperforms the wisdom of crowds is always equal to or larger than two times the collective error. This can be shown by examining two opposite extreme scenarios. If the sensitivity is small (i.e., when the anchoring procedure does not depend on the distance between the anchor and the truth), the range of values where the method outperforms the wisdom of crowds converges to, at the very least, twice the collective error (i.e., if → 0, then → 0 , and therefore ∆→</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">2| − | 0</formula><p>). In the opposite case, when the sensitivity is large (i.e., when the anchoring effect is stronger as anchors become closer to the correct answer), then this method is always better than the wisdom of crowds (i.e., if → ∞, then → 0, and thus ∆→ ∞). To evaluate empirically the effectiveness of the proposed method, we performed four experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1: Estimation of unbounded quantities Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants and Questions</head><p>In Experiment 1, N=120 participants (48 female, aged 37.2 ±11.6 yr, from the USA, recruited online on Amazon Mechanical Turk) provided estimates about 14 general-knowledge quantities ( <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table S3</ref>). All variables were positive and unbounded, like the example used in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> (e.g., "how many bridges are there in Paris?"). Participants had monetary incentives to estimate these variables as accurately as possible.</p><p>Participants were informed that their participation was completely voluntary, and that they could withdraw their participation at any time. All data were completely anonymous. The experimental protocol was approved by a local ethics committee (anonymized for peer review purposes).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>This experiment was developed using Psytoolkit <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Stoet 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Stoet 2017)</ref>. One third of the sample was randomly assigned to a control condition where they simply estimated a variable. The other two thirds of the participants were randomly assigned to the experimental condition where, before estimating the quantity, they were asked to consider either an extremely low or extremely high value (e.g., is the number of bridges in Paris higher or lower than 349?). Half of the anchored participants considered a low value, and the other half considered a high value (randomly assigned). Crucially, these extreme values were not manually chosen by the experimenters, but set automatically as the 5 and 95 percentiles of the empirical values observed in the control condition (to this aim, the data from the first third of the sample was collected prior to the remaining data). Overall, we collected data from 41 participants in the control condition and 79 participants in the experimental condition. Our motivation for collecting this number of participants per condition was related to the maximum crowd size which could be obtained for our resampling procedure (see "Data Analysis" below). We aimed for a crowd size of at least 30. In all cases, the questions were randomly ordered. All participants had a maximum of 15 seconds to answer. Participants were paid a flat fee of 1.5 USD for their participation. Estimation accuracy was incentivized by rewarding a bonus payment of 0.5 USD to the top 10% most accurate respondents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Analysis</head><p>We discarded data from participants that completed the survey in less than three minutes, or those who failed to complete the survey. We also excluded participants with two or more exactly correct answers (which is likely to reflect cheating).</p><p>To compare different conditions in a properly balanced way, we developed a resampling bootstrapping strategy. For each crowd size, we randomly selected with replacement a fixed number of individuals and estimated the collective error, predictive diversity, and mean individual error for that crowd size and that iteration. We repeated that procedure 1,000 times for crowd sizes that varied from 2 to different maximum values in different experiments (i.e., n=32 in Experiment 1, n=50 in Experiment 2, n=100 in Experiment 3, and n=70 in Experiment 4). In all cases those values allow perceiving the asymptotic behavior of the collective error as a function of crowd size.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>By employing a simple bootstrapping resampling method, we estimated the collective error of differentlysized groups for both the wisdom of crowds and the wisdom of extremized crowds ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2A)</ref>. We observed that the average collective error of the latter was always smaller than the former. For example, the collective error of 34 individuals randomly taken from the control condition was substantially larger than the collective error of 34 extremized individuals (unpaired t-test: t(998)=29.7, p=2x10 -139 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 1.8 ± 0.1, 95% CL). This collective error reduction was due to an increase in predictive diversity <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig.   2B</ref>, unpaired t-test: t(998)=54.8, p&lt;10 -200 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 3.3 ± 0.1, 95% CL) that was higher than the increase in mean individual error ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2B</ref>, unpaired t-test: t(998)=24.2, p=5x10 -102 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 1.4 ± 0.1, 95% CL).</p><p>One limitation of Experiment 1 is that the anchors were defined after collecting the data of the nonanchored population. Because this procedure may be inconvenient from a practical point of view, we performed a second pre-registered experiment with bounded quantities, where anchors were pre-defined and fixed across all questions (https://aspredicted.org/RYC_4Y5).  See <ref type="table">Table S4</ref> for the full list of questions used in Experiment 2). Unlike the previous study, here we used the same anchors for all questions, always set at either 5% (low anchor ) or 95% (high anchor ).</p><p>Participants were recruited online, and resided in Argentina at the time of the experiment. All questions came from a variety of representative surveys carried out by official entities. The contents of the questions were explicitly related to Argentina, and ranged from demographic (e.g. what percentage of the population over 20 years old is either overweight or obese?) to personal perceptions of the country (e.g., what</p><p>percentage of the population believes abortion is not morally acceptable?). When necessary, we referenced the year in which the corresponding survey had taken place.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>This experiment was also developed using Psytoolkit <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Stoet 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Stoet 2017)</ref>. In order to reduce the length of the survey, we divided the questions into two subsets of 15 questions. Each participant was randomly assigned to one of these sets of questions. In addition, following a very similar procedure to the previous experiment, we randomly divided the sample in two groups. Participants in the control condition were asked to directly estimate the answer to the 15 questions (e.g., What percentage of the population of the USA is under 18 years old?). Participants in the experimental condition answered the same questions but after an "anchoring" question (Do you think the percentage of the population of the USA under 25 years old is above or below 95 %?). The assignment to the low anchor or high anchor condition was random across questions. Overall, we collected data from 119 participants in Group 1, and 277 participants in Group 2. In all cases, the questions were randomly ordered (within each subset of 15 questions). In this case, we estimated the number of participants per condition required from power analyses derived from our previous experiment (as per our pre-registration, https://aspredicted.org/RYC_4Y5). All participants had 20 seconds to answer the questions. Estimation was not incentivized for accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Analysis</head><p>For this experiment we followed the same exclusion criteria as for the previous one. In this case, the exclusion criteria were pre-registered. For Experiment 2 we followed the same bootstrapping procedure as stated for our previous experiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>We observed very similar results to Experiment 1 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 3A and 3B)</ref>. Collective error was lower for the extremized crowd (crowd size N=50, unpaired t-test: t(998)=19.1, p=2x10 -69 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 1.2 ± 0.1, 95% CL). This was accompanied by an increase in mean individual error (unpaired t-test: <ref type="bibr">-200</ref> ; effect size: Cohen's d = 7.6 ± 0.3, 95% CL) as well as an increase in predictive diversity (unpaired t-test: t(198)=162.5, p&lt;10 -200 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 10.3 ± 0.3, 95% CL).</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">t(198)=121.1, p&lt;10</formula><p>Given that this experiment used fixed anchors across all questions, it allowed us to test one key element of the model, i.e., the anchoring extremeness effect (Eq.</p><p>[4]). We did so by performing two separate analyses. First, we examined the biases associated with each experimental condition. We reasoned that, if anchoring was sensitive to the distance to the correct answer, then the effectiveness of the procedure should be higher when the correct answer is close to the anchor. For example, we should see that participants considering a low value (5%) should be more attracted to the anchor when the correct answer is low (below 50%) compared to when the correct answer is high (above 50%). Consistent with this idea, when the correct answer was below 50% (17 questions), we did not observe any statistical difference between the distribution of estimates provided by the population considering the "low anchor" and the correct answer, Second, we directly examined the anchoring extremeness effect by studying the association between the strength of the anchoring procedure and the distance between the anchor and the correct answer (Eq. 4).</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">(</formula><p>We estimated the strength of the anchoring effect by calculating the anchoring weight, which has very similar properties to the "anchoring index" from previous literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Jacowitz &amp; Kahneman, 1995)</ref>. Both quantities (see Eq. 7 in Supplementary Information for details) take a value of 0 when the anchoring procedure does not produce any effect on the estimates, and a value of 1 when the estimates are on average equal to the anchor. Consistent with the existence of the anchoring extremeness effect (Roseler et al., 2022), we observed a significantly negative correlation between the anchoring weight and the distance between the anchor and the correct answer (Pearson correlation coefficient, r=-0.56, p=3x10 <ref type="bibr">-6</ref> ). This empirical observation provides support to the proposed model of the anchoring effect used in Eqs 2-4.</p><p>To test the functional form of the proposed model, we compared it with two other monotonically decreasing functions. One is a linear function and the other one is a general hyperbolic function</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">= 0 1+ | − | ,<label>[7]</label></formula><p>which is similar to the one used in the temporal discounting literature <ref type="bibr">(Ruggeri et al., 2022)</ref>. We found that the exponential model led to better fits to the data as assessed by both the Akaike and Bayesian Information Criteria (Linear model: ∆AIC = 1.9, ∆BIC = 1.9; Hyperbolic model: ∆AIC = 0.59, ∆BIC = 0.59).</p><p>Another assumption of the proposed anchoring model is that low and high anchors elicit the same anchoring weights. Given that this feature of the model could be an oversimplification for specific problems (e.g., city populations), we compared the goodness of the fits achieved with a single anchoring weight per question, with the one obtained with different weights for low and high anchors. Formal model comparison indicated that having a single weight per question led to better fits than the model with asymmetrical weights (∆AIC = 1.6, ∆BIC = 5.7).</p><p>Finally, this experiment allowed us testing if the proposed method is robust to the use of different aggregation procedures like the simple average, the median, and a performance-weighted average <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Mannes et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr">Collins et al, 2023)</ref>. We found evidence that, regardless of the specific aggregation procedure, crowds extremized through anchoring were always more accurate than non-extremized crowds ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. S3;</ref> for details, see Supplementary Information). the correct answer for each question, for the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green), the crowd extremized using a high anchor (red), and the crowd extremized using a low anchor (blue). We separate the cases where the correct answer is above 50% (left panel) and where it is above 50% (right panel). The black line depicts the case where the mean value is equal to the correct answer. (D) Empirical anchoring weight (w) for each question. Blue dots show estimates using low anchors and red dots show the same with high anchors. The horizontal axis represents the distance between the corresponding anchor and the correct answer (logarithmic units on anchoring weight), and the black line shows the best linear fit of the data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3: Forecasting</head><p>Subsequently, we asked whether the proposed method can be useful to outperform the wisdom of crowds on forecasting tasks, i.e., for domains where the truth is unknown and unavailable at the time of the experiment. To answer this question, we performed a third pre-registered experiment that took place in the midst of the COVID-19 crisis (https://aspredicted.org/HZC_PTH).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants and Questions</head><p>We recruited N=620 participants (312 female, aged 46.1 ± 15.7 yr.) from the USA, and asked them to estimate the total number of COVID-19 cases and deaths that would occur in the United States in the following week (from 27 July to 2 August, 2020). Thus, the answers were positive (unbounded), resembling a typical wisdom-of-crowds experiment, but related to quantities that were unknown at the time of the experiment. Participants were recruited online by using Prolific (https://www.prolific.co/), and resided in the United States at the time of the experiment. Participants had monetary incentives to estimate these variables as accurately as possible. Anchors were selected as extreme values based on historical data, namely, two orders of magnitude less or more the number of COVID-19 cases and deaths reported in the two weeks before the beginning of the experiment (see <ref type="table">Table S4</ref> for the questions used in Experiment 3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>In Experiment 3, developed using Survey Monkey (https://www.surveymonkey.com/), we asked two questions related to the COVID-19 pandemic: we asked participants to forecast the number of COVID-19 deaths and cases in the week following the experiment. Anchors were selected as extreme values based on historical data, namely, two orders of magnitude less or more the number of COVID-19 cases and deaths reported in the two weeks before the beginning of the experiment. The correct answers to those questions were unknown at the time of the experiment. Since all participants answered both questions, there were a total of six conditions in this experiment. In Condition 1, we used a "low anchor" on COVID-19 deaths.</p><p>We asked participants whether they thought there would be more or less than 40 new deaths in the week following the experiment, and then asked them to forecast the number of new deaths. In the next screen, participants also forecast the number of new COVID-19 cases in the week following the experiment).</p><p>Condition 2 was the same as Condition 1, but with a "high anchor" (400,000) on COVID-19 deaths. In Condition 3, we did not anchor people's expectations (which served as a control for Conditions 1 and 2).</p><p>We first asked people to forecast the number of new deaths in the following week. In the following screen, participants forecast the number of new COVID-19 cases in the same week. Condition 4 was analogous to</p><p>Condition 1, but changing the order of questions and setting an anchor on cases, instead of deaths. First, we asked participants whether they thought there would be more or less than 8,000 new cases in the following week, and then asked them to estimate the number of new cases. In the next screen, participants forecast the number of new COVID-19 deaths in the same week. Condition 5 was the same as Condition 4, but with a "high anchor" (8,000,000) on COVID-19 cases. In Condition 6, we did not ask any anchoring questions and participants were directly asked to forecast the number of new cases and then the number of new deaths in the week following the experiment. This condition was analogous to Condition 3, but changing the order of questions, and serves as a control for Conditions 4 and 5.</p><p>We collected data from 117 participants in Condition 1, 105 participants in Condition 2, 97 participants in Condition 3, 92 participants in Condition 4, 97 participants in Condition 5, and 112 participants in Condition 6. The total sample of 600 participants, obtained through Prolific (https://www.prolific.co/), was representative of the US population in terms of age, gender and ethnicity. In this case, we aimed for 100 participants per condition, in order to have a maximum crowd size of 100 for our resampling analysis (as was pre-registered at https://aspredicted.org/HZC_PTH). This was done to further assess the asymptotic behavior of the collective errors with crowd size. All participants received a flat participation fee of 1.0 USD and, to incentivize forecasting accuracy, we paid a bonus of 2.0 USD to the top 10% performers.</p><p>There was no time limit to answer these questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Analysis</head><p>For Experiment 3, given that it consisted in forecasting questions, and since every participant completed the survey, there was no need to exclude any of them. All of them answered both forecasting questions.</p><p>We followed the same bootstrapping procedure as stated for our previous experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>Again, as in Experiments 1 and 2, we observed that the collective error was lower for the extremized crowd for all group sizes compared to the non-extremized wisdom of crowds <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 4A)</ref>. We found that the decrease in collective error (specifically, for the largest crowd size N=100, unpaired t-test: t(998)=16.4, p=7x10 -54 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 1.04 ± 0.09, 95% CL) was due to an increase in predictive diversity (crowd size N=100, unpaired t-test: t(998)=37.6, p=7x10 -193 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 2.5 ± 0.1, 95% CL).</p><p>This increase in predictive diversity was in turn greater than the increase in mean individual error <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 4B,</ref> crowd size N=100, unpaired t-test: t(998)=18.1, p=1x10 -64 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 1.2 ± 0.1, 95% CL).</p><p>Overall, this study demonstrates that the presented strategy is also useful for a forecasting task. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 4: Self-generated anchors</head><p>One limitation of Experiments 1-3 is that, in all cases, participants had access to additional information (either because anchors were pre-defined by the experimenters or based on the responses given by other participants). Experiment 4 addressed that limitation by using self-generated anchors. The experiment was pre-registered (https://aspredicted.org/YQ4_LYS), and used questions similar to those tested in Experiment 1. The key difference is that participants were prompted to generate their own anchors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants and Questions</head><p>We recruited N= 226 participants (110 female, aged 37.2± 12.1 yr, residents of Argentina at the time of the experiment, recruited online) and asked them 10 general-knowledge questions that involved the estimation of the height of a building (e.g. what is the height of the Eiffel Tower?). Unlike all the previous experiments, the anchors were self-generated, meaning that participants provided their own respective anchors (See <ref type="table">Table S5</ref> for the full list of questions).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Procedure</head><p>This experiment was developed using Psytoolkit <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Stoet 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Stoet 2017)</ref>. One third of the sample was randomly assigned to a control condition, where they simply estimated a variable. After participants completed all ten questions, we asked them to provide new, different estimates for each one of them. This procedure allowed us comparing whether the self-generation of anchors in the treatment conditions was different or not to the phenomenon of dialectical bootstrapping <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Herzog &amp; Hertwig, 2009)</ref> The two other thirds of the participants were randomly assigned to the experimental condition where, before starting the main questionnaire, they were asked to estimate the height of the tallest building on Earth and the height of the shortest building on Earth. The values they provided were used as the high and low anchors, respectively, for all the estimation questions. We added 10% zero-mean uniform noise to these preliminary estimates, so that each question with the same base anchor had a slightly different value.</p><p>Thus, before estimating the quantity in question, they were asked to consider either an extremely low or an extremely high value (e.g., is the height of the Eiffel Tower higher or lower than 1000 meters?). For each question, half of the anchored participants considered a low value, and the other half considered a high value (randomly assigned). Overall, we collected data from 75 participants in the control condition and 151 participants in the experimental condition. The sample size for each condition was determined through power analyses (as per our pre-registration, for details see https://aspredicted.org/YQ4_LYS). In all cases, the questions were presented in random order. All participants had a maximum of 25 seconds to answer.</p><p>Estimation was not incentivized for accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Analysis</head><p>We discarded data from participants that completed the survey in less than two minutes, or those who failed to complete half or more of the questions in the survey. We also excluded participants with two or more exactly correct answers (which likely reflects cheating). These were the same exclusion criteria as for Experiments 1 and 2. These exclusion criteria were pre-registered. For Experiment 4 we followed the same bootstrapping procedure as stated for our previous experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>As with previous experiments, we observed that collective error was lower for the extremized crowd for all group sizes compared to the non-extremized wisdom of crowds <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 5A)</ref>. We found that the decrease in collective error (specifically, for the largest crowd size N=70, unpaired t-test: t(998)=58.4, p&lt;10 -200 ;</p><p>effect size: Cohen's d = 3.7 ± 0.1, 95% CL) was due to an increase in predictive diversity (crowd size N=70, unpaired t-test: t(998)=78.5, p&lt;10 -200 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 4.9 ± 0.2, 95% CL). This increase in predictive diversity was in turn greater than the increase in mean individual error <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 5B</ref>, crowd size N=70, unpaired t-test: t(998)= 33.9, p=2x10 -168 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 2.2 ± 0.1, 95% CL). Overall, this study demonstratesd that the presented strategy is also useful when employing self-generated anchors. This means that the problem of choosing appropriate anchors can be easily solved by asking participants to provide their own anchors.</p><p>We then studied the relationship between this procedure and the wisdom-of-the-inner-crowd effect.</p><p>Given that participants generated their own anchor, we reasoned that this effect could , in principle, partially explain the efficacy of the method. However, we were able to rule out this possibility, as the wisdom of extremized crowds produced much more accurate collective estimates than the wisdom of the inner crowd (for details, see "Self-generated Anchors and the Wisdom of the Inner Crowd" in Supplementary Information). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>In this work, we introduce a novel strategy to outperform the wisdom of crowds <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Surowiecki, 2005</ref>) that has both practical and theoretical implications. By means of the anchoring effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">(Tversky, &amp; Kahneman, 1974)</ref>, we show we can reduce collective error by increasing predictive diversity <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Page, 2007)</ref>. In previous literature, methods to increase the wisdom of crowds often involved strategies to reduce individual error <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Madirolas &amp; de Polavieja, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Mannes, Soll &amp; Larrick, 2014)</ref>. However, while theoretical analysis suggested this goal could also be achieved by increasing the predictive diversity (as seen in Eq.</p><p>[1]), that possibility remained unexplored. Here, we thoroughly studied this approach both theoretically and empirically: first, by developing a mathematical model of the anchoring effect and, second, by performing four behavioral experiments.</p><p>In all of the experiments, regardless of differences in sample size, country of implementation, use of bounded or unbounded quantities, anchor-setting procedure, and whether the task involved estimation or forecasting, we observed very similar results. Extremized crowds always produced estimates with lower collective error, and this was always accompanied by an increase in both mean individual error and predictive diversity. This demonstrates that it is possible to increase collective intelligence while concurrently reducing individual accuracy, an approach that remained heretofore empirically untested.</p><p>Therefore, this should inspire future research aimed at increasing the wisdom of crowds using a similar strategy.</p><p>One limitation of the proposed method is that the selection of appropriate anchors could potentially prove hard (for example, in forecasting problems). However, our model-based analyses as well as our empirical findings suggest that the range of values where this method improves the wisdom of crowds is large (Equation 4). We also showed that adequately selecting anchors is empirically feasible across four very different setups. In Experiment 1, the anchors were chosen based on extremely high and low values (5 and 95 percentiles) of the non-anchored distribution. This procedure, however, has the disadvantage that it shares information between different groups of participants and this could partly explain changes in collective performance (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Navajas et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Becker et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Becker et al., 2021)</ref>. In Experiment 2, we studied the estimation of percentages while keeping anchors fixed at 5% and 95%. With this experiment we showed that the method still works in a condition where anchors were pre-defined across all questions. This setup also allowed us obtaining empirical support for the proposed anchoring model. In Experiment 3, we shifted the focus of attention to forecasting problems. Anchors were defined a priori, using historical data. Given that the correct answer was unknown to the experimenters before conducting the study, this setup demonstrated that -even in highly uncertain forecasting problems-it is feasible to select anchors so that the method would still work. However, one limitation of Experiments 1-3 is that, in all cases, participants had access to additional information (either because anchors were pre-defined by the experimenters or based on the responses given by other participants). Experiment 4 addressed that limitation by using self-generated anchors. This demonstrates that this method is useful even in conditions where anchors are not selected by the experimenters.</p><p>The first study on the wisdom of crowds <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Galton, 1907)</ref> was regarded as an empirical demonstration that democratic aggregation principles can be reliable and efficient. This was counterintuitive at the time, since it showed that erroneous individuals could make good collective choices. Nowadays, when political opinions tend to become extremized, these results seem to suggest that democratic decisions can still be surprisingly accurate, even if collective choices proceed from misinformed voters, as long as they are sufficiently diverse. Therefore, one interpretation of these findings is that opinion polarization, which may stem from the attraction towards political extremes <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Goldenberg et al., 2023;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Zimmerman et al., 2022)</ref>, can potentially improve democratic judgement, as previously proposed <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Shi et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Studies examining how diversity influences group performance have provided dissimilar results, with both positive (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Mohammed &amp; Ringseis, 2001</ref>) and negative (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Navajas et al., 2022)</ref> effects present in the collective decision-making literature (for a review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sulik, Bahrami &amp; Deroy, 2022)</ref>. This suggests that accumulating diverse evidence (Couch, 2022) may not be good or bad per se, but depend on the interaction with variables such as group size <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Pescetelli, Rutherford &amp; Rahwan, 2021)</ref> and network structure <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Baumann, Czaplicka, &amp; Rahwan, 2024)</ref>. This paper adds to this literature by showing that increasing diversity may reduce accuracy at the individual level but increase it at the collective level.</p><p>Crucially, we demonstrated this novel insight in a complex forecasting domain, where there is a longstanding tradition examining the epistemic value of combining diverse predictions <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bates &amp; Granger, 1969)</ref>. Although this work demonstrated the existence of this phenomenon and studied its robustness across different aggregation methods, we believe future work can refine the wisdom of extremized crowds, for example, by combining them with the use of debiasing through generative models <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Lee, &amp; Danileiko, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Lee et al., 2023)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Information Diversity Prediction Theorem</head><p>The diversity prediction theorem <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Page, 2007)</ref>  with N being the size of the population, the index i covering the N individuals, the index q covering all questions asked, θ q being the correct answer for each question, ( ) being the answer provided by each individual i in response to question q, and = 1 ∑ <ref type="bibr">( )</ref> being the mean answer for question q.</p><p>When we subtract ϵ and δ, the term ( ) 2 cancels out. Since the parameters and are independent of i, we get: This identity indicates that the collective error is exactly equal to the mean individual error minus the predictive diversity. One implication of this result is that, in principle, collective error can be reduced not only by decreasing the mean individual error (in other words, employing or selecting wiser individuals), but by increasing the predictive diversity of the crowd, which is related to its variance. It is important to note that this mathematical identity applies to convex error measures (relevant for all the problems addressed in this work) but fails in the case of concave error measures.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">− = ∑</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conditions to Outperform the Wisdom of Crowds</head><p>To find the range of parameters under which the collective error of extremized crowds is lower than the non-extremized wisdom of crowds, the following expression should hold:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">| − | &lt; | − | [S5]</formula><p>where is the mean of the extremized crowds, is the mean of the wisdom of crowds, and is the correct answer. Assuming that μ ≠ θ (i.e., the wisdom of crowds does not reach the correct answer, meaning that there is room for improvement), we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">| − | | − | &lt; 1 [S6]</formula><p>Furthermore, without loss of generality, we assume that the crowd underestimated the correct answer, and so − &gt; 0. (The procedure is analogous in the case of overestimation). We then expand the absolute</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">value | − − |</formula><p>, and multiply by − on each side, reaching</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">−( − ) &lt; − &lt; − [S7]</formula><p>We then subtract − on all sides, and reach</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">−2( − ) &lt; − &lt; 0 [S8]</formula><p>For the sake of clarity, we now simplify the problem and assume a constant anchoring weight 0 . This particular case is informative, as a constant anchoring weight would produce conditions which are less favorable for the model, given that it would lack access to the correct value through Eq.</p><p>[4] (the proof for the general case can be found below). If we have a constant anchoring weight, using Eq. Now we divide by 0 and sum on all sides, reaching</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">− 2 0 ( − ) + &lt; ̅ &lt; [S11]</formula><p>The inequality in Eq.</p><p>[S11] implies that the range of values of ̅ to outperform the wisdom of crowds is of the form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">∆ 0 = 2| − | 0 [S12]</formula><p>This result indicates that the conditions under which the model improves the wisdom of crowds depend on the midpoint of the anchors (its average ̅ ). It also implies that the range of values for ̅ that fulfills those conditions is at least twice the size of its error.</p><p>If we drop the assumption of constant anchoring weight, we can still follow the same procedure and reach, instead of Eq.</p><p>[S11], the general expression </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competition between Increasing Diversity and Accuracy</head><p>Given the predictions of the model, and the empirical results of the four behavioral experiments, one may ask if it is possible to increase predictive diversity (via anchoring) while, at the same time, reducing mean individual error. In principle, there is nothing in the Diversity Prediction Theorem that would prevent us from approaching both simultaneously (i.e., one could reduce the first term ε and increase the second term δ). However, in all the experiments and simulations presented here, we observed that every time we reduced collective error by increasing diversity, we also increased mean individual error. To better understand this phenomenon, we performed a new model-based analysis: we ran a series of simulations of the proposed model, while systematically varying the distance between the two anchors. Each of these simulations produced a set of estimates with roughly the same collective error, but different predictive diversity and mean individual error. Across simulations, we found a positive association between those two variables <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. S1</ref>, Pearson correlation coefficient, r=0.998, p=2x10 -62 ), suggesting that our approach establishes a tradeoff between increasing accuracy and diversity, and that they are indeed in competition. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Evaluation of Different Aggregation Methods</head><p>When analyzing the data of Experiment 2, we found strong evidence consistent with the existence of a bias towards intermediate probabilities ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure S2</ref>). This holds true for both the non-extremized wisdom of crowds and the wisdom of extremized crowds. This result implies that, in principle, there is still room for improvement over our method by performing different aggregation procedures. We tested three different strategies. The first two strategies are the mean and the median, which have been widely used and compared since the first implementation of the wisdom of the crowds <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Galton, 1907)</ref>. The third aggregation strategy is a performance-weighted average (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Collins et al, 2023)</ref>. We estimated each participant's weight using a "leave-one-out" procedure. We first computed the mean individual error of each participant based on the responses to all but one question, and then normalized (so that they add up to 1) to define each participant's weight for the question that was left out.</p><p>As seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S3</ref>, in all cases, our method proves useful for reducing the error of the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green). However, there are some differences between the aggregation methods. Using median instead of mean slightly increased the error of the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (specifically, for the largest crowd size N=50, unpaired t-test: t(998)=2.37, p=0.02; effect size: Cohen's d = 0.16 ± 0.09, 95% CL), but reduced the error of the extremized crowds (for the largest crowd size N=50, unpaired t-test: t(998)=6.38, p=3x10 -10 ; effect size: Cohen's d = 0.35 ± 0.09, 95% CL), resulting in the biggest difference between the two crowds. Performance-weighted averages worked best for smaller crowds, but show no statistical differences with the mean for the largest crowd size (unpaired t-test: t(998)=0.33, p=0.74; effect size: Cohen's d = 0.02 ± 0.09, 95% CL). Overall, these results further support not only the robustness but also the versatility of our method, which can be used with different aggregation strategies.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Definition of "Anchoring Index"</head><p>From Eq.</p><p>[2] and [3], it follows that the anchoring index <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Jacowitz &amp; Kahneman, 1995)</ref> is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">= − − [16]</formula><p>where j represents either L for the low anchor or H for the high anchor.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental Design Variables</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Wisdom of extremized crowds. (A) The method for estimating a variable through the wisdom of crowds consists in asking a crowd of individuals to estimate a given quantity, and averaging all answers (averages represented by µ). The proposed alternative method consists in promoting the adoption of divergent opinions within a crowd by dividing it in two halves, asking an anchoring question with either a low (L) or a high (H) value to each half, and then averaging all answers (µx). (B) Mathematical model of the anchoring effect. The anchored mean is a weighted average of the anchor and the wisdom-of-crowds value. The weight w depends on the difference between the anchor and the correct answer, reflecting an internal sensitivity to the correct answer. (C) Simulations performed using the proposed model show that the method is expected to outperform the wisdom of crowds. (D) Mean individual error and predictive diversity on simulated data show an increase in both individual error and predictive</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Empirical results for Experiment 1. (A) Collective error as a function of crowd size, for the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green) and for the wisdom of extremized crowds (purple). The standard error of each curve is within the line width. The inset shows the distribution of values from the resampling method for the largest crowd size (N=34). The orange line depicts the probability of a sample from the distribution of collective errors of the extremized crowd (purple distribution, Ex) being smaller than a sample from the distribution of collective errors of the non-extremized crowd (green distribution, Ec). (B) Mean individual error and predictive diversity for both the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green) and the wisdom of extremized crowds (purple). The error bars are the standard deviation of the means.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Empirical results for Experiment 2. (A) Collective error as a function of crowd size, for the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green) and for the wisdom of extremized crowds (purple). The standard error of the curves is within the line width. The inset shows the distribution of values from the resampling method for the largest crowd size (N=50). The orange line depicts the probability of a sample from the distribution of collective errors of the extremized crowd (purple distribution, Ex) being smaller than a sample from the distribution of collective errors of the non-extremized crowd (green distribution, Ec). (B) Mean individual error and predictive diversity for both the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green) and for extremized crowds (purple). The error bars show the standard deviation of the means. (C) Distributions of values corresponding to the difference between the mean answers and</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Empirical results for Experiment 3. (A) Collective error as a function of crowd size, for the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green) and for the wisdom of extremized crowds (purple). The standard error of the curves is within the line width. The inset shows the distribution of values from the resampling method for the largest crowd size (N=100). The orange line depicts the probability of a sample from the distribution of collective errors of the extremized crowd (purple distribution, Ex) being smaller than a sample from the distribution of collective errors of the non-extremized crowd (green distribution, Ec). (B). Mean individual error and predictive diversity for both the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green) and the extremized crowd (purple). The error bars are the standard deviation of the means.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Empirical results for Experiment 4. (A) Collective error as a function of crowd size, for the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green) and the wisdom of extremized crowds (purple). The standard error of the curves is within the line width. The inset shows the distribution of values from the resampling method for the largest crowd size (N=70). The orange line depicts the probability of a sample from the distribution of collective errors of the extremized crowd (purple distribution, Ex) being smaller than a sample from the distribution of collective errors of the non-extremized crowd (green distribution, Ec). (B) Mean individual error and predictive diversity for both the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green) and the extremized crowd (purple). The error bars are the standard deviation of the means.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>allows us to express the collective error of a crowd (E, defined as the squared difference between the crowd's mean answer and the correct answer) as two separate components: the predictive diversity (δ) defined as the squared difference between each individual answer A and the mean answer); and the mean individual error (ϵ), where individual error is defined as the squared difference between the individual answers and the correct answer). The proof of this mathematical identity is straightforward:As expressed, we require the following definitions:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>mean value of the anchors), and replace in Eq. [S8], we get −2( − ) &lt; 0 ̅ + (1 − ) − &lt; 0[S10]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>that the range of values where extremized crowds outperform the wisdom of crowds is given by Eq. [6].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Fig. S1 .</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>Competition between increasing diversity and accuracy. Model simulations of changes in MeanIndividual Error as a function of changes in Predictive Diversity. Model parameters were: w 0 = 0.2 (weight when the anchor is the correct answer), A = −1 (average of anchors), µ = 0.2 (mean crowd answer), n = 10,000 (crowd size), σ = 1 (standard deviation of crowd answers), θ = 0 (correct answer). Across simulations, we systematically varied the distance between anchors from ∆= 5 to ∆= 10 in steps of 0.1. Blue dots show results from different model specifications, and the dashed line depicts the identity.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Fig. S2 .</head><label>S2</label><figDesc>Average Responses vs. Correct Answer. Average answers to each question as a function of the correct answer, for both the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green dots) and the wisdom of extremized crowds (purple dots). Lines depict the best linear fits.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Fig. S3 .</head><label>S3</label><figDesc>Comparison of aggregation procedures for Experiment 2. (A-C) Collective error as a function of crowd size, for the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green) and the extremized crowds (purple). The standard error of the curves is within the line width. The orange line corresponds to the probability of a sample from the distribution of collective errors of the extremized crowd (purple distribution, Ex) of being smaller than a sample from the distribution of collective errors of the normal crowd (green distribution, Ec). (A) Aggregation method: mean. (B) Aggregation method: median. (C) Aggregation method: performance-weighted mean. (D) Comparison of the collective error of the largest crowd (N=70) for each aggregation method. The wisdom of crowds is presented in green, and the wisdom of extremized crowds is presented in purple.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>Fig. S4 .</head><label>S4</label><figDesc>Comparison with the Wisdom of the Inner Crowd for Experiment 4. Collective error as a function of crowd size, for the non-extremized wisdom of crowds (green), the wisdom of extremized crowds (purple), and the wisdom of the inner crowd (orange). The standard error of the curves is within the line width.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Experiment 2: Estimation of bounded quantities with fixed anchors Methods</head><label></label><figDesc>, we recruited N=396 participants online (235 female, aged 27.9±8.8 yr), and asked them 30 general-knowledge questions that involved the estimation of a percentage. Therefore, all answers were bounded in the range [0,100] (e.g. what percentage of the population of Argentina is under 15 years old?</figDesc><table><row><cell>Participants and Questions</cell></row><row><cell>In Experiment 2</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Conversely, when the correct answer was above 50% (13 questions), we observed the opposite pattern: the population considering the "high anchor" provided a distribution of estimates that was not statistically distinct from the correct answer (paired t-test, t(12)=2.01, p=0.07, effect size: Cohen's d = 0.56 ± 0.78, 95% CL), and Bayes factor analysis suggested very weak evidence in favor of the alternative hypothesis</figDesc><table><row><cell>paired t-test, t(16)=0.95, p=.36, effect size: Cohen's d = 0.23 ± 0.67, 95% CL), and Bayes factor analysis</cell></row><row><cell>provided moderate support for the null hypothesis (Bayes factor = 2.7). More importantly, both the non-</cell></row><row><cell>anchored (paired t-test, t(16)=4.16, p=3x10 -4 , effect size: Cohen's d = 1.11 ± 0.72, 95% CL) and the</cell></row><row><cell>population anchored to a high value (paired t-test, t(16)=5.99, p=2x10 -5 , effect size: Cohen's d = 1.45 ±</cell></row><row><cell>0.76, 95% CL) provided a distribution of estimates that significantly overestimated the correct answer (Fig.</cell></row><row><cell>3C). (Bayes factor = 0.77). Crucially, both the non-anchored population (paired t-test, t(16)=3.90, p=0.001,</cell></row><row><cell>effect size: Cohen's d = 1.08 ± 0.82, 95% CL) and the population anchored to a low value (paired t-test,</cell></row><row><cell>t(16)=4.90, p=4x10 -4 , effect size: Cohen's d = 1.36 ± 0.85, 95% CL) provided a distribution of estimates</cell></row><row><cell>that significantly underestimated the correct answer.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table S1 :</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>main design variables of Experiments 1-3. According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage of the population living in private homes has health coverage? 63.9 What percentage of women aged between 18 and 60 years old have jobs in Argentina? 50.2What percentage of the Argentine population has access to the internet at home, either through a computer or mobile device?</figDesc><table><row><cell>Experiment 2: Questions and correct answers</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Question</cell><cell>Correct Answer</cell></row><row><cell>What percentage of the population of Argentina is not affiliated with any religion?</cell><cell>12.2</cell></row><row><cell>What percentage of the population of Argentina aged 20 or older is either overweight or obese?</cell><cell>52.0 73.0</cell></row><row><cell>What percentage of the members of the House of According to a representative survey conducted in 2013, what Representatives of Argentina are women? old or younger? relationships? What percentage of the population of Argentina is 14 years percentage of the Argentine population believes that it is not morally acceptable for unmarried adults to have sexual</cell><cell>39.0 24.9 22.0</cell></row><row><cell>According to a representative survey conducted in 2013, what percentage of the population of Argentina believes that What percentage of the Argentine population lives in a housing unit that they own?</cell><cell>27.0 72.0</cell></row><row><cell>homosexuality is not morally acceptable? According to a representative survey conducted in 2013, what What percentage of the Argentine population owns a smartphone?</cell><cell>48.0</cell></row><row><cell>percentage of the population of Argentina believes that According to a representative survey from 2013, what abortion is not morally acceptable? percentage of the Argentine population believes that most</cell><cell>56.0 19.2</cell></row><row><cell>According to a representative survey conducted in 2014, what people are trustworthy?</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>percentage of the population of Argentina believes they have</cell><cell>75.0</cell></row><row><cell>good or very good health? What percentage of the Argentine population believes that some vaccines can cause autism in healthy children?</cell><cell>10.0</cell></row><row><cell>What percentage of male deaths between 15 and 24 years of age in Argentina were due to suicide? In Argentina, what percentage of the total real estate wealth belongs to the richest 1% of the population? What percentage of the population of Argentina aged 13 or older has a Facebook account? According to a representative survey conducted in 2017, what According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage of people over 20 years old have completed high school?</cell><cell>15.3 44.0 60.0 20.1</cell></row><row><cell>percentage of the population of Argentina believes they are able to distinguish between real news and "fake news" According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage</cell><cell>72.0</cell></row><row><cell>(completely invented stories or facts)? of the population over 80 years old was born in another</cell><cell>11.8</cell></row><row><cell>country?</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>of the population between 3 and 18 years old attends an According to a representative survey conducted in 2013, what</cell><cell>88.9</cell></row><row><cell>educational institution? percentage of the population of Argentina is not at all</cell><cell>30.7</cell></row><row><cell>interested in politics?</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>of the population lives in a housing unit without water According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage</cell><cell>15.2</cell></row><row><cell>discharge or without a toilet? of the population living in the Santa Fe province is under 65</cell><cell>88.2</cell></row><row><cell>years old?</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage of women over 14 years old have never had a child? According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage of the population is single?</cell><cell>30.3 33.5</cell></row><row><cell>According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage of the population over 20 years old either has or is looking for According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage of the population does not live in an apartment?</cell><cell>70.6 88.1</cell></row><row><cell>a job?</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>According to the 2010 census in Argentina, what percentage of people aged 20 to 29 both work and study?</cell><cell>19.2</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table S3</head><label>S3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note>: Questions tested in Experiment 2 and correct answers</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Self-generated Anchors and the Wisdom of the Inner Crowd</head><p>While Experiment 4 proved that the proposed method can be effective, even without prior knowledge by the experimenters, by asking participants to provide their own anchors, one issue remain unaddressed: could the wisdom-of-the-inner-crowd effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Herzog &amp; Hertwig, 2009)</ref> explain the efficacy of the method?</p><p>If so, it could be argued that it is not the anchoring procedure, but the latter effect, the driver of error reduction in the extremized crowd for this Experiment. In order to assess this, and as was mentioned in the Methods section of Experiment 4, we asked participants in the control condition to provide new (different) estimates for each question. We then compared the wisdom of crowds, the wisdom of extremized crowds, and the wisdom of the inner crowd for each possible crowd size ( <ref type="figure">Figure S4</ref>).</p><p>Results show that the wisdom of the inner crowd (which, according with <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">Vul &amp; Pashler (2008)</ref>, gives a 10% improvement over the original estimates) is not statistically distinct from the wisdom of crowds in this experiment (for the largest crowd size N=70, unpaired t-test: t(998)=0.84, p=0.40; effect size: Cohen's d = 0.04 ± 0.09, 95% CL; Bayes factor for the null hypothesis: 18.01). This could have been expected, since assuming a 10% average improvement over the original individual estimates, for a large crowd involving estimates from different participants, the improvement becomes negligible when compared with the variance of the estimates themselves. Overall, this results show that our method's efficacy does not hinge on the wisdom-of-the-inner-crowd effect, but it is itself a distinct phenomenon.   What is the height of the "Obelisco de Buenos Aires"? 67</p><p>What is the height of the "Catedral de La Plata"? 112</p><p>What is the height of the "Palacio de Aguas Corrientes"? 21</p><p>What is the height of the "Palacio del Congreso de la Nación Argentina"? 80</p><p>What is the height of the "Torre de los Ingleses de Retiro"? 60</p><p>What is the height of the Eiffel Tower (to the tip)? 330</p><p>What is the height of the Empire State Building (to the tip)? 443</p><p>What is the height of the Buckingham Palace? 24</p><p>What is the height of the Tower of Shanghai? 632</p><p>What is the height of the Tower of Pisa? 56 <ref type="table">Table S5</ref>: Questions tested in Experiment 4 and correct answers</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scaling up fact-checking using the wisdom of crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Arechar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pennycook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4393</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The combination of forecasts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Granger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the operational research society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="468" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network structure shapes the impact of diversity in collective learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Baumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Czaplicka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Rahwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2491</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network dynamics of social influence in the wisdom of crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Brackbill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Centola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the national academy of sciences</title>
		<meeting>the national academy of sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5070" to="5076" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The crowd classification problem: Social dynamics of binary-choice accuracy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Guilbeault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3949" to="3965" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The wisdom of partisan crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Centola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10717" to="10722" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The diversity principle and the evaluation of evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Couch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1270" to="1294" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Essai sur l&apos;application de l&apos;analyse à la probabilité des décisions rendues à la pluralité des voix. L&apos;impremerie royale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>De Condorcet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1785" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social influence undermines the wisdom of the crowd in sequential decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Frey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Van De Rijt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4273" to="4286" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A literature review of the anchoring effect. The journal of socioeconomics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Furnham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Boo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="42" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vox populi</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Galton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="450" to="451" />
			<date type="published" when="1907" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Goldenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Abruzzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schöne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bailey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Willer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Homophily and acrophily as drivers of political segregation</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="219" to="230" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The wisdom of many in one mind: Improving individual judgments with dialectical bootstrapping</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Herzog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="237" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Groups of diverse problem solvers can outperform groups of high-ability problem solvers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Page</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16385" to="16389" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measures of anchoring in estimation tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Jacowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1161" to="1166" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Jayles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Escobedo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Cezera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Blanchet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kameda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Theraulaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How social information can improve estimation accuracy in human groups</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12620" to="12625" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Jönsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Hahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Olsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The kind of group you want to belong to: Effects of group structure on group accuracy</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">142</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="191" to="204" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information aggregation and collective intelligence beyond the wisdom of crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kameda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Toyokawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Tindale</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="357" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision accuracy in complex environments is often maximized by small group sizes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Couzin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">281</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1784" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Counteracting estimation bias and social influence to improve the wisdom of crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Berdahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Hartnett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Bak-Coleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ioannou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Couzin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of The Royal Society Interface</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">141</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018-01-30" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Understanding crowdsourcing projects: A review on the key design elements of a crowdsourcing initiative. Creativity and innovation management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Karachiwalla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pinkow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="563" to="584" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhancing the wisdom of the crowd with cognitive-process diversity: The benefits of aggregating intuitive and analytical judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Keck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1272" to="1282" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting human olfactory perception from chemical features of odor molecules</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Gerkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Guan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dhurandhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Turu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Szalai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">355</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6327</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="820" to="826" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Boosting medical diagnostics by pooling independent judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kurvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Herzog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Carney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bogart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Zalaudek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wolf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8777" to="8782" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Debiasing people&apos;s estimates with cognitive models to improve crowd aggregation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Villarreal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1m7XIehCumtkeIfUvfw4Hxc-Yy8QOhuHS/view?usp=drive_link" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Poster presented at the Annual Meeting of the Society for Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>San Francisco, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using cognitive models to combine probability estimates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Danileiko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="273" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How social influence can undermine the wisdom of crowd effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lorenz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Rauhut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Schweitzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Helbing</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the national academy of sciences</title>
		<meeting>the national academy of sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9020" to="9025" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving collective estimations using resistance to social influence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Madirolas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>De Polavieja</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS computational biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1004594</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The wisdom of select crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mannes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Soll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Larrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">276</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological strategies for winning a geopolitical forecasting tournament</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mellers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ramos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Gurcay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Fincher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1106" to="1115" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cognitive diversity and consensus in group decision making: The role of inputs, processes, and outcomes. Organizational behavior and human decision processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mohammed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ringseis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="310" to="335" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Considering the impossible: Explaining the effects of implausible anchors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mussweiler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Strack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="160" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diversity of opinions promotes herding in uncertain crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Navajas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Armand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Deroy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Royal Society Open Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aggregated knowledge from a small number of debates outperforms the wisdom of large crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Navajas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Niella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Garbulsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sigman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Prediction diversity and selective attention in the wisdom of crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nobre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Fontanari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2001.10039</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Making the difference: Applying a logic of diversity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Page</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>Academy of Management Perspectives</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6" to="20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The difference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Page</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Difference</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modularity and composite diversity affect the collective gathering of information online</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Pescetelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rutherford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Rahwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3195</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prediction markets and the financial&quot; wisdom of crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ray</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Behavioral Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="4" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Open Anchoring Quest Dataset: Anchored Estimates from 96 Studies on Anchoring Effects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Röseler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Helgerth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Günther</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Tegethoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Schütz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Open Psychology Data</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ruggeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Panin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vdovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Većkalov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Abdul-Salaam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Achterberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The globalizability of temporal discounting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Toscano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1386" to="1397" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The wisdom of polarized crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Teplitskiy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Duede</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature human behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="329" to="336" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">PsyToolkit: A software package for programming psychological experiments using Linux. Behavior research methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Stoet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1096" to="1104" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PsyToolkit: A novel web-based method for running online questionnaires and reactiontime experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Stoet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Teaching of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The diversity gap: when diversity matters for knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sulik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Deroy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="752" to="767" />
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The wisdom of crowds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Surowiecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<pubPlace>Anchor</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judgment under Uncertainty: Heuristics and Biases: Biases in judgments reveal some heuristics of thinking under uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">185</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4157</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1124" to="1131" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring the crowd within: Probabilistic representations within individuals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Vul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Pashler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="645" to="647" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implications of attitude change theories for numerical anchoring: Anchor plausibility and the limits of anchor effectiveness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wegener</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Petty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Detweiler-Bedell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B G</forename><surname>Jarvis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="62" to="69" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Political coherence and certainty as drivers of interpersonal liking over and above similarity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zimmerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Garbulsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ariely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sigman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Navajas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1909</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
