<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Influences of familiarity and recollection on value-based decisionmaking</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Avinash</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Vaidya</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Cognitive, Linguistic and Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Brown University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Providence</settlement>
									<region>RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute on Drug Abuse Intramural Research Program</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Baltimore</settlement>
									<region>MD</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johanny</forename><surname>Castillo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Cognitive, Linguistic and Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Brown University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Providence</settlement>
									<region>RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology and Brain Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Massachusetts Amherst</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amherst</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alejandro</forename><surname>Torres</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Cognitive, Linguistic and Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Brown University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Providence</settlement>
									<region>RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Badre</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Cognitive, Linguistic and Psychological Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Brown University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Providence</settlement>
									<region>RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Carney Institute for Brain Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Brown University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Providence</settlement>
									<region>RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Influences of familiarity and recollection on value-based decisionmaking</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:13+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We regularly retrieve information from memory to inform decisions we make in daily life. For example, when choosing a place to eat, we may be enticed by a brand name because of its familiarity or drawn to an independent restaurant because of recollections of a delicious lunch we had there once before. Despite the centrality of memory in such everyday choices, it remains unclear how these different memory processes (i.e., familiarity versus recollection) influence decision-making. Here we describe a novel experimental paradigm that tests the independent contributions of these processes to value judgement during riskbased decision-making. In this task, participants had to retrieve the source of an image from an earlier encoding task to infer the probability of a bet being rewarded. We examined behavior in this task across two experiments, one conducted fully online and the second both online and in-laboratory. We found that familiarity, manipulated by the number of presentations during encoding, increased subjective value during memory-based decisionmaking. False familiarity even increased betting on lure items with which participants had no prior exposure. Further, we observed evidence that familiarity and source value information interacted, such the effect of both familiarity and source value information on betting were enhanced when both were high. Our results highlight the importance of subjective familiarity in both directly increasing perceived value, and indirectly influencing the use of value information retrieved from source memory.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Memory informs how we form preferences and evaluate options during our daily decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Weber &amp; Johnson, 2006)</ref>. For example, when choosing where to go for dinner, we might recall the uniquely enjoyable meal we had at a restaurant, or alternatively, the case of indigestion that followed the next day. Recently, several lines of research within cognitive neuroscience and psychology have focused on how recollection of this kind of value-relevant information serves learning and decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bakkour, Zylberberg, Shadlen, &amp; Shohamy, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bornstein &amp; Norman, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Scimeca &amp; Badre, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Shadlen &amp; Shohamy, 2016)</ref>.</p><p>Value judgments are not just influenced by information retrieved from memory, but directly impacted by internal memory signals. Familiarity, the sense of having previously observed an item absent any specific spatiotemporal context <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Yonelinas, 2001)</ref>, is thought to exert a direct influence on value judgment. Mere exposure, the presentation of a novel, affectively neutral stimulus, is enough to shift preferences towards greater liking on a rating scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bornstein &amp; D'Agostino, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Zajonc, 1968)</ref>, even under conditions when participants do not report observing the stimulus <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Zajonc, 2016)</ref>. Familiarity also affects behavior during risky decision-making: participants are averse to betting on novel stimuli, and are less willing to bet on relatively unfamiliar stimuli more generally <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Vaidya &amp; Badre, 2020)</ref>. Other recent work has demonstrated that participants are biased towards choosing options whose values and identity they can recollect, even when the values of these options are no better than the average value of alternatives <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Gluth, Rieskamp, &amp; Buchel, 2014)</ref>. This literature suggests that both recollection and familiarity can shape decision-making by reducing subjective uncertainty about option values.</p><p>Despite several lines of work pointing to the role of these memory signals in decisionmaking, there has been little work directly examining the separate and joint contributions of recollection and familiarity to value-based decision-making. These two processes are generally thought to be distinct and rely on dissociable neural substrates <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Ranganath et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Yonelinas, 2001)</ref>, and thus, they might make different contributions to the problem of value judgment. While familiarity signals are more general and would be expected to nonspecifically increase subjective value, recollection would be expected to change value judgments according to the specific details retrieved from a prior episode. Moreover, it is unclear whether participants would still rely on a non-specific familiarity signal when more specific and relevant information is available to bring to bear on a decision.</p><p>In this study, we sought to test the contributions of familiarity and recollection to risky decision-making. We developed a memory-based gambling task where participants could attempt to recollect trial-unique source information about a prior encounter with a stimulus in order to determine the probability of a bet being rewarded. Importantly, these stimuli had been encoded with different numbers of repetitions in an earlier phase and so also varied in their familiarity. Unlike other past work in this area, the value of these stimuli was not apparent at encoding and only became obvious at the betting stage. This design thus allowed us to decouple value at encoding from the contributions of familiarity and recollection to constructing the value of these options during decision-making.</p><p>Using this design, we tested the following four hypotheses: 1. Greater familiarity increases the subjective value of risky options, 2. Familiarity only increases the values of options in the absence of recollection, 3. Recollection and confidence in recollected information increases the value of options independent of the information retrieved, 4. Recollection of value-relevant information drives more accurate decision-making (i.e. better use of the real value of these options).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods: Experiment 1 Preregistration</head><p>The study hypotheses and experimental design were pre-registered prior to the start of data collection (https://osf.io/6qfdh).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Incidental encoding task</head><p>Participants first completed an encoding task where they saw 256 photos of scenes <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Konkle et al., 2010)</ref> in four quadrants of a 2 x 2 grid and were asked to complete the incidental encoding task of classifying these images as indoors or outdoors ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1a</ref>). The strength of this encoding varied with the number of stimulus presentations, with half of these scenes presented just once, and half appearing three times during this phase of the experiment. Each scene appeared in one of the four quadrants, with stimuli presented multiple times always appearing in the same quadrant on each presentation. The spacing of repeated presentations was randomized over the course of this encoding task, so there was no correlation between scenes in the one versus three presentation condition appearing earlier or later in the encoding task. Participants classified images by pressing the 'q' or 'p' keys on their keyboard, corresponding to text prompts on the left and right side of the screen indicating whether the scene was indoors or outdoors. The mapping between the keys and the indoor/outdoor classification was randomized trial-to-trial. Participants completed this encoding task in four blocks, each consisting of 128 trials. Each scene image appeared onscreen for three seconds. After participants responded, the text prompt corresponding to their response was underlined until the trial terminated. Trials were separated by a jittered inter-trial interval generated from a lognormal distribution with a mean of 1.0 s and standard deviation of 1.2 s.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Practice betting task</head><p>All participants completed a short practice (20 trials) of the risk-based betting task. The purpose of this practice task was to familiarize participants with the cues and probabilities for risky-decision making in the main task, and to act as a distraction during the delay separating the main memory-based betting task from the encoding phase ( <ref type="figure">Figure   1b)</ref>. In this task, participants learned that four color swatches were associated with different risk levels for rewarding a bet (red: 10%, light-red: 40%, light-green: 60%, green: 90%). A reference for these reward likelihoods and the color swatches was displayed throughout this task in the same 2 x 2 grid used in the encoding phase ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1b)</ref>, though there was no mention made of any relation between the two grids. The positions of these colors on this grid were randomized for each participant so that each quadrant was equally likely of being associated with higher or lower risk across participants.</p><p>On each trial, a square swatch in one of these colors was presented in the center of the screen (below the reference grid), and participants were offered the opportunity to either bet or pass on a chance of earning a bonus at the risk-level indicated by the swatch. Participants chose to bet or pass using the 'q' and 'p' keys on a keyboard, with the text prompts for each option randomly presented on either the left or right side from trial-totrial. Each trial was presented for 4 s. After a decision was made, the text prompt for the selected response was underlined until the end of this period.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Memory-based betting task</head><p>Next, participants were asked to complete a risky-decision task where the values of options depended on information that had to be retrieved from memory ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1c</ref>). This task consisted of 338 trials, the first 16 of which were a practice block which was not included in data analysis. The remaining trials were divided into seven blocks of 46 trials. Each trial consisted of a decision phase and two memory judgment phases. In the decision phase, the display was similar to that of the practice risk-based betting task, except a scene <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Example screenshots from different phases of the task. a. Incidental encoding phase where participants made judgments about whether scenes were indoors (in) or outdoors (out). b. Practice betting phase where participants made choices based on explicit risk indicated by a color swatch. c. Memory-based betting phase, where risk level had to be inferred from the position of the stimulus during incidental encoding. d. Familiarity judgment phase where participants rated the subjective familiarity of each image on a continuous scale from 1-5, e. Source judgment phase, where participants selected the previous quadrant in which the image appeared. f. Source confidence judgment where participants rated their confidence on a continuous scale from 1-5. image was presented in the center of the screen in place of a color swatch. Critically, the probability of the bet being rewarded depended on the quadrant in which that scene image had appeared during the encoding phase. The association between the different risk-levels and the quadrants was maintained from the practice betting task. The mapping between quadrant and risk was provided by the reference grid appearing at the top of the screen on every trial -as in the practice betting task.</p><p>Participants chose to bet on a chance of earning an extra $5 bonus, or to pass and accept a safe $2 bonus. Participants selected a response using their mouse to click on prompts that were randomly positioned on the left or right side of the screen. Participants were asked to use a mouse in this task (unlike the practice betting phase) so that they would not need to transfer between the keyboard and mouse in each trial between the decision phase and subsequent memory judgments (see below). The instructions stated that a single trial would be selected at random and their decision to bet or pass would be played out, so each choice was independently incentivized. Participants had 10 s to respond on each trial. After responding, their choice would be highlighted, and the trial would terminate after 1 s.</p><p>Following this decision phase, participants were asked to use their mouse to rate their familiarity for each image on a continuous scale from 1-5, with labels of 'sure new,' 'unsure' and 'sure old' at the 1, 3 and 5 positions, respectively ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1d</ref>). The image from the betting phase appeared above the scale with a prompt asking 'How sure are you that this is an OLD or NEW item?' Participants were given 10 s to respond to these familiarity ratings.</p><p>If participants indicated that they believed that the item was 'old' (i.e. a familiarity rating greater than 3), then participants were given 10 s to respond to an additional query about the source of the image <ref type="figure">(Figure 1e</ref>). Participants were presented with the image to the left of a small gray 2 x 2 grid representing the same grid from the encoding phase. They were asked to click the location in which the image had previously appeared during encoding. Participants were then asked to rate their confidence in this source judgment on a continuous scale from 1-5, with labels 'not at all,' 'somewhat' and 'very sure' at the 1, 3 and 5 positions ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1f</ref>).</p><p>In addition to the scenes from the encoding phase, participants also saw lure images during the betting phase of the experiment (i.e., scenes that had never appeared during encoding). Because of a coding error, the proportion of lure trials varied slightly for each participant (range 32.9-36.6%, mean = 34.6%, SD = 0.8%). This variance in the proportion of lures was randomized across participants and not systematically linked to any other change in the task conditions. All trials were presented in a randomized order with respect to their lure status, number of presentations and position of presentation in the encoding phase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Ninety-three participants were recruited via Amazon Mechanical Turk (MTurk) and completed the task on the online experiment platform Pavlovia. Participants were required to have a 90% approval rate on MTurk and had to correctly complete a simple math question to begin the task. Data was excluded from participants where accuracy was below 75% in the encoding task (N = 37), or because betting rates were extreme (i.e. greater than 99%, or less than 1%, N = 4). Data from eight participants was lost due to an error in saving data to the Pavlovia server. The average age for the remaining participants (N=44, 34 male, 10 female) was 38.1 years, SD = 10.7 years. Participants gave their informed consent to participate in this study via a checkbox, as approved by the Human Research Protections Office at Brown University and were compensated for their participation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical analysis</head><p>Generalized linear mixed effects models (LMEs) with a logit link function were used to estimate the contributions of different memory signals to bet or pass decisions. We first fit a model to data from all trials that included standardized familiarity ratings from each individual participant, a categorical variable coding whether an item was a target or lure, and the interaction between these terms.</p><p>We examined the contributions of source memory and familiarity to decision-making for target items that were deemed 'old' by the participants in a separate LME. This model included fixed effects parameters for standardized familiarity and source confidence ratings, as well as the standardized probability of reward associated with the source location that participants chose during the source judgment phase of the trial (i.e., the 'subjective probability of reward'). All two-way and the three-way interaction between these variables were also included. We also included the three-way interaction between source accuracy, source confidence and subjective probability of reward, and all two-way interactions between these variables.</p><p>For both models, we also included random effects for all model terms and their correlations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results: Experiment 1</head><p>We first examined the overall risk tolerance across all trials in the memory-based betting task and practice betting task. There was a significant negative effect for the intercept term (OR = 0.38, 95% CI: 0.20-0.71, P = 0.003), indicating a general tendency to avoid betting in the memory-based betting task (mean betting rate = 0.42, SD = 0.24).</p><p>We next turned toward answering how familiarity influenced betting rates. There was also a strong effect of familiarity <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 2a</ref>), with participants tending to bet more on items that they had rated as highly familiar (OR = 2.93, 95% CI: 2.04-4.19, P &lt; 0.001). Participants also bet less on lure items compared to targets overall (OR = 0.78, 95% CI: 0.33-0.92, P = 0.003). Nonetheless, the effect of familiarity was maintained for lure items when tested on their own (OR = 1.50, 95% CI: 1.08-2.08, P = 0.01), and there was no interaction between target/lure status and familiarity. (OR = 0.81, 95% CI: 0.57-1.13, P = 0.2). Thus, the perceived familiarity of an item increased willingness to bet even in absence of exposure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 2 b)</ref>.</p><p>To examine the role of source memory during choice, we specifically focused on target items that participants had correctly judged as 'old,' and then were queried about their source. Here we could examine how betting was adjusted according to participants' subjective probability of reward inferred from their source decisions, as well as their confidence in this source choice, and the objective accuracy of their source choice. As expected, participants bet more on items when they believed they had appeared in a source location associated with a higher probability of reward (OR = 2.09, 95% CI: 1.22-3.60, P = 0.008). While there was a trend for greater betting on items with greater source confidence, this did not reach significance (OR = 1.41, 95% CI: 0.95-2.0, P = 0.08), nor did the two-way interaction between source confidence and subjective probability (OR = 1.06, 95% CI: 0.90-1.26, P = 0.4). There was also no main effect of overall source accuracy (OR = 0.88, 95% CI: 0.55-1.40, P = 0.6). Thus, while betting was clearly influenced by subjective probability of Lure items. Familiarity ratings have been binned for easier visualization. Individual solid green and blue lines represent means for individual participants. Dashed black line represents the mean across participants. c. Mean betting frequencies for target items as a function of source memory accuracy (correct or error), confidence (low: source confidence rating ≤ 3, high: source confidence rating &gt; 3) and subjective probability of reward (10% or 40% (10-40), 60 or 90% (60-90)). Error bars in all panels represent the standard error of the mean. reward, we did not find evidence that participants' confidence and accuracy in these source judgments exerted a strong overall bias on decision-making, contrary to our hypothesis.</p><p>Notably, there was a significant three-way interaction between subjective probability, source confidence and source accuracy (OR = 1.47, 95% CI: 1.14-1.92, P = 0.003), as well as a significant negative interaction between source confidence and source accuracy (OR = 0.44, 95% CI: 0.28-0.69, P = 0.0003). Examining these data ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2c</ref>), these interactions appeared to be driven by an unexpected tendency for participants to bet more on items where they correctly indicated that the source was associated with a low probability of reward and had low confidence, compared to trials where they made errors in the source or then they remembered the item appearing in a high probability location.</p><p>We also tested if the contribution of familiarity to betting choices changed as a function of recollection in this same analysis of target items with reported high familiarity.</p><p>There was a trend toward an effect of familiarity and source confidence that did not reach significance (OR = 1.19, 95% CI: 0.99-1.42, P = 0.07). There was no significant interaction between familiarity and subjective probability of reward, nor any three-way interaction between familiarity, subjective probability of reward and source confidence (P's &gt; 0.3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion -Experiment 1</head><p>In this first experiment, we confirmed our hypothesis that subjective familiarity increases participants' tendency to bet. These results replicate the pattern observed in our previous study <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Vaidya &amp; Badre, 2020)</ref>, wherein participants were generally averse to betting on items that had not been observed before or had not been encountered for a long time. Our results also extend the classic mere exposure effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Zajonc, 1968)</ref>, demonstrating that the subjective feeling of familiarity increases the value of lure items to which participants were never exposed on the encoding phase.</p><p>As expected, participants also used recalled source information during decisionmaking -choosing to bet on options that they believed had appeared in sources associated with a higher probability of reward. However, confidence in the recalled source did not significantly impact betting decisions, though there was a trend in the expected direction. Contrary to our predictions, source confidence or accuracy did not change how participants weighed the recalled probabilities. Indeed, if anything, there was a surprising tendency for participants to bet more on low probability items when they had correctly identified the source, albeit with low confidence, compared to trials where they had made a source error. This was an unexpected effect and difficult to interpret. One possible explanation is that participants were more uncertain about the source in low confidence source error trials compared to trials where they correctly guessed the source, contributing to further discounting of the value of bets on these trials.</p><p>The interactions between familiarity and source memory were also different than we had hypothesized. Contrary to our expectations, the effect of familiarity was not reduced for successful recollection of the relevant source, or by confidence in recollected source information. If anything, there was a trend towards an over-additive interaction between source confidence and familiarity.</p><p>Importantly, a few design limitations complicated the conclusions we could draw from this initial experiment. First, all memory judgments were made immediately after participants made a bet or pass decision. This close temporal proximity could increase the chance that participants' memory judgments would be influenced by their choice, complicating our analysis of the causal role of these memory signals on choice. Second, by thresholding source memory judgments using familiarity, we reduced the amount of data available to test the effects of source memory. Further, we might have encouraged a strategy by which weaker items were rated as even less familiar in order to avoid a cognitively demanding source decision. This design also limited the range of familiarity signals included in these analyses to items that were perceived as 'old,' hampering our ability to test how the interaction between familiarity and source memory influences decision-making more generally. This reduction in the amount of data available similarly impacted our ability to test whether this recollection process differs in the case of lure items, where there was no true source memory.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2</head><p>In Experiment 2, we aimed to replicate and extend the results of the first experiment by making changes to the task that would address the limitations described above. First, memory judgments and betting decisions were presented in two separate phases, reducing the potential for participants to simply make memory judgments that conform to their decisions. Second, the order of memory judgments and betting decisions were counterbalanced across participants, so that we might control for any order effects for these two tasks. Third, participants made familiarity and source memory judgments in two separate phases of the experiment, and queries about the source were made about all items, old and new, regardless of their rated familiarity. This allowed us to break the interdependency between familiarity ratings and source judgments. Lastly, Experiment 2 was tested first online and then in an in-laboratory sample to address concerns about the quality of data in the online sample (described in further detail below).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods: Experiment 2 Preregistration</head><p>The study hypotheses and experimental design were pre-registered prior to the start of data collection (https://osf.io/wqfh2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>One hundred and seventy-three participants were recruited for the online version of this study via MTurk and completed the task on the online experiment platform Pavlovia. Requirement for participation were made stricter than the earlier online experiment with the aim of ensuring that more participants would adhere to task instructions: Participants were required to have a 95% approval rate and have completed at least 50 HITs on MTurk in addition to completing a simple math experiment. Data was excluded for participants where accuracy was below 75% in the encoding task or a substantial percentage of responses were missing (N = 59), or because betting rates were highly extreme (betting or passing on greater than 99% of trials, N = 9). Data from 17 participants was lost due to an error in saving data to the Pavlovia server. The remaining 88 participants (59 male, 28 female and participant who did not disclose their gender) had a mean age of 30.0 years (SD = 3.2 years). Participants gave their informed consent to participate in this study via a checkbox, as approved by the Human Research Protections Office at Brown University and were compensated for their participation.</p><p>The behavior of participants in the online sample indicated a failure of most participants to follow task instructions, particularly in engaging with the more demanding recollection of source memories during decision-making (see below). We thus also collected data from an in-laboratory sample of participants that we analyzed in the same way. Thirtysix participants were recruited for this in-laboratory replication of the online study (24 female, 12 male), with a mean age of 19.2 years (SD = 1.8 years). All participants in the inlaboratory sample had normal or corrected-to-normal vision and were screened for colorblindness, had no current psychiatric or neurological illness, and were not currently taking any psychoactive medications. Participants gave their written informed consent to participate in this study, as approved by the Human Research Protections Office at Brown University and were compensated for their participation. The rate of compensation was the same for the in-laboratory and online samples.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental design</head><p>The experimental design was very similar to that of Experiment 1, with a few important changes. As in Experiment 1, all participants first performed an incidental encoding task and practice betting task to familiarize them with the process of making bet or pass decisions based on reward probability. Participants were assigned to either a 'Memory-Betting' group where they were first asked to make familiarity and source judgments on all target and lure items before proceeding to the betting phase, or a 'Betting-Memory' group where the betting task preceded these memory judgments. This assignment was counterbalanced so that participants were evenly split between these two groups in both the in-laboratory (N=18 per group) and online samples (N=44 per group).</p><p>Unlike in Experiment 1, the familiarity and source judgments were made in separate tasks, each consisting of two blocks of 184 trials. Participants made source memory judgments on all target and lure items, independent of their familiarity ratings. However, the familiarity rating task always preceded the source judgment task for both groups. The format of these tasks was identical to the source and familiarity rating tasks in Experiment 1. However, for the in-laboratory group, the position of the mouse was reset to a location in the center of the screen beneath the Likert scale or source options at the start of each decision to minimize the degree to which the mouse position from the previous trial from influenced behavior on the current trial. Controlling the position of the mouse was not possible for the online sample.</p><p>The value of the safe option was also reduced to $1.50 from $2 in Experiment 1, as some participants in the previous experiment displayed very low overall betting rates across all trials -making it difficult to interpret how the memory conditions impacted their evaluation of each choice. We thus decreased the value of the safe option to encourage participants to consider the risky option more and engage further with the recollective processes needed to assess its value.</p><p>As with Experiment 1, the percentage of lure and target trials varied somewhat for each participant due to a programming error. Variance in the percentage of lures was randomly distributed across participants and not linked to changes in the proportion of other conditions. These percentages did not substantially differ between within the online or in-laboratory samples in the 'Betting-Memory (online: range: 32.3-36.3%, mean = 34.6%, SD = 0.9%; in-laboratory: range: 33.8-37.0%, mean = 35.2%, SD = 0.9%) or 'Memory-Betting (online: range: 32.5-37.0%, mean = 34.7%, SD = 1.1%; range: 33.5-37.3, mean = 35.1%, SD = 0.9%) groups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical analysis</head><p>As in Experiment 1, LMEs with a logit link function were fit to participants' betting data in both samples. The first model included all trials with fixed effects parameters for standardized familiarity, standardized source confidence, standardized subjective probability of reward, lure status and task order (i.e. 'Betting-Memory' or 'Memory-Betting') We also included interactions between lure status and each of these terms, interactions between task order and each of these terms, and the three-way interaction between lure status, familiarity and task order.</p><p>We also fit separate models to target and lure items. For target items, we included main effects of familiarity, source confidence, subjective probability of reward, task order, and source accuracy. We also included the three-way interactions between subjective probability of reward, source confidence and familiarity, as well as subjective probability of reward, source confidence and source accuracy, and all two-way interactions. Two-way interactions between task order and all of these terms were also included. For the lure item model, we included all of the same terms, excluding source accuracy and its interactions. All LMEs included participant random effects for all model terms, and their interactions, grouped by task order.</p><p>We also computed participant-wise metrics of familiarity performance from a model of familiarity based on signal detection theory. Specifically, we calculated d-prime metrics for each participant by taking the difference between z-scores corresponding to the hit and false alarm rates expected from the cumulative frequencies of these responses based on a standard normal distribution.</p><p>We also conducted secondary analyses examining the relationship of familiarity and source confidence. Exponential and linear functions were fit to the relationships between familiarity and source confidence ratings. In both cases, the functions were fit using the Matlab function 'fminunc' with a cost function based on the negative log likelihood estimated using a Gaussian probability density function. To avoid local minima, the models were fit 10 times for each participant with the parameters initialized at starting points randomly sampled from independent standard normal distributions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results: Experiment 2</head><p>As mentioned above, the behavior of participants in the online sample indicated that a sizeable percentage of participants were not compliant with the task instructions. In particular, betting rates did not vary significantly as a function of the subjective probability of reward, suggesting that they were not engaging with recalling the source of each item during the memory-based betting phase of this new version of the experiment where memory judgments and value-based choices were separated. Further, the overall performance of this group on the familiarity and source memory tasks was fairly poor. Given that we had little evidence that online participants followed the task instructions, results from the online sample are hard to interpret with regard to the experiment's goals. Nevertheless, we describe the results of the online study in the Supplementary Material to provide a more comprehensive accounting of our results.</p><p>We reasoned that an in-laboratory sample would be more likely to comply with the task instructions, and thus reproduced the same study design in-laboratory with the same analyses. Below we describe the result of the in-laboratory sample.</p><p>We first tested overall betting behavior in both the memory-based decision task and the practice betting task. There was a significant effect of the intercept term, indicating that participants tended to avoid betting overall (OR = 0.40, 95% CI: 0.25-0.64, P = 0.0001), similar to Experiment 1.</p><p>We next examined how betting varied according to item familiarity. Participants bet much more on items that they rated as familiar <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3a</ref>; OR = 1.93, 95% CI: 1.50-2.47, P &lt; 0.0001), and less on lure items (OR = 0.42, 95% CI: 0.29-0.60, P &lt; 0.0001). However, as with Experiment 1, the interaction of lure status and familiarity was not significant <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3b</ref>; OR = 0.92, 95% CI: 0.74-1.15, P = 0.5).</p><p>There were also much clearer main effects of source memory on betting rates. In line with instructions, participants bet more on items with a higher subjective probability of reward (OR =1.38, 95% CI: 1.19-1.60, P &lt; 0.0001). Participants also bet more on items they rated as having higher source confidence (OR = 1.36, 95% CI: 1.18-1.60, P &lt; 0.0001). The influence of subjective probability of reward on betting decreased for lure items compared to targets (OR = 0.87, 95% CI: 0.76-0.99, P = 0.04), though the influence of source confidence was not significantly changed for lures (OR = 0.90, 95% CI: 0.77-1.05, P = 0.2). There was no difference in overall betting rates for the 'Betting-Memory' and 'Memory-Betting' orderings of the task (OR = 1.61, 95% CI: 0.83-3.10, P = 0.1). Participants tended to bet more on lure items when completing the 'Memory-Betting' task order, but this effect did not reach statistical significance (OR = 1.62, 95% CI: 0.98-2.71, P = 0.06). The effects of familiarity, source confidence and subjective probability of reward also did not differ as a function of task order (P's ≥ 0.6).</p><p>Decisions were modulated based on recalled values, confidence in these recollections and accuracy <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3c</ref>). As with the online sample, there was no overall main effect for source accuracy (OR = 1.09, 95% CI: 0.91-1.23, P = 0.4), nor any significant two-way interaction between source accuracy and source confidence on betting rates (OR = 0.95, 95% CI: 0.83-1.10, P = 0.5). However, there was an interaction between source accuracy and subjective probability of reward such that participants in the in-laboratory sample bet more when they were correct about the item belonging to a source with a high probability of reward (OR = 1.18, 95% CI: 1.04-1.34, P = 0.01). This effect was also modulated by their confidence in this source decision, indicated by a significant three-way interaction of source accuracy, subjective probability of reward, and source confidence (OR = 1.27, 95% CI: 1.10-1.46, P = 0.0009). Participants thus used information from source memory during the decision task and weighted this recalled information based on their own confidence and the accuracy of recall.</p><p>The use of information from source memory was also modulated by familiarity <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3d)</ref>. In contrast to Experiment 1, there was a strong, over-additive three-way interaction between familiarity, subjective probability of reward and source confidence (OR = 1.12, 95% CI: 1.03-1.21, P = 0.007), such that participants bet most when all three of these factors were higher. This interaction indicates that participants bet much more when they reported an item was familiar, was associated with a high reward source and they were confident in this source. There were also significant positive two-way interactions between subjective probability of reward and source confidence (OR = 1.11, 95% CI = 1.02-1.21, P = 0.02), familiarity and subjective probability of reward (1.11, 95% CI: 1.02-1.20, P = 0.01), but not familiarity and source confidence (OR = 1.03, 95% CI: 0.94-1.12, P = 0.5). Thus, participant betting increased overadditively when they reported items were familiar and were confident in the item being from a source associated with a high perobability of reward.</p><p>We also carried out the same analyses on lure items. This interaction between source memory and familiarity was not as evident for lure items. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3e</ref>). Unlike targets, betting rates on lures did not vary according to a three-way interaction between familiarity, subjective probability of reward or source confidence (OR = 1.01, 95% CI: 0.93-1.10, P = 0.8). There were also no significant interactions between familiarity and source confidence and subjective probability of reward (P's &gt; 0.08). However, participants bet more on lures that they reported had been in high reward sources with high confidence (OR = 1.13, 95% CI: 1.02-1.26, P = 0.01), and that were rated as more familiar (OR = 1.64, 95% CI: 1.35-1.99, P &lt; 0.0001). This effect was modulated by task order, with the influence of familiarity on betting rates reduced in participants in the 'Memory-Betting' group (OR =0.72, 95% CI: 0.57-0.92, P = 0.008).</p><p>To establish whether this main effect of familiarity held for lures independent of task order, we separately tested this same LME in the 'Betting-Memory' and 'Memory-Betting' groups. The familiarity effect was present in participants who completed the 'Betting-Memory' order (OR = 1.67, 95% CI: 1.37-2.07, P&lt; 0.0001), and trended in the same direction but did not reach statistical significance for lures in the 'Memory-Betting' group (OR = 1.17, 95% CI: 0.99-1.39). Thus, familiarity appeared to drive betting most on lure items in absence of prior or proximal familiarity judgments, or any previous exposure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment -relationship of familiarity and source confidence</head><p>While we had initially hypothesized that familiarity and recollection of value relevant information might trade off in their influence on decision-making, instead we found evidence for an overadditive interaction between recalled probability of reward, source confidence and familiarity such that participants' betting rates raised most when all three of these were high. We hypothesized that both source confidence and familiarity ratings might be influenced by recollection in a subset of target trials, increasing the relationship between these two measures. Based on this hypothesis, we predicted that the relationship between familiarity and source confidence might be stronger on correct source memory judgments of targets compared to source errors and lure items. We further predicted that if recollection show betting rates as a function of familiarity for targets (a) and lures(b). Green and blue lines show individual participants, mean and standard error shown in dashed black lines. c. Betting rates as a function of the three-way interaction of source accuracy (correct or error), confidence (low: source confidence rating ≤ 3, high: source confidence rating &gt; 3) and subjective probability of reward (10% or 40% (10-40), 60 or 90% (60-90)). Panels d. and e. both show interaction between familiarity ratings (low: rating ≤ 3, high: rating &gt; 3), and source confidence for target items (d), and for lures (e). has non-linear dynamics (i.e. an 'all or nothing' process), then this relationship might better resemble an exponential function. We first assessed whether the relationship between source memory and familiarity could be better explained by an exponential or linear function. We focused this analysis on correct source judgments of target items, as we anticipated that the recollective process would be most pronounced within a subset of these trials. Neither model was strongly preferred based on the total negative log-likelihood across participants, though if anything, the linear model provided a slightly better fit (in-laboratory: linear = 1181.86, exponential = 1182.10). Comparison of the negative log-likelihood of each model for individual participants also indicated that the linear model was better fit for only a slightly larger percentage of participants (in-laboratory: 61.1%). The relationship between familiarity and source confidence was thus not obviously better fit by either function, though the linear function was slightly preferred.</p><p>Next, we asked whether the relationship between familiarity and source confidence changed as a result of recollection. We compared the slopes for the linear function fit to the familiarity and source confidence ratings for target items where participants made correct and incorrect source judgments, and for lure items. The relationship between familiarity and source confidence had higher slopes for both target items with correct and erroneous source judgments over lures (t(35) ≥ 6.36, P's ≤ 0.0001, Cohen's d's ≥ 1.06, corrected), and for items where participants made correct source judgments over errors (t(35) = 5.36, P &lt; 0.0001, Cohen's d = 0.89, corrected). The same general pattern of results was observed in the online sample (Supplementary Material), and when the slope was fit using an exponential function (not shown).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion -Experiment 2</head><p>The second experiment replicated the general effect of familiarity increasing participants' betting rates for target items in both samples. We also extended the findings of <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. Slopes for a linear function fit to the relationship between familiarity and source confidence for different item types (lures, targets with correct and incorrect source judgments). *** P &lt; 0.0001, two-tailed within-subjects t-test, corrected for multiple comparisons. the first experiment by demonstrating how familiarity interacted with value information recalled from source memory. Participants bet most when they were confident that target items originated from sources associated with a higher probability of reward, and these items were subjectively familiar. This relationship between familiarity and source confidence was stronger for targets compared to lure items in both samples, and generally higher for correct source judgements compared to errors, suggesting that this relationship was strongest when source information was retrieved. However, based on these data alone, we could not reliably determine whether this relationship was linear or exponential. These ratings may both reflect a common recollective process, creating the perception of a more linear relationship. There may also be individual differences between participants in how much they separate between these constructs in their judgments. Notably, the main effect of familiarity on betting also held for both task order variations, whether betting preceded or followed memory judgements. Thus, we were able to overcome a limitation of the first experiment by showing that the influence of familiarity on decision-making does not just reflect a confirmatory judgement on the part of the participant. Participants also tended to bet more on lures if they made memory judgments about these stimuli prior to the betting task. This behavior could reflect the influence of mere exposure on subjective value <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Zajonc, 1968)</ref>, or the re-encoding of these novel lures as subjectively old stimuli during the memory judgement phase. However, this effect did not appear to be related to a change in use of familiarity for making betting decisions about these lures. Indeed, if anything, the influence of familiarity on betting for lure items appeared to be reduced for participants who had completed the memory judgment tasks first. Completing these familiarity ratings on lures thus did not create a confirmatory bias for participants to bet more in line with their previous ratings. Thus, exposure to lures in the memory judgment phase tended to increase participants tendency to bet on these items while also reducing the influence of subjective familiarity for lures. Carrying out these memory judgments might provide a meta-memory benefit by making participants more aware of the presence of these lures, leading them to discount their familiarity during the betting phase.</p><p>As noted above, our online sample did not appear to be as engaged with the memorybased aspects of the task. Unlike Experiment 1, participants had to make source and familiarity judgements for every item, unbroken by other tasks -like the memory-based decisions. This made the memory judgments in Experiment 2 longer and more repetitive, and may have contributed to online participants disengaging from the task, reducing the quality of their performance.</p><p>The differences between participants' behavior in the two samples provides an instructive example of the challenges of running online studies with open-ended problems like value-based decision-making, where multiple behavioral strategies might be considered legitimate. For example, participants in the online sample may have considered the marginal value of carrying out recollection to be lower than that of betting randomly, given the time and cognitive effort that a recollection strategy would require -particularly when further time commitment could come at the cost of not completing other online tasks for additional compensation. We further discuss the interpretation of data from the online sample in the supplementary material. While it is typical to increase sample size in anticipation of higher inter-individual variance in an online sample, as we did here, this design provides limited protection against the differences in strategies and priorities for online samples compared to those in-laboratory <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Stewart et al., 2017)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>Here we describe two experiments examining the role of different memory processes during risky decision-making. We introduced a novel experimental paradigm that allows for reward probability and strength of encoding to be experimentally orthogonalized and makes it possible to examine the interactions of familiarity and recollection during value judgment. We had hypothesized that familiarity would increase the perceived value of options, but this effect would be tempered by recollection of relevant source memories. We further hypothesized that recollection and subjective confidence in recalled value information would increase subjective value, and increase the precision of decision-making so that participants would make choices more in line with recalled values. We confirmed that familiarity exerts a strong influence on decision-making, however contrary to our expectations, the influence of familiarity did not diminish with better source memory. Instead, we observed an increase in betting rates when participants judged an item was familiar and associated with a high probability of reward with high confidence. These results indicate that familiarity enables increases in subjective value when participants recall high value associations.</p><p>Across both experiments, we found that item familiarity increased participants' betting rates across all reward probabilities, in line with the hypothesis that familiarity generally increases subjective value of options, even when unrelated to task goals <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bornstein &amp; D'Agostino, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Zajonc, 1968)</ref>. Notably, we also found that familiarity increased betting rates even in absence of prior exposure (i.e., with lures) in Experiment 1 and in the inlaboratory sample in Experiment 2. This observation across experiments indicates that exposure is sufficient, but not necessary, to increase familiarity-driven changes in subjective value. The familiarity attributed to lures, likely driven by the frequency of their contents in daily life or commonalities with targets <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Coane, Balota, Jacoby, &amp; Dolan, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Reder et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Roediger &amp; McDermott, 1995)</ref>, thus contributes to an increase in value that is not explained by exposure alone. While this effect of familiarity was not observed in the online sample in Experiment 2, the null effect is likely related to the higher behavioral variance in the online sample, and the smaller number of trials for lures relative to targets, providing less samples per participant to sample this intra-individual variance.</p><p>Contrary to our initial hypothesis, participants did not rely on familiarity less when they could recall value relevant information from source memory across experiments. Instead, in the in-laboratory sample in Experiment 2, familiarity appeared to act as a gate on the use of this source information in making betting decisions -evident in an overadditive three-way interaction between familiarity, source confidence and subjective reward probability on betting frequency. Our findings thus suggest a dual role for familiarity in memory-based decision-making, both in increasing subjective value directly and in mediating the use of retrieved values.</p><p>This interaction between familiarity and value information in source memory is in line with evidence that retrieval is gated by familiarity signals, allowing for more selective engagement of this more demanding process when familiarity is higher <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Hayama &amp; Rugg, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Kahn, Davachi, &amp; Wagner, 2004)</ref>. Thus, the present evidence suggests familiarity might similarly gate retrieval of value information from source memory. This function would also be consistent with adaptive memory theories suggesting that retrieval is balanced between the importance of the memory being retrieved and likelihood of retrieval success, and the costs associated with retrieval <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Anderson &amp; Milson, 1989)</ref>.</p><p>This interaction between source memory and familiarity during decision-making might depend on cortico-striatal-thalamic circuitry that has been more broadly implicated in action selection. Several lines of evidence point toward the striatum playing a key role in gating motoric and cognitive actions and thus mediating control over behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Frank, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Goldberg et al., 2013)</ref>. Our group has previously proposed the striatum as a hypothesized neurobiological mechanism for gating retrieved information <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Scimeca &amp; Badre, 2012)</ref>. In particular, across studies, we have previously shown that signals in the striatum are correlated with feedback-related changes in decision threshold during familiarity judgments <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Scimeca et al., 2016)</ref>, and with betting decisions for unfamiliar items <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Vaidya &amp; Badre, 2020)</ref>. This striatal gating mechanism could thus be a common feature of decisions about memory, value and recollection.</p><p>An alternative to this gating account is that familiarity and value information in source memory are integrated together into a common scalar value signal. For example, familiarity might have a multiplicative influence on risk, or lower the ambiguity for the range of plausible values, resulting in the same kinds of non-linear dynamics that are well characterized for probability and amount in standard risky decision-making tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Hsu et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Levy et al., 2010)</ref>. Recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Weilbächer et al., (2020)</ref> showed that individual differences in memory bias during a decision-making task were not correlated with behavior in descriptive risk and ambiguity tolerance tasks, suggesting that memory biases on decision-making rely on separate processes from those involved in risk and ambiguity tolerance. However, it is possible that ambiguity or risk derived from memory signals could influence decision-making more like experienced risk, where behavior tends to also deviate from that in descriptive risk tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hertwig &amp; Erev, 2009)</ref>.</p><p>Another alternative explanation for how familiarity impacts choice is that this signal might increase confidence in decisions based on the value of retrieved information. Decision confidence can increase for both positive and negative values when based on an increased distance from the decision boundary -i.e. when a bet or pass choice is less ambiguous <ref type="bibr">(De Martino et al., 2012)</ref>. Similarly, familiarity might increase decision confidence for retrieved values on either side of the decision boundary, sharpening the choice function. However, the average betting rate did not substantially drop for high familiarity, high source confidence decisions where the subjective probability of reward was lower, arguing against this explanation.</p><p>Retrieval of source information appeared to influence both familiarity and source confidence ratings, as these measures were correlated, and the strength of this correlation increased in trials where accurate recollection was more likely (correct source judgements), or possible (target items). One explanation for this increased slope is the recollection of highly specific memories from encoding -which could increase both of these measures. Taken together with our findings from the betting phase of the task, participants may bet most when they can recollect that an image was linked to a high reward source.</p><p>One noteworthy limitation of our experimental design was that we only focused on conditions where there was a potential reward for betting and an opportunity cost for passing. We did not examine any conditions with aversive outcomes or losses where recalled values should actively drive participants away from betting more. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Weilbächer et al., 2020)</ref> showed that participants' bias towards recalled items flips for losses, as they prefer to choose options with an indefinite value than a retrieved loss. However, it is not clear how the familiarity effects observed here would interact with losses. For example, if familiarity is truly serving a dual role, the interaction between familiarity and loss amount might be expected to flip into the negative direction, though the main positive effect of familiarity on betting rates might be preserved.</p><p>Here we examined the separate contributions of familiarity and source memory in a novel decision paradigm that allowed us to test the role of these memory processes on value judgment while removing any potential circular influence of value information on memory strength. Our findings highlight the centrality of familiarity in memory-based valuation and decision-making. Familiarity both increases subjective value and positively interacts with value information that must be recalled from source memory. Future behavioral or neuroimaging studies may help untangle the mechanisms by which familiarity influences value judgement, or examine how the use this information is disrupted by memory impairments. The paradigm described here provides a promising platform for testing these mechanisms and understanding how dysfunction within memory systems could contribute to decision impairments in neurodegenerative disorders.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment -Online Sample</head><p>The behavior from the online sample indicated a failure of a large proportion of these participants to comply with the basic task instructions and that they did not engage with the memory-related aspects of the task. As a consequence, these data are challenging to interpret and bear limited relevance to the hypothesis we intended to test. However, in an effort to provide full reporting and to limit publication bias (i.e. the 'file drawer problem'), we are reporting the planned analyses that we conducted on these data. We believe these findings may be informative, particularly for those wishing to reproduce our results or design similar experiments. We discuss these implications following our report of the results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2 -Memory and Decision-Making Performance</head><p>We first evaluated the effects of familiarity, source memory and lure status, as well as their interactions, on participants betting decisions in a model that included both target and lure trials. Unlike in Experiment 1, there was no significant effect for the intercept term (OR = 0.89, 95% CI: 0.59-1.34, P = 0.6), indicating that participants did not show any overall bias towards betting or passing.</p><p>Next, we assessed how familiarity influenced decisions during the memory-based betting task. We replicated the strong overall effect for familiarity to increase betting rates ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure S1a</ref>; OR = 1.25, 95% CI: 1.11-1.40, P = 0.0001), and the tendency for participants to bet less frequently on lure items in general (OR = 0.68, 95% CI: 0.58-0.79, P &lt; 0.0001). However, unlike in Experiment 1, there was a significant interaction between lure status and familiarity such that the influence of familiarity was reduced for these lure items ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure S1b</ref>; OR = 0.90, 95% CI: 0.82-0.98, P = 0.03).</p><p>We also examined how source memory for reward information affected betting rates across all trials. There was a significant effect of source confidence (OR = 1.06, 95% CI: 1.00-1.13, P = 0.04), but no significant effect for the subjective probability of reward (OR = 1.04, 95% CI: 0.98-1.10, P = 0.2). Unlike familiarity ratings, there was no significant interaction between these effects and the lure status of items (P's ≥ 0.4).</p><p>We also tested whether these effects differed by the order of the betting and memory judgment tasks within the experiment (i.e. 'Memory-Betting' or 'Betting-Memory'). There was no change in the overall rate of betting based on task order (OR = 0.79, 95% CI: 0.44-1.40, P = 0.4) While there was a trend toward a greater effect of subjective probability of reward for the 'Memory-Betting' group (OR = 1.08, 95% CI: 0.99-1.17, P = 0.07), the effects of familiarity and source confidence reward did not differ by task order (P's ≥ 0.1). However, participants were much more likely to bet on lure items if they had completed the memory judgment task before betting (OR = 1.39, 95% CI: 1.13-1.72, P = 0.002), indicating that either exposure or probing participants about their memory for these lure items changed their willingness to engage with a bet. This change in betting on lures did not seem to be driven by a change in the role of familiarity, as the three-way interaction between lure status, familiarity ratings and task order was not significant (OR = 0.92, 95% CI: 0.80-1.06, P = 0.2).</p><p>Next, we specifically examined how retrieval of source memories impacted betting on targets by examining the main effect of source accuracy and its interactions with source confidence and subjective probability of reward ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure S1c</ref>). There was no main effect of source accuracy on betting rates, nor any significant two-or three-way interactions between source accuracy and subjective probability of reward and source confidence (P's ≥ 0.5). Thus, there was no clear evidence that participants were using information retrieved from source memory in this betting task.</p><p>We also examined the interactions of source memory judgments and familiarity, as part of our planned analyses. Betting rates tended to increase more for items with a higher subjective probability of reward and higher familiarity -but this trend was not statistically significantly ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure S1d</ref>; OR = 1.04, 95% CI: 1.00-1.07, P = 0.07). There were also no significant interactions between familiarity and source confidence, or any significant threeway interaction between familiarity, source confidence and subjective probability of reward (P's ≥ 0.5). As in Experiment 1, the two-way interaction of source confidence and subjective probability of reward was not significant (OR = 1.01, 95% CI: 0.96-1.05, P = 0.7). Thus, not surprisingly, given the lack of evidence for a use of source memory, participants' choices were not clearly influence by source confidence and the subjective probability of reward and there was no evidence interaction with familiarity.</p><p>We finally examined the role of familiarity and source memory on betting for lure items ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure S1e</ref>). Unlike in Experiment 1, there was no significant effect for familiarity in lure items alone (OR = 1.08, 95% CI: 0.97-1.20, P = 0.1). There were also no main effects of source confidence or subjective probability of reward (P's ≥ 0.4), nor any significant two-or three-way interactions between these source memory signals with each other or with familiarity (P's &gt; 0.3). There was thus little indication of what, if anything, changed participants' betting behavior for lure items in the online sample in Experiment 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment -Comparison of memory performance across samples</head><p>The betting behavior in the online and in-laboratory samples for Experiment 2 differed considerably. While both samples showed the expected increase in betting on subjectively familiar items, the influence of source information on betting rates was generally much clearer in the in-laboratory sample. We suspected that this difference might reflect a disparity in the extent to which participants in these two samples engaged in the memory judgments in this task. To answer this question, we compared these two samples on source memory accuracy and recognition performance.</p><p>Participants in the in-laboratory sample performed significantly better on memory tasks compared to the online sample. We estimated the accuracy of participants' source memory by calculating frequency in which they accurately identified the correct source Betting rates as a function of the three-way interaction of source accuracy (correct or error), confidence (low: source confidence rating ≤ 3, high: source confidence rating &gt; 3) and subjective probability of reward (10% or 40% (10-40), 60 or 90% (60-90)). Panels d. and e. both show interaction between familiarity ratings (low: rating ≤ 3, high: rating &gt; 3), and source confidence for target items (d), and for lures (e).  during the source judgment phase of the task ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S2a</ref>). The source accuracy of both samples was significantly greater than chance in both the online sample (one-sample, onetailed t-test: t(87) = 3.91, P &lt; 0.0001, Cohen's d = 0.42), and in-laboratory sample (t(35) = 6.42, P &lt; 0.0001, Cohen's d = 1.07). However, overall, the source accuracy of the in-laboratory sample was also significantly greater than their online counterparts (independent samples, two-tailed t-test: t(122) = 5.19, P &lt; 0.0001, Cohen's d = 1.03). We also examined performance on the recognition memory test, calculated as a d-prime score ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S2b</ref>). The d-prime score was significantly greater than zero in the online sample (one sample, one-tailed t-test: t(87) = 9.84, P &lt; 0.0001, Cohen's d = 1.05), and in-laboratory samples (t(122) = 14.61, P &lt; 0.0001, Cohen's d = 1.56). However, as with source memory performance, the in-laboratory d-prime scores were significantly greater than the online sample (independent samples, two-tailed t-test: t(122) = 6.26, P &lt; 0.0001, Cohen's d = 1.24).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2 -relationship of familiarity and source confidence</head><p>We carried out the same test of the relationship between source memory and familiarity in the online sample which we had also tested for the in-laboratory participants. As with that sample, neither a linear nor exponential function was overwhelmingly a better fit to these data based on the total negative log-likelihood across participants (online: linear = 2464.89, exponential = 2464.97. Similarly, the linear model was a better fit for only a slightly larger percentage of participants (online: 55.7%).</p><p>We also compared the slopes for the linear function fit to the familiarity and source confidence ratings for target items where participants made correct and incorrect source judgments, and for lure items. Similar to the in-laboratory sample, the slope of this function <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S2</ref>. Comparison of performance in recognition memory and source memory between Experiment 2 samples. a. Source accuracy for target items, chance rate (25%) is indicated by the red dashed line. b. d-prime based on hit and false alarm rates in recognition memory judgements. *** P &lt; 0.0001, two-tailed between-subjects t-test, ### P &lt; 0.0001, two-tailed one sample t-test against chance. was higher on both correct and erroneous source judgments compared to lures ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S3</ref>; within-subject, two-tailed t-test: t(87) ≥ 4.92, P's ≤ 0.0001, Cohen's d ≥ 0.52, corrected). The slope of this function was also numerically higher for correct source judgments compared to errors, though this effect did not survive correction for multiple comparisons (t(87) = 2.13, P = 0.1, Cohen's d = 0.23, corrected).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2 -Online Sample Discussion</head><p>The behavior of this online sample indicated lack of compliance with task instructions. In particular, these participants did not significantly modulate their betting rates according to the subjective probability of reward. In a value-based decision-making paradigm such as this, there is no one 'right' way to complete the task, as the problem is inherently one of personal choice and subjective assessment. However, we would expect that decisions should be modulated by the subjective probability of reward -if participants were trying to recall the source of each item during the memory-based decision-making phase. These online participants also performed significantly worse in source memory and familiarity judgments compared to the in-laboratory sample. Thus, the on-line participants seemed to be less engaged with the memory-related aspects of the task and/or less willing to use information stored in memory to make choices. As our hypotheses assumed participants engagement with the task and active use of memory during decision-making, we believe these data have limited value for answering our scientific questions. However, these results do provide some useful insight into how small differences in task design and administration can substantially alter results, which we explore below.</p><p>There are many potential reasons for these differences from the in-laboratory sample, who completed the same experiment, and the participants in Experiment 1 who <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure S3</ref>. Slopes for a linear function fit to the relationship between familiarity and source confidence for different item types (lures, targets with correct and incorrect source judgments). *** P &lt; 0.0001, two-tailed within-subjects t-test, corrected for multiple comparisons. completed a similar task online. The task itself was longer than in Experiment 1, and the memory judgments were more repetitive and had a greater separation from the decision task. Our in-laboratory participants were also monitored by an experimenter throughout the task, while online participants completed the experiment without any external supervision. Online participants are also likely more motivated to complete experiments quickly and devote less time and cognitive effort to demanding recollection tasks so that they may complete other tasks and earn more money in a shorter amount of time. The participants in the online sample were also likely more experienced with these kinds of tasks, which may have made them less interested in this particular experiment. Notably, there were some commonalities in the results for the online and inlaboratory samples. There was a small, albeit noisy, bias towards betting on more subjectively familiar target stimuli in the online sample. The steepness for the relationship between source confidence and familiarity also increased for targets compared to lures, as in the in-laboratory sample. Thus, effects of familiarity might be more easily detectable than those that depend on a more demanding and complicated retrieval process.</p><p>The differences between the online and in-laboratory sample indicate important considerations for designing studies examining interactions between memory and decisionmaking. Future work will need to ensure that participants are equally motivated to engage in the value-based decision-making aspects of the task as well as memory judgments that help support interpretation of decision behavior. These data also speak to how small changes in the way an experiment is conducted can dramatically change the results. Experimenters must exercise caution when interpreting replication failures and consider how seemingly small changes in the sample or task administration can have cascading consequences for compliance with instructions and task strategy.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Behavioral results from Experiment 1. Panels a and b show betting frequencies as a function of item familiarity ratings in Experiment 1. a. Target items, b.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Behavior from the in-laboratory sample in Experiment 2. Panels a. and b.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure S1 .</head><label>S1</label><figDesc>Behavior from online sample in Experiment 2. Panels a. and b. show betting rates as a function of familiarity for targets (a) and lures(b). Green and blue lines show individual participants, mean and standard error shown in dashed black lines. c.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human-Memory -an Adaptive Perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Milson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295x.96.4.703</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/Doi10.1037/0033-295x.96.4.703" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="703" to="719" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Value-based decisions involve sequential sampling from memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bakkour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zylberberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/269290</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1101/269290" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reinstated episodic context guides samplingbased decisions for reward</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bornstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.4573</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4573" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stimulus recognition and the mere exposure effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Bornstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Agostino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037//0022-3514.63.4.545</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037//0022-3514.63.4.545" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="552" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Not all sources of familiarity are created equal: The case of word frequency and repetition in episodic recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Coane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Balota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Jacoby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/S13421-010-0069-5/FIGURES/6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/S13421-010-0069-5/FIGURES/6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="791" to="805" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational models of motivated action selection in corticostriatal circuits</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/J.CONB.2011.02.013</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/J.CONB.2011.02.013" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Neurobiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="386" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural evidence for adaptive strategy selection in value-based decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Buchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/cercor/bht049</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bht049" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cereb Cortex</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2009" to="2021" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Basal ganglia output to the thalamus: still a paradox</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Farries</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/J.TINS.2013.09.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/J.TINS.2013.09.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Neurosciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="695" to="705" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Right dorsolateral prefrontal cortex is engaged during post-retrieval processing of both episodic and semantic information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rugg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/J.NEUROPSYCHOLOGIA.2009.04.010</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/J.NEUROPSYCHOLOGIA.2009.04.010" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2409" to="2416" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The description-experience gap in risky choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Erev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/J.TICS.2009.09.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/J.TICS.2009.09.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="517" to="523" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neuroscience: Neural systems responding to degrees of uncertainty in human decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bhatt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Adolphs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tranel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Camerer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/SCIENCE.1115327/SUPPL_FILE/HSU.SOM.PDF</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/SCIENCE.1115327/SUPPL_FILE/HSU.SOM.PDF" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5754</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1680" to="1683" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Functional-Neuroanatomic Correlates of Recollection: Implications for Models of Recognition Memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Kahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Davachi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0624-04.2004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0624-04.2004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4172" to="4180" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scene memory is more detailed than you think: The role of categories in visual long-term memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Konkle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Alvarez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797610385359</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797610385359" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural representation of subjective value under risk and ambiguity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Snell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rustichini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Glimcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1152/JN.00853.2009/ASSET/IMAGES/LARGE/Z9K002109952000</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1152/JN.00853.2009/ASSET/IMAGES/LARGE/Z9K002109952000" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1036" to="1047" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recollection is a continuous process: Implications for dual-process theories of recognition memory: Research Article</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mickes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Wais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="509" to="515" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recollection is a continuous process: Implications for dual-process theories of recognition memory: Research Article</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mickes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Wais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/J.1467-9280.2009.02324.X/FORMAT/EPUB</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/J.1467-9280.2009.02324.X/FORMAT/EPUB" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="509" to="515" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissociable correlates of recollection and familiarity within the medial temporal lobes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ranganath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Yonelinas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Esposito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/J.NEUROPSYCHOLOGIA.2003.07.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/J.NEUROPSYCHOLOGIA.2003.07.006" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Mechanistic Account of the Mirror Effect for Word Frequency: A Computational Model of Remember-Know Judgments in a Continuous Recognition Paradigm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Reder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nhouyvanisvong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Schunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Ayers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Angstadt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hiraki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0278-7393.26.2.294</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0278-7393.26.2.294" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="294" to="320" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating False Memories: Remembering Words Not Presented in Lists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Roediger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Mcdermott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0278-7393.21.4.803</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0278-7393.21.4.803" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Striatal contributions to declarative memory retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Scimeca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Badre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2012.07.014</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2012.07.014" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="380" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Striatal prediction errors support dynamic control of declarative memory decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Scimeca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Katzman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Badre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/ncomms13061</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms13061" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision Making and Sequential Sampling from Memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.neuron.2016.04.036</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2016.04.036" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="927" to="939" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crowdsourcing Samples in Cognitive Science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chandler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Paolacci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/J.TICS.2017.06.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/J.TICS.2017.06.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="736" to="748" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural systems for memory-based value judgment and decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Vaidya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Badre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1162/jocn_a_01595</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1162/jocn_a_01595" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Constructing Preferences from Memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Construction of Preference</title>
		<editor>Lichtenstein &amp; P. Slovic</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Reflection Effect in Memory-Based Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Weilbächer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kraemer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797620956315</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797620956315" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1439" to="1451" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Components of episodic memory: the contribution of recollection and familiarity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Yonelinas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/RSTB.2001.0939</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/RSTB.2001.0939" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London. Series B: Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">356</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1363" to="1374" />
			<date type="published" when="1413" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attitudinal Effects of Mere Exposure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Zajonc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/H0025848</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/H0025848" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2 PART 2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mere Exposure: A Gateway to the Subliminal</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Zajonc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1467-8721.00154</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/1467-8721.00154" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="224" to="228" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
