<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Running head: EFFECT OF MEMORABILITY ON CHOICE</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xinyue</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Chicago</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wilma</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Chicago</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Chicago</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Akram</forename><surname>Bakkour</surname></persName>
							<email>bakkour@uchicago.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Chicago</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Chicago</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>5848 S University Ave</addrLine>
									<postCode>60637</postCode>
									<settlement>Chicago</settlement>
									<region>IL</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Running head: EFFECT OF MEMORABILITY ON CHOICE</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:17+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>While making decisions, we often rely on past experiences to guide our choices. However, not all experiences are remembered equally well, and some elements of an experience are more memorable than others. Thus, the intrinsic memorability of past experiences may bias our decisions. Here, we hypothesized that individuals would tend to choose more memorable options than less memorable ones. We investigated the effect of item memorability on choice in two experiments. First, using food images, we found that the same items were consistently remembered, and others consistently forgotten, across participants. However, contrary to our hypothesis, we found that participants did not prefer or choose the more memorable over the less memorable items when choice options were matched for the individuals&apos; valuation of the items. Second, we replicated these findings in an alternate stimulus domain, using words that described the same food items. These findings suggest that stimulus memorability does not play a significant role in determining choice based on subjective value.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Memorable but not chosen: no effect of memorability on value-based decisions</head><p>Decisions are ubiquitous in everyday life. When deliberating about what to eat, for example, an individual can compare the values they place on different choice options and choose the food that holds higher value. When one of the choice options holds much higher subjective value than the others, the choice is easy, and a decision is made quickly. However, when deciding between choice options of equal value, the decision is more difficult, and the same individual requires more time to make a decision <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Basten et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hunt et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Krajbich et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Mormann et al., 2010)</ref>. Previous research has shown that some of this additional time for difficult decisions may go toward memory processes that help resolve the decision conflict <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bakkour et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Biderman et al., 2020)</ref>. However, it is unlikely that these memory processes are deployed equally across choice options, given that not all items are equally memorable. Evidence has shown that some items are intrinsically more memorable than others across observers <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bainbridge, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">Xie et al., 2020)</ref>. If individuals retrieve memories to guide their value-based decisions, it stands to reason that items that are more prioritized in memory would have more influence on the individuals' choices. The current study investigates the influence of memorability (i.e., how likely an item is memorized and later remembered) on people's value-based choices.</p><p>Relational memory, or the ability to remember the associations between elements of an event or a series of events, influences decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Biderman et al., 2020)</ref>. By retrieving experiences related to the choice options at hand, individuals can predict the outcome of different choices to guide their decision <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Bornstein &amp; Norman, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Liashenko et al., 2020)</ref>. This important role for relational memory in choice is supported by past research that identified a role for the hippocampus (a brain region that is crucial for relational memory) in deliberation during value-based choices <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bakkour et al., 2019)</ref>. Healthy individuals deliberate more when the decision is difficult, like when the values of choice options under consideration are matched. However, amnesic patients due to damage to the hippocampus did not exhibit a relationship between deliberation time and choice difficulty. These findings provide evidence for a necessary role of the hippocampus in deliberation and suggest an important role for relational memory in normative value-based decision making processes.</p><p>Relatedly, factors such as familiarity may impact the deliberation process during valuebased decisions and sometimes bias individuals to choose less preferred options. For example, individuals tend to evaluate more familiar names of cities as more popular, suggesting that individuals' memory influences the decision making process <ref type="bibr">(Honda et al., 2011)</ref>. Past research has also shown that differences in memory strength can bias decisions for better-memorized options <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Mechera-Ostrovsky &amp; Gluth, 2018)</ref>. The impact of memory and personal experience in value-based choices is well known. Yet not all elements of an experience are equally well remembered. Indeed, when asked to commit items to memory, people remember certain items better than others, regardless of the individual's familiarity with the items. Thus, more memorable items may be prioritized for retrieval during decision making and bias choices.</p><p>Memorability refers to the extent to which items are accurately remembered across people <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bainbridge, 2019)</ref>. Despite individual differences in prior experiences and familiarity, people consistently remember and forget the same images <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bainbridge et al., 2013)</ref>. Crucially, this implies that images can be quantified by a "memorability score" that reflects the likelihood that a given image will be remembered across people. A growing body of work has shown that the memorability of a given image is indeed constant across different experimental tasks and image contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bainbridge, 2020)</ref>, participant samples <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Xie et al., 2020)</ref>, and image categories . This consistency across tasks, people, and images occurs regardless of the specific measure used, including corrected recognition (CR), d-prime, hit rate, and false alarm rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bainbridge et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bainbridge &amp; Rissman, 2018)</ref>. Functionally, given that memorability is intrinsic to the stimulus, it can be quantified using trained machine learning algorithms and used to predict memory behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Khosla et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Khosla et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr">Needell &amp; Bainbridge, in press)</ref>. Memorable items also result in stereotyped brain patterns in late visual and memory areas <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bainbridge et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bainbridge &amp; Rissman, 2018)</ref>, and are reinstated earlier in the brain and cause more memory intrusions than forgettable items <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Xie at al., 2020)</ref>. These results support the notion that memorable items may be prioritized for retrieval.</p><p>Here, we investigated whether people's decisions are influenced by the memorability of choice options. By bridging prior research on both value-based decision making and memorability, the current work clarifies the cognitive mechanisms underlying value-based decisions. Based on previous literature that implicates relational memory in biasing decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Basten et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Biderman et al., 2020)</ref>, we hypothesized that participants will be more likely to choose items that have a higher memorability score when the subjective values of the choice options are the same. According to our hypothesis, participants will need more time to deliberate to resolve conflict when memorability is matched across choice options. Thus, we predicted that there would be a relationship between reaction times and the difference in memorability scores of the choice options, controlling for value.</p><p>In the two experiments reported here, we tested the predicted relationship between memorability and value-based choices for food items. We examined this relationship across two different modalities, testing visual-based decisions (with food photographs) and semantic-based decisions (with food names). In Experiment 1, we first measured the memorability scores of food images using a continuous recognition memory task (Experiment 1A). We then tested another group of participants' value-based choices for these foods (Experiment 1B). In a second experiment, we replicated our results using names of the food items depicted in the images used in Experiment 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1</head><p>The goal of Experiment 1 was to (1) measure memorability scores of images of food through a "memory game" <ref type="bibr">(Isola et al., 2011, Experiment 1A)</ref>, and (2) test whether participants tended to choose more memorable food items using a value-based choice task (Experiment 1B).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1A: Memorability Task</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Stimuli. The image stimuli in Experiment 1 were taken from the Food Folio stimulus set published by the Columbia Center for Eating Disorders <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Lloyd et al., 2020)</ref>. This stimulus set contains 138 images of food items that are familiar to the U.S. population and form a variety of categories (high/low calories and fat, fruits, snacks, etc.) All images were 410 × 410 pixels in size and depicted different food items located at the center of the image placed on a white plate with a black background.</p><p>Participants. Two hundred and nineteen participants in total were recruited on Amazon Mechanical Turk (AMT) and compensated $7.50/hour for their time. All participants provided informed consent before participating in the study. Instructions for the task were provided to the participants at the beginning of the experiment, followed by two comprehension questions regarding the instructions. The comprehension checks were designed to ensure participants were proficient in English and fully understood the task. Only participants who answered the questions correctly within 3 attempts continued to the task. Twenty participants who performed poorly on the memory task (defined by fewer than 3 hits or 3 correct rejections) were excluded. This resulted in a final sample of 199 participants (35% women, ages ranging between 18-35). The sample size was selected so that each image was viewed as a target in the memory task by at least 40 participants, to allow for a reliable estimate of image memorability .</p><p>All experimental procedures were approved by the University of Chicago Internal Review Board (IRB).</p><p>Task. To measure each food item's memorability score, participants engaged in a continuous recognition task where they identified repeats amongst a stream of food images. We adopted and modified the Memorability Experiment Maker to create our online experiment <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bainbridge, 2017)</ref>. During the study, participants viewed a stream of food images and were asked to press the 'r' key on the keyboard when they saw an image for a second time <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bainbridge et al., 2013)</ref>. Each image was displayed for 1 second, with a 1-second interstimulus interval ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1A</ref>). For each participant, the stimuli were randomly divided into 29 targets and 109 fillers. The targets were repeated after more than 60 trials (120 seconds). The fillers were used to fill in the gaps randomly between the first and second presentations of targets, and some of them repeated at most once after a brief delay (1-7 trials). The task took approximately 14 minutes to complete. Only the performance for target images was used to calculate the memorability score.</p><p>Filler responses were used to check if participants were paying attention to and performing the task as instructed. Each image was randomly assigned as a target for 42 participants on average.</p><p>After completing the task, participants provided demographic information and answered questions about their general food preferences (i.e., whether they are vegetarian, and whether they have any food allergies). . Participants (N = 199) were asked to view a stream of images and press the 'r' key on the keyboard if they saw a repeated image. Images were randomly classified as filler or target for each participant, and the spacing between the first and second display was different for targets and fillers. B. Value-based choice task (Experiment 1B). In the rating phase, participants (N = 44) were asked to rate all of the 138 food items based on their preference (0 = least prefer to eat this food, 10 = most prefer to eat this food). In the choice phase, participants were asked to choose the item that they would like to eat as a snack. Participants had 3s to make their choice. The chosen item was then highlighted for 500ms. Choice trials were separated by 1000ms intertrial interval.</p><p>Data Analysis. Analyses of the data were conducted using R software (R Core Team, 2017). The memorability score of each food item was calculated as Corrected Recognition (CR), which is the hit rate minus the false alarm rate for trials where the image was assigned as the target <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bainbridge, 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Consistency of memorability scores. To evaluate whether the memorability scores were consistent across participants, we split participants into two random halves and calculated memorability scores (CR) for all images for each half. We repeated this process for 1000 iterations. We then calculated the Spearman rank correlation between the two sets of CR scores (first random half versus second random half) across items for each iteration.</p><p>Data and code availability. Data and analysis code for all experiments is available at the following link: https://github.com/christineli0330/mem_dm_share.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The calculated memorability scores showed variability across 138 food stimuli with a median of 0.48 ( <ref type="figure">Figure 2A</ref>). The minimum score was -0.03 for saltine crackers, meaning that participants did poorly in remembering this image and tended to misidentify it as old when seeing it for the first time. The maximum score was 0.86 for sliced pizza, meaning that participants were good at remembering this image and correctly identifying it with minimal false alarms. The consistency analysis revealed that the memorability scores were consistent across participants (ρ = 0.29, p &lt; 0.001, <ref type="figure">Figure 2B</ref>), indicating that participants indeed tended to remember and forget the same images, regardless of individual experiences. We also predicted the memorability scores for images using ResMem, which is a recently developed deep neural network (DNN) model for predicting image memorability (hit rate) across a wide range of images <ref type="bibr">(Needell &amp; Bainbridge, in press)</ref>. ResMem predictions were significantly positively correlated with the hit rates measured in Experiment 1A (r(136) = 0.24, p = 0.004), suggesting that the memorability scores are robust and intrinsic to the stimuli. The consistency of memorability across participants and methods implies that memorability is a meaningful property of these images: some of these food images are easier to remember than others. This allows us to directly test how images with different memory fates influence decision making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2. Image memorability scores differ across items but are consistent across participants.</head><p>A. Distribution of calculated memorability scores (corrected recognition, CR) for food items with an example of items with extreme memorability scores. The median of the memorability scores is 0.48 (dotted vertical line). B. Consistency of image memorability scores. Split-half consistency is depicted using ranked average memorability scores across 1000 iterations of random sample splits. For each iteration, we randomly grouped participants into 2 groups: Group 1 and Group 2, and calculated the memorability scores for each image. We plotted the image memorability scores for Group 1 participants (dark blue line) against their memorability rank on the x-axis, the image memorability scores for Group 2 participants (light blue line), and the line for a permuted estimate of chance (grey line) against the same memorability rank. Group 1 and Group 2 show significant consistency in which images they remembered and forgot (p &lt; 0.001).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1B: Value-Based Choice Task</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Stimuli. The stimuli were the same as in Experiment 1A.</p><p>Participants. Sixty-one participants were recruited on the online behavioral research platform CloudResearch <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Litman et al., 2017)</ref>, where the experiment was conducted through AMT, and participants were compensated $7.50/hour for their time. All participants provided informed consent before participating in the study. Seventeen participants were excluded because they failed to pass the comprehension check or did not reach inclusion criteria based on their reaction times (RT) and choice performance. The criteria are detailed in the next paragraph. This resulted in a final sample of 44 participants (30% women, ages ranging between 21-42). All participants in the two experiments were located in the U.S. and proficient in English.</p><p>We established exclusion criteria to make sure participants fully understood our task and were attentive. First, we checked if participants tended to choose left or right items disproportionately. We excluded three participants whose probability of choosing items on the right was 2 standard deviations away from the mean of all participants. We also excluded 2 participants because their average RT was less than 300 ms in more than half of the trials, which is not enough time to make value judgments. Moreover, we calculated delta value (Δvalue): the difference in subjective values of the two choice options. We z-scored the subjective values placed on all items for each participant, and then we used the z-scored value of the item on the right minus the z-scored value of the item on the left for each choice trial. Then, we performed logistic regressions to test the effect of Δvalue on choices for each participant separately. We excluded 12 participants that had negative parameter estimates or a non-significant effect of Δvalues on choices, since this indicated that their rated subjective values (from the rating phase described below) were not in accord with their choice preferences. Note that this means that, by necessity, we will observe a relationship between value and choice in the analyses of Δvalue.</p><p>However, our key questions focus instead on the role of memorability in choice.</p><p>Task. Experiment 1B was made up of two phases: a rating phase and a choice phase ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1B</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Rating phase.</head><p>Participants were asked to rate all 138 food stimuli on a scale from 0 to 10 for how much they would prefer to eat that food today. A score of 0 indicated they did not want to eat that food at all, while 10 indicated that they most strongly preferred to eat that food. The images were presented on the screen one at a time, with a slider bar at the bottom ranging from 0 (least) to 10 (most). Participants used a computer mouse to make their responses. Preference ratings that reflected the subjective value placed on the food stimuli (from 0 to 10) were recorded.</p><p>Choice phase. After the rating phase, the 138 food items were ranked based on the individual participant's subjective value ratings that they just reported during the rating phase.</p><p>The food items were then grouped into two sets of pairs for the choice phase of the experiment.</p><p>First, items that were close in terms of subjective value were paired together, forming 69 pairs of items of similar value. Second, items that were distant in terms of subjective value were paired together, with a distance of 68 ranks (e.g. the 1 st ranked and the 69 th ranked items were paired together), forming another 69 pairs of items. Therefore, half of the image pairs were very close in terms of subjective value, while half were distant in terms of subjective value. The combined 138 pairs of items were unique for each participant, and all pairs were presented once in separate trials during the choice phase.</p><p>After a short break following the rating phase, participants took part in the choice task. In the choice phase, two food items appeared on the screen, placed to the left and right of a central fixation point. Participants were instructed to choose one item per trial by pressing one of two keys on their keyboard; they pressed the 'j' key to select the item on the left and the 'k' key to select the item on the right. They were allotted up to 3 seconds to make their choice. After they made a response, the chosen item was highlighted with a green box for 0.5 seconds, followed by fixation. The trial duration was fixed at 3.5 seconds so that participants could not finish the task early by making faster choices. If they made the choice faster than 3 seconds, the rest of the time was added to the inter-trial fixation period. Participants were notified if they made a choice too quickly (shorter than 300 ms) or too slowly (longer than 3s). The order of trials and the positions of the items on the screen (left/right) were randomized. Participants' choices and RT were recorded.</p><p>Data analysis. We calculated absolute delta memorability (|Δmem|) for each trial: the absolute difference in corrected recognition score between paired items in each choice trial. We used the lme4 package in R <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bates et al., 2015)</ref> and performed repeated-measures mixed-effects logistic regression models to test the effects of absolute value difference (|Δvalue|) and |Δmem| on value-based choices among all participants separately. In order to investigate the relationship between value and choice behavior without influence from memorability, we used a median split on |Δmem| to select the half of the choice trials where items had a low difference in memorability. We entered |Δvalue| as a fixed effect in the mixed-effects logistic regression model to predict the probability of choosing the higher-valued item. As random effects, we included intercepts for subjects and by-subject random slopes for the effect of |Δvalue|. For a second model, we used a median split on |Δvalue| to select the half of the trials where items had a low value difference, in order to investigate the relationship between memorability and choice behavior without influence from value. We entered |Δmem| as fixed and by-subject random slopes in the mixed-effects logistic regression model in predicting the probability of choosing more memorable items.</p><p>Beyond choice behavior, we also examined the relationship between RT during the choice phase and the two variables of |Δvalue| and |Δmem| by fitting a linear mixed-effects model. Prior studies have shown that participants tend to make slower decisions if the subjective values of the two items are similar <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Mormann et al, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Krajbich &amp; Rangel, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bakkour et al., 2019)</ref>. Therefore, when the values of the two items in a pair are similar, we predicted slower RTs compared to when the two items differed on value. We also predicted that when items are close in terms of value but different in terms of memorability, participants would tend to spend longer on choices when |Δmem| is small compared to when |Δmem| is large. Reaction times are not normally distributed; thus we logistically transformed the RT data to reduce skewness and conform to the regression model's assumptions. For testing the relationship between RT and value difference, we entered |Δvalue| as a fixed effect to predict the log-transformed RT in the linear mixed-effects model. We entered random intercepts for subjects and by-subject random slopes for the random effect of |Δvalue|. Also, to explore the relationship between RT and the difference in memorability between options, we entered |Δmem| as a fixed effect to predict the log-transformed RT in the linear mixed-effects model We also entered random intercepts for subjects and by-subject random slopes for the random effect of |Δmem|.</p><p>To explore the relationship between the subjective values obtained in the rating phase and the memorability scores, we averaged subjective value ratings across participants for each of the 138 items, and calculated the correlation between averaged subjective ratings and memorability scores.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Relationship between value and choice. First, we tested the relationship between choices and item value. To eliminate the potential influence of memorability on choices, we selected trials where |Δmem| was low or close to zero using a median split (Supplement S1). The mixed-effects logistic regression showed that |Δvalue| was related to choice behavior (Odds Ratio (OR) = 3.57, 95% Confidence Interval (CI) = 2.88 -4.43, p &lt; .001), meaning that the difference between the values significantly predicted participants' choice of items in trials for which |Δmem| was near zero ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3A)</ref>. Note that based on our exclusion criteria, this relationship is necessarily significant. Furthermore, in the linear mixed-effects model of RT, |Δvalue| significantly negatively related to RT <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 3B)</ref>, where the greater the difference in value between the two items, the less time was needed to make the decision (β = -0.04, CI = -0.06 --0.02, p &lt; .001). This finding is in accord with previous studies that showed individuals tend to make faster choices for larger |Δvalue| pairs <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Krajbich &amp; Rangel, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Mormann et al, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bakkour et al., 2019)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relationship between memorability and choice.</head><p>To answer the main question posed in this study, we also examined the effect of |Δmem| on participants' choices and RTs. We selected trials where |Δvalue| was low or close to zero using a median split (Supplement S1) so that the effect of value difference can be controlled. Contrary to our prediction, |Δmem| was not related to choice behavior (OR = 0.80, CI = 0.42 -1.52, p = 0.49, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3C</ref>). In addition, there was no significant relationship between |Δmem| and RT ( = -0.03, CI = -0.13 -0.06, p = 0.51, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure   3D</ref>). These results do not support our hypotheses that participants would choose more memorable items, or that participants would make slower choices when options are equally memorable compared to when one item is much more memorable than the other. Relationship between memorability and subjective value. To investigate whether a relationship between subjective value and memorability scores could explain the non-significant results, we explored possible correlations between the two variables across food images. The Pearson correlation between averaged subjective values of food stimuli and the memorability scores showed a non-significant positive correlation (r(136) = 0.15, p = 0.07), meaning that the memorability scores do not explain much variance in the averaged subjective value of foods in this sample.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The measured memorability was consistent across participants as well as the DNN predictions for this set of image stimuli <ref type="bibr">(Needell &amp; Bainbridge, in press</ref>). However, the memorability scores and the average per-item subjective values were not correlated. These results are in accord with previous literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bainbridge, 2019)</ref> that memorability is an independent attribute of visual stimuli that cannot be fully explained by any other attributes.</p><p>By design, the difference in values between choice options (|Δvalue|) showed a strong relationship with the choices participants made: participants tended to choose higher-valued items. Based on previous literature that showed people's value-based choices are highly related to their indicated subjective values of each item <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Mormann et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Krajbich &amp; Rangel, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bakkour et al. 2019)</ref>, this pattern of results functions as a sanity check for participants' performance. Moreover, replicating this prior work, we observed a significant inverse relationship between |Δvalue| and RT: individuals tended to respond faster when they encountered choice options that had a larger value difference, and they tended to respond slower when the choice options were close in value.</p><p>While our main hypothesis for the study was that individuals would tend to pick more memorable items over less memorable ones if the value difference between items remains relatively close, our results did not show a significant relationship between memorability and choice behavior. There is no evidence to suggest that participants preferred the more memorable items over the less memorable ones while making decisions between food items. The difference in memorability between choice options is also not related to reaction times while making decisions; two items that are equally memorable are not necessarily harder to choose between.</p><p>This finding contradicts our prediction that participants would make faster choices if one of the items was much more memorable than the other. Additionally, we did not observe a correlation between memorability and the subjective value of food images. This led us to further explore whether the memorability of semantic representations of food biases peoples' value-based choices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2</head><p>Since Experiment 1 showed no relationship between image memorability and choice preference for food images, we tested whether the semantic representations of food items are an important factor in the relationship between memorability and choice. If the image is not representative of the food, participants may make different decisions when presented with word labels of the choice options than if images are used. Therefore, the procedure of Experiment 2 followed that of the previous experiment except that (1) the stimuli were changed from images to words, and (2) we conducted an additional first experiment (Experiment 2A) with a different participant sample to evaluate how representative a given semantic label was for its corresponding food image. The measure of representativeness ensures that the stimuli used in Experiments 1 and 2 are equivalent, and allows us to test whether any effects of value or memorability are related to how well the food images match their corresponding words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2A: Representativeness Task</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Stimuli. We used the same set of food items as in Experiment 1. The words for the food items were coded based on the file name of the images from the original stimulus set <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Lloyd et al., 2020)</ref>. To make the words standardized, we removed the brand names of the food when they were not necessary for identification (for example, we removed the brand name "Skippy" from peanut butter). All of the words were displayed in lower case, and the length of words ranged from 3 to 34 characters with a mean of 12.5 characters. Some examples of words were: pizza, mini muffins, and kit kat (see <ref type="table">Supplement Table S1</ref> for the full list).</p><p>Participants. Forty participants (48% women, ages ranging between 22-39) were recruited on CloudResearch <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Litman et al., 2017)</ref>, which is a participant-sourcing platform for online research, and the experiment was conducted through AMT.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task.</head><p>To check if the images of food items in Experiment 1 are representative of their word labels used in Experiment 2, we designed a representativeness task and recruited a new sample of participants online. On each trial of the representativeness task, participants saw the name of a food item for 4 seconds. Participants were asked to picture the food depicted by the word(s) in their mind on a white plate. They were then presented with the image (used in Experiment 1) of the food depicted by the label. Participants were instructed to rate how much the image on the screen matched the food they depicted in their mind. They rated each image on a scale from 0 to 10, with 0 being 'does not match all' and 10 being 'perfect match' ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4A</ref>). Participants (N = 40) were asked to picture the food depicted by the word in their mind first, then view and rate how representative the presented image was of the food they imagined. B. The memorability task in Experiment 2B was identical to that in Experiment 1A, except the foods were depicted by words, rather than images (N = 195). C. The value-based choice task in Experiment 2C was identical to that in Experiment 1B, except the food choice options were depicted by words, rather than images of food (N = 45).</p><p>Data analysis. We calculated the z-scored representativeness ratings across items for each participant, and averaged the z-scored representativeness rating for each image across all participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The representativeness scores were calculated based on the averaged z-scored ratings (M = 6.9, SD = 1.23). The representativeness of images was positively correlated with the average value of images across participants (r(136) = 0.18, p = 0.03), suggesting that participants tend to evaluate highly representative images as higher valued in general. There was no correlation between the representativeness scores and neither image memorability (r(136) = 0.08, p = 0.33) nor word memorability (see Experiment 2B, r(136) = 0.04, p = 0.65), indicating that the memorability of images are not associated with whether the images are representative of the food items at the semantic level.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2B: Memorability Task</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Stimuli. The stimuli were the same words as in Experiment 2A.</p><p>Participants. In Experiment 2B (memorability task), 227 participants were recruited on AMT in order to calculate memorability scores from the average memory response of at least 40 participants for each word stimulus . We excluded 32 participants because they performed poorly on the memory task (fewer than 3 hits or 3 correct rejections). This resulted in a final sample of 195 participants (27% women, ages ranging between 18-35).</p><p>Task. The memorability task followed the same procedures in Experiment 1A. The only difference is that each visual image was changed to the word(s) for the corresponding food item ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4B</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data analysis.</head><p>We performed the same analysis as in Experiment 1A.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The calculated word memorability scores varied across items (M = 0.26, SD = 0.12, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5A</ref>). The minimum score was -0.03 for "skittles", and the maximum score was 0.59 for "kit kat". The split-half consistency analysis indicated that the word memorability scores were consistent across participants (ρ = 0.25, p = 0.01, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5B)</ref>; people remembered and forgot the same food words. Distribution of calculated word memorability scores for food items, with examples shown for words with extreme memorability scores. The median of the word memorability scores was 0.25 (dotted vertical line). B. Consistency figure for word memorability scores in Experiment 2B. The split-half consistency is plotted using ranked average word memorability scores across 1000 iterations of random participant splits. As in Experiment 1A, we plotted the averaged word memorability scores for Group 1 participants (dark blue line) against their rank on the x-axis, scores for Group 2 participants (light blue line), and the scores estimated by random permuted chance (grey line) against the same memorability rank. Group 1 and Group 2 show significant consistency in which words participants remembered and forgot (p &lt; 0.001).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2C: Value-based Choice Task</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Stimuli. The stimuli were the same as in Experiments 2A and 2B.</p><p>Participants. In Experiment 2C (value-based choice task), 59 participants were recruited.</p><p>Fourteen of them were excluded based on the same exclusion criteria as in Experiment 1: three participants were excluded because their probability of choosing items on the right was 2 standard deviations away from the mean across participants. As in Experiment 1B, we calculated delta value (Δvalueword), and performed logistic regressions to test the effect of Δvalueword on choice preferences for each participant separately. Eleven participants were excluded because they had negative parameter estimates or a non-significant effect of Δvalueword on choices, which indicates that their choice preferences did not conform to the subjective preferences they stated during the rating phase. This resulted in a final sample of 45 participants (45% women, ages ranging between 22-48).</p><p>Task. The value-based choice task followed the same procedures as in Experiment 1B.</p><p>The only difference was that each visual image was changed to the word(s) for the corresponding food item ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4C</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data analysis.</head><p>We performed the same analyses as in Experiment 1B.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Relationship between value and choice. Like in Experiment 1, we first tested the relationship between choices and item value. To control for the possible effect of memorability on choices, we selected trials where |Δmemword| was low or close to zero using a median split (Supplement S2). The mixed-effects logistic regression showed that value was related to choice behavior (OR = 6.56, CI = 5.05 -8.51, p &lt; .001), meaning that the value placed on food words predicts food choices ( <ref type="figure">Figure 6A</ref>). Note that this relationship is necessarily significant because of our exclusion criteria. In the linear mixed-effects model of RT, |Δvalueword| was significantly negatively related to RT (β =-0.06, CI = -0.08 --0.05, p &lt; .001, <ref type="figure">Figure 6B</ref>), which is consistent with previous literature and Experiment 1B. This finding confirms that individuals tend to spend more time deliberating when faced with choice options that are close in value <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Mormann et al, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Krajbich &amp; Rangel, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bakkour et al., 2019)</ref>. The significant relationship between |Δvalueword| and choices (as well as RT) replicate well-known effects and indicate that participants were actively engaged in the word choice task. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>. Subjective value, but not word memorability, relates to choice behavior and speed. The proportion of more-valuable item choice (A) and RT (B) plotted as a function of |Δvalueword| for trials where |Δmemword| was low or near zero. The proportion of more-memorable item choice (C) and RT (D) plotted as a function of |Δmemword| for trials where |Δvalueword| was low or near zero. All of the models had 3080 trials. In each plot, the solid black line represents the predicted regression line. The shaded gray area represents the 95% confidence intervals. The trial data were binned into 5 equal-sized bins on the x-axis. The black dots represent the mean proportion of choosing a higher-valued item (top-left), choosing the more memorable item (top-right), or mean RT (bottom) across participants within bins. Error bars are standard error of the mean across participants within bins.</p><p>Relationship between memorability and choice. We tested the effect of |Δmemword| on participants' choices and RTs to test whether word memorability influences item choice. We controlled for the influence of value difference on choices by selecting trials where |Δvalueword| was close or equal to zero (Supplement S2). Consistent with what we found in Experiment 1B, |Δmemword| was not related to choice behavior (OR = 1.10, CI = 0.55 -2.20, p = 0.79, <ref type="figure">Figure   6C</ref>), and was not related to RT (β = -0.04, CI = -0.13 -0.06, p = 0.46, <ref type="figure">Figure 6D</ref>). These results replicate the non-significant findings in Experiment 1B and do not support our hypothesis that participants may prefer more memorable food items and make choices slower if the memorability scores for food items are close to one another.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The words used in Experiment 2 to describe the images of food used in Experiment 1 were largely representative of the latter. More representative word-image pairs were rated higher on value by participants, but representativeness was not associated with either word or image memorability. These results further support prior findings that memorability is an attribute that differs from semantic information or subjective preferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bainbridge, 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Compared to image memorability <ref type="figure">(Figure 2A</ref>), word memorability ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5A</ref>) scores were lower on average, but still showed high variance, with some words having high memorability scores, and others having very low memorability scores. Furthermore, like for the images, memorability scores for the words were highly consistent <ref type="bibr">(Figures 5B)</ref>. This suggests that the memorability of semantic information-like image memorability-is also a stimulusbased attribute that is independent from personal experiences.</p><p>The results of Experiment 2B and 2C fully replicated those of Experiment 1. The difference in values between the choice options showed expected and characteristic relationships with choices and RT. We had predicted that participants would tend to choose more memorable words than forgettable ones when the values of the two options were similar. But no evidence was found to support this prediction. These results support an account that memorability has no influence over value-based decisions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>The purpose of the current work was to quantify the influence of memorability on valuebased choices. We hypothesized that individuals may prefer more memorable items in binary value-based choices when the values of the choice options are similar. To test the hypothesis, we measured the memorability scores for food stimuli and conducted choice tasks in which the pairs of items varied in terms of the difference in memorability scores and difference in subjective values. Surprisingly, replicating across different stimulus formats (images and words), we did not find a relationship between item memorability and the choices participants made. Although participants were highly consistent in what food items they remembered and forgot, their choice behavior did not reflect these stimulus-based memory effects.</p><p>One possible explanation of these results is that memorable items may not be positively valenced, and thus not preferred, even though they are prioritized in memory. For example, more negative attributes are correlated with face memorability while positive attributes are not <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bainbridge et al., 2013)</ref>. It could be that more extreme items are more memorable regardless of valence and therefore would not drive choices uniformly. In addition, one study has shown that imbuing a stimulus with reward value does not alter its memorability <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bainbridge, 2020)</ref>.</p><p>Specifically, even when participants are rewarded with money to remember and forget certain images, the original memorability of the image has a stronger influence on their memory than the reward ascribed to that image, suggesting that the encoded value based on past experiences might not interact with the memorability of stimuli to influence memory. The current results add evidence to these prior accounts that stimulus memorability is dissociable from valence or preference.</p><p>Although we do not observe a relationship between stimulus memorability and choice behavior here, extensive prior work has shown a direct link between memory and decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Bornstein &amp; Norman, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bakkour et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Liashenko et al., 2020)</ref>. These results could thus suggest two dissociable aspects of memory: the specific memory experiences of an individual, and the intrinsic pull of the stimulus (memorability).</p><p>Specifically, the effect of memory on decision making could be driven by individuals' specific memories, such as their prior experiences with those food items, or the contexts in which they learned about those food items. In contrast, global stimulus memorability (which stimuli are easier to remember or forget) may have less influence on individuals' decisions. Indeed, key differences have been observed between subject-based memory and stimulus-based memorability in other work. For example, for scene and face images, there are low or no correlations between true image memorability and what people think they will remember <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Isola et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bainbridge, 2017)</ref>, indicating that memorability is dissociable from individualized inferences of memorability. Other work has shown that an individual's current state and image memorability are independent, non-interacting predictors of memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Wakeland-Hart et al., 2021)</ref>. Further, neuroimaging work has identified separable patterns in the brain for stimulus memorability and markers of memory in a given individual <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bainbridge et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bainbridge &amp; Rissman, 2018)</ref>. These results, in combination with the current work, support the idea that memory retrieval processes involved in making decisions might be distinct from retrieval of the features that make certain stimuli memorable or forgettable. Furthermore, it is thought that the construction of subjective value may rely on familiarity or individual memory <ref type="bibr">(Honda et al., 2011</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">, Mechera-Ostrovsky &amp; Gluth, 2018</ref>, rather than on stimulus memorability. Therefore, memorability may be a global stimulus feature that helps to organize and prioritize perceptual information in memory, but decision making is driven by more idiosyncratic or familiarity-based memories at the individual level.</p><p>The current study presents some limitations that can guide future study. First, the study was conducted online, and participants made hypothetical decisions that were not incentive compatible; participants were not offered a food chosen during the task as a snack to eat at the end of the experiment. In contrast, in the value-based choice task conducted by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bakkour et al. (2019)</ref> and others, participants had a chance to receive the actual food item as a snack based on their indicated subjective values after the rating, which may have motivated participants to make more veridical evaluations about their preference of each food item. Future in-person studies that better incentivize participants and encourage them to pay full attention to the task are needed to solidify conclusions from the null effect of memorability on value-based choices found in the current study. Second, we used food stimuli in this study because people have strong pre-existing subjective preferences for food. However, the subjective values placed on food might be too strong a determinant of choice that they override a moderate, if any, effect of memorability on choice. Future studies are needed to investigate the effect of memorability on choice in a reward learning design: participants might have better performance in associating rewards with memorable items versus forgettable ones, and make subsequent decisions differently. Future studies should also replicate these effects across other stimulus types beyond food images and names, in case there are behaviors or processes specific to food-related decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Xue et al, 2022)</ref>.</p><p>Despite these limitations, the current research can be seen as a first step towards integrating two lines of research-value-based decision making research and the field of memorability. To our knowledge, the effect of memorability on choice has not been previously investigated. The finding that value-based choices and reaction time is largely related to the subjective value of foods is consistent with previous literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Krajbich et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Krajbich &amp; Rangel, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bakkour et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Biderman et al., 2020)</ref>, suggesting that people spend more time deliberating their choice when the values of choice options are close. Also consistent with previous work, the measure of food item memorability was highly consistent across participants using both image and word stimuli. Measured image memorability was consistent with predictions from a neural network, demonstrating that memorability is a robust attribute of these stimuli <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bainbridge et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Needell &amp; Bainbridge, in press</ref>).</p><p>Finding no relationship between memorability and choice is informative and useful.</p><p>Beyond the contribution to understanding the role of memory in decision making processes, these results have important implications for the real world. The results of this study suggest that people's value-based decisions are not biased by more memorable environments (or advertisements)-individuals do not tend to choose more memorable options when asked about their preferences. Also, our results show that memorability is unlikely to be a confound in valuebased choice tasks. While the specific images and words that we use may have a strong influence on our memories, those same forces do not appear to influence our decisions. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure S1</ref>. Distribution of absolute delta image memorability among choice trials in Experiment 1B. <ref type="figure">Figure S2</ref>. Distribution of absolute delta word memorability among choice trials in Experiment 2C.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplement</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table S1</head><p>List of Words Used in Experiment 2.</p><p>babybel cheese with crackers</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Diagram of tasks in Experiment 1. A. Memorability task (Experiment 1A)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Subjective value, but not image memorability relates to choice behavior and speed. The proportion of higher-valued-item preferences (A) and RT (B) plotted as a function of |Δvalue| for pairs of items that have low |Δmem|. The proportion of higher-memorability choices (C) and RT (D) plotted as a function of |Δmem| for pairs of items that have low |Δvalue|. All of the models had 2939 trials.In each plot, the solid black line represents the predicted regression line. The shaded gray area represents the 95% confidence intervals. The trial data were binned into 5 equal-sized bins. The black dots indicate the mean proportion of choosing a higher-valued item (top-left), choosing the more memorable item (top-right), or mean RT (bottom) across participants within bins. Error bars are standard error of the mean across participants within bins.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Diagram of tasks in Experiment 2. A. Representativeness task in Experiment 2A.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Word memorability scores differ across items but are consistent across participants. A.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memorability: how what we see influences what we remember</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Psychology of Learning and Motivation</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The resiliency of image memorability: A predictor of memory separate from attention and priming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuropsychologia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">107408</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memorability: A stimulus-driven perceptual neural signature distinctive from memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Dilks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NeuroImage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="152" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dissociating neural markers of stimulus memorability and subjective recognition during episodic retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rissman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">8679</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The intrinsic memorability of face photographs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Isola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology. General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">142</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1323" to="1334" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The hippocampus supports deliberation during value-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bakkour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Palombo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zylberberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Reid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Verfaellie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shadlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7554/eLife.46080</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.46080" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How the brain integrates costs and benefits during decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Basten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Biele</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Heekeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fiebach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21767" to="21772" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fitting Linear Mixed-Effects Models Using lme4</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mächler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bolker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Statistical Software</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Articles</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Characterization of the decision-making deficit of patients with ventromedial prefrontal cortex lesions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bechara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tranel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Damasio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain: A Journal of Neurology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2189" to="2202" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Pt 11</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What Are Memories For? The Hippocampus Bridges Past Experience with Future Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Biderman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bakkour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="542" to="556" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reminders of past choices bias decisions for reward in humans</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bornstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Khaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15958</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reinstated episodic context guides sampling-based decisions for reward</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bornstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="997" to="1003" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A First Course in Factor Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Comrey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memory states influence value-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Duncan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology. General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">145</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1420" to="1426" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">CNG scree test: an objective procedure for determining the number of factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gorsuch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Paper presented at the annual meeting of the Society for Multivariate Experimental Psychology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effective Connectivity between Hippocampus and Ventromedial Prefrontal Cortex Controls Preferential Choices from Memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sommer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rieskamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Büchel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1078" to="1090" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mechanisms underlying cortical activity during value-guided choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Hunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kolling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Soltani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Woolrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F S</forename><surname>Rushworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E J</forename><surname>Behrens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="3" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the Intrinsic Memorability of Images</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Isola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Parikh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Torralba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<editor>J. Shawe-Taylor, R. Zemel, P. Bartlett, F. Pereira, &amp; K. Q. Weinberger</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2429" to="2437" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Isola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Torralba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">What makes an image memorable? CVPR 2011</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="152" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Isola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Parikh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Torralba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">What makes a photograph memorable? IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1469" to="1481" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Memorability of Image Regions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khosla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Torralba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<editor>Pereira, C. J. C. Burges, L. Bottou, &amp; K. Q. Weinberger</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Curran Associates, Inc</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="296" to="304" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modifying the memorability of face photographs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khosla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Torralba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3200" to="3207" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding and predicting image memorability at a large scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khosla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Raju</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Torralba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2390" to="2398" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual fixations and the computation and comparison of value in simple choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Armel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1292" to="1298" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multialternative drift-diffusion model predicts the relationship between visual fixations and choice in value-based decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13852" to="13857" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Common Mechanism Underlying Food Choice and Social Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Krajbich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bartling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Morishima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1004371</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Memorability and Decision Making Task Analysis Code</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Source code</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memory guidance of value-based decision making at an abstract level of representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Liashenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Dizaji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Melloni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Schwiedrzik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">21496</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TurkPrime.com: A versatile crowdsourcing data acquisition platform for the behavioral sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Litman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Abberbock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13428-016-0727-z</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-016-0727-z" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="442" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Food Folio by Columbia Center for Eating Disorders: A Freely Available Food Image Database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lloyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Shehzad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schebendach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bakkour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Assaf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jilani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Walsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Steinglass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Foerde</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3556</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing and Contrasting the Cognitive Effects of Hippocampal and Ventromedial Prefrontal Cortex Damage: A Review of Human Lesion Studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Mccormick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ciaramelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>De Luca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Maguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">374</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="318" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memory Beliefs Drive the Memory Bias on Valuebased Decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mechera-Ostrovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gluth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">10592</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Drift Diffusion Model Can Account for the Accuracy and Reaction Time of Value-Based Choices Under High and Low Time Pressure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mormann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Malmaud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Huth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="437" to="449" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Needell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Embracing New Techniques in Deep Learning for Predicting Image Memorability. Computational Brain &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in press</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reward representations and reward-related learning in the human brain: insights from neuroimaging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>O'doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Neurobiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="769" to="776" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What makes a picture memorable?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Isola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khosla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1117/2.1201304.004806</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1117/2.1201304.004806" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SPIE Newsroom</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How does the hippocampus shape decisions?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Palombo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Verfaellie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurobiology of Learning and Memory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">an R package for parallel analysis and non graphical solutions to the Cattell scree test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Raiche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=nFactors" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>R package version 2.3.3.1.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The diffusion decision model: theory and data for two-choice decision tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ratcliff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mckoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural Computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="873" to="922" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fear of food as a treatment target: exposure and response prevention for anorexia nervosa in an open series</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Steinglass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Albano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schebendach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Attia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The International Journal of Eating Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="615" to="621" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A specific role for posterior dorsolateral striatum in human habit learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Tricomi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Balleine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The European Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2225" to="2232" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Predicting memory across images and within individuals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Wakeland-Hart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Debettencourt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rosenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/zbu3k</idno>
		<ptr target="PsyArXiv,10.31234/osf.io/zbu3k" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memorability of words in arbitrary verbal associations modulates memory retrieval in the anterior temporal lobe</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Inati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Zaghloul</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="937" to="948" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Foerde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Walsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Steinglass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shohamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bakkour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural Representations of Food-Related Attributes in the Human Orbitofrontal Cortex during Choice Deliberation in Anorexia Nervosa</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="120" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
