<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Dissociation of the sources of the risk-seeking bias in motor decisionmaking based on the subjective-objective relationship in riskattitudes</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryoji</forename><surname>Onagawa</surname></persName>
							<email>ryoji.onagawa@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Waseda University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Research Fellow of Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazutoshi</forename><surname>Kudo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Life Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Graduate School of Arts and Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory of Sports Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Tokyo</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsumi</forename><surname>Watanabe</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Waseda University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Dissociation of the sources of the risk-seeking bias in motor decisionmaking based on the subjective-objective relationship in riskattitudes</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:18+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>decision-making</term>
					<term>motor planning</term>
					<term>variability</term>
					<term>risk attitude</term>
					<term>Bayesian decision theory</term>
					<term>statistical decision theory</term>
					<term>strategy selection</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Motor planning involves consideration of the variability and value of potential motor outcomes. Previous studies have reported a preference for risky motor planning when success and failure are juxtaposed, such as in chicken game situations. Here, we investigated the sources of this bias by examining the relationship between subjective risk-attitudes (i.e., as perceived by the individual) and objective risk-attitudes (i.e., as assessed by a computational model). For this purpose, participants were required to perform a temporal response task (Experiments 1-2) and a reach movement task (Experiment 3) with instructions on subjective risk-attitudes. Five (Experiment 1) or three (Experiments 2-3) levels of risk-attitudes from risk-seeking to riskaverse were set in each experimental block, which consisted of 25 trials. A free condition was also set to confirm the risk-attitudes in free-choice situations. Subjective risk-attitudes were assessed before and after each block using visual analog scales. Based on Bayesian decision theory, we estimated the optimal plan based on the variability of motor outcomes in each participant. We then assessed the objective risk-attitudes based on the distortion of the observed behavior from the optimal plan. The subjective-objective relationship in riskattitudes showed that, in the instruction condition, participants performed actions in accordance with the instructed risk attitudes and strategies, indicating accurate computational 2 capacity with respect to risk-attitudes. However, in the free condition, participants exhibited both subjective and objective risk-seeking behaviors. Furthermore, a linear regression model revealed that the degree of risk-seeking bias in the free condition was related to the discrepancy between subjective and objective risk-attitudes. These results suggest that both 1) the subjective preference for risk-seeking behavior and 2) the subjective-objective mismatch of risk-attitudes underlie the objective risk-seeking bias.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Decision-making under uncertainty is a central aspect of human behavior, encompassing various contexts ranging from economic decisions to motor actions. In these scenarios, individuals face the challenge of managing risk, which involves making choices with potentially divergent outcomes.</p><p>In motor behavior, an essential function of our daily lives, action outcomes exhibit variability, influenced by both intrinsic and extrinsic factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Faisal et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Wolpert, 2007)</ref>.</p><p>Even when the brain plans the same movement, the executed movement is not always identical to the planned one in both spatial and temporal features. Motor variability cannot be eliminated no matter how much one's skill improves <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Chaisanguanthum et al., 2014)</ref> and it is an inevitable property of all forms of movement. Recently, based on Bayesian decision theory, optimality in motor decision-making has been investigated, focusing on how individuals optimize motor planning to maximize expected rewards while accounting for sensorimotor variability <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Maloney &amp; Mamassian, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Maloney &amp; Zhang, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Trommershäuser et al., 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Trommershäuser et al., , 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Wolpert, 2007)</ref>.</p><p>A consistent risk seeking bias has been observed in motor behaviors encountering a chicken game situation <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(O'Brien &amp; Ahmed, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Ota et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Ota et al., , 2016</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ota, Shinya, Maloney, et al., 2019)</ref>. In this type of task, the gain of the trial increases as one's action approaches a reference point (or time), but no score or loss is recorded beyond that point. Such situations are found in various sports, including shooting to goal in soccer, selecting a shot course in tennis, jumping position in the long jump in track and field, and starting timing in short-distance sprints. According to Bayesian decision theory, the theoretically optimal aiming point is the point that appropriately balances the potential for high scores against no score or loss.</p><p>Comparisons between observed behavior and the theoretically estimated optimal motor plan have consistently shown that individuals tend to exhibit more risk-seeking behavior than the optimal plan <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(O'Brien &amp; Ahmed, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Ota et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Ota et al., , 2016</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ota, Shinya, Maloney, et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><p>Importantly, this risk-seeking bias represents an objective assessment of risk attitudes <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Dyer &amp; Sarin, 1982)</ref> and is distinct from whether they engage in subjective risk-seeking behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Slovic, 1987)</ref>.</p><p>Two primary hypotheses have been proposed to explain this risk-seeking bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(O'Brien &amp; Ahmed, 2016)</ref>. The first hypothesis is that risk-seeking behavior is preferred in this type of motor task. The second is that the estimation of one's own motor performance, which is a factor specific to the motor situation, is inaccurate, leading individuals to overestimate their movement accuracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Zhang et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Zhang et al., , 2015</ref>. These two hypotheses are not mutually exclusive, and both factors could simultaneously influence the tendency to engage in riskseeking behavior. A notable complication arises when individuals, while attempting to be riskaverse, objectively exhibit risk-seeking behavior due to a significant underestimation of their own motor variability. This complexity makes it difficult to determine the relative impact of each factor on actual human behavior.</p><p>It may be useful to obtain information on subjective risk-attitudes to examine the involvement of these two hypotheses. By instructing risk-attitudes and examining the correspondence between subjective and objective risk-attitudes, we can determine how the behaviors that participants themselves consider risk-neutral are objectively evaluated. If there is a mismatch, then the involvement of computational capacity in the participant's risk-attitude is evident as the cause of the risk-seeking bias. In addition, the subjective risk-attitude when performing the task in free-choice situations also reveals the involvement of an active risktaking process.</p><p>The current study aimed to bridge the gap between subjective risk-attitudes and actual, objective behavior. By modulating explicit instructions regarding subjective risk-attitudes and examining the correspondence between subjective and objective risk-attitudes, we investigated the underlying causes of the objective risk-seeking bias. Participants performed a temporal response task (Experiments 1-2) and a reach movement task (Experiment 3) task with instructions on subjective risk-attitudes. We set five (Experiment 1) or three (Experiments 2-3) levels of risk-attitudes from risk-seeking to risk-averse in each experimental block, which consisted of 25 trials. We also set a free condition to confirm the risk-attitudes in free-choice situations. Subjective risk-attitudes were assessed before and after each block using visual analog scales. Based on Bayesian decision theory, we estimated the optimal aiming timing/direction based on the variability of response time (RT) and reach direction in each participant. We then assessed the distortion of the actual mean RT/reach direction from the optimal as the objective risk-attitudes These procedures provide information on the subjective-objective discrepancy in risk-attitude (computational capacity) and subjective risk preference in the free-choice situation and allow us to assess the extent to which each factor is involved.</p><p>Finally, we successfully decomposed the causes of risk-seeking bias into subjective preferences for risk-seeking behavior and subjective-objective discrepancies in risk-attitudes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1 -Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Thirty-three Japanese university students (13 males, age: 21.3 ± 1.8) participated. The population was similar in terms of age and social attributes, as in previous studies that found a risk-seeking bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Ota et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Ota et al., , 2016</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ota, Shinya, Maloney, et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><p>The sample size was determined to detect modulate to strong effects (Cohen's d was 0.5-0.7) for assessing the distortion of objective and subjective risk-attitudes from risk neutral.</p><p>Based on G*power 3.1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Faul et al., 2007)</ref>, in the case of α = 0.05 and β = 0.2, sufficient sample sizes to detect Cohen's d = 0.5, 0.6, and 0.7 were 33, 24, and 19, respectively. Even if we exclude about 30% of the ineligible data (see details in Data analysis), the sample sizes in each experiment were detectable at least d = 0.7. All participants self-reported normal vision (including corrected vision). This study was approved by the Institutional Ethics Committee of Waseda University and adhered to the Declaration of Helsinki. All experimental procedures adhered to approved guidelines. Informed consent was obtained from each participant before the experiments using a web questionnaire format.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment setup</head><p>All experiments were conducted using the online experimental tool Gorilla Experiment Builder (https://gorilla.sc). Participants performed the experiments on a web browser using personal computers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment task</head><p>The trial sequence is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1a</ref>. First, the trial order was presented for 1000 ms.</p><p>Then, after a random foreperiod of 1800-2200 ms, a red circle was presented in the center of the screen (i.e., stimulus onset). Participants were required to arbitrarily press the space key.</p><p>The time interval between stimulus onset and the key press determined their score for each trial. After the red circle was presented for 3000 ms, the time interval (i.e., response time) and the score were presented as feedback for 1500 ms.</p><p>The gain functions are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1b</ref>. In Experiment 1, the gain (G) as a function of response time (t) was determined as follows: G(t) = 0 (when t &lt; 500 or t &gt; 1500) and G(t) = 100+(t-1500)/10 (when 500 ≤ t ≤ 1500). The relationship between response times and gains was instructed for the participants prior to performing the experiment (see Experimental procedures for details). Importantly, in this task, participants should consider their own temporal variability in performing a movement <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Hudson et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Ota et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ota, Shinya, Maloney, et al., 2019)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Subjective rating of risk-attitude and satisfaction</head><p>Participants provided subjective ratings of risk-attitude and satisfaction by manipulating the slider on a visual analog scale (VAS). Subjective risk-attitudes were collected 1) to detect whether participants accurately recognized what they were instructed to do and 2) to quantitatively examine changes in their ratings before and after the sessions. Subjective satisfaction was collected to assess how participants rated their own strategies.</p><p>Participants were asked "How much risk do you plan to take in this session?" in the previous assessment of trials in each set. In the posterior assessment, they were asked "How much risk did you take in this session?" and "How satisfied are you with the strategies you used in this session?". Digitized data were obtained with values ranging from 0 to 100 in increments of 0.1. For risk-attitudes, the right edge (i.e., 100) indicated "very risk-seeking," and the left edge (i.e., 0) indicated "very risk-averse." For satisfaction, the right edge (i.e., 100) indicated "very satisfied," and the left edge (i.e., 0) indicated "very unsatisfied."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experimental procedures</head><p>Participants completed 25 trials × 8 sessions. The first and second sessions were practice trials (50 trials). The number of practice trials was sufficient for the participants to understand the task procedure, to recognize the length of the response time and the scores associated with the response time, and to make the behavior stable.</p><p>At the beginning of the experiment, the participants were instructed on how to perform the task and how the score was determined in each trial, using figures to visualize this ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1ab</ref>). Thus, the structure of the gain function was known to the participants prior to testing. Along with the explanation of the gain function, the participants were instructed to perform the task taking into account the risk associated with no gain, which existed next to the high score. The participants were then informed about the entire procedure of the experiment. At this time, participants were informed that they would be given instructions regarding attitudes before each session and were asked to perform the tasks according to these instructions.</p><p>Before each session, the participants were instructed about the risk-attitudes in the session. Next, they were asked to report their planned risk-attitudes in the session. After each session, participants were given an average score for the session. Participants were asked to report their risk attitudes and satisfaction in the session. After the reporting, the participants were allowed to take a rest, and when they were sufficiently rested, they proceeded to the next session at their own pace. In Experiment 1, instructions regarding risk-attitudes (high riskseeking, low risk-seeking, risk-neutral, low risk-averse, high risk-averse) were given during the third to seventh session (upper low in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1c</ref>). In the high risk-seeking condition, participants were instructed as "Please take risk very much when performing the task". In the low risk-seeking condition, participants were instructed as "Please take risk a little when performing the task". In the risk-neutral condition, participants were instructed as "Please perform the task without taking or avoiding risk". In the low risk-averse condition, participants were instructed as "Please avoid risk a little when performing the task". In the high risk-averse condition, participants were instructed as "Please avoid risk too much when performing the task". The order of the riskattitudes was randomized across participants. Then, in the eighth session, a free condition was conducted in which participants were instructed as "Please perform the task to maximize the score in the session". Participants were required to press a space key at an arbitrary time after the stimulus' onset. Response time was defined as the time interval between the stimulus onset and key press. b) Gain functions. A score in each trial yielded the gain function. Three types of gain functions were set in Experiments 1-2. c) Condition sequences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data analysis</head><p>Data analysis was performed with MATLAB 2022a. Response time (RT) was determined as the time interval between a stimulus onset and a key press. In each session, the RT data were subjected to outlier removal per participant to remove data points three SDs from the mean.  Mean RT, SD of RT, mean score, and SD of score were then calculated for each session for each participant.</p><p>In an online experiment, some unusable data are inevitable, and it is necessary to exclude participants datasets from analyses based on experiment-specific criteria <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Rodd, 2019)</ref>.</p><p>To exclude samples that may not have understood the task instructions or may have been less motivated to perform the task, we excluded ineligible data based on task performance. Here,</p><p>given the characteristics of the gain functions, the mean RT should be between 1000 and 1500 ms, regardless of the planned strategies. Therefore, participants with more than two of the six main sessions with mean RT &lt; 1000 or mean RT &gt; 1500 were excluded from the analysis. Finally, nine of the 33 participants were excluded (see supplementary information for details).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Estimation of Bayesian optimal solution and objective risk-attitudes</head><p>Optimal RT was estimated using aiming RT (i.e., mean RT) and trial-to-trial motor variability. The distortion from the optimal RT was then calculated as the objective risk-attitude.</p><p>The optimal RT was estimated as follows: First, as an index of motor variability, the mean SD of RT was calculated using the SD of RT from session three to session eight for each participant. The validity of this calculation was ensured as there were no significant main effects of the conditions on SD of RT. Next, assuming that the distribution of motor outcomes follows a normal distribution, as determined by the aiming point (μ) and SD ( ), the distribution of motor outcomes is defined as follows: <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 2a</ref>). The expected gain as a function of aiming point (μ) and motor variability (σ) was calculated by integrating the motor outcome distribution ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2a</ref>) and the gain function ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2b)</ref> as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">( |µ, ) = ! √#$% ! exp (− ('()) ! #% ! )</formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">∫ ( |µ, ) × ( ) + ',-</formula><p>. The aiming point (μ) was set every 1 ms in the range of 1000-2000 ms, and the expected gain was calculated as a function of μ and σ <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 2c</ref>). The RT that maximized the expected gain was defined as the optimal RT. The optimal RT and the mean objective riskattitude (observed RT -optimal RT) for each condition were calculated for each participant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical analysis</head><p>First, one-way repeated measures ANOVAs (conditions) were conducted on mean RT, SD of RT, objective risk-attitude, subjective risk-attitude, and subjective satisfaction with instruction conditions using the "aov" function in R version 4.1.0. When significant main effects were found, post hoc multiple comparisons with Holm corrections were performed using the "pairwise.t.test" function in R version 4.2.1.</p><p>Second, to confirm whether the risk attitudes were statistically distorted from riskneutral, for both objective and subjective risk-attitudes, multiple one-sample t-tests were performed based on the coefficients of a linear model fitting with no intercept and conditions as independent variables, using the "lm" function in R version 4.2.1.</p><p>Third, to assess the relationship between subjective and objective risk-attitudes, robust linear regressions with bi-square weighting were performed using the "robustfit" function in MATLAB R2022a. Distortions from the optimal correspondence (i.e., subjective risk-neutral equals objective risk-neutral) were assessed using the intercept where subjective risk-attitudes equal 50 (i.e., subjective risk-neutral). We conducted the analysis both between subjective riskattitudes before trials and objective risk attitudes, and between subjective risk-attitudes after trials and objective risk attitudes.</p><p>For all statistical analyses, the statistical significance level was set at p &lt; .05. All statistical results are reported in the supplementary information. Only the primary results are discussed in the main text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data availability</head><p>All data and codes underlying the results are deposited in the Open Science Framework (https://osf.io/qr2ps/?view_only=f3edb0b5b4f14395a7684a54d24d4d29).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Characteristics of temporal aiming task</head><p>This study used a temporal aiming task ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1a)</ref>, in which the participants were required to press a space key at an arbitrary time after a red circle appeared on the screen. The score for each trial was determined by a predetermined gain function, which increased as response time (RT, i.e., the time interval between stimulus onset and key press) approached the maximum of 100 points at 1500 ms, and no score when RT exceeded 1500 ms in Experiment 1 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Fig. 1b</ref>). Participants were required to plan an action timing taking into account the low scores that they were willing to tolerate and to try to obtain high scores. Participants were instructed on subjective risk-attitudes.</p><p>In this task, based on Bayesian decision theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Maloney &amp; Mamassian, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Maloney &amp; Zhang, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Trommershäuser et al., 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Trommershäuser et al., , 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Wolpert, 2007)</ref>, potential outcomes can be predicted depending on participants' trial-to-trial motor variabilities and aiming points. For example, under the gain function of Experiment 1 ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2a</ref>), assuming that the participants' trialto-trial motor variabilities followed a normal distribution,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">( |µ, ) = ! √#$% ! exp (− ('()) ! #% ! )</formula><p>, and a participant with = 200 ms aimed at = 1100 ms, 1300 ms, and 1500 ms ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2b)</ref>, the expected gains for each aiming point were 57.6, 62.5, and 42.1 points, respectively ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2c</ref>).</p><p>Under this assumption, the aiming point to maximize expected gain is 1248 ms with an expected gain of 63.5 points. If this participant attempts to aim at RTs longer than 1248 ms, the participant may be engaging in risk-seeking behavior. Thus, by estimating potential outcomes for various aiming points based on the participant's own motor variability and comparing them with the participant's actual behavior, the participant's decision-making characteristics can be quantitatively assessed.</p><p>Previous studies have evaluated the characteristics of motor decision-making by comparing the observed behavior with the optimal behavior estimated to maximize the expected gain <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hudson et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Onagawa et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Ota et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ota, Shinya, Maloney, et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Trommershäuser et al., 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Trommershäuser et al., , 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Trommershäuser et al., , 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Wu et al., 2006)</ref>. If the aiming point (i.e., mean motor outcome) is distorted from the optimal plan toward higher scores, the observed behavior can be considered risk-seeking. However, if it is distorted in the opposite direction, it can be considered risk-averse behavior. It is important to note that this is an objective riskattitude, as distinguished from the subjective risk-attitude of the participant. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 1 -Results</head><p>In Experiment 1, participants completed 8 sessions of 25 trials each. After the first two sessions as practice trials, five levels of risk-attitudes (high risk-seeking, low risk-seeking, riskneutral, low risk-averse, and high risk-averse) were instructed in sessions 3-7. Subsequently, a free condition in which the participants were instructed to maximize the mean score during the session was applied in session 8. Subjective risk-attitudes were assessed using VAS before and after each session. was estimated based on the trial-to-trial variability of RT ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2e)</ref>, and the expected gain was estimated as a function of aiming RT <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 2f)</ref>. Seemingly, the actual relationship between mean RT and mean score fitted well with the estimated EG. There was no significant main effect of condition on SD of RT (F[5, 137] = 0.65, partial η 2 = 0.02, p = .662; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 3b</ref>), indicating that trial-to-trial variability of RT was not systematically affected by the aiming points. Therefore, this result validated our approach of estimating potential outcomes and optimal aiming points using the mean SD of RT across 3-8 sessions. In addition, the relationship between objective risk-attitude and mean score showed that the mean score decreased as the objective risk-attitude deviated from risk-neutral (i.e., 0), indicating that process of estimating expected gain using the participants' motor variability worked effectively <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 3c</ref>). low risk-averse (p &lt; .001), high risk-averse (p &lt; .001), and free conditions (p = .034; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig. 3d</ref>). In contrast, there were no significant differences from risk-neutral in the low risk-seeking (p = .075) and risk-neutral (p = .158) conditions.</p><p>To determine the correspondence between subjective and objective risk-attitudes, robust linear regression analyses were conducted, calculating the t and p values of the intercept coefficients as a function of subjective risk-attitudes reported both before and after trials. The results indicated that objective risk-attitudes approached zero at a subjective risk-attitude of 61.4 for both assessments before and after sessions. Since the values of subjective risk-attitudes were 73.7 and 74.9 before and after the sessions in the low-risk-seeking condition, respectively, this value was close to risk-neutral. Furthermore, the intercept at which subjective riskattitudes equaled 50.0 was -32.9 ms (t = -4.95, p &lt; .001) based on the subjective risk-attitude before the session and -35.0 ms (t = -4.94, p &lt; .001) that after the session. Considering that the mean SD of RT across participants was 154.5 ms, this deviation from risk-neutral (= 0) appeared to be considerably small when viewed through the lens of the standardized mean difference.</p><p>Taken together, the results of Experiment 1 showed that the participants engaged in computations that were closely aligned with accurate risk-attitudes. Furthermore, we found that the risk-seeking bias was present in the free condition not only in terms of objective stand point, as previously reported <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(O'Brien &amp; Ahmed, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Ota et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Ota et al., , 2016</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ota, Shinya, Maloney, et al., 2019)</ref>, but also in terms of subjective preferences. Therefore, these results demonstrate that the risk-seeking bias stems from a conscious tendency to actively engage in risk-seeking. Here, we used two gain functions with different characteristics as follows: Experiment 2a used an inverted function from Experiment 1 to eliminate the effect of temporal asymmetry on the results. At the same time, Experiment 2b used a function that included a loss penalty of -50 points for response times longer than 1500 ms, in order to evaluate the effect of the size of the penalty on risk-attitudes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2 -Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Thirty-two (20 males, age: 20.5 ± 2.0) and 33 (12 males, age: 20.5 ± 1.8) Japanese students participated in Experiments 2a and 2b, respectively. The population of participants and sample sizes were determined using the same criteria as those in Experiment 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment setup</head><p>The experimental setup was the same as in Experiment 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment task and procedures</head><p>The trial sequence was the same as in Experiment 1. In Experiment 2a, the gain (G) as a function of response time (t) yielded G(t) = 0 (when t &lt; 1500 or t &gt; 2500) and G(t) = 100+(1500t)/10 (when 1500 ≤ t ≤ 2500). In Experiment 2b, G(t) = 0 (when t &lt; 500), G(t) = -50 (when t &gt; 1500), and G(t) = 100+(t-1500)/10 (when 500 ≤ t ≤ 1500).</p><p>Participants completed 25 trials × 6 sessions. The first and second sessions were practice trials (i.e., 50 trials). Importantly, the different levels of instruction were used in Experiments 1 and 2 (5 levels in Experiment 1 and 3 levels in Experiment 2). In Experiment 1, we used a 5-step instruction regarding risk-attitudes to closely assess the objective riskattitude deviation according to the instructed risk-attitude. However, since the main purpose of Experiment 2 was not to detect fine-grained deviations, but only to test whether the objective risk attitudes were consistent with the subjective risk-attitudes, a 3-step instruction (i.e., riskseeking, risk-neutral, and risk-averse) was used.</p><p>Instructions regarding risk-attitudes (risk-seeking, risk-neutral, risk-averse) were given in the third-fifth sessions, and a free-choice session was conducted in the sixth session (middle row in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1c</ref>). In the risk-seeking condition, participants were instructed as "Please take risk when performing the task". In the risk-neutral condition, participants were instructed as "Please perform the task without taking or avoiding risk". In the risk-averse condition, participants were instructed as "Please avoid risk when performing the task". The order of the risk-attitudes was randomized across the participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data analysis</head><p>The same analyses as in Experiment 1 were performed. Here, give the characteristics of the gain functions, the mean RT should be between 1000 and 1500 ms, regardless of the planned strategies. Participants with more than one out of four main sessions with mean RT &lt; 1000 or mean RT &gt; 1500 were excluded from the analysis. Finally, eight of the 32 participants in Experiment 2a and eight of the 33 participants in Experiment 2b were excluded (see supplementary information for details).</p><p>The analysis methods and statistical analysis were the same as in Experiment 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 2 -Results</head><p>The results effectively replicated the findings of Experiment 1 and were consistent across Experiments 2a <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Fig. 4) and 2b (Fig. 5)</ref>. One-way repeated-measures ANOVAs on mean RT <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figs. 4a and 5a</ref>) revealed significant main effects of condition in Experiments 2a (F[3, 91] = 29.08, partial η 2 = 0.49, p &lt; .001) and 2b (F[3, 95] = 16.06, partial η 2 = 0.34, p &lt; .001), indicating that the aiming points varied across instructions. As in Experiment 1, there were no significant main effects of RT's SD <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figs. 4b and 5b</ref>) in Experiments 2a (F[3, 91] = 0.214, partial η 2 = 0.007, p = .887, n.s.) and 2b (F[3, 95] = 1.078, partial η 2 = 0.03, p = .362, n.s.). Therefore, we again estimated the optimal aiming points and objective risk-attitudes <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">(Figs. 4d, 5d</ref>) for each participant based on the average SD of RTs in the main experimental sessions (i.e., sessions 3-6).</p><p>Accurate correspondences between subjective and objective risk-attitudes were consistently found under two gain functions (panels g-h in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figs. 4-5)</ref>. In addition, risk-seeking behavior was observed both subjectively and objectively in the free-choice situation. The coefficients of a linear model fitting indicated that objective risk-attitude was significantly different from risk-neutral in the risk-seeking (Exp 2a: p &lt; .001; Exp 2b: p &lt; .001), risk-averse (Exp 2a: p &lt; .001; Exp 2b: p &lt; .001), and free conditions (Exp 2a: p = .011; Exp 2b: p = .003) (panel d in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figs 4-5)</ref>. In contrast, there were no significant differences from risk-neutral in the risk-neutral condition (Exp 2a: p = .933; Exp 2b: p = .592). Furthermore, the coefficients of the intercept in robust linear regressions between subjective and objective risk-attitudes were also consistent with the accurate correspondence (see <ref type="figure">Supplementary Information)</ref>.</p><p>Taken together, we concluded that 1) objective risk-attitudes corresponded with subjective risk-attitudes and 2) risk-seeking behaviors were preferred subjectively and objectively in the free-choice situation, irrespective of gain functions.   Experiments 1 and 2. This task requires decision making to account for uncertainty in the direction of movement. We tested whether the results of Experiments 1-2 could be replicated in this type of motor task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3 -Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>Thirty-four (13 males, age: 20.2 ± 1.5) Japanese students participated in Experiment 3.</p><p>Participants were randomly assigned to clockwise (N = 17) and counterclockwise (N = 17)</p><p>groups. The population of participants and the sample size were determined using the same criteria as in Experiments 1 and 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment setup</head><p>The experimental setup was almost the same as in Experiments 1 and 2. Participants performed a reaching task using their own device to control a cursor (computer mouse: N = 10; trackpad: N =23; other: N = 1). The experiment was conducted in a browser window in full screen mode.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment task and procedure</head><p>The experimental task and procedure are shown in in that direction along the target line. In the current study, the initial vector at the beginning of the movement determined the reach direction of the cursor in order to eliminate the influence of differences between participants in the setting of the cursor velocity and acceleration. The gain of the trial was determined according to the reach direction and presented to the participants for 3000 ms <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Fig. 6b</ref>). Simultaneously, feedback was provided if the participant started the reach "too early" (before the start cue) or "too late" (more than 500 ms after the start cue). After the feedback, participants could move the cursor and prepare for the next trial.</p><p>There were two gain functions, and participants were randomly assigned to one of the two gain functions <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Fig. 6b)</ref>. In both conditions, the upper right direction produced the largest gain (i.e., 100 points), but the regions where points could be obtained were either clockwise or counterclockwise. These two conditions were set to offset spatial asymmetry. The gain (G) as a function of the relative reach direction yielded G( ) = 0 (when &lt; -45 or &gt; 0) and G( ) =</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">100+ !-- ./</formula><p>(when -45 ≤ ≤ 0) <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Fig 6b)</ref>, where, the relative reach direction ( ) is indicated as the residual from the reach direction where the score is maximized to the direction where the largest gain was obtained. This means that the relative reach directions were negative where the gain was assigned, and the relative reach directions were positive where the zero points were assigned. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 6</ref>. Experimental design in Experiment 3. a) Trial sequence in the temporal aiming task. Participants were required to press a space key at an arbitrary time after the stimulus' onset. Response time was defined as the time interval between the stimulus onset and key press. b) Gain functions. A score in each trial yielded the gain function. Two types of gain functions were set. c) Condition sequences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data analysis</head><p>Data analysis was performed using MATLAB 2023a. In each session, the reach direction data were subjected to outlier removal per participant to remove data points beyond three SDs from the mean. Next, the mean and SD of the relative reach direction, mean score, and SD of the score were calculated for each session for each participant.</p><p>Given the characteristics of the gain functions, the mean relative reach direction should range from -22.5 to 0 degrees, regardless of the planned strategies. Participants with more than one out of the four main sessions with a mean relative reach direction &lt; -22.5 or &gt; were excluded from the analysis. Finally, two of the 34 participants were excluded.</p><p>The same concepts as in Experiments 1 and 2 were used in the analysis. Optimal relative reach direction was estimated using aiming points (mean relative reach direction) and trial-totrial motor variability. The distortion from the optimal aiming point was then calculated as the objective risk-attitude. Optimal relative reach direction was estimated as follows: First, as an index of motor variability, the mean SD of reach direction was calculated using the SD of relative reach direction from sessions three to six for each participant. The validity of this calculation was ensured by the fact that there were no significant main effects of the conditions on relative reach direction. Next, assuming that the distribution of motor outcomes follows a normal distribution, as determined by the aiming point (μ) and SD ( ), the distribution of motor outcomes is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">( |µ, ) = ! √#$% ! exp (− (0()) ! #% ! ) .</formula><p>The expected gain as a function of aiming point (μ) and motor variability (σ) was calculated by integrating the distribution of motor outcomes and the gain function <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">(Fig. 6b)</ref> as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">∫ ( |µ, ) × 0,12- 0,- ( ) .</formula><p>The aiming point (μ) was set every 0.1 degree in the range from -45 to 15 degrees, and the expected gain was calculated as a function of μ and σ. The relative reach direction that maximized the expected gain was defined as the optimal relative reach direction. The optimal relative reach direction and the mean objective risk-attitude (mean relative reach directionoptimal relative reach direction) for each condition were calculated for each participant.</p><p>Statistical analysis was the same as in Experiments 1 and 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment 3 -Results</head><p>The results of Experiment 3 partially replicated the findings of Experiments 1 and 2.</p><p>One-way repeated-measures ANOVAs on mean reach direction <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">(Fig. 7a</ref>) revealed significant main effects of condition (F[3, 123] = 18.75, partial η 2 = 0.31, p &lt; .001), indicating that the aiming points varied across instructions. There were no significant main effects of reach direction's SD (F[3, 123] = 0.322, partial η 2 = 0.008, p = .81, n.s.) <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">(Fig. 7b)</ref>. Therefore, we again estimated the optimal aiming points and objective risk-attitudes ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">Fig. 7d)</ref> for each participant based on the average SD of reach direction in the main experimental sessions (i.e., sessions 3-6).</p><p>Although an accurate correspondence between subjective and objective risk-attitudes was consistently found in Experiment <ref type="figure">(Fig. g-h)</ref>, there were statistical discrepancies between subjective and objective risk-attitudes. The coefficients of a linear model fitting revealed that objective risk-attitude deviated significantly from risk-neutral in the risk-seeking (p &lt; .001) and risk-averse (p &lt; .001) conditions <ref type="figure" target="#fig_13">(Fig. 7d)</ref>. By contrast, there were no significant differences from risk-neutral in the risk-neutral (p = .056) and free (p = .144) conditions. This result showed that, inconsistent with Experiments 1 and 2. However, since the 95 % biascorrected-accelerated CI calculated with the bootstrap method (1000 times) was [0.096 -1.643], the tendency of risk-seeking bias was found in the free condition in Experiment 3.</p><p>Regarding subjective risk-attitudes, significant deviations from risk-neutral were found in the risk-seeking, risk-averse, and free conditions. This means that the participants tended to intend and perform risk-seeking behaviors subjectively.</p><p>Taken together, we concluded that 1) objective risk-attitudes were consistent with subjective risk-attitudes and 2) a subjective, but objectively weak, risk-seeking was confirmed subjectively in the free-choice situation of a reach movement task.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results -Disentangling the causes of the objective risk-seeking bias</head><p>Previous studies have proposed that both subjective risk preferences and misestimation of motor performance are possible sources of the objective risk-seeking bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(O'Brien &amp; Ahmed, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Ota et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Ota et al., , 2016</ref>. Our data showed that the influence of subjective risk preferences is strong, and the overall trend was a good correspondence between subjective and objective risk-attitudes. However, individual differences in the discrepancy between subjective and objective risk-attitudes could be an additional factor for the degree of the risk-seeking bias.</p><p>To address this question, a linear model fitting was conducted using all data obtained in Experiments 1-3 to examine whether two factors, 1) subjective risk-attitudes in free-choice situations and 2) the degree of discrepancy between subjective and objective risk-attitudes, are associated with the degree of risk seeking bias <ref type="figure" target="#fig_14">(Fig. 8a)</ref>. Specifically, a linear model was fitted with the dependent variable as objective risk-attitude in the free condition and the independent variables as 1) subjective risk-attitude in the free condition (before and after trials), 2) objective risk-attitude in the risk-neutral condition as the discrepancy between objective and subjective risk-attitudes, and 3) experiment ID <ref type="figure" target="#fig_14">(Fig. 8b)</ref>. To reduce the influence of the differences in gain functions and types of motor tasks, the objective risk-attitudes were standardized by dividing by each participant's SD of motor outcomes (i.e., SD of RT in Experiments 1 and 2 and SD of reach direction in Experiment 3). This analysis was performed in Matlab 2023a using the "fitlm" function.</p><p>The results showed that both the effects of the subjective risk-attitude in the free condition after trials (standardized coefficient = 0.45, t = 3.67, p &lt; .001) and the objective riskattitude in the risk-neutral condition (standardized coefficient = 0.34, t = 3.78, p &lt; .001) were significant <ref type="figure" target="#fig_14">(Fig. 8b, c, e</ref>). The effect of the subjective risk-attitude in the free condition before trials was not significant (standardized coefficient = -0.15, t = -1.33, p = .23) ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_14">Fig. 8b, d</ref>). There was no significant effect of experiment (p = .69). In addition, there was no significant correlation between the subjective risk-attitude in the free condition after trials and the objective riskattitude in the risk-neutral condition (r[104] = 0.10, p = .29), indicating that these factors independently influence the risk-seeking bias.</p><p>These results suggest that participants 1) who perceived that they were taking risks and 2) whose objectivity was biased in the risk-seeking direction in the risk-neutral condition had greater objective risk-seeking bias in the free condition. Furthermore, in terms of subjective risk-attitudes, post-trial perceptions were shown to be more reflective of actual objective riskattitudes than pre-trial plan. It is possible that the significant effect of pre-trial planning was not found because many participants commonly intended to engage in risk-seeking behavior.</p><p>In contrast, the significant effect of post-trial perception may have been identified because participants were able to accurately recognize the deviation from their intentions after they acted.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results -Subjective satisfaction</head><p>The results of subjective satisfaction were not consistent across experiments.</p><p>Significant main effects of condition were found in Experiments 1 (p = .003) and 2a (p &lt; .001), but not in Experiments 2b (p =.095) and 3 (p = .050). Multiple comparisons showed that the satisfaction in the free condition was never significantly lower than that in the risk-seeking condition, suggesting that participants were satisfied with the behavior with the risk-seeking bias.</p><p>Importantly, in the current study, participants reported their satisfaction with the strategy after knowing the mean score of the trial. Therefore, the report was correlated with the mean score of the session (Experiments 1: r = 0.43, p &lt; .001; 2a: r = 062, p &lt; .001; 2b: r = 0.64, p &lt; .001; 3: r = 0.51, p &lt; .001), as the participants may have considered not only their satisfaction with the strategy itself, but also their satisfaction with the results. Future research could reveal participants' subjective ratings of the strategy by varying the timing of the assessment of satisfaction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The current study examined the correspondence between subjective planned/perceived and objective risk-attitudes in motor decisions under risk in Japanese university students. The results revealed that objective and subjective risk-attitudes were generally consistent, indicating that the computation of risk-attitudes was close to the theoretical optimum. In addition, a risk-seeking bias-both subjective and objective-was consistently found in the free-choice situation. These findings were replicated across the four experiments, regardless of the gain function or motor task type. Furthermore, a linear model fitting revealed that the subjective-objective discrepancy in risk-attitudes was related to the degree of the risk-seeking bias in free-choice situations. Thus, our findings demonstrated that multiple factors are independently involved in the objective risk-seeking bias.</p><p>Earlier research on motor decision-making found a tendency for decisions to be closer to the theoretical optimal than in economic contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Trommershäuser et al., 2008)</ref>. However, more recent studies have reported a preference for risk-seeking behavior in specific motor context <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(O'Brien &amp; Ahmed, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Ota et al., 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Ota et al., , 2016</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ota, Shinya, Maloney, et al., 2019)</ref>, which was tested in the current study. Our results build on both findings, suggesting that although individuals can generally optimize their motor decisions, there is a preference for riskseeking behaviors.</p><p>Previous studies have investigated optimality in motor decision-making by comparing the observed behavior required to maximize performance with the optimal solution estimated by participants' motor performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hudson et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Onagawa et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Ota et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ota, Shinya, Maloney, et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Trommershäuser et al., 2005</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Trommershäuser et al., , 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Trommershäuser et al., , 2003</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Wu et al., 2006)</ref>.</p><p>However, this approach remains complex with respect to the strategic factor to select an attitude and the computational capacity to perform the selected attitude, resulting in a wide range of interpretations to explain behavior. Consequently, even if individuals perform the optimal behavior on the model, such actions could be explained by a combination of suboptimal computations and suboptimal strategic selections. In contrast, our approach to evaluating the relationship between subjective and objective attitudes separates computational optimality in risk-attitudes from strategy selection.</p><p>The consistency between subjective and objective risk-attitudes as a general tendency suggests that our participants can represent the probability distribution of potential outcomes by optimally accumulating past motor outcomes and selecting motor plans according to subjective risk-attitudes. Computational optimality is consistent with previously existing theoretical models of motor control and empirical behavioral evidence. Motor control models have emphasized that motor planning requires acute recognition of movement variability <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Harris &amp; Wolpert, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Todorov &amp; Jordan, 2002)</ref>. These models posit that the motor system selects the motor plan that minimizes task-relevant variability without constraining taskirrelevant variability <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Nashed et al., 2012)</ref>. Furthermore, in some contexts of motor decisionmaking, individuals perform near-optimal actions considering their own motor variability, and decisions are flexible to changes or differences in motor variability <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Hudson et al., 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Hudson et al., , 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Landy et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Trommershäuser et al., 2005)</ref>. Therefore, the accurate representation of motor variability is a fundamental component of adaptive motor control.</p><p>It is noteworthy that the accurate correspondence between the subjective and objective risk-attitudes was observed even within a relatively limited number of trials. Specifically, in our experimental setting, the participants performed only 50 practice trials. Given that it is rare in natural situations for individuals to repeatedly perform a task under identical conditions, the ability to adaptively select a movement based on their own variability should be important, even in scenarios characterized by limited trials or in some cases, minimal prior experience.</p><p>Consistent with our finding, a previous study showed that, when performing a pointing task to a target region adjacent to a penalty region, individuals rapidly acquired an estimate of their new task-relevant variability in less than 120 trials, leading them to adjust their aiming strategies accordingly <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Trommershäuser et al., 2005)</ref>. Future studies should clarify the computational models and neural mechanisms that allow optimal computation to identify motor variability based on experience, estimate potential outcomes in the context of planning, and modulate motor output in accordance with their subjective strategy selection.</p><p>In contrast to the accurate correspondence between subjective and objective riskattitudes, most participants actively engaged in risk-seeking behavior during the free-choice sessions. Importantly, we found a tendency for most individuals to want to take risk-seeking behaviors, thereby causing the objective risk-seeking bias. These findings underscore that the determinants of human behavior may be distorted by mere computational capacity in deriving optimal solutions. As the origin of risk preference, the characteristics of the gain function possibly may have a significant influence on the risk-seeking bias. When the value increases linearly, as in our experiment, there may be a bias to try to score higher due to the juxtaposition of better outcomes, possibly related to emotional factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Lerner et al., 2015)</ref>. In contrast, previous studies using gain functions without the benefit of proximity to the loss region have not identified a risk-seeking bias <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Hudson et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Trommershäuser et al., 2006</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Trommershäuser et al., , 2003</ref>.</p><p>Thus, the interplay with the value space embedded in the environment or task may shapes strategic preferences. Future studies are required to clarify the relationship between the specific attributes of a task, construed as a value function, and the resulting preferences in strategy selection.</p><p>Not only the effect of the subjective risk-seeking preference, the discrepancy in the relationship between subjective and objective risk-attitudes was also related to the degree of the risk-seeking bias <ref type="figure" target="#fig_14">(Fig. 8f</ref>). Based on Bayesian decision theory, several processes could generate the discrepancy: the first process is the estimation of the motor outcome distribution <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Onagawa et al., 2022)</ref>; the second process is the representation of the gain function; the third process is the estimation of the expected gain based on the motor outcome distribution and the gain function; the fourth process is the selection of the optimal plan based on the expected gain.</p><p>Future research should isolate the process by which the discrepancy is generated.</p><p>The generalizability of our results should be emphasized. Although we carefully confirmed the robustness of our findings by using multiple gain functions and two types of motor tasks, we did not consider how participants' characteristics might affect the results.</p><p>Clearly, further empirical research is needed to examine the reproducibility of our findings in different populations.</p><p>We believe that our methodology, which examines the relationship between subjective goals and the objective attributes of behavior, will be a profoundly insightful tool for analyzing the intricacies of decision-making processes. In the current study, two sources of the riskseeking bias were identified <ref type="figure" target="#fig_14">(Fig. 8</ref>). This finding indicates that the same bias arises from different factors that can be dissociated based on the relationship between subjective goal setting and model-based objective assessment of the behavior. This approach possibly facilitates the evaluation of the extent of bias within an individual, paving the way for tailored intervention strategies aimed at mitigating one's own bias. Furthermore, extending this association-based approach beyond just motor scenarios to a broader range of situations promises to enhance our comprehensive understanding of human decision-making.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Experimental design in Experiments 1-2. a) Trial sequence in the temporal aiming task.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Estimation of an optimal solution to maximize expected gain and representative participant' data in Experiment 1. a) Response time (RT) distribution. The RT distribution followed a normal distribution ( |µ, ), where t is time, µ is the aiming point (i.e., mean RT), and is the standard deviation. Solid lines represent the RT distributions of (µ, ) = (1100, 200), (µ, ) = (1300, 200), or (µ, ) = (1500, 200). b) Gain function. c) Expected gain. The expected gain at each aiming point was estimated by integrating the RT distribution for the aiming point and gain function. Scatter plots present the relationship between the aiming point and expected gain, in the case of (µ, ) = (1100, 200), (µ, ) = (1300, 200), or (µ, ) = (1500, 200). d) RT in each trial. RT, as a function of the trial number for a representative participant, is presented. e) Probability density function as the function of RT in optimal planning based on this participant's variability. f) Expected gain depending on aiming points for this participant. Scatter plots depict the relationship between each session's mean score and mean RT.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig.</head><label></label><figDesc>2d-f shows the representative data from one participant. As shown inFig. 2d, RTwas modulated as a function of condition. The probability density function (RT distribution)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>shows the group data. Mean RT was modulated as a function of the risk-attitude instructions (Fig. 3a). One-way repeated measures analysis of variance (ANOVA; six conditions) revealed a significant main effect of condition on mean RT (F[5, 137] = 26.7, partial η 2 = 0.49, p &lt; .001). Post hoc multiple comparisons revealed significant differences between all combinations-except Free vs. Low risk-seeking conditions, and High risk-averse vs. Low riskaverse conditions. As risk-seeking behavior was associated with aiming for high rewards, the participants showed a gradual change in the aiming point in response to the risk-attitudes instruction.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Subjective risk-attitude seemed to correspond to the objective risk-attitude (Figs. 3g and 3h). Similarly, the objective risk-attitude was most proximal to risk-neutral in the riskneutral condition, and objective risk-seeking (risk-averse) behavior was observed in the riskseeking (risk-averse) condition. Coefficients of a linear model fitting indicated that objective risk-attitude was significantly different from risk-neutral in the high risk-seeking (p &lt; .001),</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Results in Experiment 1. a) Mean RT in each condition. b) RT's SD in each condition. c) Relationship between objective risk-attitude and mean score. The solid curve line depicts the estimated EG depending on objective risk-attitudes, using RT's average SD across participants. d) Objective risk-attitude in each condition. e) Subjective risk-attitude before trials in each condition. f) Subjective risk-attitude after trials in each condition. g-h) Relationship between subjective risk-attitude before and after trials and objective risk-attitude. Scatter plots depict the data in each condition in each participant. For each panel, error bars indicate interparticipant SD.Experiment 2 -PurposeExperiment 2 was designed to determine whether the phenomena observed in Experiment 1 were dependent on the specific characteristics of the gain function. In Experiment 2, we used the temporal aiming task under two different gain functions to confirm the robustness of two main findings from Experiment 1: first, that participants demonstrated a reasonable recognition of their risk-attitudes, thereby aligning objective risk-attitudes with subjective risk-attitudes. Second, the risk-seeking bias was found both subjectively and objectively.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Results in Experiment 2a. a) Mean RT in each condition. b) RT's SD in each condition. c) Relationship between objective risk-attitude and mean score. The solid curve line depicts the estimated EG depending on objective risk-attitudes, using RT's average SD across participants. d) Objective risk-attitude in each condition. e) Subjective risk-attitude before trials in each condition. f) Subjective risk-attitude after trials in each condition. g-h) Relationship between subjective risk-attitude before and after trials and objective risk-attitude. Scatter plots depict the data in each condition in each participant. For each panel, error bars indicate interparticipant SD.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Results in Experiment 2b. a) Mean RT in each condition. b) RT's SD in each condition. c) Relationship between objective risk-attitude and mean score. The solid curve line depicts the estimated EG depending on objective risk-attitudes, using RT's average SD across participants. d) Objective risk-attitude in each condition. e) Subjective risk-attitude before trials in each condition. f) Subjective risk-attitude after trials in each condition. g-h) Relationship between subjective risk-attitude before and after trials and objective risk-attitude. Scatter plots depict the data in each condition in each participant. For each panel, error bars indicate interparticipant SD. found that 1) objective risk-attitudes are consistent with subjective risk-attitudes and 2) risk-seeking behaviors are subjectively and objectively preferred in the free-choice situation, regardless of gain functions. Although Experiments 1 and 2 examined decision making under uncertainty of RTs, it is unclear whether these findings could be replicated in other aspects of motor outcomes. Here, in Experiment 3, we developed a reaching movement paradigm with the same gain function characteristics as those in</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Fig 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>The experimental procedure was the same as in Experiment 2, but the experimental task was different. In Experiment 3, participants performed a reaching task in which the score changed depending on the direction of the movement. The trial sequence is shown inFig 6a.First, the participant moved the cursor (black open circle; radius = 1% of the screen height) to the starting point (black open circle; radius = 1% of the screen height) in the center of the screen. When the cursor was held in the circle at the start point for 500 ms, it changed to a black filled circle and moved to the perfectly centered position of the start point (initial setting). After the initial setting, the cursor remained at the start point until a reach movement was detected. Five hundred milliseconds after the initial setting, the color of the target line (radius = 25% of the screen height) changed from black to red, indicating the start of a reach movement. After the start cue, participants moved the cursor in the direction they chose. The movement direction at the time of the 1% of screen height offset was detected as the reach direction of the trial, and the cursor immediately moved</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Relative reach direction θ (deg)clockwise group: relative reach direction = reach direction -45 conterclockwise group: relative reach direction = 45 -reach direction in analysis</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Subjective risk-attitude (before trials)Subjective risk-attitude (after trials)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_13"><head>Figure 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Results in Experiment 3. a) Mean relative reach direction in each condition. b) Relative reach direction's SD in each condition. c) Relationship between objective risk-attitude and mean score. The solid curve line depicts the estimated EG depending on objective riskattitudes, using relative reach direction's average SD across participants. d) Objective riskattitude in each condition. e) Subjective risk-attitude before trials in each condition. f) Subjective risk-attitude after trials in each condition. g-h) Relationship between subjective riskattitude before and after trials and objective risk-attitude. Scatter plots depict the data in each condition in each participant. For each panel, error bars indicate inter-participant SD.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>Figure 8 .</head><label>8</label><figDesc>The causes of the objective risk-seeking bias. b) coefficients in the linear model regression. Error bars indicate SE. c) Relationship between the objective risk-attitude in the risk-neutral condition and that in the free condition. d) Relationship between the subjective risk-attitude before trials and objective risk-attitude in the free condition. e) Relationship between the subjective risk-attitude after trials and objective risk-attitude in the free condition. f) Conceptual diagram of two causes of the objective risk-seeking bias. #1 and #2 show cases where risk-seeking bias is generated for different reasons. Depending on the cause, there may be different interventions to optimize motor decisions. je c t iv e R A inF r e e ( b e f o r e t r ia ls ) s u b je c t iv e R A in F r e e ( a f t e r t r ia ls ) β coefficient RA: risk-attitude RN: risk neutral condition Free: free condition</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Author contributions: RO, KK, and KW designed the experiments. RO performed the experiments. RO programmed and analyzed the results. RO, KK, and KW interpreted the results.</p><p>RO wrote the paper. KK, and KW revised the paper. RO, KK, and KW confirmed and approved the final version of the paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Competing Interests Statement:</head><p>The authors declare no competing interests.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motor variability arises from a slow random walk in neural state</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Chaisanguanthum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Sabes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12071" to="12080" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trading off speed and accuracy in rapid, goaldirected movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-W</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relative risk aversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Sarin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="875" to="886" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Noise in the nervous system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Faisal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">P J</forename><surname>Selen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wolpert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews. Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="292" to="303" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Faul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Erdfelder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A.-G</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Buchner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G*</forename><surname>Power</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="191" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signal-dependent noise determines motor planning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wolpert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">394</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6695</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="780" to="784" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal compensation for temporal uncertainty in movement planning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hudson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1000130</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compensation for changing motor uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hudson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Tassinari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1000982</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Speeded reaching movements around invisible obstacles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hudson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Wolfe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1002676</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic estimation of task-relevant variance in movement under risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trommershäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12702" to="12711" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotion and decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lerner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Valdesolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kassam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="799" to="823" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian decision theory as a model of human visual perception: testing Bayesian transfer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mamassian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Visual Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="155" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-theoretic models of visual perception and action</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Vision Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2362" to="2374" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overconfidence in an objective anticipatory motor task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mamassian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="601" to="606" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk-sensitive optimal feedback control accounts for sensorimotor behavior under uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Nagengast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wolpert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1000857</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk-sensitivity and the mean-variance trade-off: decision making in sensorimotor control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Nagengast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wolpert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings. Biological Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">278</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2325" to="2332" />
			<date type="published" when="1716" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence of the behavioral goal and environmental obstacles on rapid feedback responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Nashed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Crevecoeur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="999" to="1009" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does risk-sensitivity transfer across movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>O'brien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Neurophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1866" to="1875" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rationality in human movement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>O'brien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Systematic bias in representation of reaction time distribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Onagawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kudo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Watanabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/vxewn</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/vxewn" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">PsyArXiv</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk aversion in the adjustment of speedaccuracy tradeoff depending on time constraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Onagawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shinya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kudo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11732</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Motor planning under temporal uncertainty is suboptimal when the gain function is asymmetric</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shinya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kudo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">88</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sub-optimality in motor planning is retained throughout 9 days practice of 2250 trials</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shinya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kudo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">37181</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sub-optimality in motor planning is not improved by explicit observation of motor uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shinya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kudo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">14850</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to maintain data quality when you can&apos;t see your participants</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rodd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.psychologicalscience.org/observer/how-to-maintain-data-quality-when-you-cant-see-your-participants" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">APS Observer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perception of risk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4799</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="280" to="285" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal feedback control as a theory of motor coordination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1226" to="1235" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal compensation for changes in task-relevant movement variability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trommershäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gepshtein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Banks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7169" to="7178" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Humans rapidly estimate expected gain in movement planning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trommershäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="981" to="988" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical decision theory and the selection of rapid, goal-directed movements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trommershäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Optical Society of America. A, Optics, Image Science, and Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1419" to="1433" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision making, movement planning and statistical decision theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trommershäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="291" to="297" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The expected utility of movement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trommershäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Neuroeconomics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="111" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic models in human sensorimotor control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wolpert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Movement Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="524" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic decision-making compared with an equivalent motor task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-W</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Delgado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6088" to="6093" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Limits to human movement planning in tasks with asymmetric gain landscapes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S.-W</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trommershäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Landy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="63" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing whether humans have an accurate model of their own motor uncertainty in a speeded reaching task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1003080</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Acquisition, representation, and transfer of models of visuo-motor error</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K C</forename><surname>Kulsa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maloney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
