<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Contextuality and context-sensitivity in probabilistic models of cognition</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bruza</surname></persName>
							<email>p.bruza@qut.edu.au</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fell</surname></persName>
							<email>l3.fell@qut.edu.au</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hoyte</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dehdashti</surname></persName>
							<email>shahram.dehdashti@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Obeid</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Moreira</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Contextuality and context-sensitivity in probabilistic models of cognition</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">Preprint submitted to Elsevier</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:21+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>quantum cognition contextuality context-sensitivity probabilistic models</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Introduces the notion of contextuality to cognitive psychology in terms of Boole&apos;s conditions of possible experience. • Conceptually and formally contrasts contextuality with context-sensitivity. • Identifies the implications of contextuality for the probabilistic modelling of cognition.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>This article presents a view of the conditions, differences and implications of two similar but distinguishable concepts -context-sensitivity and contextuality -and their application to probabilistic models of cognition. After briefly describing context-sensitivity, we explain the nature of contextuality and contrast it with context-sensitivity in order to clarify the distinction between them. The context-sensitivity of cognition is well known, and has been demonstrated across a wide range of cognitive functions such as perception, memory, judgement and decision making. For example, a common demonstration of context-sensitivity is the well-known Ponzo illusion in which two parallel lines of equal length appear to be of unequal length when framed by two angled lines. The framing lines constitute the context, and when the context is changed by displaying the framing lines to be orthogonal to the two parallel lines, the perceptual illusion disappears.</p><p>A representationalist view of cognition offers a ready explanation for such context-sensitive effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Anderson, 1996)</ref>. Within this view, the context conditions internal cognitive representations, which erroneously present a picture that is at odds with external reality. Not all context-sensitive effects are illusions, however, it is not hard to imagine that many context-sensitive effects can be explained in the same way. A critical component is the purported alignment between internal cognitive representations and external reality. As will be argued in the following, an assumption of realism can be seen underpin this alignment, which affects probabilistic models of cognition in significant and largely undiagnosed ways. One effect of this assumption of realism is that it determines how the nature of the underlying uncertainty is to be viewed. Another is that these models can account for the context-sensitivity of cognitive phenomena but cannot adequately account for their contextuality due to the fact that at its very inception, probability theory was based on a realism that is non-contextual.</p><p>Contextuality on the other hand is a concept that has emerged from the field of quantum physics where it has, and continues to be, extensively studied within quantum foundations. Notwithstanding contextuality being a subtle notion, rigorous theoretical and empirical methods have been developed in order to study it. Within the field of quantum cognition there has been speculation for some time that quantum-like contextuality may be present in human cognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Atmanspacher and Filk, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Khrennikov, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aerts, Broekaert and Gabora, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Busemeyer and Bruza, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Atmanspacher and Filk, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Aerts, Gabora and Sozzo, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Bruza, Wang and Busemeyer, 2015b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Acacio De Barros and Oas, 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Empirical evidence for the presence of contextuality is mounting. For example, Basieva, Cervantes, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Dzhafarov and Khrennikov (2019)</ref> present a series of crowdsourced experiments that exhibit contextuality in human choice. They found evidence for a certain extended notion of contextuality that is derived from but not the same as contextuality as defined in physics. The empirical study was based on six experiments using three, or four, experimental contexts. In each context, a participant was introduced to a pair of choices to be made by a fictional Alice; each choice involving two alternatives. For example, in one experiment, Alice wishes to order a two-course meal. For each course (context) she can choose a high-calorie option (indicated by H) or a low-calorie option (indicated by L). Alice does not want both courses to be high calorie nor does she want both of them to be low calorie. The three contexts in this scenario are 1) Starters: Soup (H) or Salad (L), 2) Main course: Burger (H) or Beans (L) and 3) Dessert: Cake (H) or Coffee (L). Statistical analysis indicated the contextuality of human choice in five of the six experiments. These results accord with the findings reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Dzhafarov and Cervantes (2019)</ref>. This study found similar evidence of contextuality in human choice using a crowdsourced study with a similar protocol and analysis methods. The authors concluded that when human choice is contextual, "the responses to two questions posed in a particular order form a whole that cannot be reduced to an action of the first question upon the second response".</p><p>Notwithstanding the evidence for contextuality presented in the preceding studies, concerns have been raised by <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Atmanspacher and Filk (2019)</ref> contesting the determination of contextuality. The protocols that were used are derived from experimental protocols used in quantum physics which rely on measurements not influencing each other. Atmanspacher and Filk (2019) argue that while the preceding studies control for direct influence, they do not however prevent hidden influence and therefore consider the determination of contextuality as inconclusive.</p><p>These variations of opinion lead to the question of what contextuality is. By way of illustration, consider a study where the eye colour, shoe size, and height of subjects are measured. In addition, imagine that only two of the three properties can be established at any given time. The view of contextuality put forward in this paper is that when the value recorded for eye colour, for example, for a given subject would differ depending on whether it is recorded together with their shoe size, as opposed to with their height. In other words, the value of a property changes depending on what other property is being co-established with it. What renders contextuality puzzling is the fact that the nature of this dependence is not what one might expect, such as a causal relationship between shoe size and eye colour.</p><p>On the surface, contextuality seems to be very similar to context-sensitivity. However, context-sensitivity is when the value of a property is dependent on what property is being co-established with it, and where this dependence has a causal explanation. For example, the framing lines of the Ponzo illusion cause the horizontal lines to appear to be of unequal length due to an underlying heuristic that converging lines signal distance. One of the goals of this article is to clarify the distinction between these two concepts. In the process of addressing this goal, a second goal is to raise awareness of contextuality within cognitive psychology and to identify its implications for probabilistic models of cognition. In order to do this, we begin by discussing some philosophical assumptions behind probability theory which implicitly determine how the modeller is required to view cognitive phenomena.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.">Boole's 'conditions of possible experience'</head><p>In the mid-nineteenth century, George Boole formulated a "theory of probabilities" which provided the foundation of a logical approach to probability (Boole, 1862). Boole formulated his probability theory in terms of "conditions of possible experience". Given that logic is a highly abstract enterprise, Boole's use of the term "experience" is a curious one and requires some grounding. He states that the calculation of probability "depends upon information contained in the data, information supposed to be derived from actual experience, or at least to be of such a nature that experience might have furnished it" [emphasis in the original] (Boole, 1862, p. 226). To provide an example, he describes an "urn containing balls distinguished by certain properties, e.g., by colour, as white or not white, by form, as round or not round, by material, as ivory or not ivory" <ref type="bibr">(Boole, 1862, p. 227)</ref>.</p><p>When reading Boole, it is clear that the senses play an important role in underpinning his notion of data. He assumes that the properties of balls can be reliably established by the sense perceptions e.g., by sight, or even the sense of touch, to establish whether a given ball is made from ivory, or marble. Moreover, these properties are logically well-defined (i.e., either white or not white, but not both). In other words, Boole's conception of experience accords with 'naive realism'. Naive realism is defined as "In a case of a subject accurately seeing an object , 's visual experience (his conscious, subjective experiential state) consists in a relation of awareness to and 's perceptible properties...Since and its perceptible properties are parts of the structure of 's experience, could not have that experience unless he were seeing and these properties." <ref type="bibr">(Kennedy, 2010, p. 77)</ref>. Naive realism is sometimes referred to as direct, or perceptual realism, however from this point on, we will simply refer to it as 'realism'. It was a prevalent view in 19th century logic <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Brockhaus, 1991)</ref>.</p><p>We are now in a position to return to Boole's thoughts about the connection between probability and experience. We retrieve balls from the urn. The current ball is experienced as white via the sense perceptions. The whiteness of the ball is constituent of our experience. Boole's notion of "information" that is derived from "actual experience" is in the form of a judgement that the ball has the property of being white; it is a perceptual belief derived from an "entailing experiential ground" <ref type="bibr">(Kennedy, 2010, p. 78)</ref>. Our experience involves a seemingly undeniable proposition; the experience relates us to the ball and its white colour because that ball was white before we experienced its whiteness. Realism thus entails that the urn contains a set of balls with well-defined properties that exist independent of observation by the subject . These properties are simply made apparent by 's experiencing of them. As balls are retrieved from the urn, the relative frequencies of balls with certain properties, or combination of properties, can be calculated. Relative frequencies instantiate the value in Boole's notion of data, "The probability of a ball that is white is " <ref type="bibr">(Boole, 1862, p. 226)</ref>. Realism underlies these relative frequencies.</p><p>At face value, Boole's framing of probability in terms of "conditions of possible experience" seems like a quaint historical footnote which can have no bearing on contemporary cognitive psychology. For example, Boole's realism assumes that visual perception is veridical whereas contemporary understanding is that perceptual illusions counter this assumption <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Galloway, 2000)</ref>. In addition, Bayesian models of cognition often employ subjective probabilities, not the frequentist probabilities described by Boole. Notwithstanding the preceding, Boole's logical approach to probability is formally equivalent to the axiomatic formulation of probability developed by Kolmogorov some seventy years later. Given that the probabilistic models are widely used in cognitive psychology, and given that the probability theory underpinning such models is founded on realism, what then are the consequences in regard to what these models can reveal to us about cognition?</p><p>In the following sections, we explore this question by first delving into Boole's "conditions of possible experience". We will argue that Boole's realism translates to a derivative form of realism called 'cognitive realism' which underpins contemporary probabilistic models of cognition. Thereafter, we introduce the concept of 'contextuality' and explain how this concept relates to Boole's "conditions of possible experience". By means of examples, we explain the nature of contextuality and contrast it with context-sensitivity in order to clarify the distinction between them. Finally, we identify some implications of contextuality for the probabilistic modelling of cognition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Realism, cognitive realism and probabilistic models</head><p>Let us return to Boole's urn. Let , and respectively denote the probability that a ball retrieved from the urn is white, round, or made of ivory. Instead of using Pr( ∧ ) to denote the probability of retrieving a white, round ball, the abbreviation will be used. Boole's "conditions of possible experience" were formalized in terms of constraints on the probabilities <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Pitowsky, 1994)</ref>. Some of the constraints are expected common sense constraints on probabilities such as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">≥ 0, ≥ , ≥ , + − ≤ 1<label>(1)</label></formula><p>and</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Pr( ∨ ∨ ) ≥ + + − − −<label>(2)</label></formula><p>so,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">+ + − − − ≤ 1<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Consider Pr(¬ ∨ ∨ ). The previous equation can be rewritten as the following with the negation of denoted̄:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">+ + −̄−̄− ≤ 1 (4)</formula><p>As̄= 1 − and̄= − and̄= − , the previous equation can be rewritten as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">(1 − ) + + − ( − ) − ( − ) − ≤ 1 1 − + + − ≤ 1</formula><p>The last equation can be rewritten as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">− − + ≥ 0<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Similarly, by considering Pr( ∨ ¬ ∨ ) and Pr( ∨ ∨ ¬ ), the following equations can be derived:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">− − + ≥ 0 (6) − − + ≥ 0<label>(7)</label></formula><p>Pitowsky points out that equations (5)-(7) are necessary and sufficient to define a polytope 1 . The points within this polytope correspond to probabilities which adhere to Boole's "conditions of possible experience". We will see below that these probabilities relate to phenomena that are non-contextual. In addition, he adds that (5)-(7) have a special significance in quantum physics as they are formulations of the Bell inequalities 2 . The Bell inequalities and related variants such as the CHSH inequalities are significant because they have been regularly employed to determine the contextuality of cognitive phenomena <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Bruza, Kitto, Ramm and Sitbon, 2015a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aerts et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dzhafarov and Kujala, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Quantum phenomena are not like objects being pulled from an urn as they can violate Boole's "conditions of possible experience". As the field of quantum cognition is based on the analogy that cognitive phenomena are like quantum phenomena, it is reasonable to hypothesize that cognitive phenomena may also violate Boole's "conditions of possible experience".</p><p>By examining how violations occur, we must inevitably address the question of what causes such violations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pitowsky proposes one possible reason:</head><p>We may attribute this failure to one of our habitual (often implicit) assumptions, namely that there exists a well defined distribution of properties over some population, and the results of our measurements merely reflect this fact. Maybe there is 'no population', or, even if there is, there are no well-defined properties, existing independent of observation and distributed in a specific manner. All that exist are the phenomena themselves, which simply occur without cause. [Emphasis added] <ref type="bibr">(Pitowsky, 1994, p. 107)</ref> Assuming there is some underlying population, then the realist assumption that objects have well-defined properties existing independent of observation is being singled out as the culprit for why there is no underlying distribution. Common sense attests that it is perfectly reasonable to assume that, without looking, some objects in the urn are white, and there is a distribution of white balls in the urn. And by pulling one of them out of the urn, their whiteness is simply being established by means of experience (Boole's notion of information).</p><p>Let us now consider this line of argument in relation to cognition and place Boole's realism within the context of contemporary probabilistic models of cognition. Consider the situation of a juror's decision. A defendant is brought in, who has committed the crime in question, and is hence guilty. Cognitive realism dictates that the juror listens to evidence and throughout this process, the juror maintains either of two beliefs: that the defendant is either guilty, or not guilty.</p><p>Bayesian models of cognition easily account for such situations as Bayes' rule allows the degree of belief to be computed as probabilities in the light of the evidence. In such models, the degrees of belief, and how they change, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The polytope is based on three propositions , , and their conjunctions, , , . There are eight possible truth assignments to the three atomicpropositions and their conjunctions. Each assignment corresponds to a vector in a six-dimensional real space and the closed convex hull in the six dimensional space is a full dimensional polytope. Satisfying inequalities (5)-(7) is a necessary and sufficient condition that the vector <ref type="bibr">( , , , , , )</ref> is an element of the polytope 2 In a footnote on p. 104 Pitowsky attributes these inequalities to Wigner but due to historical vagaries they have been associated with the inequalities developed by the physicist John Bell. tends to be the focus, rather than the beliefs themselves. In fact, one of the advantages of Bayesian modelling is its "pluralism" in regard to how beliefs are represented <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Griffiths, Chater, Kemp, Perfors and Tenenbaum, 2010)</ref>. However, it is important to keep in mind the relationship between beliefs and their representation. In epistemology, a belief is commonly assumed to be a relation between an agent at a particular time to an object of belief and that relation has a propositional representation, e.g., "the defendant is guilty" <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Huber, 2016)</ref>. Such propositional representations correspond to cognitive belief states that have a definite value at all times, i.e., either true or false.</p><p>We are now in a position to describe how Boole's realism has implicitly entered into the Bayesian model. Consider once again the situation of the juror. From the standpoint of realism, the defendant has the property of being guilty. This property is mirrored as a cognitive property of the juror, e.g., the cognitive belief state that the defendant is guilty. Cognitive realism is therefore realism applied to cognitive phenomena. By this, we mean that there are well-defined cognitive properties that exist independent of observation. So when the juror is asked, the response simply reveals the value of the cognitive property just prior to observation, e.g., "the defendant is guilty". <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Yearsley and Pothos (2014)</ref> were the first to introduce the term 'cognitive realism' and define it as follows: "For any set of judgements, and at all times, an observer has a definite opinion about all judgements". This definition aligns with ours however the authors additionally state cognitive realism entails that "any judgement at the cognitive level is ultimately (in principle, if not in practice) reducible to processes at the neurophysiological level". Our definition of cognitive realism doesn't include this additional assumption. We accept that there are neural correlates of cognitive properties, but do not concern ourselves with this aspect.</p><p>Just like Boole's realism, it is important to bear in mind that in the cognitive realist view there is no inherent uncertainty about such states, i.e., the analog of the ball is "white or not white". Therefore, prior to asking, the juror is, at all times, in a definite state regarding their beliefs. The probabilistic modeller (or even the juror) might not know what these values are, hence the use of probabilities to formalize degrees of belief. In other words, the uncertainty is merely epistemic in nature, meaning that there is no uncertainty about the underlying fact of the matter: that is, the cognitive phenomenon is in state or it is not, but the modeller just does not know which <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Colyvan, 2004)</ref>.</p><p>In contrast to epistemic uncertainty, there is non-epistemic uncertainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Colyvan, 2004)</ref>. Non-epistemic uncertainty means that there is no underlying fact of the matter: in other words, the uncertainty is ontological -it relates to the state of being of the phenomenon in, and of itself, not uncertainty relating to knowing what state it is in. Quantum phenomena exhibit non-epistemic uncertainty which is often referred to as 'indeterminacy' <ref type="bibr">(Jaeger, 2020)</ref>. The field of quantum cognition assumes that cognitive phenomena may be indeterminate, e.g., prior to asking, the juror's cognitive belief state is neither in the cognitive belief state 'guilty', nor in the belief state 'not guilty' <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Trueblood and Busemeyer, 2011)</ref>. Indeterminacy is related to 'contextuality', another quantum concept, which is a major focus of this paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Contextuality and Context-sensitivity</head><p>In order to understand contextuality, its converse non-contextuality is a useful starting point. The following is a fairly typical depiction of non-contextuality as described in quantum physics:</p><p>Specifically, the belief of non-contextual realism asserts that the predefined value of a real property is independent of the way the observer employs to measure it. In particular, in the framework of quantum mechanics, it implies that the (supposedly predefined) value of a quantum observable is independent of other compatible observables that are measured along with it <ref type="bibr">(Rivas, 2019, p. 2)</ref>.</p><p>Observables and , like the colour and size of a ball pulled from the urn, are compatible as their respective values can be jointly established. Boole's urn conforms to the preceding definition of non-contextual realism: When a ball is retrieved and is observed to be white, it was supposedly white before it was retrieved. Moreover, its whiteness does not depend on properties that are jointly established with its colour, e.g, its shape, or the material from which it is made. In other words, when non-contextual realism holds, probability assignments are context-insensitive which means that they do not depend on the outcomes of measurements of other observables that are co-measured with this observable <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Jaeger, 2016)</ref>. For example, the probability of a ball being white does not vary when measured with its shape (e.g., roundness) or material substance (e.g., ivory), i.e., = +̄= +̄. As Boole's "conditions of possible experience" are a formalisation of non-contextual realism, probability assignments are context-insensitive. In contrast, context sensitivity occurs when these probabilities do vary, i.e., +̄≠ +̄. Such a situation can be therefore be seen as "contextual realism" as opposed to "non-contextual realism", therefore Boole's "conditions of possible experience" are not applicable when the urn is context-sensitive. The variation in probabilities is sometimes referred to as 'disturbance'. In quantum physics, disturbance is assumed to have a causal explanation. We do not believe it to be controversial to assume that disturbance within human cognition also has a causal basis. In short, context-sensitivity is based on realism where causality is the basis of the context-sensitivity.</p><p>We will now attempt to describe a contextual urn. Imagine a bizarre situation in which a given object is pulled from the urn and its colour and shape is established as being white and round but its material substance is not able to be established, e.g., as ivory or plastic. In another situation, the same object happens to be retrieved and now only its colour and substance can be jointly established. In this case, the object is now observed to be yellow and made of ivory, but its shape cannot be determined, e.g., whether it is round or square or some other shape. Nor can this change of color be explained causally. The question arises as to what could be behind this bizarre situation.</p><p>Following Pitowsky, consider the possibility that the object does not have well-defined properties existing independent of observation, i.e., its properties are indeterminate. In this case, the colour of the object, for example, only becomes well-defined at the point of observation. In addition, there is incompatibility, i.e., the impossibility to jointly establish the colour, shape and substance of the object at the same time. Finally, there is contextuality, i.e., the colour of the object retrieved changes depending on what property is co-measured with it. Appendix ?? illustrates in more detail how indeterminacy, incompatibility and contextuality interrelate.</p><p>We will now move beyond urns by proposing empirical protocols that illustrate the differentiation between contextsensitivity and contextuality in relation to human judgements of facial traits. We first focus on contextuality, followed by context-sensitivity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Contextuality of facial trait judgements (Experiment 1)</head><p>Contextuality is commonly examined in relation to experiments adhering to the following conditions:</p><p>(a) at least three measurements are defined, (b) at least three measurement contexts are defined involving at least two measurements, (c) each measurement appears in two different contexts, and (d) measurements within a given context are assumed to be compatible. That is, the properties can, at least in principle, be measured simultaneously. Our experimental protocol for determining contextuality follows the above set of conditions and comprises of:</p><p>(a) judgements of three facial traits: intelligence ( ), dominance ( ) and trustworthiness ( ), (b) three measurement contexts: { , }, { , }, { , }, with (c) each measurement appearing in two contexts. Perhaps the most difficult of the four conditions is d), where measuring multiple properties in a truly simultaneous manner is difficult to experimentally realize. Firstly, it is assumed that , and are incompatible, i.e., these three judgements cannot all be simultaneously measured together. The reason for this is that we do not think it plausible that participants can assess all traits at the same time. However, we assume that pairs of traits are compatible as specified in the three measurement contexts.</p><p>Experiments in quantum physics also face the challenges of multiple simultaneous measurements. However, quantum physics protocols are sometimes simplified by serializing the measurements. We adopt an analogous approach: whilst judgements of dominance and trustworthiness can be assumed to be established simultaneously as they occur fast and preconsciously <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Todorov, Pakrashi and Oosterhof, 2009</ref>; Rule, Adams Jr, Ambady and Freeman, 2012; Stewart, Ajina, Getov, Bahrami, Todorov and Rees, 2012; Stein, Awad, Gayet and Peelen, 2018), this is not true of all trait judgements of faces, e.g., judgements of intelligence of faces take longer to process <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bar, Neta and Linz, 2006)</ref>, presumably due to the lesser value of this judgement for survival. More specifically, by the time intelligence is measured, preconscious judgements of trustworthiness or dominance have already been made, or are in the process of being made. Therefore a serial approach is justifiable, whereby intelligence is measured first followed by either dominance or trustworthiness. This serial approach has been used in a previous multi-facial trait study in which intelligence was asked first <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Fell, Dehdashti, Bruza and Moreira, 2019)</ref> where it was found that it reduces disturbance. This is a necessary pre-condition in order to test Boole's "conditions of possible experience", and thus determine whether the judgements are contextual.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1.">Participants</head><p>Participants consisted of 300 subjects recruited from the crowd-sourcing platform Prolific. Participants were 18 years and older, and from a variety of countries across North America, Europe, UK, Australasia, Middle East and Asia. All participants had been verified as proficient in English by Prolific, and had an approval rate in previous studies above 95%. Remuneration was in the form of a small payment (£0.26), as per Prolific convention, and an informed consent page was presented to participants prior to commencement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2.">Materials</head><p>Two face stimuli <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figures 1 and 2)</ref> were sourced from a collection of computer generated faces from <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Oosterhof and Todorov (2008)</ref>, where features such as dominance and trustworthiness were manipulated in their generation. The two stimuli chosen were "Face 1", which is moderately high on trustworthiness, and "Face 2", which is moderately low on trustworthiness. Moderate values of trustworthiness were selected to promote the possibility of outcomes changing across measurement contexts due to, e.g., trustworthiness correlating positively with intelligence and negatively with dominance. Such changes of outcome are intrinsic to both contextuality and context-sensitivity. The two images were altered to display at a slightly lower resolution to mask their artificial nature, as shown in Figures 1 and 2. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.3.">Experimental procedure</head><p>A between-subjects design was used that consisted of three measurement contexts, for each of the two stimuli. Participants were randomly assigned to one of these three contexts, and each participant judged only one of the faces. Each measurement context comprised of two facial traits:</p><p>Context 1 Intelligence is first measured, followed by trustworthiness ( = 50) Context 2 Intelligence is first measured, followed by dominance ( = 50) Context 3 Dominance and trustworthiness are co-measured ( = 50)</p><p>In each of the three measurement contexts, questions were hidden until the image had been displayed for a total of 600ms, at which point, the image disappeared from the screen. Questions were then presented in the form of radiobutton responses. For example, in context 1, the intelligence question is first presented as two radio-buttons:</p><p>The person in this image:</p><p>• appears to be an intelligent person</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>• appears to be an unintelligent person</head><p>After the response has been recorded, the trustworthiness question is then presented:</p><p>The person in this image: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 3</head><p>Data for contextuality analysis (Exp. 1): Face 1</p><p>• appears to be a trustworthy person</p><p>• appears to be an untrustworthy person A similar format to the above was used for context 2.</p><p>In context 3 trustworthiness and dominance were co-measured using the following response format:</p><p>The person in this image:</p><p>• appears to be a trustworthy, dominant person</p><p>• appears to be a trustworthy, vulnerable person</p><p>• appears to be an untrustworthy, dominant person</p><p>• appears to be an untrustworthy, vulnerable person</p><p>In each of the three contexts, the order in which each of the four options appeared, as well as the order of [dominant] and [trustworthy] wording within each option in context 3, was randomised for each trial.</p><p>Finally, confidence ratings, qualitative impressions of the face, and demographic details were collected.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.4.">Results</head><p>Joint probabilities are required to test Boole's "conditions of possible experience". Measurements contexts 1 and 2 allow and ( | ) and ( | ) to be computed from the data because the questions are sequenced, with intelligence being asked first. From these probabilities, the required joint probabilities and are computed. In the third measurement context, is computed directly as the protocol measures these two properties simultaneously. The resulting pairwise joint probabilities across the three measurement contexts are given in Tables 1-3 (Face 1) and 4-6 (Face 2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.5.">Analysis</head><p>In the analysis, facial trait judgements will be deemed contextual if any of Boole's "conditions of possible experience" fail. However, as Boole's conditions require that there is no disturbance, the data must first be analysed for the presence of disturbance, before Boole's conditions can be tested for violations. No disturbance is rarely achieved in cognitive experiments, so statistical tests are applied to determine whether the level of disturbance is significant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Face 1</head><p>The data for Face 1 reveal that there is no disturbance in regard to judgements of intelligence across measurement contexts 1 and 2: +̄= +̄= 0.72. Judgements of dominance show an insignificant level of disturbance across measurement contexts 2 and 3:</p><p>+̄= 0.44 vs +̄= 0.38 ( 2 (1, = 100) = 0.3721, &gt; .01). The same holds for judgements of trustworthiness (measurement contexts 1 and 3):</p><p>+̄= 0.68 vs +̄= 0.62. ( 2 (1, = 100) = 0.3956, &gt; .01).</p><p>As the level of disturbance is not significant, Boole's "conditions of possible experience" can be tested. Significantly, none of Boole's conditions are violated. For example, recall that the Bell inequalities (equations (5)-(7)) are particular "conditions of possible experience" defined by Boole. By appropriately substituting probabilities from the data, the following Bell inequality does not produce a violation: As none of Boole's conditions are violated, the the data are consistent with the hypothesis that subjects are in a definite cognitive belief state regarding judgements of trustworthiness, dominance and intelligence prior to measurement. Together with the fact that there is no, or insignificant, disturbance the situation conforms to Boole's non-contextual realism. Consequently, judgements of intelligence, trustworthiness and dominance for Face 1 are deemed non-contextual. At this point it is worth clarifying the distinction between context-insensitivity and non-contextuality. These are distinct concepts. The preceding analysis of Face 1 suggests that facial trait judgements are context-insensitive because the level of disturbance is insignificant. They are also deemed non-contextual as none of Boole's "conditions of possible experience" are violated. However, it is possible for facial trait judgements to be both context-insensitive and contextual, as will be illustrated in regard to Face 2.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">− − + = 0.72 − 0.58 − 0.32 + 0.2 (= 0.02) ≥ 0</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Face 2</head><p>The data for Face 2 reveal that there is insignificant disturbance in regard to judgements of intelligence (measurement contexts 1 and 2): = +̄= 0.64 vs. = +̄= 0.62. This means that the probability of intelligence does not significantly change when judged together with dominance or intelligence: ( 2 (1, = 100) = 0.0429, &gt; .01). In addition, there is also an insignificant level of disturbance in regard to judgements of dominance ( 2 (1, = 100) = 0.2079, &gt; .01) and trustworthiness ( 2 (1, = 100) = 1.9798, &gt; .01). As there is an insignificant level of disturbance in relation to all three judgements, Boole's "condition of possible experience" can be tested.</p><p>Substituting The violation suggests that the facial trait judgements maybe contextual. A determination of contextuality also occurs by applying the Contextuality-by-Default (CbD) theory shown in Appendix B, but the determination is not statistically reliable. Even though the data do not support a statistically reliable determination of contextuality, it is important to clarify what a violation of Boole's "conditions of possible experience" means. Drawing on Pitowsky's view which was stated above in section 2: a possible explanation for the violation is judgements of trustworthiness, intelligence or dominance are not well-defined cognitive properties "existing independent of observation". Consequently, one or more of these cognitive properties could be indeterminate prior to observation, e.g., dominance is only established as a cognitive property with a definite value at the point of observation, a happening that contradicts cognitive realism, and which can be viewed as a constructive influence in judgements <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(White, Pothos and Busemeyer, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">White, Pothos and Jarret, 2020)</ref>. Indeterminancy in regard to facial traits means that different judgements are 'potentialities', one of which is made actual (constructed) at the point of measurement.</p><p>Indeterminacy is a sufficient condition for incompatibility, e.g., when the traits of intelligence and dominance are co-measured, trust is indeterminate. The indeterminacy of trust leads to incompatibility as it does not permit all three facial traits to be co-measured.</p><p>Incompatibility, in turn, allows for judgements of the face to be contextual: just like the contextual urn in Appendix B where the colour of the object changes depending on whether its size or shape is co-measured, the judgement of trustworthiness changes depending on whether it is co-established with intelligence or dominance. However, contextuality occurs when such a dependence cannot be reduced to a causal explanation. This is because there is no "underlying distribution", which Pitowsky views as a basis for causal explanations. In this regard, he states that a probability distribution is a "special case of the human habit to look for causal explanations, even in cases where only the effects are present" <ref type="bibr">(Pitowsky, 1994, p. 117)</ref>. In short, contextuality is an acausal form of context dependence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Context-sensitivity of facial trait judgements (Experiment 2)</head><p>The experiment to examine the context-sensitivity of facial traits has a similar design to that of the contextuality experiment. Context-sensitivity can be examined in relation to experiments adhering to the following conditions:</p><p>(a) at least three measurements are defined, (b) at least two measurement contexts are defined involving at least two measurements, (c) at least one measurement appears in two different contexts, and (d) measurements within a given context are assumed to be compatible. Note that these conditions are less stringent than those stipulated for contextuality with regards to the number of measurement contexts and the requirements for participation of measurements in those contexts.</p><p>In order to allow the contextuality and context-sensitivity analyses to be compared and contrasted, our experimental protocol for determining context-sensitivity both adheres to the above set of conditions and mirrors Exp.1 and comprises of:</p><p>(a) judgements of three facial traits: intelligence ( ), dominance ( ) and trustworthiness ( ), (b) three measurement contexts: { , }, { , }, { , }, with (c) each measurement appears in two contexts, (d) measurements are compatible, and are measured simultaneously.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1.">Participants</head><p>Participants consisted of a second set of 300 subjects recruited from the crowd-sourcing platform Prolific. As for the previous experiment, participants were 18 years and older, and from a variety of countries across North America, Europe, UK, Australasia, Middle East and Asia. All participants had been verified as proficient in English by Prolific, and had an approval rate in previous studies above 95%. Remuneration was in the form of a small payment (£0.26), as per Prolific convention, and an informed consent page was presented to participants prior to commencement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2.">Materials</head><p>The same two face stimuli were used in Exp. 2 as were used in Exp. 1, i.e., Face 1 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1)</ref> and Face 2 ( <ref type="figure">Figure  2</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.3.">Experimental procedure</head><p>As for the previous experiment, Exp. 2 used a between-subjects design that consisted of 3 measurement contexts, for each of the two stimuli. Again, participants were randomly assigned to one of these three contexts, and each participant judged only one of the faces.</p><p>Each measurement context comprised of co-measurement of two facial traits: In each of the three measurement contexts, questions were hidden until the image had been displayed for a total of 600ms, at which point, the image disappeared from the screen. Questions were then presented in the form of radio-button responses. The procedure to co-measure facial traits in each of the three measurement contexts in this experiment was the same as described in Experiment 1 (context 3), that is, using the response format given for context 1 as an example:</p><p>The person in this image:</p><p>• appears to be a trustworthy, intelligent person</p><p>• appears to be a trustworthy, unintelligent person  <ref type="table">Table 8</ref> Condition 20</p><p>.34 0.24 0.24 0.18 <ref type="table">Table 9</ref> Condition 30 .10 0.40 0.20 0.30</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 5</head><p>Data for context-sensitivity analysis (Exp. 2): Face 1  • appears to be an untrustworthy, intelligent person</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>• appears to be an untrustworthy, unintelligent person</head><p>Again, the order in which each of the four options appeared, as well as the order of the traits within each option, was randomised for each trial.</p><p>Finally, confidence ratings, qualitative impressions of the face, and demographic details were collected.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.4.">Results</head><p>Figures 5 and 6 display the results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.5.">Analysis</head><p>A significant level of disturbance implies context-sensitivity, i.e., when the probability of judging a facial trait is significantly different depending on what trait it is co-measured with across different measurement contexts.</p><p>In regard to Face 1, the difference in the probability of intelligence across context 1 and context 2 is not significant: 1 = +̄= 0.54 vs. 2 = +̄= 0.58, 2 (1, = 100) = 0.3636, &gt; .01. The probability of dominance is significantly different across measurement contexts 2 and 3: 2 = +̄= 0.58 vs. 3 = +̄= 0.30, 2 (1, = 100) = 7.9545, = 0.005. The difference in the probability in trustworthiness across contexts 1 and 3 is also significant, 1 = +̄= 0.78 vs. 3 = +̄= 0.50, 2 (1, = 100) = 8.5069, = .0035. These data are consistent with the hypothesis that judgements of dominance and trustworthiness are context-sensitive.</p><p>In regard to Face 2, there is a significant difference in the probability of intelligence across measurement contexts 1 and 2: 1 = +̄= 0.36 vs. 2 = +̄= 0.70, 2 (1, = 100) = 11.6018, &gt; .000659. There is a significant difference between the probability in dominance across measurement context 2 and context 3: 2 = +̄= 0.48 vs. 3 = +̄= 0.76, 2 (1, = 100) = 8.3192, &gt; .0039. Finally, the difference in the probability of trustworthiness across contexts 1 and 3 is also significant, 1 = +̄= 0.66 vs. 3 = +̄= 0.38, 2 (1, = 100) = 7.8526, = .005. These data are consistent with the hypothesis that judgements of intelligence, dominance and trustworthiness are context-sensitive.</p><p>Recall that context-sensitivity is assumed to have a casual basis. A possible causal explanation for the contextsensitivity of dominance in regard to Face 1 is the following: when dominance is judged in the context of intelligence, some subjects may view dominance as being assertive, whereas when dominance is judged in the context of trustworthiness, dominance may be viewed negatively, e.g., as relating to unreliability. Consequently, assessments of dominance will differ in each context, leading to differences in across both of these contexts. <ref type="table">Table 8</ref> shows a small positive correlation between judgements of intelligence and dominance are not correlated ( [ ] = 0.04), whereas <ref type="table">Table 9</ref> reveals a negative correlation between dominance and trustworthiness ( [ ] = −0.20). This negative correlation for faces aligns with the same finding presented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Stolier, Hehman, Keller, Walker and Freeman (2018)</ref>. According to Reichenbach's principle <ref type="bibr">(Reichenbach, 1956)</ref>, such correlations have a causal basis, e.g., the judgement of the property co-measured within dominance is assumed to causally determine how dominance is interpreted <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">(Trueblood, Yearsley and Pothos, 2017)</ref>. In short, context-sensitivity can be understood as causal form on context dependence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Contextuality vs. Context-sensitivity</head><p>A determination of contextuality is only possible if there are insignificant levels of disturbance. When this condition holds, contextuality can be determined by violation of Boole's "conditions of possible experience", or other related analysis methods such as CbD. In contrast, a significant level of disturbance allows the judgements to be deemed context-sensitive.</p><p>Comparing the data for Face 2 in Exp. 1 and Exp. 2 illustrates how judgements can be contextual and contextsensitive. These two concepts preclude each other because contextuality can only be determined when the level of disturbance is insignificant. In contrast, a significant level of disturbance is required to establish context-sensitivity. The difference in these findings can be explained in terms of the protocols. In the protocol for contextuality analysis (Exp. 1), the intelligence question is asked first in context 1 and context 2. As discussed above in section 3.1, this serializing of the measurement of intelligence with the other traits follows quantum experimental protocol for co-measurement. In effect, this judgement prepares the participants for subsequent judgements of dominance and trustworthiness in a way that reduces disturbance. The protocol for context-sensitivity analysis does not control for disturbance which masks the potential for the contextuality to be determined. The prevalence of disturbance raises the question whether assumption d) of the protocol holds, namely that measurements within a context are compatible. It is also possible that the protocol to simultaneously co-measure pairs of facial traits within a measurement context induces disturbance.</p><p>A differentiating factor between contextuality and context-sensitivity is whether cognitive realism holds, which in turn has implications for causality, as causality is bound up with realism. If cognitive properties conform to cognitive realism they are considered to be in a definite state at any given time. For such properties, context-sensitivity is a form of context dependence whereby their values change across measurement contexts due to causal influences depending on what properties they are co-measured with. If cognitive properties are indeterminate, they violate cognitive realism, because their state is indefinite. Indeterminacy is a sufficient condition for incompatibility, and incompatibility is a necessary condition for contextuality <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Khrennikov, 2020)</ref>. Therefore, the indeterminacy of cognitive properties leads to contextuality, which is an acausal form of context dependence, meaning the values of cognitive properties change across measurement contexts, but where the changes are not due to causal influences. It is, however, a challenge to rule out causal influences in cognitive experiments as an insignificant level of disturbance cannot be used to conclusively rule out hidden causal factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Atmanspacher and Filk, 2019)</ref>. Our position on the relation between indeterderminacy, incompatibility, causality and contextuality aligns with a concept called 'reality without realism' (RWR), which is elaborated in Appendix C. RWR also aligns with Pitowsky's view in important ways.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussion</head><p>This article set out to clarify the distinction between contextuality and context-sensitivity in a way that reveals why this distinction is important for cognitive psychology. By examining probabilistic modelling through the lens of Boole's "conditions of possible experience", we have argued that if a cognitive phenomenon is contextual, it does not adhere to these conditions. This is because a contextual phenomenon transcends what Boole's realism considers as being possible to experience.</p><p>There is mounting evidence demonstrating that cognitive phenomena are sometimes contextual <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Dzhafarov and Cervantes, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Basieva et al., 2019)</ref>. Furthermore, It should be emphasized at the outset that it would be incorrect to think of contextuality as being surprising and strange, whereas noncontextuality is trivial and expected. In the absence of constraints imposed by a general psychological theory, comparable with quantum mechanics, we have no justification for such judgements. One might argue in fact that it is most surprising that so many experiments in psychology are described by noncontextual systems of random variables <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Basieva et al., 2019</ref><ref type="bibr">(Basieva et al., , p. 1926</ref>.</p><p>Why then, hasn't contextuality appeared on the radar screen of cognitive psychology? One reason derives from the underlying experimental protocols. As described in section 3.1, in order to determine whether a cognitive phenomenon is contextual requires experimental protocols with at least three measurement contexts. Many experiments in cognitive psychology do not involve three measurement contexts, let alone those of the required specialized nature, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Bruza et al., 2015a)</ref>. Moreover, experimental designs based on a single sample (also common in cognitive psychology) can never reveal contextuality because Boole's "conditions of possible experience" can never be violated in the context of a single sample <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Pitowsky, 1994)</ref>.</p><p>Given the extensive successful track record of probabilistic models of cognition, why should cognitive modellers care about contextuality? One reason is connected to the implicit assumptions they employ regarding the nature of the uncertainty being modelled. Recall that cognitive realism assumes that a cognitive property has a well defined value independent of observation, although the modeller may not know what this value is, hence the need for probabilities. Therefore, the uncertainty in this case is necessarily epistemic in nature. That is, the cognitive phenomenon is in state or it is not, but the modeller does not know which <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Colyvan, 2004)</ref>. In other words, when cognitive realism holds, the uncertainty is based on determinacy.</p><p>In contrast, we have argued that cognitive phenomena can be viewed as indeterminate with regards to uncertainty, i.e., the uncertainty relates to the state of being of the phenomenon in and of itself, not what is or can be known about it. Indeterminacy can result in incompatibility between properties. Two properties and are incompatible when it is not possible to simultaneously establish the values of both properties. This is because when a value is established, indeterminacy might prevail in regard to property meaning that there is no underlying fact of the matter in regard to this property. For example, in regard to the judgements facial traits, dominance and trustworthiness are incompatible properties when a subject cannot simultaneously decide across both alternatives. In other words, dominance and trustworthiness are not co-measurable. The underlying basis would seem to be that the two properties are incongruent in some way, or can't easily be reconciled, for some reason 4 . Incompatibility can also occur when more than two properties are involved. For example, it is reasonable to assume that a human subject may be able to simultaneously judge two facial properties, but not three. This assumption was employed in the experiments.</p><p>How to reliably determine whether two cognitive properties are co-measurable is an open question. It is necessary to address this question as contextuality analysis relies on cognitive properties to be co-measurable within an experimental condition. In quantum cognition, it is well accepted that incompatibility between cognitive properties entails that the properties are not co-measurable <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Bruza et al., 2015b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Busemeyer and Wang, 2017)</ref>, which in turn implies an order effect between them <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Wang and Busemeyer, 2013)</ref>. However, it is debatable whether the presence of order effects is a sufficient condition to empirically determine incompatibility and therefore that co-measurability is not possible. This impacts the ability to determine contextuality because the co-measurability of cognitive properties is necessary in order to reliably derive joint probabilities across properties, which in turn are used to test for a violation of Bell inequalities. In terms of judgements of facial traits, the pairs of properties { , }, { , } and { , } must be co-measurable, whilst not being possible to co-measure all three. The experimental protocol is an important factor in relation to co-measurability. A protocol can cause measurements to be incompatible, which produces disturbance. In this way, the potential for seeing contextuality ends up being masked, as an insignificant level of disturbance is required to determine contextuality.</p><p>Incompatibility is a necessary condition for contextuality in quantum physics <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Khrennikov, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr">Jaeger, 2020)</ref>. As indeterminacy is a sufficient condition for incompatibility, and incompatibility is a necessary condition for contextuality, indeterminacy can therefore lead to contextuality. The significance of this argument for cognitive psychology is the following: if a cognitive phenomenon is found to be contextual, then there is reason to believe that it may be indeterminate. Pitowsky argues that a consequence of such indeterminacy is that the phenomenon cannot be modelled using a single probability distribution.</p><p>The preceding leads to a second reason why cognitive psychologists should take notice of contextuality. Contextuality is like a line in the sand beyond which the use of standard probabilistic tools can be questioned <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Khrennikov, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Busemeyer and Wang, 2018)</ref>. For this reason, additional probabilistic frameworks should be considered in order to determine the presence of contextuality. Contextuality-by-Default (CbD) <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Dzhafarov and Kujala, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Dzhafarov, Kujala and Cervantes, 2015)</ref> is one such framework which is both theoretically sophisticated and has demonstrated its effectiveness in determining contextuality in cognition and quantum physics <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Dzhafarov and Cervantes, 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Basieva et al., 2019)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Jones (2019)</ref> has detailed the connection between CbD and probabilistic causal models, which are often used in cognitive psychology.</p><p>A third reason why contextuality is significant for cognitive psychologists is because it forces a re-evaluation of the metaphysical position in regard to the cognitive phenomena being modelled. Contextuality implies that (cognitive) realism does not hold. In this connection, Pitowsky's remarks, "there are no well-defined properties, existing indepen-dent of observation and distributed in a specific manner. All that exist are the phenomena themselves, which simply occur without cause". This position can be construed as not denying the reality of such properties, but rather do not conform to realism -a position known as "reality without Realism" (See Appendix C). Phenomenologically the cognitive properties are no longer properties in a traditional sense but would seem to have the character of in-the-moment affordances that involve no preceding processing <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Schlicht and Tarzak, 2019)</ref>. If so, a connection could be speculated between contextuality and enactivist approaches to cognition. Enactivist cognition views embodied agents as being coupled with their environment, and this coupling provides affordances for action. In this dynamic process of engaging with affordances, the embodied agent does not always need to reply on cognitive representations of the environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Schlicht and Tarzak, 2019)</ref>. If affordances aren't cognitively represented, it can be speculated that this may be due to indeterminacy, e.g., the trustworthiness of a face is indeterminate until the embodied agent encounters the face. In this example, trustworthiness can be seen as an affordance, given in the encounter, and made available to the embodied agent. The non-representational basis of this view aligns with weak RWR, which precludes a representational realism.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusions</head><p>Contextuality is an intriguing concept that has been explored within quantum foundations for decades. It is a subtle notion which forces us to rethink the nature of cognitive phenomena and the ways in which they can be studied and modelled. Theoretical speculation and empirical evidence for the presence of quantum-like contextuality in cognition is mounting. We have argued that the indeterminacy of a cognitive phenomenon is sufficient for incompatibility between cognitive properties. In turn, we have argued that incompatibility is necessary for contextuality. The significance of this argument for cognitive psychology is the following: if a cognitive phenomenon is found to be contextual, then there is reason to believe that it may be indeterminate. In other words, contextuality challenges the commonsense view that cognitive properties have well established values in advance of measurement. In addition, due to an assumption of realism that we have traced back to George Boole's theory of probabilities, current probabilistic models developed within cognitive psychology may be unknowingly being applied to phenomena for which they were not designed. What renders contextuality surprising is the fact that the nature of this dependence seemingly cannot be reduced to causal explanations. Context-sensitivity, on the other hand, is reducible to causal explanations. A differentiating factor between contextuality and context-sensitivity is whether cognitive realism can reasonably assumed to hold. Moreover, it is possible that a cognitive phenomenon examined in one experimental setting may be deemed contextual, and in another it may appear to be context-sensitive. In this sense, cognitive phenomena are like quantum phenomena -they cannot be considered independent of the experimental conditions in which they are studied.  Imagine that we have 8 objects in an urn as depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 7</ref>. Each object is individually sampled, and all three properties of shape, colour and size can be co-measured, so the sample depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 8</ref> can be collected. Let (circle) , (square) denote the object's shape ; (large), (small) it's size; (blue), (green) it's colour. The corresponding probabilities are as follows: = = 0.5, = = 0.625 and = = 0.375.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Boole's Urn</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.1. Co-measuring two properties at a time</head><p>Now, let's consider the case where only two properties are co-measured so the sample in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 8</ref> cannot be directly established. Without loss of generality, we will assume that we sample the objects in the same order (preserving the numbers assigned to each). We start by co-measuring shape and size <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 13</ref>). This sample reveals the following joint probabilities: = 0.25, = 0.25, = 0.375 and = 0.125. Next, shape and colour are co-measured <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 14)</ref>. This sample reveals the following joint probabilities: = 0.25, = 0.25, = 0.125 and = 0.375. Finally, size and colour are co-measured <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 15</ref>). The final sample reveals the following joint probabilities: = 0.25, = 0.5, = 0.125 and = 0.125. In addition, there is no disturbance, the probability that an object has a certain shape does does not depend on whether the size or colour are being co-measured with the shape property, e.g., = +̄= +̄. Boole's "conditions of possible experience" hold. Therefore, Boole's "conditions of possible experience" can be tested. For example, the following illustrates how one of the Bell inequalities (Equations <ref type="formula" target="#formula_5">5</ref> Similarly, the following Bell inequalities are also satisfied:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">− − + ≥ 0 − − + ≥ 0</formula><p>This suggests that the objects have "well defined properties existing independent of observation and distributed in a specific manner" <ref type="bibr">(Pitowsky, 1994, p. 107</ref>).  <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1  circle  large  2  circle  large  3  circle  small  4  circle  small  5</ref> square small 6 square small 7 square small 8 square large <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 14  Shape and colour   Object Shape Colour  1  circle  blue  2  circle  blue  3  circle  green  4  circle  green  5</ref> square blue 6 square green 7 square green 8 square green <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 15  Size and colour  Object Size  Colour  1  large  blue  2  large  blue  3  small green  4  small green  5</ref> small blue 6 small green 7 small green 8 large green</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 9</head><p>Three tables corresponding to measuring two properties at a time from Boole's urn .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.2. An impossible urn</head><p>Let us now illustrate when Boole's "conditions of possible experience" fail. Once again, only two of the three properties are co-measured at a time. However, this time it not possible to simultaneously establish values for all three properties. Tables 16, 17 and 18 depict the pairwise samples. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 16</ref> has the following statistics where <ref type="formula">circle</ref> There is no disturbance, e.g., the probability that an object has a certain shape does does not depend on whether the size or colour are being co-measured with the shape property, e.g., = +̄= +̄. Therefore, Boole's "conditions of possible experience" can be tested. However, substituting the relevant probabilities into the following Bell inequality leads to a violation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">− − + ≥ 0 0.5 − 0.375 − 0.375 + 0 (= −0.25) ≱ 0</formula><p>According to Pitowsky, a possible explanation for the violation is that the objects that do not have "well-defined properties, existing prior to observation and distributed in a specific manner". In other words, such properties are indeterminate. By trying to join the <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Tables 16, 17 and 18 into a single table illustrates</ref> Pitowsky's conclusion (See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 11</ref>). As can be seen from this table there are some cells in the table corresponding to objects 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and 8 which seem to have two values of a property, illustrating indeterminacy. 5 Indeterminacy leads to incompatibility, e.g., when the size and shape of object 1 are co-measured, it is not possible to establish a definite value for its colour. Finally, objects 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and 8 have different properties depending on what other property is being co-measured, e.g., for objects 1 and 2, the object is blue if colour is measured alongside shape, but is green if measured along with size, and there is no causal explanation for this change. This illustrates the essence of contextuality, a happening that George Boole would consider as an impossible experience.  <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1  circle  large  2  circle  large  3  circle  large  4  circle  small  5</ref> square small 6 square small 7 square small 8 square small <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 17  Shape and colour   Object Shape Colour  1  circle  blue  2  circle  blue  3  circle  blue  4  circle  green  5</ref> square green 6 square green 7 square green 8 square green <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 18  Size and colour  Object Size  Colour  1  large  green  2  large  green  3  small blue  4  small blue  5</ref> small blue 6 small green 7 small green 8 large green</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 10</head><p>Three tables corresponding to co-measuring two properties at a time from the impossible urn. square small/large green</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 11</head><p>The impossible urn</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Example of Contextuality-by-Default</head><p>In Contextuality-by-Default (CbD), equation (8) defines a necessary and sufficient condition to show the CbDcontextuality for the special class of cyclic systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Kujala and Dzhafarov, 2016)</ref>. Importantly, CbD offers a definition of contextuality for systems with disturbance which is common is cognitive experiments. Whilst CbD-contextuality is related to the notion of contextuality presented in this article, they are distinct. An important difference is that CbD is not tied to realism. The experiments reported in this article comprise a cyclic system of = 3. As there are three variables = 3. Finally, the quantity Δ is a measure of disturbance in the system. It is computed as the sum of the absolute values of differences between the marginal probabilities across the measurement contexts, e.g, = 0.5 + 0.14 = 0.64 in measurement context 1 <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">(Table 4</ref>) and = 0.62 in measurement context 2 <ref type="table">(Table 5)</ref>. Therefore the absolute difference is 0.02. The respective marginal differences for dominance, <ref type="table">(Tables 5 and 6</ref>) and trust (Tables 4 and 6) are 0.04 and 0.14. Therefore, Δ = 0.02 + 0.04 + 0.14 = 0.20.</p><p>Substituting the preceding into equation <ref type="formula">8</ref>shows that this inequality is satisfied:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">odd − ( − 2) − Δ =</formula><p>1.4 − (3 − 2) − 0.2 = 0.2(&gt; 0)</p><p>Therefore, according to CbD the judgements of the face depicted in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> would seem to be contextual. Bootstrap analysis using 100,000 independent resamples produces a confidence interval of <ref type="bibr">[-2.2,1.5</ref>] with a mean of -0.09. As the lower bound of the confidence interval is not greater than zero, the determination of contextuality is not statistically reliable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Reality without Realism</head><p>In quantum physics, non-contextual realism is defined as when "the (supposedly predefined) value of a quantum observable is independent of other compatible observables that are measured along with it" <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Rivas, 2019)</ref>. Realism is bound up with the assumption that quantum observables (or cognitive properties) have definite values at all times. In the literature, this assumption is variously referred to as "realism" <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Hermens, 2011)</ref>, "outcome determinism" <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Masse, 2021)</ref>, "value definiteness" <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Held, 2018)</ref>. We will henceforth refer to the assumption as "determinism". In addition, "non-contextual" (NC) means that the value of a quantum observable or cognitive property does not depend on other (cognitive) properties that are co-measured with it. Determinism and non-contextuality are independent aspects of the realism behind Boole's "conditions of possible experience". In the preceding quote, the qualifier "supposedly predefined" alludes to the possibility that the values of observables may not be definite, at least for some of them. <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Pitowsky (1994)</ref> states such possibility as follows: when Boole's conditions are violated, "maybe there are no well defined properties, existing independently of observation and distributed in a specific manner. All that exist are the phenomena themselves, which simply occur without cause" (p. 107). Whilst Pitowsky clearly questions determinism for such properties, it is important to note that he does not totally give up on realism. In his own words, his position regarding realism is "peculiar". He states (p. 118) "When we deny that some properties exist (independently of observation), and are distributed in a certain way, we do not reject 'realism' as a metaphysical position. After all, the peculiarities of quantum statistics are associated with certain observablesbut not all" [emphasis in the original]. In short, Pitowsky is advocating acausality and indeterminacy as a possible explanation for why some properties violate Boole's "conditions of possible experience".</p><p>We think it reasonable to assume that cognitive properties might be viewed in the same way. A cognitive property might be definite prior to measurement, e.g., due to a cognitive bias. But like Pitowsky, we propose that this might hold for some cognitive properties. So where does that leave us in terms of the underlying reality of cognitive properties that are not in a definite state prior to measurement.</p><p>In our opinion, Pitwosky adopts a weak form of 'reality without realism' (RWR) <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Plotnitsky, 2016</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Plotnitsky, , 2021</ref>. As the name suggests, RWR denies realism whilst preserving a some concept of 'reality'. In strong RWR, the nature of the underlying reality is beyond conception. Weak RWR, on the other hand, assumes an independent reality, which cannot be represented due to epistemological limitations. Irrespective of weak or strong, RWR eschews causality, as does Pitowsky. Value-definiteness, i.e., determinism (as defined above), is also rejected, so indeterminacy is assumed.</p><p>We now move onto how indeterminacy is related to contextuality. In quantum theory, there is a strong connection between the Kochen-Specker theorem and contextuality. The reason for this is that the theorem resulted from the question whether hidden variables could be used to complete quantum theory, whereby the charge of incompleteness was originally raised by Einstein. Bohr believed the quantum state describes nature "exhaustively", whereas Einstein viewed it as not "completely" <ref type="bibr">(Belinfante, 2014, p.17)</ref>. Belinfante states that the main driving force behind the belief in hidden variables is that "nature must be deterministic" and that "everything happening in nature must be predetermined by previous happenings in the physical world", even when our knowledge is too limited to grasp the physical causes of what is happening. Therefore, hidden variable theories are not only about completing quantum thoery but also a way to retain realism.</p><p>The Kochen-Specker theorem is widely interpreted as quantum theory (QT) being incompatible with holding Determinism (D), Non-contextualtity (NC) and a one-to-one correspondence between properties and projection operators (PP). In order to resolve this incompatibility, a minimal approach is to accept indeterminacy (ND) or contextuality (C), but not both, with PP held. Therefore, there are two possible resolutions:</p><p>1. QT is compatible with (ND and NC and PP), or 2. QT is compatible with (D and C and PP).</p><p>In order to preserve realism, hidden variable theories adopt 2). That is determinism (and causality) are retained, with contextuality assumed. Note that the realism has become contextual rather than a non-contextual. As Boole's "conditions of possible experience" are predicated on non-contextual realism, phenomena that are contextually real can violate his conditions.</p><p>RWR opens up a third stance that we believe is appropriate for cognitive properties that violate Boole's "conditions of possible experience". This stance is stated as: QC is compatible with (ND and C and PP), where QC denotes the theory of quantum cognition.</p><p>The justification for assuming indeterminacy has already been laid out above following Pitowsky. Moreover, indeterminacy is a fundamental assumption held by the field of quantum cognition. Further, contextuality is automatic in RWR given incompatibility. (See <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Khrennikov (2020)</ref> for an aligned view). Finally, PP is an implicit assumption in quantum cognition, namely there is an assumed one-to-one correspondence between cognitive properties and projection operators, so PP is retained. We will denote this stance QC-RWR.</p><p>QC-RWR can be challenged from the perspective of hidden variable theories, namely QC is compatible with (D and C and PP). Note that by assuming D, this stance holds that cognitive properties are always in a definite state. We will term this the Quantum Cognitive Hidden Variable (QC-HV) stance.</p><p>An important underlying distinction between QC-RWR and QC-HV is the the nature of uncertainty attributable to the cognitive properties. By assuming ND, QC-RWR allows for ontological uncertainty, i.e., the uncertainty is intrinsic to the very nature of the property, and we can't ever know what state it is in. In contrast, uncertainty in QC-HV is purely epistemic, i.e, the cognitive property is always has a definite state, but we may not know what that is. In addition, QC-RWR assumes acausality, which is a challenging issue to empirically verify. In quantum theory, the space-like separation of quantum systems is used to rule out causal influences during experiments, which ensures no disturbance between the systems. Unfortunately, no disturbance cannot be used assume that acausality holds in cognitive experiments, as there may be hidden causal influences which conspire to produce no differences of marginal probabilities across experimental conditions <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Atmanspacher and Filk, 2019)</ref>. Nevertheless, we don't believe it to be impossible to reliably verify acausality in cognitive experiments. It is often the case that development of suitable empirical methods lags behind theoretical/philosophical assumptions.</p><p>Just as in the decades long debates found in quantum physics, the chosen stance depends on what philosophical assumptions one is willing to make. Following Pitowsky and RWR, we believe that assuming indeterminacy, acasuality and contextuality for some cognitive properties is worth serious consideration, hence we favour QC-RWR over QC-HV. Whilst empirically showing contextuality of cognitive properties does not necessarily entail that they are indeterminate, there is however reason to believe that this might be the case.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Face 1 (trustworthiness = moderately high)Figure 2: Face 2 (trustworthiness = moderately low)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>probabilities into the following Bell inequality illustrates a violation of one of Boole's conditions: 3 :</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Context 1 Context 2 Context 3</head><label>123</label><figDesc>Trustworthiness and intelligence are co-measured ( = 50) Dominance and intelligence are co-measured ( = 50) Dominance and trustworthiness are co-measured ( = 50)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 6</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Data for context-sensitivity analysis (Exp. 2): Face 2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Boole's urn containing 8 objects of various sizes, shapes and</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>A table corresponding to Boole's urn depicted inFigure 7</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Finally,</head><label></label><figDesc>, (square), (large), (small):Table 17has the following statistics where (circle), (square), (blue), (green):Table 18has the following statistics where (large), (small), (blue), (green):</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>odd − ( − 2) − Δ &gt; 0 (8) The quantity odd is a maximal summation of correlations where the summation involves an odd number of minus signs. The correlations from Tables 4-6 are respectively as follows: [ ] = 0.68, [ ] = 0.48 and [ ] = −0.24 where , and are dichotomous random variables corresponding to judgments of intelligence, dominance and trustworthiness. odd = 0.68 + 0.48 − (−0.24) = 1.40</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Table 2</cell><cell>Table 3</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Context 10</cell><cell>Context 20</cell><cell>Context 30</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>.58 0.14</cell><cell>.32 0.40</cell><cell>.2</cell><cell>0.42</cell></row><row><cell>0.10 0.18</cell><cell>0.12 0.16</cell><cell>0.18</cell><cell>0.2</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Table 5</cell><cell>Table 6</cell></row><row><cell>Context 10</cell><cell>Context 20</cell><cell>Context 30</cell></row><row><cell>.50 0.14</cell><cell>.54 0.08</cell><cell>.26 0.12</cell></row><row><cell>0.02 0.34</cell><cell>0.18 0.20</cell><cell>0.50 0.12</cell></row><row><cell>Figure 4</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Data for contextuality analysis (Exp. 1): Face 2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 7</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Condition 10</cell></row><row><cell>.42 0.12</cell></row><row><cell>0.36 0.10</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 10</head><label>10</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Table 11</cell><cell>Table 12</cell></row><row><cell>Condition 10</cell><cell>Condition 20</cell><cell>Condition 30</cell></row><row><cell>.24 0.12</cell><cell>.34 0.36</cell><cell>.26 0.12</cell></row><row><cell>0.42 0.22</cell><cell>0.14 0.16</cell><cell>0.50 0.12</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Even though varies slightly across conditions 1 and 2, the value 0.62 was used in the preceding equation as in other experiments that we conducted with this face, the was equal to, or very close to this value.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">An analogous explanation was used in the Linda example<ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Busemeyer and Bruza, 2012)</ref> In this case, the incongruence arises from the subject trying to consider Linda to be both a feminist and bank teller.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5">Alternatively, a cognitive property could be determinate and it's pre-existing value changes due to measurement in different experimental conditions. This possibility is discussed in Appendix C.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This research was supported by the Asian Office of Aerospace Research and Development (AOARD) grant: FA2386-17-1-4016.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Acacio</forename><surname>De Barros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Oas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1512.00033</idno>
		<title level="m">Some examples of contextuality in physics: Implications to quantum cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A case for applying an abstracted quantum formalism to cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Aerts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Broekaert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gabora</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New ideas in psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="136" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Concept combination, entangled measurements, and prototype theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Aerts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gabora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sozzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Topics in Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The architecture of cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A proposed test of temporal nonlocality in bistable perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Atmanspacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Filk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="314" to="321" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Necker-Zeno model for bistable perception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Atmanspacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Filk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Topics in Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Atmanspacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Filk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-21908-6_10</idno>
		<title level="m">Quanta and Mind: Essays on the Connection between Quantum Mechanics and Consciousness</title>
		<editor>de Barros, J.A., Montemayor, C.</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="127" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Contextuality revisited: Signaling may differ from communicating</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Very first impressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Neta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Linz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">269</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">True contextuality beats direct influences in human decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Basieva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Cervantes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dzhafarov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khrennikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">148</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1925" to="1937" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Survey of Hidden-Variables Theories: International Series of Monographs in Natural Philosophy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Belinfante</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="1862" />
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>On the theory of probabilities</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Realism and pyschologism in 19th century logic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Brockhaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophy and Phenomenological Research LI</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="493" to="524" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A probabilistic framework for analysing the compositionality of conceptual combinations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bruza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kitto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ramm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Sitbon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum cognition: a new theoretical approach to psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bruza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="393" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Quantum cognition and decision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bruza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is there a problem with quantum models of psychological measurements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>e0187733. Busemeyer</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="572" to="591" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>PLoS ONE</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The philosophical significance of Cox&apos;s theorem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Colyvan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Approximate Reasoning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">True contextuality in a psychophysical experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dzhafarov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Cervantes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="127" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On selective influences, marginal selectivity, and Bell/CHSH inequalities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dzhafarov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kujala</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Topics in Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextuality-by-default: A brief overview of ideas, concepts, and terminology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dzhafarov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kujala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Cervantes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Symposium on Quantum Interaction</title>
		<editor>Atmanspacher, H., Filk, T., Pothos, E.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An experimental protocol to derive and validate a quantum model of decision-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dehdashti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bruza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Moreira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 41st Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society (COGSCI&apos;19)</title>
		<meeting>the 41st Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society (COGSCI&apos;19)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Direct realism and the analysis of perceptual error</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Galloway</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Theory &amp; Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="605" to="613" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic models of cognition: exploring representations and inductive biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kemp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Perfors</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="364" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Kochen-Specker Theorem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Held</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy</title>
		<editor>Zalta, E.N.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Metaphysics Research Lab, Stanford University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Challenging the classical notion of time in cognition: a quantum perspective. The problem of contextuality and the impossibility of experimental metaphysics thereof</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hermens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="214" to="225" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Formal representations of belief</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy. Spring</title>
		<editor>Zalta, E.N.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Metaphysics Research Lab, Stanford University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uncertainty relations and possible experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Jaeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3390/math4020040</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2020. Quantum contextuality and indeterminacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">22080867</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Entropy</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relating causal and probabilistic approaches to contextuality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society A 377. Kennedy, M</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="109" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of the Aristotelian Society</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ubiquitous quantum structure: From Psychology to Finance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khrennikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Contextuality versus incompatibility: Searching for physical meaning of contextuality peeled off incompatibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Khrennikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2005.051242v2</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Proof of a conjecture on contextuality in cyclic systems with binary variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kujala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dzhafarov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Foundations of Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="299" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">From the problem of future contingents to peres-mermin square experiments: An introductory review to contextuality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Masse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2105.13821</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The functional basis of face evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Oosterhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">105</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11087" to="11092" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">George Boole&apos;s &quot;conditions of possible experience&quot; and the quantum puzzle</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Pitowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal for the Philosophy of Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="125" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spooky predictions at a distance: reality, complementarity and contextuality in quantum theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Plotnitsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Plotnitsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phil. Trans. R. Soc. A</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">377</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1956" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>The Direction of Time. Berkeley: University of Los Angeles Press</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Reality Without Realism: Matter, Thought, and Technology in Quantum Physics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the role of joint probability distributions of incompatible observables in Bell and Kochen-Specker theorems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rivas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of Physics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">411</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceptions of dominance following glimpses of faces and bodies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Rule</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Adams</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ambady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perception</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="687" to="706" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prospects of enactivist approaches to intentionality and cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Schlicht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tarzak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Synthese</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unconscious processing of facial dominance: The role of low-level factors in access to awareness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Awad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gayet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Peelen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unconscious evaluation of faces on social dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ajina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Getov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Rees</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">141</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">715</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The conceptual structure of face impressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Stolier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hehman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PNAS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9210" to="9215" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating faces on trustworthiness after minimal time exposure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Pakrashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Oosterhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="813" to="833" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A quantum probability explanation for order effects on inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1518" to="1552" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A quantum probability framework for human probabilistic inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trueblood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yearsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Pothos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">146</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1307" to="1341" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A quantum question order model supported by empirical tests of an a priori and precise prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Topics in Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="689" to="710" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sometimes it does hurt to ask: The constructive role of articulating impressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Pothos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Busemeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">133</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="48" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The cost of asking: How evaluations bias subsequent judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Pothos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jarret</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="286" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Challenging the classical notion of time in cognition: a quantum perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yearsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Pothos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the Royal Society B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">218</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
