<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Family favoring effects across intent and outcome-based moral judgments and decisions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Valentino</forename><forename type="middle">Marcel</forename><surname>Tahamata</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate Institute of Mind, Brain and Consciousness</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Taipei Medical University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="TW">Taiwan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Tseng</surname></persName>
							<email>ptseng@ntu.edu.tw</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Taiwan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="TW">Taiwan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Research Center for Mind, Brain &amp; Learning</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Chengchi University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Taipei</settlement>
									<country key="TW">Taiwan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Family favoring effects across intent and outcome-based moral judgments and decisions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1177/17470218231216428)</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:22+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>morality</term>
					<term>judgment</term>
					<term>decision-making</term>
					<term>family membership</term>
					<term>favoritism</term>
					<term>victimization</term>
					<term>familicide</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Doing harm is a moral violation, but helping a family member is morally obligatory. In this study, participants encountered this ethical dilemma through stories featuring their sibling (i.e., brother) as either the perpetrator or victim in various moral scenarios. Subsequently, they provided their moral judgments (i.e., moral acceptability and perceived transgression) and made decisions (i.e., willingness and difficulty to disclose what the agent did to the police) regarding the perpetrator. The manipulation of family membership was integrated into the moral scenarios, which were crafted based on whether the perpetrator had malicious intent and whether those intentions resulted in a harmful outcome (i.e., intentional harm, failed attempts to harm, accidental harm, and a harmless/baseline). While we initially expected that individuals would exhibit favoritism toward their brother when harmful intent or outcomes were absent, our findings revealed that both agent/victim identities (brother/stranger) and intent-outcome-based moral scenarios had an additive effect on both measures of moral judgment. This suggests that the family-favoring effect was observed across all intent-outcome scenarios, with a slightly more pronounced effect when the brother accidentally harmed a stranger compared to a stranger accidentally harming the brother. Regarding moral decisions, participants demonstrated a willingness to disclose what they witnessed regardless of their familial relationship with the agent or victim, but it was universally perceived as a difficult decision to make. Together, our results underscore the context-specific nature of moral judgments and decisions, emphasizing the significant impact of family members when they are involved as moral characters.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>"A judge should not practice law and should not serve as a family member's lawyer in any forum." -Code of Conduct for United States Judges It is widely acknowledged that a judge should not adjudicate cases involving their family members to prevent potential bias. This code of conduct recognizes that even a trained legal professional may have a tendency to make unfair judgments when facing such situations. In the field of moral psychology, the use of hypothetical moral vignettes (e.g., trolley dilemma, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Greene, Sommerville, Nystrom, Darley, &amp; Cohen, 2001</ref>) has been a very popular way to investigate this family favoring effect (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kurzban et al., 2012)</ref>. Unlike natural observations, the use of moral vignettes allows philosophers or psychologists to flexibly manipulate the wide array of moral reasoning to obtain cleaner results. Despite this huge advantage, the majority of studies under this paradigm include neutral character scenarios where participants were asked to judge an anonymous agent for their moral thought or act toward the anonymous victim (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Gawronski &amp; Beer, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Greene et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Greene, Morelli, Lowenberg, Nystrom, &amp; Cohen, 2008)</ref>. This scenario, however, may not be the moral event people encounter in their everyday life.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.">Family membership on moral judgment</head><p>In real-life settings, moral judgment rarely involves neutral agents or victims. That is, even a stranger (agent or victim) on the street cannot escape group identity or social labels (e.g., race, gender, religion, socioeconomic class) based on their appearance or behavior. In a review on ethics, <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Nagel (1979)</ref> pointed out the personal and situated conditions where the agent's moral decision can be dependent on their relative obligation. One of the classic examples is perhaps parents tend to prioritize their own children's welfare over others in need <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Pinker, 2011)</ref>. This family favoritism effect can also be observed in moral dilemma experiments (for a review, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bloom, 2011)</ref>, where individuals are willing to sacrifice one person to save five but hesitate to do so if the person is a family member, friend, or ingroup member <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Kahane et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bonnefon, Shariff, &amp; Rahwan, 2016)</ref>. In essence, the cost of sacrificing one significant ingroup member is perceived as greater than losing five strangers. This phenomenon, known as the highconflict moral dilemma, applies even to individuals inclined towards utilitarianism <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Koenigs et al., 2007)</ref>.</p><p>Similarly, recent studies have shown that familial relationships (i.e., parent-child and siblings) establish a caregiving system, making it morally obligatory to care for family members <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Earp et al., 2021)</ref>. A similar pattern emerges in other socially close relationships, such as close friends and romantic partners, and to some extent, it is observed in other types of social relationships, including neighbors, classmates, teacher-student, and bossemployee dynamics, among others. These observations illustrate the 'homo justlikeus' tendency <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Greene, 2014)</ref>, wherein people prioritize themselves and those who share the same group identity over anonymous individuals. Recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lee and Holyoak (2020)</ref> showed that when one's brother is a perpetrator, people tend to judge their brother as less unethical and are therefore less likely to report their brother to the police compared to an anonymous perpetrator. This bias, or tolerance effect, is particularly strong when there is room for biased interpretations so that participants can rationally justify what their family member did as the moral agent. For example, when the agent's face is unclear (i.e., ambiguous condition), such tolerance effect becomes more pronounced because there is enough 'grey area' for biased interpretation.</p><p>While studies have started to document the family tolerance effect, which primarily focuses on family members as perpetrators, there remains a notable gap in the literature when it comes to examining the situation where a family member is the victim. To the best of our knowledge, no study has yet explored this specific aspect. However, certain related studies shed light on relevant dynamics. For instance, <ref type="bibr">Nordgren and McDonnell (2010)</ref> found that people tend to assign higher blame to the agent when the victim is identifiable, as opposed to when the victim is unidentifiable (i.e., faceless). This effect is believed to result from greater sympathy towards personalized victims as compared to "statistical victims" (i.e., faceless masses), which in turn leads to a higher willingness to help identifiable victims <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Small &amp; Loewenstein, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Small, Loewenstein, &amp; Slovic, 2007)</ref>. Additionally, a study by McManus et al. (2020) revealed intriguing dynamics. When an agent decides to help someone, agents who helped a stranger were judged as significantly more morally good than agents who helped their kin. However, when both kin and a stranger require assistance, the effect reverses, with agents who helped strangers over kin being considered morally worse. While these studies didn't directly involve family members as victims of harm, they suggest the possibility of an exacerbation effect. This effect implies that people may tend to excessively blame others when their family members become victims. Consequently, just as people tend to defend their family members when they are the moral agents (i.e., the tolerance effect), they may also defend their family members when they become victims, possibly by adopting a more punitive judgment and action towards the agent (i.e., the exacerbation effect). Such a bias pattern could have significant implications in scenarios where responsibility must be attributed, such as legal court cases, as exemplified experimentally in moral scenarios. Therefore, this family member bias may manifest not only when the agent is unneutral but also when the victim is unneutral.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.">Harmful intent and outcome as potential room for biased judgment and decision</head><p>As previously mentioned, <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lee and Holyoak (2020)</ref> illustrated the existence of a family tolerance effect in cases where there is sufficient ambiguity to allow for favorable interpretations. Interestingly, these authors introduced ambiguity in their study via the use of non-moral circumstantial factors (i.e., an unclear view of the perpetrator). As such, it remains unclear what would happen when elements that are central to moral reasoning and judgments become the source of such "grey area".</p><p>In the domain of moral blame, two significant factors influencing moral reasoning related to harm are intent and outcome. More specifically, having the intent to harm is generally considered morally worse than causing unintentional harm, such as an accident. This distinction holds not only in research studies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Cushman, 2015)</ref> but also in legal practice, where different weight is assigned to murder (i.e., premeditated) and manslaughter <ref type="bibr">(i.e., unintentional)</ref>. Based on the presence or absence of intent and outcome, moral scenarios can be orthogonally decomposed into four experimental conditions: (1) harmful (both intent and outcome are present), (2) attempt (failed execution of bad intent), (3) accident (unintentional harmful outcome), and (4) harmless (no harmful intent or outcome).</p><p>As both harmful intent and outcome are integral considerations in moral judgment and decision-making, the presence of both components constitutes a clear and unequivocal moral violation. Therefore, akin to the unambiguous condition in <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lee and Holyoak's (2020)</ref> study, where the agent's identity is evident, it is unlikely that the intentional harm scenario would permit biased interpretations in favor of a family member. However, ambiguity is possible when one of these components is absent, thus allowing room for bias to emerge. For instance, if our brother attempted to intentionally harm someone but failed, we might argue that our brother is not to blame because no one was hurt (i.e., attempt condition: the harmful outcome is absent). Similarly, we may adopt a more punitive stance towards an anonymous agent who accidentally harmed our brother compared to a stranger (i.e., accident condition: the harmful intent is absent). Thus, the absence of either intent or outcome, but not both, is considered to be the potential conditions (i.e., grey areas of biased judgment) in which one can reasonably defend a family member for their moral actions</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3.">Present Study</head><p>This study aimed to investigate whether the absence of either harmful intent or outcome can lead to biased judgments and decisions when a family member is involved as the agent or victim. As previously mentioned, such bias might manifest as a tolerance effect when a family member harms an anonymous individual (i.e., the baseline character) and conversely, as an exacerbation effect when a stranger victimizes a family member. To test these hypotheses, we conducted simultaneous analyses considering both factors (i.e., agent/victim identities and intent-outcome based moral scenarios) as well as independent analyses of each factor. We designated accident and attempt scenarios as potential grey areas for judgment, which were expected to provoke favoring bias towards a family member represented by a brother. Note that the involvement of a brother character aimed to control for potential gender effects (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Feess, Feld, &amp; Noy, 2021)</ref>, aligning with previous studies on moral judgments <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kurdi et al., 2020)</ref>. Taken together, this study sought to delineate how the availability or unavailability of the bad intent and outcome of a moral action can systematically alter one's moral judgments and decisions with the involvement of their family member, both as the agent and/or victim.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Participants</head><p>The minimum of 286 sample size was estimated using g*Power 3.1. with an effect size of 0.25, 0.9 power, and 0.05 alpha. All participants are the United States residents, aged 20 or older, and controlled to participate only once. We then used Amazon Mechanical Turk to recruit and compensate 651 participants from the United States. However, 234 of them failed to fulfil the predetermined memory-check questionnaires (see the section 2.2. below) and 13 did not complete the experiment. Hence, they are excluded from subsequent analysis, resulting in 404 participants (177 females, 216 males, 11 others; Mage = 42.08 years, SDage = 11.50). The more detailed descriptive data based on the experimental conditions is available in <ref type="table">Table B1</ref>, Appendix B.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Materials, Design, and Procedure</head><p>A total of 12 moral vignettes, adapted from <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Young et al. (2007)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kurdi et al. (2020)</ref> with necessary modification, were used in this study (refer to Appendix A for details of each story). Each vignette featured two characters: 1) the agent (the moral actor) and 2) the victim (the other person who is affected by the agent's action). In the original version, not all characters were male, and the victim remained nameless. However, in our modified version, both agent and victim were assigned a Western male name (e.g., George, Gary, Sam) as we designated brother as the unneutral character. As outlined in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, each vignette was presented across four different slides, consisting of 1) background information, 2) the true state of the world, 3) the agent's belief or intention, and 4) the outcome. Each story can be flexibly manipulated into four distinct scenarios according to the presence and absence of intent and outcome: 1) harmless (i.e., both harmful intent and outcome are absent, baseline story), 2) accident (i.e., harmful outcome is present without harmful intent), 3) attempt (i.e., the presence of intent and absence of outcome), and 4) harmful (i.e., the presence of both intent and outcome).</p><p>Here, the harmless stories were chosen as the baseline condition, particularly because these stories do not contain any moral violation (i.e., no harmful intent and outcome) and were phrased similarly to the other harm-related stories. This harmless condition was also used to anchor participants' responses in the target stories. Similar approach has also been done before to establish a reference point for participants to differentiate between morally relevant factors in the target scenarios <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Young &amp; Saxe, 2011)</ref>.</p><p>Furthermore, as both accident and attempt are absent of outcome or intent respectively, we assume that these specific conditions would provoke bias in moral judgments and decisions (i.e., grey areas). On the other hand, harmful and harmless conditions are deemed apparent moral conditions (i.e., apparent violation and nonviolation), where these conditions were expected to provoke non-biased judgment. See <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> for a sample of the vignettes. In addition, we manipulated the agent/victim identities (i.e., agent-victim) into four scenarios according to the neutrality of each character: 1) Stranger-Stranger, 2) Brother-Stranger, 3) Stranger-Brother, and 4) Brother-Brother (See <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>). This agent/victim character manipulation could be identified via the instruction that was placed right before the first part of each story (see <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> for an example).</p><p>Each participant would receive two independent stories in a counterbalanced manner: 1) baseline story (i.e., Harmless condition with Stranger-Stranger scenario), and 2) one target story from a pool of 12 possible combinations (i.e., Accident, Attempt, or Harmful condition with either Stranger-Stranger, Brother-Stranger, Stranger-Brother, or Brother-Brother scenario). After the presentation of each story, participant would have to rate their moral judgments: 1) perceived-transgression <ref type="formula">(</ref> name] did to the officer?) in a yes/no binary format to depict the real-life nature of this situation where people have to make a choice, and 2) the difficulty of doing so ("Based on your response above, how difficult is it to consider disclosing/ not disclosing what [agent's name] did to the police officer?") in a 5-point Likert scale. The use of 5-point Likert scale to measure difficulty to disclose what agent did and 6-point Likert scale for moral judgments was adapted from <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lee and Holyoak (2020)</ref> to maintain consistency across studies. In order to fit the scoring direction between both measures of moral judgment, we did reverse scoring the moral acceptability measure that would then reverse the interpretation accordingly: the higher score indicates what agent did is more morally unacceptable. Adapting the procedure of analysis from <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kurdi et al., (2020)</ref>, we performed subtraction between the score of target story and baseline story, resulting in the final score of each moral judgment (i.e., perceived-transgression and moral acceptability).</p><p>On the other hand, we assessed moral decisions (i.e., willingness to disclose what the agent did to the police and the difficulty of doing so) without utilizing the subtraction method. Instead, we derived these scores directly from the original data of the target story. This approach was chosen because the willingness to disclose what the agent did to the police was designed to measure the decision to let the agent be punished (by law enforcement). Therefore, if participants gave higher ratings for their willingness to disclose what the agent did to the police in the target conditions, it could imply a willingness to see the agent punished. However, such an interpretation would not apply to the harmless scenario, presumably because equally high ratings in the harmless condition might simply indicate a willingness to disclose because there's nothing to hide, as the agent is considered innocent. Therefore, using the subtraction method in this context could potentially obscure the true nature of moral decisions.</p><p>We subsequently asked the participants if they actually have a brother in real life, as well as how close they feel they are to the brother on a 5-point Likert scale. Lastly, we adopted the procedure from <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kurdi et al., (2020)</ref> to use only the data from those who passed the memory-check questionnaire. This questionnaire consisted of two questions regarding the presence or absence of harmful intent and outcome respectively: 1) "In the story about [agent's name], did something bad happen to the other person?", 2) "Did [agent's name] believe that something bad would happen to the other person?". For a clearer flow of the experimental design, please check the video in our online Appendix. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Moral judgments</head><p>We performed a 4 (agent/victim identities: stranger-stranger, stranger-brother, brother-stranger, brother-brother) x 3 (intent-outcome-based scenarios: accident, attempt, harmful) between-subjects ANOVA for each dependent measure of moral judgment (i.e., moral acceptability and perceived-transgression). Note that group means are reported as mean ± standard deviation. For the primary analysis, each factor (i.e., agent/victim identities and intent-outcome scenarios) showed significant main effect while there was no interaction between those factors in both perceived-transgression and moral acceptability, in details below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1.">Moral Acceptability</head><p>For moral acceptability ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>), both intent-outcome scenarios (F(2, 392) = 65.51, p &lt; 0.001, ηp 2 = 0.248) and agent/victim identities (F(3, 392) = 3.86, p = 0.009, ηp 2 = 0.026) showed significant main effect without interaction (F(6, 392) = 1.68, p = 0.123, ηp 2 = 0.025). Since the scoring was reversed, note that higher score indicates higher moral unacceptability. As predicted, participants judged the agent in the Stranger-Brother (MStranger-Brother = 3.57 ± 1.68) to be more morally unacceptable than the agent in the Brother-Stranger condition (MBrother-Stranger = 2.79 ± 2.06, t(392) = 3.091, p = 0.025). Furthermore, the Brother-Brother (MBrother-Brother = 3.08 ± 1.99) is equally unacceptable as the Stranger-Stranger condition (MStranger-Stranger = 3.19 ± 1.96; t(392) = -0.858, p = 1.000), indicating Brother-Stranger cancelled out the effect of Stranger-Brother condition. For the intent and outcome moral scenarios, participants indicated that what agent did in the accident scenario (MAccident = 1.75 ± 1.82) is more morally acceptable than in the attempt (MAttempt = 3.66 ± 1.47, t(392) = -8.95, p &lt; 0.001) and harmful (MHarmful = 3.91 ± 1.76, t(392) = -10.65, p &lt; 0.001) scenarios. Interestingly, attempt and harmful here showed no significant difference (t(392) = -1.25, p = 0.65). All post-hoc comparisons are Bonferroni-corrected. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2.">Perceived-Transgression</head><p>For perceived-transgression ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>), there were significant main effects in agent/victim identities (F(3, 392) = 5.148, p = 0.001, ηp 2 = 0.035) and intent-outcome scenarios (F(2, 392) = 63.135, p &lt; 0.001, ηp 2 = 0.244) without interaction (F(6, 392) = 0.815, p = 0.558, ηp 2 = 0.012). Although what the agent did in attempt and harmful conditions are equally unacceptable, participants judged the agent in harmful (MHarmful = 3.99 ± 1.57) scenario to be more transgressive than in attempt condition (MAttempt = 3.33 ± 1.53, t(392) = 3.58, p = 0.001), whereas the agent in accident (MAccident = 1.90 ± 1.67) is judged to be less transgressive than in both harmful (t(392) = -11.14, p &lt; 0.001) and attempt (t(392) = -7.18, p &lt; 0.001) conditions. Similar to moral acceptability, Brother-Stranger (MBrother-Stranger = 2.72 ± 1.93) and Stranger-Brother conditions (MStranger-Brother = 3.51 ± 1.65) showed significant difference (t(392) = -3.401, p = 0.011), and the agent in Brother-Brother (MBrother-Brother = 3.02 ± 1.81) condition is judged to be equally transgressive as in Stranger-Stranger (MStranger-Stranger = 3.28 ± 1.78, t(392) = -1.575, p = 1.000) condition, indicating the cancelling-out effect as observed in moral-acceptability. All post-hoc comparisons are Bonferroni-corrected. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Moral decisions</head><p>We performed two distinct inferential statistical analyses to analyze: 1) the willingness to disclose what the agent did to the police (i.e., willingness) and 2) the difficulty of doing so (i.e., difficulty). As the willingness was measured on a binary scale (i.e., yes/no), we performed a binomial logistic regression using both agent/victim identities and intent-outcome moral scenarios as predictors. We also conducted the same 4 (agent/victim identities) x 3 (intent-outcome scenarios) ANOVA to analyze the results for the difficulty.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1.">Willingness to disclose what agent did</head><p>The significant effect was only found on intent-outcome moral scenario, whereas no significant difference between each level of agent/victim identities (see Appendix B, <ref type="table">Table  B4</ref>). When harmful was set as the reference, the slope for the accident condition was negative and statistically significant (b = -0.937, 95% CI: [-1.563; -0.290], p = 0.004), indicating that participants were more willing to disclose what agent did in harmful scenario than accident. Likewise, the slope for the attempt condition was negative and statistically significant (b = -1.439, 95% CI: [-2.049; -0.819], p &lt; 0.001), indicating that participants were more willing to disclose what agent did in harmful scenario than attempt. Subsequently, we changed the reference to be the attempt, and found the slope for accident to be non-significant (b = 0.502, 95% CI: [-0.037; 1.052], p = 0.069), indicating that participants were equally willing or unwilling to disclose what agent did to the police in both attempt and accident scenarios.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2.">Difficulty in disclosing what agent did</head><p>Overall, there was a significant main ANOVA effect on agent/victim identities (F(3, 392) = 7.949, p &lt; 0.001, ηp 2 = 0.06), but intent-outcome moral scenarios (F(3, 392) = 1.171, p = 0.311, ηp 2 = 0.005) and their interaction (F(6, 392) = 0.841, p &lt; 0.539, ηp 2 = 0.013) were non-significant. We therefore performed the post-hoc analysis (with Bonferroni correction) only on agent/victim identities. The score of difficulty in Brother-Stranger (MBrother-Stranger = 1.47 ± 1.54) condition was found to be higher than Stranger-Stranger (MStranger-Stranger = 0.703 ± 1.05, t(392) = 3.995, p &lt; 0.001) and Stranger-Brother (MStranger-Brother = 0.703 ± 1.23, t(392) = 3.941, p &lt; 0.001) conditions, indicating that it is more difficult to disclose the moral violation of the brother than a stranger. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Two-way interaction between Stranger-Brother and Brother-Stranger in accidental scenario</head><p>Although we found no interaction between both intent-outcome moral scenarios and agent/victim identities, we suspect such absence of interaction may have been caused by the non-significant statistical outcome from the majority of levels in each factor, yet some of them could potentially show informative results. To explore this possibility, we performed an exploratory two-way post-hoc comparison between these factors. We found that participants judged the agent in brother-stranger (MBrother-Stranger = 1.06 ± 1.75) as more morally acceptable than the agent in stranger-brother condition (MStranger-Brother = 2.52 ± 2.00) in accidental harm scenario only (t(392) = -3.4213, p = 0.045, Bonferroni Corrected). Interestingly, when we performed t-test without correction, brother-stranger and strangerbrother also showed similar significant differences over perceived-transgression (MBrother-Stranger = 1.23 ± 1.69, MStranger-Brother = 2.48 ± 1.73, t(392) = -3.1581, p = 0.002, d = -0.802) and marginal difference on the difficulty of disclosing what agent did to the police (MBrother-Stranger = 1.10 ± 1.19, MStranger-Brother = 0.452 ± 1.09, t(392) = 1.933, p = 0.054, d = -0.491).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A B</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Independent analyses on agent/victim and intent-outcome manipulations</head><p>In addition to the joint factor analyses (i.e., 3x4 analyses on 3.1. and 3.2. sections) above, we independently investigate the effects of agent/victim [i.e., 2 (agent: brother vs. stranger) x 2 (victim: brother vs. stranger) ANOVA] and intent-outcome scenarios (i.e., one-way ANOVA: accident vs. attempt vs. harmful).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.1.">Independent analyses on agent/victim identities</head><p>For moral acceptability, we found a significant main effect of agent's identity (MBrother = 2.94 ± 2.03, MStranger = 3.38 ± 1.83; F(1, 400) = 5.389, p = 0.020, ηp 2 = 0.013), and marginally significant effect of victim's identity (MBrother = 3.32 ± 1.86, MStranger = 2.99 ± 2.01; F(1, 400) = 3.101, p = 0.079, ηp 2 = 0.008), and no interaction between them (F(1, 400) = 0.063, p = 0.802, ηp 2 &lt; 0.001). For perceived transgression, we observed a main effect of agent's identity (MBrother = 2.87 ± 1.87, MStranger = 3.40 ± 1.72; F(1, 400) = 8.627, p = 0.003, ηp 2 = 0.021), but not victim's identity (MBrother = 3.26 ± 1.75, MStranger = 3.00 ± 1.87; F(1, 400) = 2.282, p = 0.131, ηp 2 = 0.006) or their interaction (F(1, 400) = 0.033, p = 0.856, ηp 2 &lt; 0.001). No effect was observed for willingness to disclose what agent did (see Appendix B, <ref type="table">Table  B11</ref>). However, difficulty to make decision is significantly higher when brother happened to be the agent (MBrother = 1.29 ± 1.47, MStranger = 0.71 ± 1.14; F(1, 400) = 20.336, p &lt; 0.001, ηp 2 = 0.05), but not the victim (MBrother = 0.91 ± 1.32, MStranger = 1.08 ± 1.37; F(1, 400) = 1.879, p = 0.171, ηp 2 = 0.005), and there was no significant interaction (F(1, 400) = 1.880, p = 0.171, ηp 2 = 0.005).</p><p>As the effect of agent/victim manipulation on moral acceptability was marginally significant, we reanalyzed the data using the original ratings of target harm-related conditions (see <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>) without using the subtraction to baseline method. This reanalysis revealed significant effects of both the agent's (MBrother = 3.32 ± 1.86, MStranger = 3.76 ± 1.60; F(1, 400) = 6.569, p = 0.010, ηp 2 = 0.02) and victim's identities (MBrother = 3.72 ± 1.68, MStranger = 3.36 ± 1.80; F(1, 400) = 4.509, p = 0.034, ηp 2 = 0.01) on moral unacceptability, as well as a significant effect of the agent's identity (MBrother = 3.25 ± 1.77, MStranger = 3.61 ± 1.67; F(1, 400) = 4.484, p = 0.034, ηp 2 = 0.01) and a marginal effect of the victim's identity (MBrother = 3.59 ± 1.64, MStranger = 3.26 ± 1.80; F(1, 400) = 3.667, p = 0.056, ηp 2 = 0.009) on perceived transgression. Similar to the results from subtracted measures, no interaction between agent and victim identities was observed on both moral acceptability and perceived transgression measures without subtraction. In addition, the results for moral decisions, which were originally not subtracted from the baseline condition, remained unchanged from the findings mentioned in the earlier sections (section 3.2.1 and 3.2.2.).</p><p>Interestingly, although the main effect of victim's identity seemed not to be as significant as the agent's, the post-hoc pairwise comparison is only significant between brother-stranger and stranger-brother. This was observed in moral acceptability (t(400) = -2.883, p = 0.025; Bonferroni corrected), perceived-transgression (t(400) = -3.141, p = 0.011; Bonferroni corrected), and the difficulty to disclose what agent did (t(400) = 4.16, p &lt; 0.001; Bonferroni corrected). This replicates our main results (in section 3.1. and 3.2.) and therefore corroborates the idea about the agent-victim canceling-out effect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.2.">Independent analyses on intent-outcome scenarios</head><p>Since the harmless scenario, in which both harmful intent and outcome are absent, served as the baseline condition, we were unable to conduct a full 2 (intent: present vs. absent) x 2 (outcome: present vs. absent) analysis. Instead, we opted for an alternative approach by performing a Welch's one-way ANOVA on the target conditions (i.e., accident, attempt, and harmful) and subsequently using the Games-Howell post-hoc test to compare each condition pair. In this analysis, we discovered significant effects on both measures of moral judgment (i.e., moral acceptability and perceived transgression) and decision-making (i.e., willingness to disclose what the agent did and the difficulty of doing so). These findings align with the explanations provided in sections 3.1 and 3.2 regarding the impact of intent-outcome scenarios. For a comprehensive view of the statistical outcomes, please refer to <ref type="table">Table B12</ref>-B15 in Appendix B.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5.">Additional analyses</head><p>We additionally explored the potential effect of having real brother in life (that may have modulated participants' subjective closeness to the brother character), perceivedcloseness to the real brother, sex, age, the story order (normal: baseline then target story vs. reversed: target then baseline story), and demographic variation on each dependent measure. Participants who reported having real brother showed no significant difference with those who did not, in both moral judgment and decision measures. Likewise, perceived-closeness to the real brother, sex, and age did not predict the variation in each moral judgment and decision measure. Lastly, we observed no order effect on moral judgment measures, although this counterbalancing influenced moral decisions. Mann-Whitney U test revealed that participants were more willing to disclose what the agent did to the police in the normal (MNormal = 0.848 ± 0.360) than in the reversed order (MReversed = 0.686 ± 0.465, U = 23687, p &lt; 0.001; rbc = 0.161). 1 Similarly, participants who were exposed to reversed order (MReversed = 1.15 ± 1.46) reported that it is more difficult to disclose what agent did than those who received normal order (MNormal = 0.838 ± 1.20, U = 18181, p = 0.040; rbc = 0.108). <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Lastly, we conducted a regional analysis using Welch's one-way ANOVA to compare each dependent measure across the United States census regions (i.e., Northeast, South, West, and Midwest) and divisions (source: www.census.gov) to probe potential demographic variations. In this analysis, we found no differences across all regions in terms of moral unacceptability, perceived transgression, and the difficulty of disclosing what the agent did. However, it is worth noting that participants from the South tended to be more willing to disclose what the agent did to the police compared to participants from the Midwest and Northeast. For a comprehensive breakdown of these results, please refer to <ref type="table">Table B17</ref>-B26 in Appendix B.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussions</head><p>In this study, participants were confronted with two conflicting moral principles that causing harm to others is morally wrong, but providing preferential treatment to own family members is considered moral obligation. They were then asked to rate their moral judgments and decisions to the perpetrator where the perpetrator and the victim happened to be their own brother or a stranger. In addition to the family membership-based manipulation on agent and victim, participants were exposed to the intent and outcomebased moral scenarios (i.e., accident, attempt, and harmful, with harmless as the baseline story), where this two-factor (i.e., agent/victim identities and intent-outcome scenario) manipulation was initially proposed to capture the potential room for bias to favor family member when malicious intent of exercising moral action or its adverse outcome is absent. However, our main results indicated that such biases due to family membership might occur despite the absence or presence of both intent and outcome. This partial judgment toward family member was observed through the participants' higher blame-related judgments (i.e., moral unacceptability and perceived-transgression) toward a stranger compared with their brother as the moral agent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Variability of the dependent measures: Wrongness and norm judgments</head><p>Under the framework of moral blame like this study, it is important to carefully consider how moral judgments are measured. We asked participants to report the extent to which what agent did is morally unacceptable (i.e., reversed scoring from moral acceptability) and constituted a form of transgression. Although closely related, in a recent review, Malle (2021) clustered moral judgment into four categories: 1) evaluations (i.e., good vs. bad), 2) norm judgments (i.e., violation of obligatory norm), 3) wrongness judgments (i.e., morally permissible vs. forbidden), and 4) blame judgments (i.e., reproach or blame). And according to this classification, moral unacceptability and perceived state of transgression fall into different categories of moral judgments, where being morally unacceptable can be sorted to wrongness judgments and perceived-transgression is a perceived norm violation.</p><p>Consistent with Malle's categorization, we also found that people treated these questions differently, especially under intent-outcome-based scenario. For our participants, having intent, despite its outcome, is morally unacceptable (i.e., harmful = attempt &gt; accident). However, to assess the state of norm violation (i.e., transgression), people take both intent and outcome into account (i.e., harmful &gt; attempt &gt; accident). In other words, when morality is considered, intent alone regardless of outcome is sufficient to trigger one's moral alarm. But when transgression is considered, both intent and outcome need to be available for people to judgement in this manner. This unique patterns of weighing intent and outcome using multiple measures of moral judgments is fairly new to this field, as the previous findings (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Kurdi et al., 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Young, Koenigs, Kruepke, &amp; Newman, 2012)</ref> generally only identified the latter pattern (i.e., harmful &gt; attempt &gt; accident), unless when the effect is moderated by empathy or compassion (i.e., <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Patil et al., 2017)</ref> or involved specific population like terrorists <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Baez et al., 2017)</ref>. One may argue that moral acceptability and transgression are fundamental distinct, or a milder interpretation would be that they are similar attributes but judged by different standards (but from the same spectrum). From our data we do not have sufficient information to tease these two explanations apart, but nevertheless this observation corroborates with <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Malle's (2021)</ref> argument that moral judgments are fundamentally multidimensional and thus should be interpreted differently.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Family membership effects: Tolerance and exacerbation</head><p>In terms of family membership, a family member's moral violation toward an anonymous victim (i.e., brother-stranger) is perceived to be less unacceptable and transgressive, as compared to a stranger who perpetrated against the brother (i.e., strangerbrother). This makes sense given the previous findings have consistently showed people's tendency to attribute lower blame to the close others relative to distant others (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Weidman, Sowden, Berg, &amp; Kross, 2019)</ref>, especially a family member. This effect is arguably driven by the obligation to favor family member <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2020)</ref> that also applies in scenarios where individuals are praised for choosing to help a family member over a stranger <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(McManus, Kleiman-Weiner, &amp; Young, 2020)</ref>. Our results further expand this concept of family obligation that the favoring effect could also manifest in the form of extra blame for to the anonymous agent when a family member is victimized (i.e., exacerbation effect). This is in line with the tendency to avoid victimizing own family members in sacrificial moral dilemmas such as the trolley scenario, despite the utilitarian moral views when the victim is neutral (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bleske-Rechek, Nelson, Baker, Remiker, &amp; Brandt, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kurzban, DeScioli, &amp; Fein., 2012)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.">Selective bias on accidental scenario</head><p>We observed an additive effect between moral agent/victim identities and intentoutcome scenarios without significant interaction. This may reflect the robustness of both tolerance and exacerbation effects across multiple types of intent-outcome moral scenario. Practically speaking, however, this non-significant overall interaction may also be a result of dilution from the more non-ambiguous moral scenarios (i.e., stranger-stranger or brother-brother scenarios). This motivated us to perform an exploratory two-way post-hoc analysis, and we observed a significant interaction in the form of a family member as the moral violator against an anonymous victim (i.e., brother-stranger) being perceived as more morally acceptable than a stranger who victimizes brother (i.e., stranger-brother) particularly under the accidental scenario. However, we did not observe the same effect in attempt condition. In other words, the absence of intent (i.e., accident), but not outcome (i.e., attempt), yielded stronger bias in moral judgment when involving family member as the agent or victim. While judging from the third person perspective, people decode the agent's intent in exercising harmful action via a brain network that represents others' thought (i.e., Theory of Mind network, <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Young et al., 2007)</ref> whereas the state of victim's feeling is represented in the "empathy for pain" network <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Patil, Calò, Fornasier, Young, &amp; Silani 2017</ref>). Here we argue that the exposure to the accidental harm scenario does inflict stronger internal conflict <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Cushman, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Patil &amp; Trémolière, 2021)</ref>, that is the presence of the empathy for the victim's pain but blaming the agent is unreasonable due to the absent of harmful intent. Taking this perspective, our participants may have employed higher empathetic judgment while being exposed to the accidental harm scenario involving family member as the victim. However, this effect is marginally significant in other measures (i.e., perceived-transgression and difficulty to disclose agent's moral violation). We speculate this marginal effect comes from our overall design that is less targeted toward empathy, and that the moral vignettes and preceding instruction may have seemed too artificial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Familicide: Cancelled-out effect</head><p>When a brother murders another brother (i.e., brother-brother scenario), the tolerance and exacerbation effects cancelled each other out, that is indicated by its nonsignificant difference with the rest of the scenarios. This cancelling-out effect is somewhat new and unexpected as no study has done this before. At face value, this effect seems plausible, even logical, because family members are both agent and victim. In other words, the family-agent effect and the family-victim effect canceled each other out. However, psychologically, we suspect this formulaic or logical judgment cannot perfectly capture those natural judgments one would make when facing the real familicide. As it is a harmful action toward family member, we would have expected this scenario became highly emotional and therefore the exacerbation would take over the tolerance effect. An alternative explanation to this observed cancelling-out effect is because the manipulation of this study is formulaic in its design, thus leading people to engage in a more "economic" way of thinking. If true, this would mean that the cancelling-out effect is highly context specific to the manipulation applied in this study, and might not predict real-life brother-brother moral judgments. This may have implications on the extent to which moral scenarios are valid predictors of real-life behaviors, but requires further research in the future.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5.">Moral decisions and their associated difficulties</head><p>In addition to moral judgments, we also assessed participants' decisions to disclose what the agent did to the police and their perceived difficulty of doing so. This is adapted and slightly modified from <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lee and Holyoak (2020)</ref> under the assumption that: if participants were protective of their brother, they would be less likely to disclose the moral violation of their brother as compared to a stranger. And if they think they have to, it would be easier for them to disclose stranger's transgression than their own brother's.</p><p>In general, participants considered both intent and outcome to decide whether or not they would disclose to the police about what the agent did (i.e., harmful &gt; attempt = accident). However, unlike <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lee and Holyoak (2020)</ref>, our participants were equally willing to disclose agent's moral violation despite their familial membership with the agent or victim. But they admitted it is more difficult to disclose the moral violation of their brother than a stranger <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3</ref>). It is important to note here, that disclosing agent's moral violation to the police is a more passive form of moral decision-making than reporting it (i.e., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2020)</ref>. This decision-making process resembles the decision-making process in the trolley dilemma (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Greene, et al., 2001</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">, Greene, et al., 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Koenigs, et al., 2007)</ref>, where people tend to be more utilitarian in indirect harm scenario (e.g., pulling the switch) and more deontological when facing a direct harm dilemma (e.g., pushing a person off a bridge). Assuming that reporting is an active and direct form of moral decision-making, whereas disclosing is rather passive and indirect, it makes sense that people are more hesitant to proactively report what their brother did to the police, but more likely to disclose the violation when the police is the one who comes and asks about what have happened. Even though participants are willing to disclose their brother's moral violation, they reported it is harder to do so when compared to disclosing stranger's violation. In this regard, our finding is consistent with previous studies that portrayed family obligation in moral decision-making (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lee &amp; Holyoak, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">McManus, Kleiman-Weiner, &amp; Young, 2020;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">McManus, Mason, &amp; Young, 2021)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6.">Limitations and future directions</head><p>Although this present research is able to illustrate the unique effects of family membership to bias moral judgments, our initial proposal that such effects would be selectively observed when intent or outcome are absent is not completely true nor rejected. First, both factors (i.e., agent/victim identities and intent-outcome based scenarios) were observed to independently modulate the moral judgments in an additive manner. This indicates that despite the intentional state of a harmful action and its forthcoming outcome, the role of family membership is powerful in the alteration of moral judgment. Second, despite this pervasive effect of family membership on intent-outcome-based moral judgments, the accidental scenario was found to inflict significant wrongness judgment differences between brother-stranger and stranger-brother. Although the 2-way analysis is an exploratory post hoc, we argue that it is worth noting particularly because, out of the vast amount of 3x4 two ways interactive levels, this meaningful interaction was specifically found in the accidental scenario between the polarized conditions (i.e., brother-stranger vs. stranger-brother condition) only. Hence, despite its meaningfulness, this particular phenomenon is inadequate to yield significant two-way ANOVA interaction. Taking this caveat in mind, future research should consider simplifying the model or experimental design to statistically refine the family membership effect on moral judgment in accidental scenario.</p><p>Taken together, the results of this study suggest that people exhibit some degree of partiality in their moral judgments toward family members. While numerous studies have reported such bias, whether this effect is entirely independent of the obligation to favor other related ingroup memberships remains inconclusive. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Clark, Earp, and Crockett (2020)</ref> argued that relative obligations may vary across social relationships, contingent upon the functions these relationships serve (e.g., mating, attachment, reciprocity, hierarchy, and coalition). Expanding on this concept, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Earp et al. (2021)</ref> conducted a comprehensive examination of these relationship functions by including a wide range of real-life social relationships (e.g., siblings, neighbors, teacher-student dynamics, etc.) and assessed the dynamic moral judgments across these relationships. This suggests that the effect observed in this study may not solely pertain to family membership but may also apply, to some extent, to other types of social relationships. While the majority of studies in moral psychology emphasize the significance of malicious intent as being more morally wrong than the outcome alone, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barrett and Saxe (2021)</ref> have highlighted that this notion may not universally apply, particularly in cultures considered to be less focused on moral judgment. These cultural differences in attitudinal bias toward ingroup members have been observed <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Ma-Kellams, Spencer-Rodgers, &amp; Peng, 2011)</ref>. This is also why we exclusively recruited US participants, aiming to minimize the impact of cultural variability. However, it's important to note that even within the United States, cultural variability exists. This variation becomes apparent in participants' moral decisions, with individuals from the Southern part of the US showing a greater willingness to disclose the agent's actions compared to participants from the Midwest and Northeast. It's worth noting that the majority of studies in moral judgment have been conducted in "WEIRD" (Western, Educated, Industrialized, Rich, and Democratic) cultures <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Henrich, Heine, &amp; Norenzayan, 2010)</ref>, which largely shape our current understanding of moral psychology.</p><p>In terms of evolutionary perspective, moral dilemma study from <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kurzban et al., (2012)</ref> indicated that people tend to victimize a stranger over close other (i.e., brother or friend). But when they have to choose between brother or friend, they are in favor of their brother (i.e., sacrifice friend). <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Kurzban et al., (2012)</ref> discussed this in light of <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hamilton's (1964)</ref> kin selection theory, a form of natural selection that favors kin to increase one's inclusive fitness. This is perhaps the reason why people feel obliged and are heuristically willing to favor their family member. Taking this kin selection theory to elucidate family membership, we suppose there are at least three properties naturally embedded to the concept of family, 1) biological connectedness (i.e., genetically binding), 2) psychological attachment (i.e., psychologically or emotionally binding), and 3) shared ingroup identity (i.e., socially binding). According to <ref type="bibr">Kurzban et al.'s, (2012)</ref> finding, we can infer that the more familial properties we have, the more biased we tend to be. However, psychological attachment and shared group identity are indirect components of fitness that are not always associated with family membership. For instance, in the context of an extremely large group (e.g., nation), we might share the same group identity although having no genetic or even psychological connection. This seemingly distant kinship is thus found to provoke group favoritism effect on moral judgment too (e.g., <ref type="bibr">Ginger, Sheikh, Atran, &amp; Argo, 2016)</ref>. As such, these evolutionary components of family membership appear to overlap with each other in modulating the favoritism effect in moral judgments and decisions, and it is worth pursuing further research into their independent effects in the future accordingly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusions</head><p>In short, family membership is capable to bias moral judgments despite the perpetrator's intent and its adverse outcome. This points to the profound influence of the obligation to favor family member that is further enhanced under the accidental scenario. When it is rationally possible (i.e., when the intent to inflict harm is absent), people tend to be lenient toward their family members. Conversely, they would be more punitive when their family member is victimized. Finally, this study suggests that family obligation does not necessarily lead to a decision to conceal moral violations committed by family members, but it does make such decisions more difficult.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>6.</head><p>Open Practice All materials, raw data files, and analysis scripts used in this article are available on the Open Science Framework (OSF; https://osf.io/xgzjq/)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>7.</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conflict of Interest</head><p>The authors declare this study is in the absence of any financial or personal relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.">Acknowledgements</head><p>This study was supported in part by Taiwan's National Science &amp; Technology Council to PT (109-2423-H-002-004-MY4, 112-2410-H-002-252).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Moral acceptability across moral agent/victim identities and intent-outcome scenarios.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Perceived-transgression across moral agent/victim identities and intent-outcome scenarios.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Significant factors in moral decisions. A: Willingness to disclose is indexed by the percentage of participants indicating "Yes". B: Difficulty to disclose is indexed by the mean of self-reported difficulty of doing so.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>"Do you think [agent's name] committed transgression?"), 2) moral acceptability (According to what you believe happened, do you think what [agent's name] did was morally acceptable?) in 6-point Likert scale, and decisions: 1) willingness to disclose what the agent did to the police ("Given what you believe happened, if a police officer comes to you and asks what happened, would you disclose what [agent's</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 1 .Table 2 .Steve and Jim. Please imagine that Steve is your own brother whileTable 3 .</head><label>123</label><figDesc>The construction of each moral scenario based on the presence or absence of intent and outcome Character manipulation instruction and 4 parts of a sample vignettesCharacter manipulationThis story is about two friends, reading the story and filling the questionnaires.BackgroundSteve and Jim are kayaking in a part of the ocean with lots of jellyfish. Jim asks Steve if he should go for a swim.Bad Outcome (absent) Steve tells Jim to go for a swim. Jim does, enjoys the swim, and is just fine.Bad Outcome (present) Steve tells Jim to go for a swim. Jim does, gets stung by jellyfish, and dies. The distribution of target and baseline stories</figDesc><table><row><cell>Scenario</cell><cell>True State of the world</cell><cell>Bad Intent/ Belief</cell><cell>Bad Outcome</cell><cell>Culpability</cell></row><row><cell>1. Harmless (baseline)</cell><cell>Positive</cell><cell>Absent</cell><cell>Absent</cell><cell>Apparent non-transgression</cell></row><row><cell>2. Accident</cell><cell>Negative</cell><cell>Absent</cell><cell>Present</cell><cell>Grey Area</cell></row><row><cell>3. Attempt</cell><cell>Positive</cell><cell>Present</cell><cell>Absent</cell><cell>Grey Area</cell></row><row><cell>4. Harmful</cell><cell>Negative</cell><cell>Present</cell><cell>Present</cell><cell>Apparent transgression</cell></row><row><cell>Part 1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">True state of the world (positive)</cell><cell cols="2">True state of the world (negative)</cell></row><row><cell>Part 2</cell><cell cols="2">It is perfectly safe to swim in the ocean because the jellyfish don't</cell><cell cols="2">It is not safe to swim in the ocean because the jellyfish sting, and their</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">sting and are totally harmless.</cell><cell cols="2">stings are fatal.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Bad Intent / Belief (absent)</cell><cell cols="2">Bad Intent / Belief (present)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Since Steve read information that</cell><cell cols="2">Since Steve read information that</cell></row><row><cell>Part 3</cell><cell cols="2">said the ocean's jellyfish are</cell><cell cols="2">said the ocean's jellyfish are deadly,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">harmless, he believes that it is</cell><cell cols="2">he believes that it is not safe to</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">quite safe to swim in the ocean.</cell><cell cols="2">swim in the ocean.</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Since the effect of story order is significant on each measure of moral decision, we used ANCOVA to reanalyze the effects of the willingness and difficulty to disclose what agent did with involving the order of the story presentation as covariate. We found that the involvement of story order as covariate did not undermine the overall pattern of moral decision making, indicating that such effects are not driven by the order of the story. Please refer to Appendix BTable B23and B24.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Outcomeoriented moral evaluation in terrorists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Baez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Herrera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>García</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Manes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ibáñez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41562-017-0118</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-017-0118" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Human Behaviour</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are some cultures more mind-minded in their moral judgements than others?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Saxe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rstb.2020.0288</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2020.0288" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">376</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1838" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolution and the trolley problem: People save five over one unless the one is young, genetically related, or a romantic partner</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bleske-Rechek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Remiker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brandt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0099295</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0099295" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Social, Evolutionary, and Cultural Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="127" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The social dilemma of autonomous vehicles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Bonnefon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shariff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Rahwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.aaf2654</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaf2654" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">352</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6293</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1573" to="1576" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Family, community, trolley problems, and the crisis in moral psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bloom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-9736.2011.00701.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9736.2011.00701.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Yale Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="43" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who are &quot;we&quot; and why are we cooperating? Insights from social psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Earp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Crockett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0140525X19002528</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X19002528" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crime and punishment: Distinguishing the roles of causal and intentional analyses in moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2008.03.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2008.03.006" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="380" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deconstructing intent to reconstruct morality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.copsyc.2015.06.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.copsyc.2015.06.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Opinion in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="103" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How social relationships shape moral wrongness judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Earp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mcloughlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Monrad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Crockett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41467-021-26067-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-26067-4" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5776</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">People Judge Discrimination Against Women More Harshly Than Discrimination Against Men-Does Statistical Fairness Discrimination Explain Why?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Feess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Feld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Noy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.675776</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.675776" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What makes moral dilemma judgments &quot;utilitarian&quot; or &quot;deontological</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Gawronski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Beer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17470919.2016.1248787</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17470919.2016.1248787" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="626" to="632" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thinking from God&apos;s perspective decreases biased valuation of the life of a nonbeliever</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ginges</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sheikh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Atran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Argo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1512120113</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1512120113" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="316" to="319" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Moral tribes: Emotion, reason, and the gap between us and them</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<pubPlace>Penguin</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pushing moral buttons: The interaction between personal force and intention in moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lowenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nystrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2009.02.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2009.02.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="364" to="371" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive load selectively interferes with utilitarian moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Morelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lowenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nystrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2007.11.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2007.11.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1144" to="1154" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An fMRI investigation of emotional engagement in moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sommerville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nystrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Darley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.1062872</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1062872" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">293</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5537</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2105" to="2108" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The genetical evolution of social behaviour. II</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0022-5193(64</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-5193(64" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Theoretical Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90039" to="90045" />
			<date type="published" when="1964" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The weirdest people in the world?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Henrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Heine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Norenzayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0140525X0999152X</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X0999152X" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond sacrificial harm: A two-dimensional model of utilitarian psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kahane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Everett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Earp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Caviola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Faber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Crockett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Savulescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000093</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000093" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="164" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Damage to the prefrontal cortex increases utilitarian moral judgements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koenigs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Adolphs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tranel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Damasio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nature05631</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nature05631" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">446</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="908" to="911" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implicit evaluations of moral agents reflect intent and outcome</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Kurdi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Krosch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2020.103990</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2020.103990" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hamilton vs. Kant: Pitting adaptations for altruism against adaptations for moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kurzban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Descioli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.evolhumbehav.2011.11.002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.evolhumbehav.2011.11.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Evolution and Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="333" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">But he&apos;s my brother&quot;: The impact of family obligation on moral judgments and decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Holyoak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">48</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13421-019-00969-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13421-019-00969-7" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moral judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Malle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev-psych-072220-104358</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-psych-072220-104358" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="318" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">I am against us? Unpacking cultural differences in ingroup favoritism via dialecticism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ma-Kellams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Spencer-Rodgers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167210388193</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0146167210388193" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What we owe to family: The impact of special obligations on moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mcmanus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kleiman-Weiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797619900321</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797619900321" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Re-examining the role of family relationships in structuring perceived helping obligations, and their impact on moral evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mcmanus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mason</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jesp.2021.104182</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2021.104182" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mortal questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Nagel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The scope-severity paradox: Why doing more harm is judged to be less harmful</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Nordgren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H M</forename><surname>Mcdonnell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1948550610382308</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1948550610382308" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Psychological and Personality Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neuroanatomical correlates of forgiving unintentional harms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Patil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Calò</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Fornasier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Silani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/srep45967</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/srep45967" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reasoning supports forgiving accidental harms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Patil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Trémolière</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41598-021-93908-z</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-93908-z" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The better angels of our nature: The decline of violence in history and its causes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Pinker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<pubPlace>Penguin UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Helping a victim or helping the victim: Altruism and identifiability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Small</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/A:1022299422219</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1022299422219" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Risk and Uncertainty</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sympathy and callousness: The impact of deliberative thought on donations to identifiable and statistical victims</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Small</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Slovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.obhdp.2006.01.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.obhdp.2006.01.005" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="153" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Punish or protect? How close relationships shape responses to moral violations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Weidman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sowden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Berg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0146167219873485</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0146167219873485" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="693" to="708" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neural basis of the interaction between theory of mind and moral judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Cushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Saxe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.0701408104</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0701408104" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8235" to="8240" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychopathy increases perceived moral permissibility of accidents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koenigs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kruepke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0027489</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0027489" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Abnormal Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">121</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="659" to="667" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When ignorance is no excuse: Different roles for intent across moral domains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Saxe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cognition.2011.04.005</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2011.04.005" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="202" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
