<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">How Forgetting Aids Medical Diagnostic Decision Making Author names and affiliation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>MSc</roleName><forename type="first">Moumita</forename><surname>Bhowmick</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Cognitive Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Neuroimaging Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Jadavpur University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>700032</postCode>
									<settlement>Kolkata</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>PhD</roleName><forename type="first">Amrita</forename><surname>Basu</surname></persName>
							<email>amrita.basu@jadavpuruniversity.in</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Cognitive Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Neuroimaging Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Jadavpur University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>700032</postCode>
									<settlement>Kolkata</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Cognitive Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Jadavpur University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>700032</postCode>
									<region>Kolkata</region>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">How Forgetting Aids Medical Diagnostic Decision Making Author names and affiliation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Forgetting information can both be boon or bane for decision making. Majority of memory studies focus on the quantity of information preserved, typically considering forgetfulness as an unfavourable result <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Lawson, 1980;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Koriat et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Pachur et al., 2009</ref>).</p><p>Yet, forgetting is essential in practical settings <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(James, 1891)</ref>. It prevents the retrieval of irrelevant information, aiding cognitive functions like generalization and categorization. For instance, a person with a near-perfect memory might struggle to recognize faces due to the overwhelming recall of every minute expression. Effective facial recognition requires selective processing, dismissing some details to grasp the general appearance <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Winterbottom, 1969)</ref>.</p><p>Similarly, forgetting avoids the clutter of outdated information, ensuring current relevance <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bjork &amp; Bjork, 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Altmann &amp; Gray, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Nørby, 2015)</ref>. Adequate forgetting is thus vital for efficient memory function and higher cognitive processes.</p><p>Whether forgetting should be viewed as regrettable loss of information for effective decision making depends on the type of information that is lost in that specific context. It is therefore necessary to understand, forgetting as a strategy for adaptation to the necessities of the contextual environment, for relevant decision making. The likelihood of retrieving an item from memory hinges on how recently and frequently it was encountered, reflecting memory's adaptability to such environmental patterns <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Anderson, 1989;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Steyvers &amp; Griffiths, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Schooler &amp; Anderson, 2016)</ref>. Retrieval of information encoded in memory gets impaired as time passes. The recency effect is a memory phenomenon in which recent information is better remembered than the outdated old information that are forgotten (R. A. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Bjork &amp; Whitten, 1974)</ref>. Similarly, multiple exposure to information or repetition enhances memory performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Chen &amp; Yang, 2020)</ref> and therefore easier to retrieve from memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Popov &amp; Reder, 2020)</ref>. In fact repetition can make an item seem recent compared to a non-repeated item <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hintzman, 2010)</ref>. Assuming decision to be based on the retrieval of information from memory, recent and frequent information thus interferes with the information search as well as selection of action from the set of alternatives.</p><p>The current study examines the impact of forgetting on the use of simple inference heuristics in medical diagnostic decision making. In emergency situations, such as a heart attack, physicians must make swift decisions about a patient's critical state. Forgetting infrequent disease alternatives aids in recognizing the possible set of diseases and narrowing down disease hypotheses for fast hypothesis verification. It is to be noted here that forgetting infrequent disease alternatives is different from ignoring infrequent disease alternatives.</p><p>Ignoring limits the processing of infrequent disease alternatives or its expression in the memory once it is encoded whereas forgetting refers to inability to retrieve information that has been encoded into the long term memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Tonev, 2002)</ref>. This paper investigates if forgetfulness assists rapid ICU admission decisions for patients with cardiac symptoms, utilizing the simple heuristics framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Gigerenzer &amp; Todd, 1999)</ref> and the Adaptive Control of Thought Rational (ACT-R) model <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Anderson et al., 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Schooler &amp; Hertwig, 2005)</ref>. Simple heuristics such as recognition heuristic (RH) and fluency heuristics (FH) focuses on using minimal information and computation to make decisions based on recognizable cues. ACT-R as unified theory of declarative memory maps environmental regularities such as frequency and temporal spacing of experience with the object onto a mental currency called 'activation'. It models procedural knowledge with sets of production rules (i.e. if-then rules) whose conditions (the 'if' part of the rule) are matched against the contents of declarative memory. In this paper, the role of forgetfulness in enhancing RH and FH's effectiveness in medical diagnostics is assessed by using ACT-R's declarative memory model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Using ACT-R to Model Heuristics in Medical Diagnostic Decision Making</head><p>In a scenario where a physician must distinguish between cardiac and non-cardiac diseases based on patient symptoms, time constraints may lead to the use of Recognition Heuristics (RH) for disease identification. The scope of the application of RH is depended on the match between the mind and the rapidly changing uncertain environment which is known as ecological rationality <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Goldstein &amp; Gigerenzer, 2002)</ref>. Recognition memory theories offer a framework to forge this connection <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Dunn, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Yonelinas, Andrew P.;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">Aly et al., 2010)</ref>.</p><p>Recognition memory is associated with the act of recognition i.e. judge whether an event experiencing currently has occurred previously. Demonstrating RH's ecological rationality in medical decision-making therefore requires linking the memory strength of diseases (a latent variable) with the binary recognition judgment (an empirical variable). To understand the role of recognition process underlying the inferential task of the physician under time constraint, let us consider the ACT-R cognitive architecture of declarative memory modelled by <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Schooler &amp; Hertwig, (2005)</ref>.</p><p>Disease identification relies on recalling the associated symptoms, a process of threshold memory retrieval that involves recognizing the presence or absence of a disease through its symptoms, as learned in medical training as well as acquired through past clinical practice. The medical diagnostic reasoning occurs in several phases such as cue acquisition, cue filtering, cue clustering, and cue interpretation for generating hypothesis followed by hypothesis verification and decision <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Hausmann et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Tanner et al., 1987)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Hypothesis generation</head><p>In the first step, the diagnoses are hypothetically generated in a rapid succession based on the limited information about the chief complaint. We define 'hypotheses as the physician's formulation of possible diseases'. It begins with the pattern recognition process based on the information presented by the patient and the information that is received, interpreted and deduced by the physician. For a correct hypothesis generation, cue acquisition and cue filtering is essential.</p><p>Cue acquisition. Initially, the physician gathers symptom information from the patient or relatives. While ideally patients would clearly articulate symptoms indicative of specific diseases, often they may not accurately convey their symptoms due to unfamiliarity with clinical terminology. For example, the patient may say, as in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, My chest is paining…both sides…while walking …also… waist aches…pain dissolves when I sit down…</p><p>The narrative of the patient has information indicative of specific disease status. The physician picks up information from this narrative.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Narrative of a Patient Complaint</head><p>Notes. The numbers in the boxes represent the medical information units or cues. In addition to the linguistic cues provided by the patient, the physician may also note down other information such as demographic information, past medical history, population data and also look for other information by examining the patient physically, using say, stethoscope.</p><p>Cue filtering. Physicians, constrained by time, must prioritize information during patient consultations. Perfect recall of clinical history is unfeasible due to selective attention and limited working memory. They may focus on a few prominent issues while overlooking others, a tendency exacerbated by the urgency of life-threatening symptoms, leading to potential neglect of less critical but relevant information <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Norman &amp; Bobrow, 1975;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Johnston &amp; Dark, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Baddeley, 2010)</ref>. The manner in which the patient narrative may be filtered can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>. Notes. The physician filters the cues that indicates ischemic heart disease. Upon hearing the patient complaint the physician filtered cue 1 and 3 of the first sentence (S1) which is 'Chest pain', cue 1 of second sentence (S2) which is 'while walking' and lastly, cue 3,4, 5 of the fifth sentence (S5) which is 'pain dissolves after sitting for a while'.</p><p>Upon hearing a list of symptoms, the physician's memory forms a trace encoding the presence of each symptom. In ACT-R theory, this encoding occurs through 'chunks', the basic units of declarative knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Anderson et al., 1998)</ref>. Each chunk type is linked to an if-then rule; when a chunk meets all rule conditions, the associated action is executed. For instance, a memory trace for 'chest pain' would activate when this symptom is reported, requiring the physician to recall what was mentioned. The memory trace that encodes whether 'chest pain' occurred in the patient complaint list during clinical history taking is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 3</head><p>A Chunk Encoding the Cue <ref type="bibr">'Chest Pain' Occurred in Patient's Complaint List</ref> Note. The image is adapted from <ref type="bibr">(Anderson et al., 1998, pg 357)</ref> The memory trace (declarative structure) in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> consists of two itemsthe word and the list context. To recognize chest pain, the physician has to access both sources of association such as the word and the list of symptoms provided by the patient. The activation of the memory trace thus can be written as A = B + W w S w + W L S L , in which B is the base level activation of the chunk, W w is the weight to the words, S w is the strength of association from word to trace, W L is the weight of the list context and S L is the strength of association from the list context to the trace.</p><p>During the inferential task of the clinical diagnosis, the physician must remember 'what has to be done' i.e. recognize the relevant cues from patient's description of symptoms, collate the cues to form cluster and match them with the corresponding disease/s (e.g. identify cardiac disease whenever the patients mention of the relevant cues related to cardiac disease) and perform the task every time during the diagnosis of the disease to determine the appropriate disease/s out of several competing diseases. In this situation the external cue (the disease symptoms as described by the patient) prompts the physician to perform the task of matching cues with the corresponding disease learnt in medical school or experienced previously every time during clinical practice. Thus, the physicians need to remember to carry out a previously planned action such as match the relevant cues with the corresponding disease characteristics whenever patient mentions the corresponding cues.</p><p>Cue clustering. The symptoms that are related to one another are then collated together to form clusters (say,i). For example, the pulse and respiration can be clustered with blood sugar. Thus, in this step, pattern-matching is used to identify features of the disease or 'pivots' that stand out and are unique <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Eddy &amp; Clanton, 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Stiegler &amp; Tung, 2014)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cue interpretation and hypothesis generation.</head><p>Cue interpretation refers to the process of understanding the meaning of the cues using prior knowledge and explain the cue clusters <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Jefford et al., 2011)</ref>. In this step, the current cue/s and cue clusters are matched with recollected cue-clusters of various disease sources i.e. various symptoms of diseases with the prior knowledge, to come up with the hypotheses. Here, the physician must recollect the source (disease name) that is associated with the cues at study (disease symptoms). The symptom of 'chest pain' may often indicate multiple sources such as either cardiac disease or musculoskeletal disease. However, if 'chest pain' is associated with 'physical exertion' and if they are collated together for chunk i that implies 'chest pain during physical exertion such as walking' then this cluster distinctively indicates the presence of 'cardiac disease'. If the patient experiences 'chest pain' 'always' and if they are collated together, then this cluster distinctively indicate towards the presence of a non-cardiac or musculoskeletal disease. The chunk corresponding to musculoskeletal disease (h) and cardiac disease (i) is presented in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 4</head><p>A Chunk Encoding the Cue 'Chest Pain' With Respect to Cardiac Disease Note. Chunk encoding 'chest pain' associated with 'physical exertion' such as walking indicating ischemic heart disease whereas constant 'chest pain' without physical exertion indicating musculoskeletal pain.</p><p>The memory trace in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> consists of two elementselement 1 corresponding to 'what' and element 2 corresponding to 'when' of the chief complaint. To recognize chest pain in relation to cardiac disease, the physician has to access both sources of association such as element 1 and element 2 from both the list of symptoms provided by the patient and learnt in the medical school. The activation of the memory trace thus can be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">A i = B + W 1 S 1i + W 2 S 2i</formula><p>, in which B is the base level activation of the chunk, W 1 is the weight to the element 1, S 1i is the strength of association from element 1 to memory trace, W 2 is the weight of the list context and S 2i is the strength of association from the element 2 to the memory trace.</p><p>Therefore, in general, the activation A i of chunk i is a function of the base-level activation, B i and associative activation such as W j (attentional weights of the source elements j in the chunk i) and S ji (strength of activation from element j in the chunk i) as shown in Equation (1).</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">A i = B i + ∑ W j S ji j ………………………………………………………………. (1)</formula><p>Thus, activation A i determines how available information will be, in which, the baselevel activation of the chunk i, B i , is a function of its history of use at times t 1 , t 2 , … . . t n , where t k measures how much time has passed since the k th use as shown in Equation <ref type="formula">2</ref></p><formula xml:id="formula_2">B i = ln(∑ t k −d n k=1</formula><p>)…………………………………………………………………. <ref type="formula">2</ref>As can be seen from Equation <ref type="formula">2</ref>, the base-level strength B i of the chunk i relating to the key symptoms in the given cardiac context, lies in the environmental pattern of the occurrence of the disease. Specifically, B i is determined by how frequently and recently the chunk of key symptoms related to cardiac disease has been experienced by the physician in the past i.e. where the disease has been encountered n times in the past with the k th encounter having occurred t k time units in the past, and with the decay parameter d, capturing the degree of forgetting in declarative memory. The more often an object and/or information about it is encountered, the more strongly the corresponding chunks are activated <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Marewski &amp; Schooler, 2011</ref>). The value of d indicates the power of forgetting where the individual experiences decays over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Rubin &amp; Wenzel, 1996)</ref>. It is set to equal to 0.5 based on several behavioural data across domains <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Anderson et al., 1998)</ref>. Thus, base level activation shows the influence of practice (∑(across experience)) and time based decay (−d). The more often an object and/or information about it is encountered, the more strongly the corresponding chunks are activated <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Marewski &amp; Schooler, 2011)</ref>. Thus, the more often the disease is encountered by the physician the more strongly the disease and its associated cues are retrieved from the memory within a short span of time. ACT-R assumes that information in the long term memory is stored in chunks and is retrieved by searching through these chunks.</p><p>The associative activation in Equation (1) comes from source activations (W j ) and its associative strength (S ji ). It is assumed that if there are n cues with equal attention given to all the cues, the weights for all sources is equally distributed across n cues, i.e.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">W j = 1 n ,…………………………………………………………………………...... (3)</formula><p>The associative strength, S ji units of activation can be written as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">S ji = S + ln (p(i|j)) ……………………………………………………………… (4)</formula><p>In Equation (4) p(i|j) is the probability of chunk i given j. Assuming there are n elements and it is equally likely that chunk i is needed whenever the elements of n appears then p(i|j) equals Thus, (4) can be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">S ji = S + ln ( 1 n ) ,</formula><p>Or, S ji = S − ln (n), where S is the scale constant………………………………... <ref type="formula">5</ref>Thus, the associative activation in Equation <ref type="formula">1</ref> Activation and Retrieval Probability. ACT-R assumes that information in the long term memory is stored in chunks and is retrieved by searching through these chunks. The probability that a chunk will be activated is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">p i = Φ X (A i ) = 1 1+e − −(A i −μ) s , −∞ &lt; A i , μ &lt; +∞, s &gt; 0…………………………… (6)</formula><p>The continuous random variable X of activation of chunk is i is said to have a logistic distribution with location parameter μ and scale parameter s, when its cumulative distribution function is of the form of Equation (6) and the p.d.f. of logistic distribution is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">If X~logistic(μ, s), then f(A i ) = e −(A i −μ) s ⁄ s(1+e −(A i −μ) s ⁄ )</formula><p>2 ,………………………………………………………..… <ref type="formula">7</ref>Where,E(X) = μ ,………………………………………………………………… <ref type="formula">8</ref>and Var (X) = σ 2 = π 2 s 2 3 ⁄ ……………………………………………………… <ref type="formula">9</ref>Therefore, odds in favour of A i is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">P i 1− P i =e A i −μ s ,</formula><p>The log odds ratio or the logit of P i is given by,</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">L i = ln ( p i 1−p i ) = A i −μ s …………………………………………………………… (10)</formula><p>After searching for information in the memory through the memory chunks, the information search terminates when the cost of attempting to match a memory chunk against a condition of production rule is greater than the expected gain from it <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Schooler &amp; Hertwig, 2005</ref>), i.e.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">p i = 1 1+e − −(A i −μ) s &lt; C G …………………………………………………………...... (11)</formula><p>In which G is the gain associated with successfully finding the target and C is the cost of matching a memory chunk against a condition of a production rule. Alternatively, (11) can be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">P(A i &gt; τ) =1 − Φ X (A i = τ) ……………………………………………………...<label>(12)</label></formula><p>In which τ = ln ( C G−C ) when transformed into the activation scale that is equivalent to proportion scale in Equation (11).</p><p>Equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_11">12</ref>represents the probability that a chunk will be retrieved i.e. its activation will exceed the retrieval criterion τ (which is estimated by fitting models to data). <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Schooler &amp; Hertwig (2005)</ref> used a value of τ = 1.44 for their experiments.</p><p>Whether a memory chunk's activation exceeds the retrieval criterion depends not only on stochastic variability in the activation level of the chunk but also on the noise associated with it. The sources of noise include momentary and permanent fluctuations in the scale parameter (s) from Equation <ref type="formula">11</ref>, scale constant (S) from Equation <ref type="formula">4</ref>, number of elements (n)</p><p>affecting p(i|j) through Equation <ref type="formula">5</ref>and number of elements (n) affecting W j through Equation</p><p>(3) referred to as activation noise. Since, the associative activation in Equation <ref type="formula">1</ref> The noise may also be in the form of different levels of expertise in the medical profession such as hypothesis formulation by a novice versus hypothesis formulation by a senior physician. A senior physicians will be able to allocate appropriate weights to the relevant cues and ignore the rest while a novice may give equal weightage to all the information, even the ones deemed unimportant thereby affecting the corresponding activations. In addition, noise can also be observed due to lack of several reliable biomarkers of a disease that are difficult to diagnose as there may be several combination of symptoms for a single disease that creates difficulty in appropriate classification of disease thereby affecting the context list.</p><p>The ACT-R architecture of cognition models the decision maker's retrieval of knowledge and perception of time to predict the accuracy inferences of the recognition and fluency heuristics. According to ACT-R model, the recognition rate of the task alternatives is determined by the probability that the chunk will be retrieved i.e. the activation (A) will exceed the retrieval criterion which is expressed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">p(i) = 1 1+e −(A i −τ) s ⁄ , ………………………………………………………………... (14)</formula><p>In which τ is the location parameter and s is the momentary and permanent fluctuations in the activation level of chunk i 1 . Thus, recognition of the disease by a physician is associated with how strongly the memory chunk related to corresponding to symptoms gets activated and whether it crosses the threshold criterion at all.</p><p>In brief, the relevance probability of each memory chunk, say 'Chest pain during physical exertion'(i), can be reflected in its activation distribution and the probability that it is retrieved from the memory. Retrieval of chunk implies recognition of the relevant cues, such as disease symptoms, which indirectly affects the recognition of the disease. Several memory chunks are searched in order of their activation until either a chunk is found that satisfies the current production rule or the activation of the next chunk to be considered is so low that it is not worth considering. Since retrieval of chuck is a function of memory decay that captures the amount of forgetting in declarative memory through the activation function, a change in the decay parameter affects the performance of RH. High forgetting rate such as d = −1, as well as too little forgetting rate such as d = 0, both lowers the recognition as well as fluency validity <ref type="bibr">(Schooler &amp; Hertwig, 2005, pg 621)</ref>.</p><p>Therefore, the activation of a relevant chunk stored in a physician's memory implies recognizing the associated disease. As seen from the above, this depends on the number of times the physician has experienced the cue and its association with the disease in the past. In addition, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Anderson et al., (1998)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Schooler &amp; Hertwig, (2005)</ref> assumed that the level of activation of a chunk determines the retrieval time. The greater activation, the lower the retrieval time -something that is crucial for clinical diagnosis during emergency. In ACT-R the retrieval time is the exponential function of activation <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Schooler &amp; Hertwig, 2005)</ref>.</p><p>Activation and Retrieval Time. The retrieval time for the chunk i is given as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">T i = Fe −A i ………………………………………………………………………… (15)</formula><p>In which, A i is the activation for chunk i and F is the scale parameter. Equation <ref type="formula">15</ref>describes the time required to retrieve chunk i. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Anderson et al. (1998)</ref> estimated F from τ in non-free recall experiment by the function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">F = 0.348e τ ……………………………………………………………………… (16)</formula><p>As can be seen from Equation (16), for τ = 1.44, F can be observed to be at 1.47 <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Schooler &amp; Hertwig, 2005)</ref>. Now, Equation (15) can be written as T i = 0.348e τ e −A i , T i = 0.348e 1.44 e −A i , Or, T i = 1.47 e −A i , ……………………………………………………………….. <ref type="formula">17</ref>Differentiating both sides of (29) w.r.t.</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">A i , d(T i )</formula><p>d(A i ) = −1.47 e −A i ,……………………………………………………………...... <ref type="formula">18</ref>Since the first order derivative is negative therefore there exists a negative log-linear relationship between A i and T i .</p><p>Or,</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">d 2 (T i )</formula><p>d(A i ) 2 = 1.47 e −A i = T i &gt; 0,…………………………………………………... <ref type="formula">19</ref>As can be seen from Equation (19) the second order derivative is positive implying T i decreases at an increasing rate as A i increases. Thus, the lower the activation, the more time it takes to retrieve a chunk.</p><p>In the recognition task experiments, the predicted recognition time of an object is the time it takes to judge the object as recognized, measured from the object's presentation until a recognition response is made by pressing a key. For the current analysis, the model considered recognition time to be equal to the retrieval time.</p><p>Let us consider for example, a physician in the outpatient-department of a tertiary public hospital with huge patient pressure, in-charge of categorising and referring the patients to relevant departments for further therapeutic interventions based on the patient complaint. If the chunk of 'chest pain' corresponding to cardiac disease appeared to the physician 14 times in the past 1 week before the current date i.e. 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2 and 1 day before the current date and chunk of 'chest pain' corresponding to musculoskeletal (non-cardiac) disease appeared to the physician 6 times in the past 1 week before the current date i.e. 7, 5 and 3 days before the current date, the resulting activation for cardiac disease and non-cardiac disease will be as follows:</p><p>For cardiac disease, ln(7 −0.5 + 6 −0.5 + 5 −0.5 + 4 −0.5 + 3 −0.5 + 2 −0.5 + 1 −0.5 ) = 1.39</p><p>For non-cardiac disease, ln(7 −0.5 + 5 −0.5 + 3 −0.5 ) = 0.34</p><p>As can be seen from Equation <ref type="formula">14</ref>, the recognition rate of the task alternatives is determined by the probability that the chunk will be retrieved i.e. the activation (A) will exceed the retrieval criterion, τ (which is estimated by fitting models to data). It is expressed as: Therefore, it can be seen that the greater the activation the greater probability of retrieval and hence the greater probability of recognition. Also, the greater the activation the lesser time taken for retrieval and therefore recognition. Thus, a chunk's retrieval implies recognizing the associated disease for hypothesis formation. The more quickly the chunk is retrieved, the greater the sense of recognition and ease of retrieval <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Marewski &amp; Schooler, 2011)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">p(i) = 1 1+e −(A i −τ) s ⁄ ,</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Verification of the Hypothesis and Final Diagnosis</head><p>If the physician's goal is to infer whether cardiac or non − cardiac, has a larger value on a given criterion, then the production rule that implements RH is summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref>. If the goal is to detect or − based on the patient information and chunk ℎ cannot be retrieved and chunk cannot be retrieved Then set a goal to guess Recognition If the goal is to detect or − based on the patient information and chunk ℎ cannot be retrieved and chunk can be retrieved Then set a goal to respond disease to be relevant disease in the current context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fluency (when both disease recognized)</head><p>If the goal is to detect or − based on the patient information and chunk ℎ can be retrieved and chunk can be retrieved Then set the goal to compare the retrieval times and respond the disease retrieved faster as relevant in the current context. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref> shows a set of production rules in clinical diagnostic decision making set up.</p><p>There are three rules applicable depending on whether chunk i or h associated with Cardiac disease or Non − Cardiac disease can be retrieved from memory. The performance of RH depends on how often these rules are applied and how accurately is it able to infer. The first two rules are essentially the production rules associated with RH and the third rule corresponds to fluency rule of fluency heuristics. The differences in the recognition time is reflected in the retrieval time difference which according to Equation (15) is function of base level activations of the corresponding chunk.</p><p>During clinical diagnostic decision, physicians often collects additional knowledge about the symptoms through several diagnostic tests after interacting with the patients. Initial screening at this stage sets a direction for further investigation to confirm the initial hypothesis.</p><p>When only one disease is recognized, further diagnostic tests are conducted about that disease only. When both the alternative diseases are recognized, diagnostic test corresponding to the disease recognized early is prioritized for further investigation followed by the other alternative (say, one of the alternative is detected at 2s 2 whereas the other after 10s). In several instances, the symptom of the diseases overlap with one another which makes it difficult for the physician to discriminate between the two disease alternatives. In such a situation, the physician may give importance to both the diseases. In addition, the physician may not be able to detect recognition time difference between the two alternatives if it falls below the just-noticeable-difference (JND) threshold <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Haigh et al., 2021)</ref>. Therefore the physician may try to gather more knowledge about both the diseases. Interestingly, recognition time difference of 1s (say) starting from 1s to 2s may not be detectable compared to a recognition time difference of 1s from 0.2s to 1.2s.</p><p>In this case, the more time it takes to recognize both the diseases, the greater the tendency of the physician to give importance to both the diseases <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Marewski &amp; Schooler, 2011)</ref>. Thus, the manner in which these thresholds changes as duration changes determine the appropriateness of the corresponding production rules. When none of the diseases could be recognized because none of the symptom cues could be clustered then the physicians tries to guess the disease and focus to contain the symptoms first to give the patient some relief for the moment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Forgetting is beneficial. Conventional wisdom may view forgetting as an obstacle to effective decision-making, yet when physicians employ RH in urgent situations, a certain level of forgetfulness becomes beneficial. <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Schooler &amp; Hertwig (2005)</ref> illustrated that forgetting can aid decision-making by eliminating irrelevant options and streamline the set of the recognized alternatives. This is particularly useful in medical diagnostics for quick recognition of pertinent diseases. Physicians use RH to swiftly identify potential diseases based on the most frequent disease the physician encountered in recent times. This strategy allows for rapid initiation of critical treatments. In addition, forgetting also helps in rearranging the relevant symptoms of the disease in order of their ranks of importance with only important symptoms being remembered and irrelevant ones forgotten. This helps in attending on to the most relevant symptoms during clinical history taking. The ACT-R model suggests that memory retrieval, and hence disease recognition, is more likely when related memory 'chunks' are activated and crosses the threshold activation level. The more active a memory chunk is, the higher the chance of its retrieval and the faster the recognition of associated diseases, allowing for prompt medical response. However, for RH and FH to be useful the memory chunk activation needs to reflect the relation between disease frequencies in the clinical practice and their values on criterion.</p><p>Less-is-more effect. RH makes a strong claim that when individuals recognize one alternative but not others, they will select the recognized one and disregard additional information, thus using fewer cognitive resources to make accurate decisions. While conclusive knowledge of disease alternatives might bypass the need for recognition in decision-making, less knowledge can be more beneficial, allowing for better inferences when recognition is more valid than comprehensive knowledge. However, in situations where there is no or very low recall of information related to diseases, more recollection leads to better inferences than RH.</p><p>Thus, a physician's application of RH can be effective with recollection of some information, enabling more accurate inferences than in cases of complete forgetfulness.</p><p>Despite its remarkable ability and accuracy, too much forgetting however, can lead to severe and systematic errors. In such situations, the physician can sometimes falsely identify a disease even though the key patient symptoms are not indicative of the disease or it may miss identifying even though the key symptoms indicates the corresponding disease. In such a situation, probabilities of hit and false alarm rate will affect the successful application of RH or FH <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Katsikopoulos, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>Fluency and availability heuristics. As seen from above, physician's memory of diseases is influenced by the frequency and recency of past encounters, which dictates the likelihood of memory retrieval. This is the key aspect of the availability heuristic, as proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Kahneman &amp; Tversky (1973)</ref>, which asserts that more frequently and recently encounteredinformation is more readily recalled. Such heuristics, encompassing recognition, fluency, and availability, rely on memory for quick retrieval and time perception to judge recognition speed, enabling experts to diagnose more rapidly and accurately than novices. These heuristics function not in isolation but interactively within the cognitive system.</p><p>Memory decay vs flashbulb memories. Although memory decay boosts the performance of RH and FH, however, flashbulb memories such as personal memories of positive experiences or negative experiences associated with a particular clinical diagnostic encounter may affect the physician so intensely that it becomes a lesson for life and is almost impossible to forget. For example, diagnosing a patient with ARDS symptoms, putting in ventilation and successfully bringing back the patient from the ventilation to normal life successfully, when the technology was at its nascent stage, can make the physician remember the cluster of symptoms and its association with the disease for life. So that whenever such cluster is encountered the physician remembers what exactly needs to be done. Also, negative personal memories associated with an incorrect diagnosis in the past, that led to the death of the patient may impact the physician severely such that whenever such cues or clusters are encountered, the physician knows what exactly not to do. In such cases, it may be impossible to forget the diagnosis of the disease. These are rare incidents which difficult to forget yet they slide into a physician's decision making strategies while diagnosing the disease.</p><p>Using other heuristics in conjunction with RH and FH. It is also crucial to keep in mind that individuals tend to use different heuristics that are beyond recognition validity in the environment. Physicians usually recruit cue knowledge (e.g., availability of ECG machine to indicate any irregularities electrical signals in the heart) beyond recognition of disease induced by forgetfulness. Initial screening of recognizing the disease at this stage sets a direction for further investigation to confirm the initial hypothesis. In remote rural villages or during any war, there is not many investigative diagnostic tools available. Even during the emergency at home, say, a cardiac arrest, a house physician will not have much access to the ECG machine immediately. In such situations, forgetfulness helps the physician use RH, FH or guessing as effective strategy to identify the disease as quickly and as accurately as possible. However, if there is any provision for further investigations and if both the diseases are recognized, then the physicians would be better-off relying on knowledge based heuristics, such as Take-the-best strategy (TTB), than on the FH <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Schooler &amp; Hertwig, 2005)</ref>. In this strategy, at first the recognition principle in invoked for both the diseases. If both the diseases are recognized then the cue values of the cue (say, ECG test) having the highest ranking from memory is retrieved and then decided whether the cue discriminates the alternatives. Forgetting helps in identifying the relevant cues eliminating the irrelevant cues. The cue is said to discriminate between two alternatives if one has a positive cue value while the other negative. The alternative with the positive cue value is chosen. If the cue discriminates then further search for the cues are stopped otherwise search for another cue with the highest ranking from memory, say, blood tests is continued until a cue that discriminates the alternatives is found. If no cue discriminates then the alternatives are chosen randomly to start the therapeutic procedure immediately. The cue search, in this case, extends through only a portion of the total knowledge in memory and is stopped immediately when the first discriminating cue is found. It is known that the larger the ecological validity of TTB in this context the better the inference. However, a cue with high ecological validity may not be useful if its discrimination rate is low. The larger the discrimination rate of the cue i.e. the relative frequency with which a cue discriminates between any two objects in the reference class, the more often the cue can be used to make inference.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Future Research</head><p>Neuroscientific studies on how perceptual uncertainty affects heuristic decision-making are scant. RH typically presume absolute perceptual certainty. However, if a physician encounters unfamiliar, uncertain cues, memory activation may be too weak to trigger recognition. By setting a lower threshold for retrieval than for recognition, a physician might retrieve a memory without confidently recognizing it, leading to guesswork. The efficacy of recognition or fluency heuristics may be compromised with uncertain perceptions, challenging their ecological rationality. Forgetting in perceptual certainty and uncertainty can lead to a better understanding of the problems in diagnosis and manage them.</p><p>Future research on how forgetting is influenced by the physicians' perception of clinical problems and external pressures, such as workplace violence leading to biased disease diagnosis. Fear induced by past litigation or aggressive interactions can lead to defensive medicine, biasing physicians towards safer, less risky choices. The emotional impact of choices, the communicative behaviour of patients and relatives, and the physicians' interpretation of their intent and cooperativeness, especially as conveyed through speech prosody, are critical factors. An ACT-R based heuristic model would deepen insights into cognitive processing in fear-laden medical environments and forgetting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>Forgetting plays a crucial role in maintaining an effective balance of information that needs to be used during fast and frugal heuristics. Heuristics involving recognition and fluency provides a precise model of how recognition of objects can be exploited to make fast and frugal decision by indirectly tapping onto the beneficial side effect of forgetting. Forgetting is usually considered to be a hindrance to heuristic decision making but it has been shown empirically that forgetting fosters heuristic performance including the one that makes use of recognition information. For example, in medical diagnostic decision making, diseases with small criterion values that the physician experiences rarely are more likely to be forgotten streamlining the possible set of diseases for hypothesis verification and thereafter further investigation. The memory system loses information at the decay rate to reach optimal level of forgetting in order to boost the performance of RH, FH and other heuristics. Problem arises when too much or too little information has been forgotten that affects outcome of the heuristic strategy. Too much information due to too little forgetting clutters the human mind and therefore confuses the decision maker whereas too little information due to too much forgetting affects the determination of relevance of the decision. Forgetting thus provides the simplest explanation of Herbert Simon's view that bounded rational decision making can arise from simple mental tools, such as recognition, caused by cognitive limitation such as forgetting, that are matched to the structure of the environment.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Cue Filtering From the Patient Complaint Narrative</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>depends on the number of chunks associated with the cue.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>depends on the number of elements (n) associated with a chunk, it contributes to the overall variability in activation by means of W j and S ji . In addition, noise can also be sourced from momentary fluctuations in a chunk's estimated gain and estimated costs referred to as criterion noise.Therefore, total retrieval noise (s) can be attributed to criterion noise (s τ ) and activation noise (s A ) i.e. momentary and permanent fluctuations in the activation level<ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Marewski &amp; Schooler, 2011</ref>): = √( 2 ) + ( 2 ) ……………………………………………………………….....(13)These noises could be a part of the physician's external environment such as a patient producing noise by giving ambiguous and conflicting information about the disease. Physicians themselves can introduce noise due to selective attention or mood during patient interaction.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>in which τ is the location parameter and s is the momentary and permanent fluctuations in the activation level of chunk i, where i is the cardiac disease. Thus, recognition of the disease by a physician is associated with how strongly the memory chunk related to corresponding symptoms gets activated and whether it crosses the threshold criterion at all.Assuming retrieval criterion τ = 0 (i.e. the disease with an activation of 0 would have a 50% chance of being retrieved), s = 0.83 and F = 0.49<ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Marewski &amp; Schooler, 2011</ref>, pg 401) the predictive recognition probability for cardiac disease is given by: p(cardiac) 84, implying cardiac disease to have 84% chance of being retrieved. Assuming retrieval time equal to recognition time, the retrieval time T cardiac is given as Fe −A = 0.49e −1.39 = 0.12 s. Now, p(non − cardiac) implying non-cardiac disease to have 60% chance of being retrieved. Assuming retrieval time equal to recognition time, the retrieval time T non−cardiac is given as Fe −A = 0.49e −0.34 = 0.35 s.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>The Production Set That Implements the Recognition Heuristics in Clinical</cell></row><row><cell>Diagnostic Decisions</cell></row><row><cell>Guessing</cell></row><row><cell>(neither</cell></row><row><cell>disease</cell></row><row><cell>recognized)</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">This relationship can also be represented as Equation (12) if the expected value of the distribution ( ) is located differently from the criterion value ( ). However, in that case it will not be possible to draw a common sigmoid curve across multiple alternatives such as , , … for comparison.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Forgetting to remember: The functional relationship of decay and interference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Altmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1467-9280.00405</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/1467-9280.00405" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A rational analysis of human memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Varieties of memory and consciousness: essays in honour of {Endel} {Tulving}</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="210" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Integrated Theory of List Memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bothell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lebiere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Matessa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Memory and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="380" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1006/jmla.1997.2553</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1006/jmla.1997.2553" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Working memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baddeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://ac.els-cdn.com/S0960982209021332/1-s2.0-S0960982209021332-main.pdf?_tid=spdf-b6ed6bcd-3774-4424-befa-47f09074097c&amp;acdnat=1519800289_4a0b5080667202ed5a552176ffdc08c5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the adaptive aspects of retrieval failure in autobiographical memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bjork</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bjork</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://doi.apa.org/psycinfo/1988-97682-044" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Practical aspects of memory: Current research and issues</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="288" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Memory in everyday life.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recency-sensitive retrieval processes in long-term free recall</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bjork</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Whitten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0010-0285</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0010-0285" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90009" to="90016" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple Exposures Enhance Both Item Memory and Contextual Memory Over Time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.565169</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.565169" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Remember-Know: A Matter of Confidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.111.2.524</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.111.2.524" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="524" to="542" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The art of diagnosis: solving the clinicopathological exercise</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Eddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Clanton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The New England Journal of Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">306</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1263" to="1268" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast and frugal heuristics: the adaptive toolbox</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Todd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Simple Heuristics That Make Us Smart</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="34" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1354067X0171006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1354067X0171006" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models of ecological rationality: The recognition heuristic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Goldstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037//0033-295X.109.1.75</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037//0033-295X.109.1.75" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="90" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The role of Weber&apos;s law in human time perception. Attention, Perception, and Psychophysics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Haigh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Apthorp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bizo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="447" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/s13414-020-02128-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13414-020-02128-6" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tracing the decision-making process of physicians with a Decision Process Matrix</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hausmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zulian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Battegay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zimmerli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1186/s12911-016-0369-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1186/s12911-016-0369-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BMC Medical Informatics and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How does repetition affect memory? Evidence from judgments of recency</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hintzman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3758/MC.38.1.102</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3758/MC.38.1.102" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="102" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Principles of Psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/1412102</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/1412102" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Journal of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1891" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision-Making Theories and their usefulness to the midwifery profession both in terms of midwifery practice and the education of midwives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Jefford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Fahy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sundin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Nursing Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="246" to="253" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1440-172X.2010.01900.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1440-172X.2010.01900.x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Selective Attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev.ps.37.020186.000355</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.ps.37.020186.000355" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="75" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PSYCHOLOGICAL REVIEW ON THE PSYCHOLOGY OF PREDICTION 1. Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">80</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The less-is-more effect: Predictions and tests</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Katsikopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Judgement and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="244" to="257" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The base rate fallacy reconsidered: Descriptive, normative, and met~odological challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Koehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BEHAVIORAL AND BRAIN SCIENCES</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a psychology of memory accuracy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Koriat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Goldsmith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pansky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual review of psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="537" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev.psych.51.1.481</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.psych.51.1.481" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adaptive Expectations and Uncertainty. The Review of Economic Studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lawson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/2296994</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/2296994" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">305</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive Niches: An Ecological Model of Strategy Selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Marewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schooler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0024143</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0024143" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why Forget? On the Adaptive Value of Memory Loss</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nørby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691615596787</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691615596787" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="578" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On Data-limited and Resource-limited Processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Bobrow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://usd-apps.usd.edu/coglab/schieber/psyc792/workload/NormanBobrow1975.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive Aging and the Adaptive Use of Recognition in Decision Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pachur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schooler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology and Aging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/a0017211</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0017211" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frequency effects on memory: A resource-limited theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Popov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Reder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/rev0000161</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000161" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">One hundred years of forgetting: A quantitative description of retention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Wenzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="734" to="760" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.103.4.734</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.103.4.734" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The adaptive nature of memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schooler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Curated Reference Collection in Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="278" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/B978-0-12-809324-5.21042-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-809324-5.21042-0" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How forgetting aids heuristic inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schooler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hertwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0033-295X.112.3.610</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.112.3.610" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="610" to="628" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rational analysis as a link between human memory and information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/acprof:oso/9780199216093.003.0015</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/acprof:oso/9780199216093.003.0015" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Probabilistic Mind: Prospects for Bayesian cognitive science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cognitive processes in anesthesiology decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Stiegler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1097/ALN.0000000000000073</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0000000000000073" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Anesthesiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="204" to="217" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diagnostic reasoning strategies of nurses and nursing students</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Tanner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Padrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Westfall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Putzier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nursing Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="358" to="363" />
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Studies of directed ignoring and directed forgetting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Tonev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Duke University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Judgment under Uncertainty : Heuristics and Biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tversky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">185</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4157</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1124" to="1131" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Mind of a Mnemonist</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Winterbottom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1097/00006842-196903000-00023</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1097/00006842-196903000-00023" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychosomatic Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="190" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recollection and Familiarity: Examining Controversial Assumptions and New Directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Yonelinas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Aly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W.-C</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Koen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/hipo.20864.Recollection</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/hipo.20864.Recollection" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Hippocampus</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1178" to="1194" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
