<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">EXPLANATORY POWER AS A SUBSTITUTE FOR STATISTICAL REASONING</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2024-04-19">19 April 2024</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
							<email>samuel.johnson@uwaterloo.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Waterloo</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bath</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Warwick</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Angie</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Boston College</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amy</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Toig</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Cognition &amp; Development Lab and Decision, Inference, and Cognitive Economics Lab for comments</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">EXPLANATORY POWER AS A SUBSTITUTE FOR STATISTICAL REASONING</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2024-04-19">19 April 2024</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note type="submission">submitted to journal) Word Count: 3999 (main text</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Note. This is a preprint and has not been peer-reviewed. Any subsequent published version of this paper will become the version of record.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Explanatory Power as a Substitute for Statistical Reasoning</head><p>We must often assess causal claims on the fly, with limited computational resources and statistical evidence. In these situations, people use several cues to assess whether a causal relationship exists, including mechanism knowledge (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Johnson &amp; Ahn, 2017)</ref>, temporal information (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bramley et al., 2018)</ref>, and event structure (e.g., . Less is known, however, about how causal strength is estimated when covariation information is unavailable-i.e., given that a causal relationship exists, how powerful is that relationship between cause and effect? Here, we examine one potential cue people might use to estimate causal strength in statistically impoverished settings-explanatory power.</p><p>Normative models of causal strength typically define causal strength in terms of statistical contingency <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Perales &amp; Shanks, 2007)</ref>, making covariation evidence indispensable.</p><p>For example, one account models causal strength as the magnitude of difference the cause makes to the probability of the effect <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Allan, 1980)</ref>. Determining these probabilities requires multiple observations to calculate the covariation between cause and effect.</p><p>Yet, we have intuitions about causal strength in one-shot cases where we observe a cause and effect occur just one time, and thus lack any statistical evidence. When a new legal statute has an unintended social consequence, when an earnings report affects a company's business plan, or when ingesting an unfamiliar drink causes a funny tingling, we have a sense of how powerful these causes are in producing the effects, even though we may lack statistical data entirely. Where do these intuitions come from?</p><p>One possible source is a cause's explanatory power. People seem to use a variety of explanatory virtues <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Lipton, 2004)</ref> or heuristics <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Johnson et al., 2019)</ref> to judge an explanation's quality, such as simplicity, scope, and depth (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Johnson et al., 2019;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Khemlani et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Lombrozo, 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Lombrozo, , 2016</ref>. Critically, these heuristics often are defined in one-shot cases, so beliefs about explanatory power can often be formed in the absence of statistical evidence. For instance, people usually prefer simpler over more complex causal explanations <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Lombrozo, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr">cf. Zemla et al., 2017)</ref>; perhaps, then, people would believe that a simpler cause would be a more potent cause than a more complex one.</p><p>Though the assumption that more "virtuous" explanations are stronger causes could sometimes lead to erroneous inferences, it may often be adaptive since explanatory power and causal strength are usually correlated <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Strevens, 2008)</ref>. For instance, if a new law inadvertently incentivizes people to drive faster, then the law will be seen as a good explanation for driving speed to the extent that the law made a large causal difference to driving speed. People might capitalize on this relationship between causal strength and explanatory power in the reverse direction, using their own explanatory judgments to predict causal strength. If explanatory power can sometimes be more easily assessed than causal strength, then this may be an effective strategy for inferring causal strength, especially in one-shot cases.</p><p>Four studies examine this case. First, Study 1 tests whether explanatory power and causal strength judgments are indeed highly correlated-a necessary condition for the heuristic value of explanatory power. Second, Studies 2 and 3 ruled out alternative explanations for this relationship, experimentally manipulating independent cues to explanatory power and looking for downstream effects on causal strength judgments. Finally, Study 4 looked for causal signatures of explanatory thinking in a putatively non-causal domain-mathematical explanation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 1</head><p>Historical events may be the prototypical example of a singular causal situation where statistical data is typically unavailable due to the unique kaleidoscope of circumstances. This lack of statistical data in the case of many pivotal-and therefore unique-historical events has fueled countless debates among professional historians, such as the role of individual agency versus societal or economic factors in driving particular historical events <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Callinicos, 1987)</ref>. In Study 1, we draw on the unique nature of historical events as an initial test of the relationship between explanatory power and causal strength in a naturalistic setting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Participants in all studies were recruited from Amazon Mechanical Turk and provided informed consent. We recruited two groups of participants (N=40 for each of Studies 1A and 1B); 16 participants were excluded for incorrectly answering more than 30% of the check questions. Statistical power was high despite the relatively small sample, since analyses were conducted at the item level and all participants completed all 54 items (i.e., the data comprise 3,456 data points after exclusions).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants read about 54 pairs of real historical events. For example:</head><p>A. The Black Plague rampaged through Europe from 1347 to 1351. B. The price of labor in Europe skyrocketed.</p><p>For a complete list of event pairs, see Appendix S1 in the Supplementary Materials. For each pair, participants in Study 1A were asked "To what extent do you think that A is a satisfying explanation for why B happened?" from 0 ("Not at all satisfying") to 10 ("Very satisfying").</p><p>Study 1B was identical, except they were told that "A happened, and this caused B to happen" and asked "How strong do you think this causal relationship is between A and B?"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>Analyses were conducted at the item level, averaging over participants and using the 54 items as the units of analysis. The correlation between explanatory power judgments <ref type="bibr">(Study 1A)</ref> and causal strength judgments (Study 1B) was of a magnitude not commonly seen in social science research, r(52)=.961, p&lt;.001 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1</ref>). For practical purposes, the dependent variables in Studies 1A and 1B were treated by participants as the same question. This result, taken alone, would be utterly unconvincing evidence for our thesis that explanatory power is a cue to causal strength because reverse causation explanations are eminently plausible: If people have beliefs about the strength of a causal relationship, it would be surprising if those beliefs did not inform their explanatory intuitions. Yet we take this exceptionally strong correlation as an important starting point for three reasons. First, the  <ref type="table">(Study 1A)</ref> correlation is a precondition for the usefulness of explanatory power as a heuristic for causal strength, as this correlation demonstrates that the cue is often valid. Second, the magnitude of this correlation strikes us as implausibly large if it reflected only the influence of causal strength on explanatory power because many other factors are known to influence explanatory judgments <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Lombrozo, 2016)</ref>. Third, the ecological validity of Study 1 is a useful supplement to our more artificial and controlled experiments to follow. White circles indicate observed predictions (known to be true) and gray circles indicate latent predictions (not known to be true or false).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 2</head><p>The quality of an explanation depends not only on its relationship with what it is explaining, but also the other predictions it makes-its scope. For example, Ferraro's Disorder (C) might have three symptoms-hair loss (E1), weight gain (E2), and night terrors (E3). When diagnosing the cause of Randy's hair loss (E1), we benefit from knowing about E2 and E3 (C's scope) in assessing whether Ferraro's Disorder is the best explanation ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2B</ref>). Scope can be broken into two parts-its observed predictions or manifest scope <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Read &amp; Marcus-Newhall, 1993)</ref>, and its potential-yet-unverified explanations or latent scope <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Khemlani et al., 2011)</ref>. For example, if we do not know whether or not Randy had night terrors (E3), then E3 is part of C's latent scope ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2C</ref>). People typically prefer explanations that make many verified predictions (wide manifest scope; <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Johnston et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Read &amp; Marcus-Newhall, 1993)</ref> and few unknown predictions (narrow latent scope; <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Johnson et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Khemlani et al., 2011)</ref>.</p><p>Study 2 used these phenomena to manipulate explanatory power, looking for downstream effects on causal strength. Participants read vignettes depicting a causal relationship, where we varied features of the explanatory structure, such that some explanations were "good" and others were "bad." In Study 2A, we contrasted explanations with wider manifest scope (the Good condition; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2A</ref>) to explanations with narrower manifest scope (the Bad-Manifest condition; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2B</ref>). For example, a Good item read: That is, Ferraro's Disorder (C) has three effects in its scope-hair loss (E1), weight gain (E2), and night terrors (E3), of which all three were observed. In contrast, a Bad-Manifest item read:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">When</formula><p>When someone has Ferraro's Disorder, they lose hair. Three months ago, Randy developed Ferraro's Disorder. Because he has Ferraro's Disorder, Randy lost hair. We also know that Randy gained weight and had frequent night terrors, but we don't know why.</p><p>Here, Randy still has the same three symptoms, but two are unexplained. We expected that</p><p>Ferraro's Disorder would be seen as a more powerful explanation for Randy's hair loss when it explained all of Randy's symptoms (in the Good condition), rather than just one (in the Bad-Manifest condition).</p><p>In Study 2B, we contrasted the same Good explanations ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2B</ref>) with Bad-Latent explanations ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2C</ref>) that predicted the same effects as the Good explanations, but where some of the predicted effects were latent. This version read:</p><p>When someone has Ferraro's Disorder, they lose hair, gain weight, and have frequent night terrors. Three months ago, Randy developed Ferraro's Disorder. Because he has Ferraro's Disorder, Randy lost hair. We don't know if he gained weight or had frequent night terrors.</p><p>In this version, Ferraro's Disorder accounts for three potential observations, with E1 observed (in the manifest scope) and E2 and E3 unknown (in the latent scope). We expected Ferraro's Disorder to be seen as a more powerful explanation of Randy's hair loss when it made predictions that were manifest rather than latent.</p><p>In all three versions, Ferraro's Disorder is said to have caused Randy's hair loss, but the extent to which Ferraro's Disorder is judged as a strong cause should differ across conditions. In contrast, if only the reverse were true-that causal strength merely influences explanatory power-then these manipulations should have no effect on causal judgments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>We recruited 100 participants each for Studies 2A and 2B; 1 participant was excluded for incorrectly answering more than 33% of the check questions.</p><p>Items were causal explanations drawn from eight categories covering a variety of topics (e.g., medicine, sports, chemistry). Each category contained two items, which were conceptually similar but differed in content (e.g., the two medical items described different fictitious diseases with distinct symptoms). Each participant thus completed a total of 16 items. In Study 2A, participants saw the Good version of one item from each category and the Bad-Manifest version of the other item from each category, in a counterbalanced manner (see above for example wordings). In Study 2B, participants saw the Good version of one item from each category and the Bad-Latent version of the other item. In both studies, each Good item was always presented adjacent to a Bad item from a different category, forming eight pairs; the order within each pair was randomized, as was the order of the pairs.</p><p>For each of the 16 items, participants first read the explanation (as worded above for each condition, with the effects color-coded to make the paragraphs easier to parse). Participants then answered a causal structure question (e.g., "Do you think that Randy having Ferraro's Disorder caused him to lose hair?") formatted as a yes/no forced-choice, to ensure that participants acknowledged the existence of a causal relationship. On the next screen, they rated causal strength ("How strong do you think this relationship is between Randy having Ferraro's Disorder and Randy losing hair?") on a scale from 1 ("Extremely Weak") to 9 ("Extremely Strong"), with the passage from the previous page at the bottom of the screen as a reminder.</p><p>They were asked to make this strength rating regardless of their response to the structure question, because we wanted to discourage participants from adopting the strategy of answering "no" to the initial question in an effort to shorten the task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>Both manipulations of explanatory structure influenced causal strength judgments, and this effect was larger in Study 2B than in Study 2A ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>). For each participant, we averaged across the items for which that participant answered "yes" to the initial causal structure question ("Do you think that [C] caused [E1]?"). These strength ratings were modestly higher for the  We predicted these results because we anticipated that explanatory scope-which is known to independently affect perceived explanatory quality-would be used as a cue to causal</p><p>strength. An alternative interpretation is that participants' answers to the strength questions may not have reflected their beliefs about causal strength at all, but instead their beliefs about causal structure-whether a causal relationship exists rather than its strength <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Griffiths &amp; Tenenbaum, 2005</ref>). However, we took several measures to guard against this possibility. Critically, we sought to eliminate possible uncertainty over the causal structure by stating explicitly that the cause occurred (e.g., "Three months ago, Randy developed Ferraro's disorder") and that it caused the effect in the token case (e.g., "Because he has Ferraro's disorder, Randy lost hair"). We also added a separate structure question prior to the strength question ("Do you think that Randy having Ferraro's disorder caused him to lose hair?"), creating pragmatic pressure to interpret strength and structure as distinct queries.</p><p>Separating out structure and strength questions also allowed us to include only causal strength ratings among those who agreed that the causal relationship occurred. First, we observe that rates of "no" responses to the structure question were rare, although slightly higher for the "bad" than for the "good" explanations <ref type="figure">(</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 3</head><p>In Study 3, participants read the same items used in Study 2, providing judgments of "how satisfying" they perceived C to be as an explanation for E1 as a measure of explanatory power. Given our results in Study 2, we would expect the Good items (with wide manifest scope)</p><p>to be seen as the best explanations, followed by the Bad-Manifest items (with narrow manifest and latent scope), and then by the Bad-Latent items (with wide latent scope).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>We recruited 60 participants from Amazon Mechanical Turk; 2 participants were excluded for incorrectly answering more than 33% of the check questions.</p><p>Participants saw each of the 16 items used in Study 2, where each item was randomly assigned to either its Good version, its Bad-Manifest version, or its Bad-Latent version. After reading the item, participants completed an explanatory power rating (e.g., "To what extent do you think that Randy having Ferraro's Disorder is a satisfying explanation for why Randy lost hair?") on a scale from 1 ("Not at all satisfying") to 9 ("Very satisfying").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4,</ref>   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Study 4</head><p>So far, we have seen that in causal scenarios, explanatory power cues causal strength.</p><p>Might an analogous effect extend even to a seemingly non-causal domain? In Study 4, we studied the downstream effects of mathematical explanation on counterfactual judgments.</p><p>Although '4-2=2' and '2+2=4' are mathematically equivalent, they are not psychologically equivalent. Addition is seen as a more primitive operation than subtraction;</p><p>therefore, people believe that "4-2=2 because 2+2=4" is a better explanation than "2+2=4 because 4-2=2" since the former grounds a less basic in a more basic operation rather than the converse <ref type="bibr">(Johnson, Johnston, Koven, &amp; Keil, 2015)</ref>. Although we doubt that people would view addition facts as "causing" subtraction facts, we speculated that explanatory power might imbue causal properties-specifically, counterfactual inferences-into mathematics.</p><p>Causal and counterfactual judgments are tightly linked <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Pearl, 2000)</ref>: To a first approximation, "C caused E" typically entails that "If C had not happened, E would not have happened" (with exceptions; <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Paul &amp; Hall, 2013)</ref>. In contrast, the converse counterfactual "If E had not happened, C would not have happened" feels unnatural because it violates the usual cause-to-effect order of reasoning. Thus, causes appear to be more stable to counterfactual alterations compared to effects. We hypothesized that, similarly, the link between explanatory power and causal strength would lead more explanatorily primitive mathematical operations (e.g., addition) to be more stable to counterfactual alterations compared to less primitive operations (subtraction). That is, it should be more difficult to imagine a world where the facts of addition are different, compared to a world where the facts of subtraction differ.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>We recruited 100 participants from Amazon Mechanical Turk; 26 participants were excluded for incorrectly answering more than 30% of the check questions, but including these participants does not alter the conclusions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants were instructed:</head><p>There was once a sorcerer named Prospero. Prospero waved his wand, and some of the facts of mathematics changed. Unfortunately, we aren't sure which facts changed and which remained the same. On the following pages, you will read about some mathematical facts that remained true and others that became false. Your task will be to help determine which mathematical facts are true even after Prospero waved his wand, and which became false.</p><p>They then made a series of choices on Likert scales. For each choice, participants were told that "After Prospero waved his wand, one of the following statements became false and the other remained true. Which one do you think is still true?" For five items, one statement was formulated in terms of addition (e.g., "3+1=4") and the other in terms of subtraction ("4-1=3");</p><p>for five items, one was multiplication ("2x3=6") and the other division ("6/2=3"); and for five items, one was exponentiation ("4^2=16") and the other rooting ("sqrt(16)=4"). In all cases, choices were made on a scale from -5 to 5, with each scale extreme marked with one of the statements (randomized by item). For analyses, scores were coded such that negative numbers correspond to the more basic operation (addition, multiplication, exponentiation). Due to a typo, we excluded one multiplication/division item from analyses, but including it does not alter the conclusions.</p><p>After the 15 items of the main task (but without a clear demarcation from the participants' perspective), a further 6 items were presented wherein one statement was true (e.g.,</p><p>("32/4 = 8") and the other false ("4x8=40"). These were used as check questions. Numeracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Lipkus et al., 2001</ref>) was then measured for exploratory purposes; however, we did not analyze numeracy and do not discuss it further.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results and Discussion</head><p>Participants preferred to retain the statement described in terms of the more 'basic' These results accord with the notion that differences in explanatory power translate into resistance to counterfactual alteration. This provides suggestive evidence that the links between explanatory power and causal strength we saw in Studies 1-3 may extend even to putatively noncausal domains such as mathematics. Future research might assess whether the imposition of mental causal models on mathematics has implications for mathematics instruction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Discussion</head><p>Even though life often fails to lay out statistical information in a digestible way, we are nonetheless able to infer causal strength from individual cases. To see whether this ability might in part draw on our explanatory capacities, we used three different methods to demonstrate the link between explanatory power and causal strength judgments. Study 1 found that, within a sample of naturalistic historical events, the two judgments were almost perfectly correlated.</p><p>Studies 2 and 3 used an experimental approach to show that manipulating a cause's perceived explanatory power, even when there is no doubt about causal structure, affects the perceived strength of that cause. Study 4 revealed signatures of explanatory power on counterfactual judgments even in the (seemingly) non-causal domain of mathematics.</p><p>These results add to previous research documenting ways that prior knowledge influences causal judgments. For example, covariation information has a stronger effect on causal judgments when the causal candidate is believable than when it is unbelievable <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Fugelsang &amp; Thompson, 2000)</ref> and both laypeople and working scientists discount data that is inconsistent with their hypotheses <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Fugelsang, Stein, Green, &amp; Dunbar, 2004</ref>).</p><p>The present results differ from these prior findings, however, in demonstrating that even in the absence of any data, beliefs about explanatory power can influence judgments of causal strength. Instead, these findings may be more closely related to analogical mappings from one causal token to another <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Holyoak, Lee, &amp; Lu, 2010)</ref>, where covariation information is not used at all. The tight coupling between causal and explanatory strength seems to license a heuristic wherein one can be used as a proxy for the other in any token case, without necessarily referring to the statistics of the broader reference class. This may explain in part why people often prefer explanatory information over statistical information when evaluating causal tokens (e.g., "Jim's smoking caused him to get lung cancer"), but prefer statistical information when evaluating causal types ("A person's smoking causes them to get lung cancer"; <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Johnson &amp; Keil, 2016</ref>).</p><p>An open question for future research is whether a similar explanatory heuristic could be at play in causal structure inference as well. The present studies were not designed with this question in mind (we specified that causal relationships existed in all cases), but participants in Study 2 were indeed somewhat more likely to reject the structure claim (e.g., "Randy having Ferraro's disorder caused him to lose hair") when explanatory quality was lower. Future studies might test this possibility by manipulating explanatory virtues that do not normatively license different inferences in structurally ambiguous cases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>We must often infer both the shapes and sizes of causal relationships without contingency information at our disposal, and in such cases we must rely on prior knowledge and cues from the environment to make these inferences. The present results show that the explanatory power of a causal relationship is one guide we use to make these strength inferences. This finding underscores the importance of research on explanatory preferences by documenting downstream consequences of explanatory reasoning for causal inference. Just as the explanatory structures in our minds mirror causal structure in the world, so do our causal perceptions mirror our explanatory intuitions. More thorough understanding of both sides of this feedback loop will be needed to ground this circle between mind and environment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EXPLANATORY POWER AS A SUBSTITUTE FOR STATISTICAL REASONING ONLINE SUPPLEMENTARY MATERIALS</head><p>Appendix S1: Stimuli from Study 1 Instructions: On each of the following pages, you will read about some true historical events, and will be asked a question about each. There will be a total of 54 questions.</p><p>On each page, participants were presented with two events, labeled <ref type="bibr">'A' and 'B', and then</ref>  A national interstate highway system was built in the US. Humans domesticated the Grey Wolf thousands of years ago.</p><p>We have house dogs as pets today.</p><p>Rich people wanted to show off their power.</p><p>The first zoos were built. Enlightenment-era thinking encouraged the scientific study of animals. World War I happened.</p><p>Prohibition was passed. Prohibition was passed.</p><p>There was a huge increase in members of religious congregations and self-professed rabbis who could still obtain wine for religious purposes. During Prohibition, many Prohibition agents and local cops succumbed to corruption.</p><p>Public trust in law enforcement faltered.</p><p>During Prohibition, more Americans were charged as criminals than the legal system could handle.</p><p>Use of the "plea bargain" became a common practice.</p><p>The Labor Movement was founded.</p><p>Workers received higher wages. There was a fire at the Triangle Shirtwaist Company factory in NYC on March 25, 1911 and 146 workers were killed.</p><p>Laws and regulations were instituted to protect the safety of workers.</p><p>On October 8th, 1871 a fire started in Mr. and Mrs. O 'Leary's barn on the outskirts of Chicago.</p><p>A massive fire destroyed the city's central business district.</p><p>In 1892, Plessy, an African American male, boarded a "whites only" train car.</p><p>In 1896, the Supreme Court ruled to uphold the "separate but equal" doctrine. The Brown v. Board of Education decision declared segregation in public schools to be unconstitutional.</p><p>The "separate but equal" doctrine ended. Detectives cut a deal with a suspect in the Willoughby case. Because the detectives cut a deal, they interviewed the victim, canvassed the neighborhood, and made an arrest.</p><p>When detectives cut a deal with a suspect in a high profile case, they interview the victim.</p><p>Detectives cut a deal with a suspect in the Willoughby case. Because the detectives cut a deal, they interviewed the victim. We also know that they canvassed the neighborhood and made an arrest, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1B</head><p>When the main suspect in a case goes missing, detectives increase highway patrol, lengthen their shifts, and interview additional witnesses.</p><p>Yesterday, the main suspect in the Pacer case went missing. Because the suspect went missing, detectives increased highway patrol, lengthened their shifts, and interviewed additional witnesses.</p><p>When the main suspect in a case goes missing, detectives increase highway patrol.</p><p>Yesterday, the main suspect in the Pacer case went missing. Because the suspect went missing, detectives increased highway patrol. We also know that they lengthened their shifts and interviewed additional witnesses, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2A</head><p>When a corporation has a good quarter, they often issue stock options, increase their social media presence, and diversify their patents.</p><p>This past quarter, Solaris Enterprises had a good quarter. Because they had a good quarter, Solaris Enterprises issued stock options, increased their social media presence, and diversified their patents.</p><p>When a corporation has a good quarter, they often issue stock options.</p><p>This past quarter, Solaris Enterprises had a good quarter. Because they had a good quarter, Solaris Enterprises issued stock options. We also know that they increased their social media presence and diversified their patents, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2B</head><p>After receiving poor ratings on recent movie releases, production companies</p><p>After receiving poor ratings on recent movie releases, production companies often increase advertising efforts, make alterations to their production team, and secure contracts with new actors.</p><p>Starlight Productions received poor ratings on recent movie releases. Because of these poor ratings, Starlight Productions increased advertising efforts, made alterations to their production team, and secured contracts with new actors.</p><p>often increase advertising efforts.</p><p>Starlight Productions received poor ratings on recent movie releases. Because of these poor ratings, Starlight Productions increased advertising efforts. We also know that they made alterations to their production team and secured contracts with new actors, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>3A</head><p>When someone has Ferraro's Disorder, they lose hair, gain weight, and have frequent night terrors. When someone has Bleeker's Disease, they experience sleep disturbances.</p><p>Five weeks ago, Sylvia was diagnosed with Bleeker's Disease. Because she has Bleeker's Disease, Sylvia experienced sleep disturbances. We also know that she developed neurotic personality tendencies and felt nauseated, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4A</head><p>When a shampoo called Sterling Shampoo is applied to hair, the hair appears darker in color, gets curlier, and becomes brittle at the ends.</p><p>While showering, Savana applied Sterling Shampoo to her hair. Because she applied Sterling Shampoo to her hair, Savana's hair appeared darker in color, got curlier, and became brittle at the ends.</p><p>When a shampoo called Sterling Shampoo is applied to hair, the hair appears darker in color.</p><p>While showering, Savana applied Sterling Shampoo to her hair. Because she applied Sterling Shampoo to her hair, Savana's hair appeared darker in color. We also know that her hair got curlier and became brittle at the ends, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4B</head><p>When someone consumes a product called EnLIGHTen, their metabolic rate increases, they have headaches, and their skin becomes pale.</p><p>When someone consumes a product called EnLIGHTen, their metabolic rate increases.</p><p>This morning, Rory consumed a bottle of EnLIGHTen. Because he consumed EnLIGHTen, Rory's metabolic rate increased, he had headaches, and his skin became pale.</p><p>This morning, Rory consumed a bottle of EnLIGHTen. Because he consumed EnLIGHTen, Rory's metabolic rate increased. We also know that he had headaches and his skin became pale, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5A</head><p>When basketball teams prepare to play a double-header, the players increase their electrolyte intake, ramp up their stretching routines, and take ice baths.</p><p>The Bears began preparing for a doubleheader. Because they were preparing for a double-header, the players increased their electrolyte intake, ramped up their stretching routines, and took ice baths.</p><p>When basketball teams prepare to play a double-header, the players increase their electrolyte intake.</p><p>The Bears began preparing for a doubleheader. Because they were preparing for a double-header, the players increased their electrolyte intake. We also know that they ramped up their stretching routines and took ice baths, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5B</head><p>When a professional athlete gets injured, they switch to pool workouts, participate in press interviews, and take potassium supplements.</p><p>Yesterday Jefferson, a professional football player, got injured during a game. Because he got injured, Jefferson switched to pool workouts, participated in press interviews, and took potassium supplements.</p><p>When a professional athlete gets injured, they switch to pool workouts.</p><p>Yesterday Jefferson, a professional football player, got injured during a game. Because he got injured, Jefferson switched to pool workouts. We also know that he participated in press interviews and took potassium supplements, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>6A</head><p>When it is mating season, chacara birds build nests, increase their magnesium intake, and sing at a higher pitch.</p><p>Mating season began last week. Because it was mating season, chacara bird #4572 built nests, increased its magnesium intake, and sang at a higher pitch.</p><p>When it is mating season, chacara birds build nests.</p><p>Mating season began last week. Because it was mating season, chacara bird #4572 built nests. We also know that it increased its magnesium intake and sang at a higher pitch, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>6B</head><p>When there is an earthquake, brownbellied weasels store food, create new burrows underground, and search for the nearest water source.</p><p>Yesterday, an earthquake was detected. Because there was an earthquake, brownbellied weasel #237 stored food, created new burrows underground, and searched for the nearest water source.</p><p>When there is an earthquake, brownbellied weasels store food.</p><p>Yesterday, an earthquake was detected. Because there was an earthquake, brownbellied weasel #237 stored food. We also know that it created new burrows underground and searched for the nearest water source, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>7A</head><p>After experiencing a successful harvest season, the Melepari tribe holds a tribal feast, performs a spiritual dance, and wears jade bracelets.</p><p>This year's harvest season was successful. Because the Melepari tribe had a successful harvest season, they held a tribal feast, performed a spiritual dance, and wore jade bracelets.</p><p>After experiencing a successful harvest season, the Melepari tribe holds a tribal feast.</p><p>This year's harvest season was successful. Because the Melepari tribe had a successful harvest season, they held a tribal feast. We also know that the tribe performed a spiritual dance and wore jade bracelets, but we don't know why. 7B</p><p>When a child is born with a cleft palate, the Sifaru tribe performs a smoke ceremony, bathes the child in the river, and builds an altar.</p><p>On the third moon of the Sifaru calendar, a child was born with a cleft palate. Because a child was born with a cleft palate, the Sifaru tribe performed a smoke ceremony, bathed the child in the river, and built an altar.</p><p>When a child is born with a cleft palate, the Sifaru tribe performs a smoke ceremony.</p><p>On the third moon of the Sifaru calendar, a child was born with a cleft palate. Because a child was born with a cleft palate, the Sifaru tribe performed a smoke ceremony. We also know the tribe bathed the child in the river and built an altar, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>8A</head><p>When the argon concentration in the atmosphere increases, cumulonimbus clouds form, flocks of geese fly at lower altitudes, and beta rays permeate more easily.</p><p>In the airspace above Lincoln, Nebraska, the concentration of argon recently increased. Because the argon concentration increased, cumulonimbus clouds formed, flocks of geese flew at lower altitudes, and beta rays permeated more easily.</p><p>When the argon concentration in the atmosphere increases, cumulonimbus clouds form.</p><p>In the airspace above Lincoln, Nebraska, the concentration of argon recently increased. Because the argon concentration increased, cumulonimbus clouds formed. We also know that flocks of geese flew at lower altitudes and beta rays permeated more easily, but we don't know why.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>8B</head><p>When the pH level in a body of water decreases, monoalgae forms, catfish populations produce more offspring, and the water level rises.</p><p>In Lake Katarza, the pH level recently decreased. Because the pH level of Lake Katarza decreased, monoalgae formed, catfish populations produced more offspring, and the water level rose.</p><p>When the pH level in a body of water decreases, monoalgae forms.</p><p>In Lake Katarza, the pH level recently decreased. Because the pH level of Lake Katarza decreased, monoalgae formed. We also know that catfish populations produced more offspring and the water level rose, but we don't know why.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results of Study 1A and 1B, plotted at the item level.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Explanatory structures used in Studies 1A and 1B. (A) Good structure (wide manifest scope), (B) Bad-Manifest structure (narrow scope), (C) Bad-Latent structure (wide latent scope).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Results of Study 2. Bars represent ±1 SE.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Results of Study 3. Bars represent ±1 SE.We also examined item-level correlations between explanatory power ratings and causal strength judgments from Study 2 (causal strength judgments for the Good items were averaged across Studies 2A and 2B). Across all 48 combinations of item and version, the correlation between explanatory power and causal strength was highly robust, r(46)=.65, p&lt;.001. Looking just within each version of each item, this correlation was significant within the Bad-Manifest items, r(14)=.70, p=.002, and positive but non-significant within the Good items, r(14)=.19,   p=.48, r(14)=.42, p=.11. These positive correlations help to buttress the case that the findings of Study 2 were indeed driven by explanatory power.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>stock market crashed in October of 1929. The Great Depression began. Computers were invented. Movie makers use CGI graphics in their films. The French economy was mismanaged during the Seven Years War and the American Revolutionary War. The French Revolution happened. State representatives wanted a guarantee of individual rights to be added to the Constitution. The Bill of Rights was written. Christopher Columbus discovered the Americas. The United Stated was created. James Wilson Marshall discovered gold in California in 1848. In 1849, the California Gold Rush began. The attitude of manifest destiny was adopted by Americans. Native Americans were forced to resettle. The Second Bank of the United States had irresponsible lending practices. The Panic of 1819 occurred.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>=2.28, p=.025, d=0.23), and considerably higher for the Good items than the Bad-Latent items in Study1B (M=7.98, SD=0.92 vs. M=7.41, SD=1.17; t(98)=6.22, p&lt;.001, d=0.62). Item analyses were also conducted, using the average for each item among those participants who responded "yes" to the structure question. Effects generalized well across items, t(15)=2.82,   p=.013, d=0.70 for Study 2A and t(15)=9.84, p&lt;.001, d=2.46 for Study 2B.    </figDesc><table /><note>Good items than the Bad-Manifest items in Study 1A (M=7.89, SD=0.99 vs. M=7.74, SD=1.08; t(99)</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Study 2A: M=8.75% vs. M=6.50%; t(99)=1.84, p=.069,   d=0.18; Study 2B: M=9.85% vs. M=3.54%; t(98)=3.68, p&lt;.001, d=0.37). However, even if we consider just those participants who responded "yes" to the causal structure question for all 16 items (about 55% of participants), the effects of our manipulations on causal strength held up for both Study2A (Ms=8.23 vs. 8.14; t(56)=1.95, p=.056, d=0.26)  and for Study2B (Ms=8.19 vs.   7.87; t(54)=3.77, p&lt;.001, d=0.51). Therefore, covert structure inferences in the place of causal strength judgments cannot explain our findings.</figDesc><table /><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>ratings of explanatory power differed across the different versions of each item. The Good items were more satisfying (M=7.69, SD=1.09) than the Bad-Manifest items (M=7.43, SD=1.27), t(57)=2.18, p=.034, d=0.29, which were more satisfying than the Bad-Latent items (M=6.68, SD=1.64), t(57)=3.54, p=.001, d=0.46. Thus, the manifest scope</figDesc><table /><note>manipulation was a weaker manipulation of explanatory power compared to the latent scope manipulation, as implied by the Study 2 results.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>To what extent do you think that A is a satisfying explanation for why B happened? [Study 1B]: A happened, and this caused B to happen. How strong do you think this causal relationship is between A and B?</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>asked:</cell></row><row><cell>[Study 1A] The pairs of events are listed below:</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell>B</cell></row><row><cell>Archduke Ferdinand of Austria Hungary was</cell><cell>World War I started.</cell></row><row><cell>assassinated.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Sir Edward Grey, the British Foreign</cell><cell>Britain joined World War I.</cell></row><row><cell>Secretary, felt that Britain had an obligation</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>to fight alongside France against the</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Germans.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>A giant asteroid hit the Earth.</cell><cell>Dinosaurs went extinct.</cell></row><row><cell>Hitler wanted to expand Germany.</cell><cell>Germany invaded Poland.</cell></row><row><cell>Germany invaded Poland in September of</cell><cell>World War II started in September of 1939.</cell></row><row><cell>1939.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>The Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1956 was</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>passed.</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The Bay of Pigs fiasco did not reflect well on President Kennedy or the US.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Kennedy launched Project Apollo, a program</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>that aimed to land on the moon by the end of</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>the 1960s.</cell></row><row><cell>The World War II draft threatened the</cell><cell>The All-American Girls Baseball League was</cell></row><row><cell>collapse of Major League Baseball.</cell><cell>created in 1943.</cell></row><row><cell>The Black Plague rampaged through Europe</cell><cell>The price of labor in Europe skyrocketed.</cell></row><row><cell>from 1347 to 1351.</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Acknowledgements. We thank Adrienne Richter Powell and Jai Gulati for assistance with the manuscript. SJ was supported by grants from Canada's Natural Sciences and Engineering Research</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The Spanish Flu swept through the world in 1918.</p><p>American soliders in Europe died.</p><p>The transcontinental railroad was completed in 1869.</p><p>There was a boom in business growth.</p><p>Britain's army failed during the Boer Wars in South Africa.</p><p>Britain shifted its expansive policy to a defensive one. France, Russia, and Germany challenged Britain's imperial superiority in the early 1900s.</p><p>Britain entered into a non-binding alliance with France and Russia.</p><p>Germany established a policy of Weltpolitik, an imperialistic drive to be a world power. Pharmaceutical industries began screening natural products for antibacterial activity. The MRI was invented.</p><p>The amount of radiation in diagnostics decreased.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix S2: Stimuli from Study 2A</head><p>On each page, participants were presented with either the 'Good' or 'Bad' version of each item. Items were constructed in pairs, with two items within a topic <ref type="bibr">(e.g., law, business, etc.)</ref> and participants assigned to one 'good <ref type="bibr">' and one 'bad' item within each topic. Pairs are labeled 'A' and 'B' (e.g.,</ref> When detectives cut a deal with a suspect in a high profile case, they interview the victim, canvass the neighborhood, and make an arrest.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of covariation versus mechanism information in causal attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kalish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Medin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="352" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A note on measurement of contingency between two binary variables in judgment tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bulletin of the Psychonomic Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time in causal structure learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bramley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gerstenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mayrhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1880</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Making history: Agency, structure, and change in social theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Callinicos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>Polity Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Theory and data interactions of the scientific mind: Evidence from the molecular and the cognitive laboratory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fugelsang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Dunbar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Canadian Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="95" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategy selection in causal reasoning: When beliefs and covariation collide</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fugelsang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Canadian Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structure and strength in causal induction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="334" to="384" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analogical and category-based inference: A theoretical integration with Bayesian causal models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Holyoak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="702" to="727" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Oxford handbook of causal reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>M.R. Waldmann</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="146" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Causal mechanisms</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Causal inference and the hierarchical structure of experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">143</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2223" to="2241" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical and mechanistic information in evaluating causal claims</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<editor>G. Gunzelmann, A. Howes, T. Tenbrink, &amp; E.J. Davelaar</editor>
		<meeting>the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society<address><addrLine>Austin, TX</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cognitive Science Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="618" to="623" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Principles used to evaluate mathematical explanations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Koven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<editor>G. Gunzelmann, A. Howes, T. Tenbrink, &amp; E.J. Davelaar</editor>
		<meeting>the 39th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society<address><addrLine>Austin, TX</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cognitive Science Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="612" to="617" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inferred evidence in latent scope explanations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Rajeev-Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 36 th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the 36 th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society<address><addrLine>Austin, TX</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cognitive Science Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sense-making under ignorance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Rajeev-Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="70" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simplicity and complexity preferences in causal explanation: An opponent heuristic account</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Valenti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">101222</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Little Bayesians or little Einsteins? Probability and explanatory virtue in children&apos;s inferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Koven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Keil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Developmental Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">12483</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Harry Potter and the sorcerer&apos;s scope: Latent scope biases in explanatory reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Khemlani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sussman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Oppenheimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="527" to="535" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time as a guide to cause</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Sloman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="460" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">General performance on a numeracy scale among highly educated samples</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lipkus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Samsa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Rimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Medical Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="44" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inference to the best explanation (2 nd Edition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Lipton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">London: Routledge</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simplicity and probability in causal explanation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lombrozo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="232" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explanatory preferences shape learning and inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lombrozo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="748" to="59" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explanation and abductive inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lombrozo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Oxford handbook of thinking and reasoning</title>
		<editor>K.J. Holyoak &amp; R.G. Morrison</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Oxford, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Causation: A user&apos;s guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Paul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Causality: Models, reasoning, and inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pearl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Models of covariation-based causal judgment: A review and synthesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Perales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Shanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="577" to="596" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explanatory coherence in social explanations: A parallel distributed processing account</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Read</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Marcus-Newhall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="429" to="447" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Depth: An account of scientific explanation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Strevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating everyday explanations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Zemla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sloman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bechlivanidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lagnado</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1488" to="1500" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
