<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Decision-Making in Sharing Personal Information of Others: An Empirical Investigation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><forename type="middle">Rasoul</forename><surname>Parsaeian</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Psychology and Educational Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tehran</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abdol-Hossein</forename><surname>Vahabie</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">College of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tehran</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Majid</forename><forename type="middle">Nili</forename><surname>Ahmadabadi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">College of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tehran</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Decision-Making in Sharing Personal Information of Others: An Empirical Investigation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:26+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Privacy</term>
					<term>Dark Personality Traits</term>
					<term>Information Sharing</term>
					<term>Dark Triad</term>
					<term>Social Value Orientation</term>
					<term>Incentives</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>The sharing of personal information by data collection entities has significantly impacted social processes, especially in recent years. This study aimed to examine the relationship between dark personality traits (Machiavellianism, psychopathy, and narcissism), social value orientation, and the behavior of sharing others&apos; personal information. We also investigated the effect of incentives on behavior change, where participants were tempted with the possibility of gaining information about the individuals whose data they were sharing. Participants completed measures of dark personality traits and made decisions about sharing others&apos; personal information in pre-test and post-test conditions with varying levels of incentives. Results indicated no significant relationship between dark triad scores and decisions to share information in the initial introduction stage or in the presence of incentives. Additionally, no significant difference in dark triad scores was found between individualistic and prosocial groups based on social value orientation. These findings contribute to our understanding of the factors influencing personal information sharing behaviors.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The sharing of personal information has become a critical issue in the digital age, with significant implications for privacy, security, and social interactions. While much research has focused on individuals' decisions to share their own personal information, less attention has been given to the factors influencing decisions to share others' personal information.</p><p>This study aims to address this gap by examining the role of dark personality traits and social value orientation in such decision-making processes.</p><p>The dark triad of personality, comprising Machiavellianism, psychopathy, and narcissism, has been associated with various antisocial and self-serving behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Paulhus &amp; Williams, 2002)</ref>. These traits may influence an individual's propensity to share others' personal information without consent. Additionally, social value orientation, which reflects an individual's preference for resource allocation between self and others, may play a role in decisions related to information sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(van Dijk, 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Understanding the factors that influence decisions to share others' personal information is crucial for developing effective privacy policies and interventions. This study seeks to answer the following research questions:</p><p>1. Is there a relationship between dark triad personality traits and the decision to share others' personal information? 2. Does the presence of incentives affect the relationship between dark triad traits and information sharing behavior?</p><p>3. Is there a difference in dark triad scores between individuals with different social value orientations? 2 2 Method</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Participants</head><p>The study sample consisted of 116 participants (59 females, 57 males) with a mean age of 32.3 years (SD = 8.9). Participants were recruited through online platforms and social media channels. The inclusion criteria required participants to be at least 18 years old and fluent in Persian. The sample was diverse in terms of education levels, with 12.9</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Measures</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1">Dark Triad</head><p>The Short Dark Triad (SD3) questionnaire <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Jones &amp; Paulhus, 2014)</ref> was used to assess Machiavellianism, psychopathy, and narcissism.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2">Social Value Orientation</head><p>Social value orientation was assessed using the SVO Slider Measure <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Murphy et al., 2011)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.3">Information Sharing Behavior</head><p>Participants' willingness to share others' personal information was measured through a custom-designed task where they were asked to provide the names and phone numbers of up to five other individuals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>subsectionProcedure</head><p>The study consisted of four main phases:</p><p>1. Pre-test: Participants were asked to decide whether to share personal information (name and phone number) of up to five other individuals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Questionnaires: Participants completed demographic information and the Short</head><p>Dark Triad questionnaire.</p><p>3. Post-test: Participants were randomly assigned to groups with different levels of incentives and again asked to share others' personal information. The incentive offered was the possibility of gaining information about the individuals whose data they were sharing. This temptation was designed to mimic real-world scenarios where sharing information might lead to reciprocal access to others' data.</p><p>4. Social Value Orientation: Participants completed the SVO Slider Measure.</p><p>In the post-test phase, participants were randomly divided into groups, each receiving a different level of temptation to share information. The temptation involved the prospect of gaining access to information about the individuals they were asked to introduce, with the level of accessible information varying between groups. This design allowed us to examine how different degrees of potential information gain influenced participants' willingness to share others' personal data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Social Value Orientation and Dark Triad</head><p>To investigate whether there were differences in Dark Triad scores between prosocial and individualistic groups based on social value orientation, an independent t-test was conducted. The Shapiro-Wilk test confirmed normality for both groups (p = 0.336 for prosocial, p = 0.153 for individualistic). Results of the t-test revealed no significant difference between the groups (t = −0.271, p = 0.788). These findings suggest that social value orientation is not strongly associated with Dark Triad traits in the context of information-sharing decisions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Behavior Change and Dark Triad Scores</head><p>The Dark Triad Scores were analyzed across two groups based on the BehaviorChangeotherPhoneNumber variable: "XX" and "NullNull". A Shapiro-Wilk test for normality revealed that the scores were normally distributed for the "XX" group (p = 0.420) but not for the "NullNull" group (p = 0.045). Therefore, a non-parametric Mann-Whitney U test was conducted to compare the two groups.</p><p>The test results indicated no statistically significant difference between the groups (U = 314.0, p = 0.920), suggesting that the Dark Triad Scores do not differ meaningfully based on this variable. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> illustrates the distribution of scores for both groups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Dark Triad and Information Sharing</head><p>No significant correlation was found between dark triad scores and the decision to share information in the pre-test phase. Similarly, there was no significant relationship between dark triad scores and information sharing in the post-test phase with incentives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Effect of Incentives</head><p>The results indicated that incentives did influence behavior, with an increase in information sharing from pre-test to post-test conditions. However, this effect was not moderated by dark triad scores. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Social Value Orientation and Dark Triad</head><p>No significant difference in dark triad scores was found between prosocial and individualistic groups based on social value orientation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Discussion</head><p>The present study investigated the relationship between dark personality traits, social value orientation, and the decision to share others' personal information. Contrary to our hypotheses, we found no significant association between dark triad scores and information sharing behavior, either in the initial stage or when incentives were introduced. These findings suggest that the decision to share others' personal information may be influenced by factors beyond individual personality traits. It is possible that situational factors, such as perceived social norms or the specific context of the information sharing request, play a more significant role in these decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Acquisti et al., 2015)</ref>.</p><p>The lack of difference in dark triad scores between prosocial and individualistic groups is also noteworthy. This suggests that social value orientation may not be strongly related to dark personality traits in the context of information sharing decisions.</p><p>The significant effect of incentives on information sharing behavior highlights the importance of external motivators in privacy-related decisions. This aligns with previous research demonstrating the privacy paradox, where individuals' stated privacy concerns often diverge from their actual behaviors when incentives are present <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Norberg et al., 2007)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Limitations and Future Directions</head><p>Several limitations of this study should be noted. First, the use of hypothetical scenarios may not fully capture real-world information sharing behaviors. Future studies could employ more ecologically valid methods, such as field experiments or analysis of actual online behaviors.</p><p>Second, our sample was limited to primarily Persian-speaking adults with a relatively high education level, which may limit the generalizability of our findings. Replication with more diverse populations is necessary to establish the robustness of these results.</p><p>Finally, while we focused on dark personality traits and social value orientation, other individual difference variables may be relevant to information sharing decisions. Future research could explore factors such as cultural values, trust propensity, or digital literacy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Implications</head><p>Despite these limitations, our findings have important implications for privacy research and policy. The lack of a strong relationship between dark personality traits and information sharing behavior suggests that interventions aimed at protecting privacy may need to focus more on situational factors and incentives rather than individual personality characteristics.</p><p>Additionally, the significant effect of incentives on information sharing highlights the need for careful consideration of reward structures in digital environments. Policy makers and platform designers should be aware of how incentives might inadvertently encourage the sharing of others' personal information without consent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>This study contributes to our understanding of the factors influencing decisions to share others' personal information. While dark personality traits and social value orientation did not show strong relationships with information sharing behavior, the impact of incentives was significant. These findings underscore the complexity of privacy-related decision-making and highlight the need for multifaceted approaches to protecting personal information in the digital age.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Box plot of Dark Triad Scores by Social Value Orientation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Box plot of Dark Triad Scores by BehaviorChangeotherPhoneNumber Groups.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy and human behavior in the age of information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Acquisti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Brandimarte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/science.aaa1465</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaa1465" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">347</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6221</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="509" to="514" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introducing the Short Dark Triad (SD3): A Brief Measure of Dark Personality Traits</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Paulhus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1073191113514105</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1073191113514105" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Assessment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring Social Value Orientation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ackermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Handgraaf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2139/ssrn.1804189</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.1804189" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SSRN Electronic Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The privacy paradox: Personal information disclosure intentions versus behaviors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Norberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Horne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Horne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1745-6606.2006.00070.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1745-6606.2006.00070.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Affairs</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="100" to="126" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Dark Triad of personality: Narcissism, Machiavellianism, and psychopathy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Paulhus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10/d2jxm9ZSCC" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research in Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4821</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social Dilemmas, Psychology of</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Van Dijk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>1016/B978-0-08-097086-8.24027-0 ZSCC: 0000000</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Encyclopedia of the Social &amp; Behavioral Sciences: Second Edition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="249" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
