<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /opt/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Impaired Goal-Directed Planning in Transdiagnostic Compulsivity is Explained by Uncertainty About Learned Task Structure</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sirichat</forename><surname>Sookud</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Neuroimaging</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">King&apos;s College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ingrid</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Neuroimaging</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">King&apos;s College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Cognitive Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Trinity College Dublin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dublin</settlement>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Trinity College Institute for Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Trinity College Dublin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dublin</settlement>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">ADAPT Centre for Digital Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Trinity College Dublin</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dublin</settlement>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toby</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
							<email>toby.wise@kcl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Neuroimaging</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology &amp; Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">King&apos;s College London</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Impaired Goal-Directed Planning in Transdiagnostic Compulsivity is Explained by Uncertainty About Learned Task Structure</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-06-29T14:27+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>compulsivity</term>
					<term>computational modelling</term>
					<term>uncertainty</term>
					<term>learning</term>
					<term>decision-making</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
				<p>Diminished use of goal-directed (&quot;model-based&quot;) decision-making is a hallmark of transdiagnostic compulsivity, promoting an over-reliance on inflexible and habitual behaviours. However, the origin of this impairment remains unclear. Here, we test the hypothesis that these impairments arise due to uncertainty within the internal world model that subserves goal-directed decision-making. We adapted a validated gamified decision-making task to characterise how individuals build an internal model of an environment, pairing this data with computational modelling to uncover the exact mechanisms underpinning behaviour and quantify individual differences. Across discovery (n=551) and replication (n=1322) samples, we found that individuals higher in compulsivity and intrusive thought updated expectations more gradually and formed a less certain representation of the task&apos;s structure. This uncertainty mediated the link between compulsive symptoms and use of goal-directed behaviour. Behaviour in the task was relatively stable over a 3 month (n=385) and 1 year (n=326) period and did not predict changes in symptoms. Our results suggest that reliance on habitual behaviours seen in those with high levels of compulsive symptoms may result from a tendency to form less certain internal models of the external world.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>After a long day of work, you decide what to make for dinner. If your goal is to lower your cholesterol, you might choose a salad, a decision guided by your ultimate goal of improving your health. This contrasts with your usual routine of making a frozen pizza, a habitual choice that does not account for longer-term health considerations. However, making this kind of goal-directed decision (accounting for distal outcomes) is only possible if you appreciate that eating healthily will reduce your cholesterol, ultimately improving your health; in essence, you must possess an internal "model" of how your actions lead to more distant consequences <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref>. Impairments in goal-directed decision-making are implicated in multiple psychiatric conditions, suggesting that symptoms in disorders such as OCD and addiction may arise from and overdependence on habitual ("model-free") processes in place of goal-directed strategies; behaviours such as checking can become ingrained habits, detached from active consideration of likely long-term benefits or costs.</p><p>More recently, efforts to characterise transdiagnostic mechanisms have clarified this preponderance of results across disorders (2); rather than being tied to a diagnostic category, impairments in goal-directed decision-making appear to underpin symptoms of compulsivity and intrusive thought patterns that are present across multiple diagnostic categories <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">4)</ref>.</p><p>A key unanswered question, however, is why this tendency to rely on model-free decision-making arises.</p><p>One intriguing suggestion is that it emerges due to uncertainty in an internal model of the world <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(5)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(6)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(7)</ref>; if I am uncertain about the long-run consequences of my actions, I should be less likely to use a decisionmaking strategy that relies on this knowledge. While uncertainty is multifaceted, here we focus on reducible uncertainty, which represents our lack of knowledge about a value and can be visualised as the variance around an estimate. For example, I may believe an event has a 75% chance of happening (representing irreducible uncertainty); but be very uncertain about this point estimate (representing reducible uncertainty).</p><p>It has been demonstrated that human behaviour follows this basic principle, whereby goal-directed behaviour depends upon a reliable model-based system <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(8)</ref>, and that model-based behaviour depends critically on knowledge of task structure <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(9)</ref>; meanwhile there is accumulating evidence that compulsive symptoms are associated with deficits in the ability to learn an internal world model <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">11)</ref>. While there is some evidence that individuals high in compulsive symptoms specifically overestimate uncertainty in relation to task structure changeability <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(12)</ref>, to our knowledge it has yet to be established whether uncertainty more generally underlies model-free decision-making.</p><p>Large-scale online 'citizen science' studies now enable us to answer these questions with greater precision and robustness than previously possible <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">14)</ref>. Mental health symptoms are highly multifactorial in their aetiology, meaning that any individual influence will likely have a subtle effect; large samples are thus vital to achieve sufficient statistical power <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref>, rendering large-scale online data collection highly valuable. Concurrently, efforts to "gamify" decision-making tasks for mass online deployment encourages greater task engagement <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">15)</ref> and naturalism <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">17)</ref>, improving our ability to detect subtle relationships and enabling research to move beyond highly selected samples and into the general population.</p><p>Here, we test the hypothesis that a reliance on model-free decision-making linked to transdiagnostic compulsivity arise due to uncertainty about learned task structure. We exploit a gamified task that indexes participants' ability to learn task structure, combined with computational modelling that permits precise quantification of individuals' estimates of uncertainty throughout the task. We demonstrate that transdiagnostic compulsivity is linked to heightened uncertainty about task structure, and further suggest that this uncertainty mediates the link between compulsivity and reliance on model-free decision-making.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1. Task overview. A)</head><p>Schematic of the original and modified Cannon Blast task, a gamified implementation of the "two-step" task. Frst stage states (cannon ball containers) have a fixed and shown probability of transitioning to second stage states (ball colour), and participants must learn the probability of each colour ball exploding. In the modified task, participants are shown the probabilities of explosion for each ball colour but must learn the probability of first to second stage state transitions. B) Estimated transition probabilities can be associated with different levels of reducible uncertainty. C) A screenshot of a standard trial in the game. Participants were tasked with firing cannon balls from the cannon to hit an alien that moved around the top portion of the screen. They could select to fire a ball from one of two containers, each of which had a varying but hidden probability of producing pink or purple balls. The probability of each ball colour exploding before reaching its target was shown by coloured bars at the top of the screen. D) A confidence trial. Participants were tasked with shooting at one of a range of pink or purple asteroids with varying values. If the colour of the ball matched the colour of the asteroid they were awarded the number of points shown next to that asteroid, but they would lose that number of points if the colour did not match. E) A "broken" trial, where all information regarding ball colour was hidden. F) Explosion probabilities for pink and purple balls changed rapidly across the task. All information regarding ball colour was removed on "broken" trials. G) Probabilities of pink and purple balls being produced by the left and right containers drifted over the course of the task. Probabiltiies for the left container are shown, and those for the right container were the inverse of these probabilities. Pointers at the top indicate confidence trials. H) Overview of the computational modelling approach. Observations of ball colours following left/right choices are used to update a probability distribution over task structure, the variance of which provides an index of uncertainty. This is then combined with the provided reward probabilities to inform the next choice. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Samples</head><p>Our final samples after exclusions (see Methods) consisted of 551 participants for the discovery sample 1322 participants for the replication sample (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for demographic information). Of the discovery sample, 385 completed the study a second time after 3 months and 326 returned a third time after 1 year. 21.05% and 23.23% scored above established cutoffs for clinically-relevant symptom severity for anxiety (GAD-7) and depression (PHQ-8) respectively, a pattern that replicated in the replication sample (18.38% and 23.6%). Participants make decisions based on learned task structure</p><p>Participants completed a two-stage decision-making task designed to index learning of task structure ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1A</ref>). This was an adapted version of the well-validated "two-step" task <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">19)</ref>, specifically a gamified version that has previously been shown to be sensitive to individual differences in model-based decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3)</ref>. The goal of the original task is to determine whether participants use information about the task structure provided to them to make goal-directed decisions, choosing options that lead to states with high rewards (where the reward value varies over time and must be learned). We reasoned that effectively inverting this approach should enable us to characterise learning about task structure;</p><p>we ask participants to learn a time-varying task structure while providing them with reward values ( <ref type="figure">Figure   1A</ref>). Crucially, this enabled us to assess individual differences in how participants learned the task structure, and quantify their reducible uncertainty over these estimates ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1B</ref>).</p><p>Participants were able to perform the task successfully, as demonstrated by increasing scores across the entire task ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2F</ref>). At the level of raw behaviour, we observed a pattern of switching between options that is indicative of model-based decision-making in trials that had a clear transition pattern (&gt;=80% chance of one colour); as in the original "two-step" task, participants tended to switch after observing a rewarded rare transition (since it is best to instead choose the option that will regularly lead to the rewarded second-stage state), and stay when observing a rewarded common transition <ref type="bibr">(</ref> Participants account for uncertainty when learning task structure</p><p>While raw behaviour indicates that participants are using model-based strategy based on a learned task structure, testing our primary hypothesis required a measure of their uncertainty in this structure. To achieve this, we turned to computational modelling, focusing on a family of models that maintain a distribution over possibly probabilities <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">20)</ref> and which provide a simple quantification of uncertainty throughout the task.</p><p>Model fitting revealed that participants' behaviour was predominantly goal-directed, being best described by a model that did not feature model-free value learning across both samples ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3A</ref>, 3B, 3C). To provide evidence that uncertainty plays a significant role in learning, we compared these models to equivalent models that learned transition probabilities using a Rescorla-Wagner learning rule, and thus only maintain point estimates of probabilities. Our uncertainty-driven learning models outperformed these comparison models ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3A</ref>, 3B, 3C), suggesting that participants learned transition structure in a manner that tracked and accounted for uncertainty.</p><p>We next extracted average uncertainty (the variance of the distribution over transition probabilities) from the winning model, providing an index of individual-level uncertainty across the task. To validate these metrics, we sought to establish their ability to predict participants' ratings on trials where they were asked to report their confidence. Confidence judgements were consistently predicted by both  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3D</ref>) derived from the winning computational model, providing assurance that these model-derived values were capturing variables that were subjectively meaningful to participants.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5B</ref>). Reliability was higher over 3 months and 1 year ( <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2)</ref>.</p><p>The model-basedness estimate from the current task was also positively, albeit modestly, correlated</p><p>with the index of model-basedness from the original Cannon Blast task (σ = 0.14, p &lt; .001). Behaviour is associated with transdiagnostic symptom dimensions</p><p>We next sought to characterise associations between task behaviour and symptoms, focusing on three well-established transdiagnostic dimensions <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">24)</ref>; namely, anxious-depression, compulsivity and intrusive thought, and social withdrawal.</p><p>We first focused on general tendencies to use a model-based strategy. In the discovery sample, we found that model-basedness in the task was predicted positively by anxious depression (β = 0.19, pcorr &lt; .001, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4A</ref>) and negatively by compulsivity and intrusive thought (β = -0.18, pcorr &lt; .001, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4A</ref>). These effects were replicated in the discovery sample (compulsivity and intrusive thought: β = -0.10, pcorr = .001;</p><p>anxious-depression: β = 0.07, pcorr = .04). Separating this metric into its constituent parts (given that it</p><p>represents the difference between model-based and model-free fit) revealed that this effect was driven specifically by the use of model-based decision-making (see Tables S14, S15, S22, S23).</p><p>We also replicated prior findings using the original Cannon Blast "two-step" task (4) within the replication sample ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4E</ref>), finding a reduction in model-basedness associated with compulsivity and intrusive thought alongside (β = -0.11, p = .001) an increase in model-basedness associated with anxiousdepression (AD β = 0.06, p = .039) and social withdrawal (SW β = 0.08, p = .008). We next asked whether this pattern of model-basedness could be explained by the way in which participants learned the task structure, and particularly whether there were links between symptom dimensions and uncertainty about task structure. Across both discovery and replication samples.</p><p>compulsivity and intrusive thought was further associated heightened uncertainty (discovery β = 0.16, p corr = .003; replication β = 0.09, p corr = .009; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4A</ref>) about task structure and more gradual updating of probability estimates (discovery β = -0.15, p corr = .015; replication β = -0.10, p corr = .002; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4A</ref>).</p><p>Anxious-depression consistently demonstrated the opposite pattern with respect to uncertainty estimates (discovery β = -0.16, pcorr = .003, replication β = -0.11, pcorr = .001; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4A</ref>) and update rates (discovery β = 0.15, pcorr = .012; replication β = 0.10, pcorr = .001; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4A</ref>). We observed no significant effects relating to the decay parameter ( ) or confidence ratings, or in relation to the social withdrawal symptom dimension (see Supplement for detailed results). We sought to clarify these relationships further by determining whether the relationship between compulsivity and intrusive thought and model-basedness was mediated by uncertainty. Across both samples, mediation analysis revealed a significant indirect effect (path values are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4C</ref> for the replication sample and in the supplement for the discovery sample) and a non-significant direct effect ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4C</ref>, supplement), suggesting that the observed association was fully mediated by uncertainty about the learned task structure. Notably, we also found that the association between compulsivity and intrusive thought and model-basedness in the original cannon blast task was partially mediated by uncertainty estimated from the novel task <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">(Table S30</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task behaviour is associated with symptoms of anxiety and depression</head><p>We also conducted further analyses examining effects of specific depression and anxiety symptoms, measured using the PHQ-8 and GAD-7 respectively. Here, the only replicable results related to depressive symptoms. We observed a positive relationship between depressive symptoms and relative model-basedness in both the discovery (β = 0.29, p corr &lt; .001; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4B</ref>) and replication (β = 0.14, p corr = .003; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4B</ref>) samples. Breaking the relative measure into its component parts, depressive symptoms</p><p>were specifically associated with greater use of model-based strategies in both samples (see <ref type="table">Table SX</ref>).</p><p>We also found that higher depressive symptoms were linked to faster learning (discovery: β = 0.35, pcorr &lt; .001; replication: β = 0.17, pcorr &lt; .001; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4B</ref>) and lower uncertainty (discovery: β = -0.32, pcorr &lt; .001; replication: β = -0.17, pcorr = 0.002; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4B</ref>). We followed this with a mediation analysis examining whether the relationship between depressive symptoms and increased model-basedness was mediated by uncertainty. This suggested that the relationship was fully mediated by uncertainty, as indicated by a significant indirect effect ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4D</ref>) and a non-significant direct effect ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4D</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Behaviour and symptoms are stable over time</head><p>A subset of participants completed the study 3 months and 1 year after participating originally. As described above, behaviour was reasonably stable over time (Table 2, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5B</ref>), with subtle learning effects as demonstrated by increasing scores ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5D</ref>). Symptoms exhibited even greater stability,</p><p>with ICCs &gt; 0.77 (Table S1, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5A</ref>). However, we found no significant associations between changes in symptoms and changes in behaviour across either timepoints when controlling for baseline scores ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5C</ref>, supplement). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Impairments in goal-directed decision-making are an established correlate of compulsive symptoms <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">25)</ref>. However, it has remained unclear why such impairments emerge. Here, we used a computational factor modelling approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref> to suggest that greater uncertainty in a learned internal model of the external environment may underpin the association between transdiagnostic compulsivity and intrusive thought and model-based planning.</p><p>We developed a novel extension of a validated, gamified two-step decision-making task (3) that required participants to learn the structure of the task in order to perform well. Using computational modelling, we were able to extract a measure of model-basedness for each individual, finding across two samples that those higher in compulsivity were less model-based in their decision-making as observed in prior studies using different tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">4)</ref>. Critically, our modelling also demonstrated that people higher in this symptom dimension updated their task structure estimates more gradually, and were more uncertain as a result. Mediation analyses demonstrated that the link between compulsivity and model -basedness was mediated by this uncertainty metric.</p><p>Taken together, these results suggest that impaired goal-directed decision-making may emerge as a result of an uncertain internal model of the world; simply, an uncertain model is less likely to be relied upon to guide behaviour. As a result, behaviour is likely to become rigid and dependent upon habits. This is in line with previous theoretical work (6,7) and empirical findings regarding perceptions of changeability <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(12)</ref>. These results also echo prior findings suggesting alterations in task structure learning associated with compulsivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">11)</ref>, and but provide an important extension by providing empirical evidence regarding the specific role of uncertainty. Notably, prior investigations into value learning processes in transdiagnostic compulsivity have observed either null results <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(26)</ref> or associations in an opposite direction <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(15)</ref>, suggesting that these results are specific to task structure learning. Future work could consider the role of additional factors that are known to influence cognitive map formation, such as motivation <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(27)</ref>, in this relationship.</p><p>We also found, unexpectedly, that anxious-depression was associated with an opposite pattern of results; people scoring higher on this symptom dimension exhibited faster learning and reduced uncertainty, along with some evidence for a greater reliance on goal-directed decision-making. Further analyses suggested that this pattern was most closely tied to depressive symptoms. We also found a similar pattern when using the original cannon-blast task (3). One intriguing possibility is that the phenomenon of repetitive negative thinking (such as worry and rumination) associated with these conditions, which can be viewed as a form of model-based planning <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">29)</ref>, may be relied on to a greater extent due to the world model being more certain. However, this is a speculative proposal and while deployment of model-based planning is dependent upon uncertainty (8), it represents a complex resource allocation process that is likely influenced by numerous additional computations <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">31)</ref>.</p><p>One potentially surprising result was a lack of association between any symptom measures and confidence reports, given that prior work has shown elevated confidence associated with compulsivity and intrusive thought and reduced confidence associated with anxious-depression <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">24)</ref>. This may be explained by the nature of the confidence rating. Prior tasks use perceptual decision-making paradigms and represent a more self-focused measure of confidence related to an individual's perceived ability to make "correct" decisions, where ours instead indexes more externally-focused confidence in a learned metric within the task (i.e., how likely each ball colour is). This disconnect from self-focused performance evaluation may explain the lack of such results here. Despite this, we might still expect to observe a relationship given that symptoms are associated with uncertainty, which is in turn associated with confidence. Another, simpler explanation may be a lack of statistical power, since we incorporated relatively few confidence trials as this was not the primarily aim of the task. More generally, our task provides a novel measure of goal-directed decision-making and the task structure learning that underpins this process. Combined with a modelling approach adapted from prior research <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">20)</ref> that aims to capture subjective uncertainty during learning, this method provides an effective way to assess both decision-making and the learning processes that facilitate it. Notably, our best-fitting model was one that relied purely on a model-based strategy (although there was variation in its fit across participants); it is not especially surprising that we do not see strong evidence of model -free strategy use at the group level since the task was with very rapid changes in reward probabilities, making model-free learning relatively challenging and ineffective.</p><p>We validated our model-derived uncertainty metrics against implicit confidence ratings in our task (a direct behavioural measure); these ratings were predicted by different types of model-derived uncertainty, indicating that our model-derived metrics are not solely abstract values but instead have subjective meaning for participants. We note, however, that while implicit confidence ratings are generally effective (32), we did not include explicit self-reported confidence ratings, and so cannot be certain that these would also be well-predicted by our model-derived uncertainty measures. We also compared our uncertainty-driven learning models to simpler reinforcement learning models that do not adapt the learning process in response to uncertainty, finding that these alternative models provided a poorer fit and suggesting that uncertainty plays a role in learning task structure.</p><p>Our longitudinal analyses demonstrated that both symptoms and behaviour were relatively stable over time, and that changes in symptoms were not predictive of changes in behaviour. This may suggest that learning profiles are relatively stable markers of trait compulsivity, and potentially reflecting a general vulnerability factor for more severe symptoms. This would be in line with suggestions that deficits in model-based planning are not ameliorated following successful treatment in OCD <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(33)</ref>. However, it is also possible that this null result arose as a result of limited variability in symptoms available in a community sample. Longer-term investigations, including in samples with more extreme symptoms, may provide greater insight into these relationships. We also found no relationship between symptoms and confidence ratings, in contrast to previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">34)</ref>; this may result from differences in tasks used, as prior tasks target confidence in challenging perceptual decisions rather than learned quantities (although see <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(35)</ref>).</p><p>The findings of this study are strengthened by the well-powered, preregistered replication of results observed in the discovery sample in a large replication sample, along with validation against an existing measure of model-based planning (3). Furthermore, the use of the computational factor modelling approach (2) enabled us to identify potential computational mechanisms with relevance for symptoms that are present across distinct diagnostic categories. The use of a gamified task also ensured greater engagement in the task than may be expected with a more traditional approach, and our novel approach takes what is sometimes a source of unwanted variability (i.e., imperfect learning of task structure (9)) and exploits this in order to capture individual differences in the formation of internal world models.</p><p>This work does also have some limitations. While the use of an unselected, general population sample recruited online allows for well-powered investigations (2), the symptoms and underlying mechanisms present in such a sample may be qualitatively different from those seen in clinical populations. However, 20% of the samples scored above established cutoffs for depression and anxiety. Furthermore, these is evidence that relationships between compulsive symptoms and goal-directed decision-making are present across both general population and clinical samples <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(25)</ref>, suggesting that this may not necessarily represent a significant problem. Additionally, while the sample was not selected based on clinical status, such individuals were not excluded. Finally, we used a reduced set of questionnaire items to approximate the transdiagnostic factors of interest <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(36,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">37)</ref>, which limits our ability to explore relationships with their constituent measures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Ethical approval</head><p>The study was approved by the King's College London research ethics committee (LRS-21/22-31704).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sample</head><p>Participants were recruited through Prolific <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(38)</ref>, selected based on having a 95% approval rate, being based in the United Kingdom, and being aged 18 or over. Participants received compensation at £9 per hour. We recruited 600 participants for the discovery sample, followed by 1400 for the replication sample (based on power calculations derived from effect sizes observed in the discovery sample). Of the discovery sample, 400 completed the study a second time approximately 3 months after the original time point, and 344 a third time approximately 1 year after. Of the replication sample, 80 completed the task a second time approximately 2 weeks after their initial participation to assess test-retest reliability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Exclusion criteria</head><p>Participants failing any attention checks or failing more than one infrequency item check (39) were excluded from analyses. We also excluded individuals reporting gender other than male or female from analyses that included gender as a covariate as we had insufficient numbers to properly estimate these effects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task Modified cannon blast task</head><p>The primary task ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1A</ref>) was a modified version of the "Cannon Blast" task (3), which is a gamified version of the "two-step" decision-making task for assessing goal-directed versus habitual decisionmaking <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(18)</ref>. The original task asks participants to make decisions about options at a first stage based on the their likelihood of transitioning to second stage states, which are associated with some value. A model-based decision-maker will use their knowledge of these transition probabilities to predict which first stage option they should choose based on its likelihood of transitioning to a rewarding second stage state. In contrast, a model-free decision-maker will simply rely on the rewards that follow their first stage choices, ignoring the structure of the task. These rewards vary over the course of the task according to a random walk, and must be learned. As such, we can infer whether an individual is relying on modelbased or model-free strategies based on their choice of first stage states.</p><p>In our task, participants were tasked with firing cannon balls to hit moving aliens ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1A)</ref>. A hit provided 100 points. During a standard trial, they operated a cannon to choose the firing direction and selected between two containers, each holding purple and pink balls. Balls had a predetermined probability of being unusable on each trial, meaning they would explode before reaching their target and 100 points would be lost. These probabilities varied throughout the task but were displayed on screen via two coloured bars. Probabilities were high to prevent frustration and disengagement, and were anticorrelated. To maximise success, participants should choose the colour that they see has the best chance of being useable. Thus, the container represents the first stage choice, and each container has a probability of transitioning to a second stage state represented by the ball colour. Each of these then has a probability of reward (i.e., not exploding).</p><p>The key manipulation in our task was that the ball colour was not shown to participants in advance of their choice. Instead, each container had a varying probability of firing pink or purple balls ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1E</ref>), which participants had to learn. This contrasts with the original "two-step" task, where participants are provided with this information. Participants were informed that the probabilities for the left and right containers were inversely related, such that if the left had a 90% chance of pink, the right had a 90% chance of purple. This constitutes the "structure" of the task; participants needed to learn an internal model of the likelihood of each colour given their choice of container, and combine this with their knowledge of explosion probabilities to determine the best option on each trial. This therefore constitutes an "inverted" variant of the original task; in the original task participants are provided with the transition probabilities but must learn the rewards associated with the second stage states, whereas here they are given the rewards but must learn the transition probabilities.</p><p>We also included trials to assess implicit confidence in task structure. Participants were presented with an array of asteroids that they could target. Those on the left were purple, while those on the right were pink, and each carried a number of bonus points. If the colour of the ball they fired matched the colour of the asteroid they would gain that number of points, while they would lose these points if it did not match. Thus, if they were more confident in the probability of getting a given ball colour, they should aim for a ball with a higher potential value. The scale of these outcomes varied according to varying multipliers across different trials, allowing us to account for effects of incentives on confidence ratings <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(40)</ref>.</p><p>Finally, we included a set of trials where information about ball colour was concealed (described to participants as "broken" trials), prompting participants to guess which containers held "good" balls. The purpose of this was to heighten uncertainty about the task structure by removing information about ball colour for a period.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Original cannon blast task</head><p>We collected data in the replication sample using the original "Cannon Blast" task ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1A)</ref>, described in detail elsewhere (3), to determine correspondence of measures across related tasks. This task followed a similar pattern to the standard trials of the modified version, whereby participants were tasked with firing cannonballs with the goal of hitting an alien. However, in this version participants were given the task structure via pink/purple cannonballs shown within the ball containers according to their probability (70% and 30% purple in left and right respectively), but were required to learn the value of the pink and purple balls (i.e., their value). Given prior results demonstrating recoverability of behavioursymptom relationships with brief versions of the task(3), our version used 75 trials. Outcome probabilities were similar to those used in the original task ("drift A" in the original paper).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Questionnaire measures Symptom measures</head><p>We measured three transdiagnostic factors identified in prior work (4): anxious-depression (AD), compulsivity and intrusive thought (CIT), and social withdrawal (SW). These factors have been linked to behaviours including model-based decision-making (4), metacognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(24)</ref>, and aversive learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(15)</ref>.</p><p>Following our prior work, we used a subset of items from the original measures to predict the true scores <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">36,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">37)</ref>. In addition, we measured state depression and anxiety using the Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ)(41) and the Generalised Anxiety Disorder assessment (GAD-7)(42).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Computational modelling Model definitions</head><p>To provide a mechanistic account of participants' behaviour in the task, we designed computational models of the processes underpinning learning about task structure. These models built on our prior work using approximately Bayesian learning strategies <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">20)</ref> to learn a probability distribution over a given outcome. A significant strength of these models is their ability to estimate uncertainty during learning, and hence to provide individual-level estimates of participants' subjective uncertainty. These models were fit to all learning trials (including "broken" trials), excluding confidence trials.</p><p>At its core, the model is a "leaky" beta learning model <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(20)</ref>, so called because it estimates a probability of an outcome (for example, the probability of getting a purple ball) using a beta distribution. This distribution is chosen as a result of it being bounded between 0 and 1, making it ideal for estimating a distribution over probabilities. The "leak" in the model refers to its capacity to lose a degree of the information it has acquired on each trial, ensuring that learned estimates account for recent information rather than relying strongly on old and potentially outdated observations. Formally, the model updates the two parameters of the beta distribution as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">+1 = (1 − ) ⋅ + ⋅ (1) +1 = (1 − ) ⋅ + ⋅ (1 − )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Here, and refer to the parameters of the beta distribution on a given trial . These effectively represent the degree of evidence for one of two outcomes (e.g., purple or pink balls when choosing the left container). The parameter is a decay parameter that determines the degree of leakiness (here, it is given as 1 − such that higher values more intuitively represent greater decay or leak). Finally, represents the update rate, which determines how much a given outcome influences the current estimates. The trial is coded as 0 or 1 (for example, purple may be coded as 1 and absence of purple -here, equivalent to the probability of pink -coded as 0).</p><p>The mean of this distribution (i.e., the current point probability estimate) can then be extracted as follows (using ( ) as an example of a probability being estimated):</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">= + (3)</formula><p>Where is the mean on a given trial. Similarly, we can extract the variance of the distribution as an index of uncertainty:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">2 = ⋅ ( + ) 2 ⋅ ( + + 1)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>Where 2 is the variance on a given trial.</p><p>We used this approach to learn both the task structure (probability of purple or pink balls) and the modelfree value estimate for the left and right ball containers (i.e., the probability of explosion for each).</p><p>This provides two potential sets of and parameters, depending on the model used. The first represents learned transition probabilities ( and ), which are updated according to Eq.1 and Eq.2, where the is observing a purple ball, and from which we can derive summary statistics and 2 . This distribution is updated according to update and decay parameters (see Eq.1 and Eq.2) specific to transition learning: and .</p><p>The second represents learned model-free value ( and ), where represents a nonexploding ball, and from which we can derive summary statistics and 2 . This distribution is updated according to update and decay parameters that are specific to model-free value learning:</p><p>and .</p><p>We then used these building blocks to construct three different models: 1) Model-free only, where</p><p>decisions are based on model-free value alone; 2) Model-based only, where decisions are not influence by model-free value; and 3) Combined model-based and model-free with weighting, where these two estimates are combined based on their relative uncertainties, with the combination skewed in favour of one model according to an additional weighting parameter.</p><p>Model based value ( ) was calculated as the conjunction of the learned beta distribution over ( ) and the scalar ( | ), which was shown on screen, ensuring that model-based value was estimated as a full distribution that accounted for uncertainty in the learned task structure.</p><p>We achieved this by first calculating the mean ( ) and variance ( 2 ) of the new beta distribution based on the mean ( ) and variance ( 2 ) of the distribution over ( ):</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">= ⋅ ( | )<label>(5)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">2 = 2 ⋅ ( | ) 2<label>(6)</label></formula><p>And then converting these values to the and parameters of a new beta distribution:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">= × ( × (1 − ) 2 − 1) (7) = (1 − ) × ( × (1 − ) 2 − 1)<label>(8)</label></formula><p>Note that this approach is an approximation and does not correctly estimate all moments of the resulting distribution (this would require the calculation of a truncated beta distribution). However, it does accurately estimate the mean and variance which is sufficient for these models.</p><p>We then calculate the total value of each option based on the summed model-based value accounting for purple and pink outcomes, as while the probabilities of these outcomes were complementary (and the model assumed this), the explosion probabilities were not. Again, this was computed using full distributions to retain information about the uncertainty of each option using an approximation for summing beta distributions <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(43)</ref>, whereby the means and variances of ( ∩ | ) and ( ∩ | ) were summed and then converted back into the and parameters of a new beta distribution to provide a single beta distribution representing the model -based value of each option.</p><p>For the model combining model-based and model-free strategies, we then calculated a weighted average of the distributions representing model-based and model-free value for each of the two options by averaging the two parameters of the beta distribution and :</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">= ( ⋅ ) + (1 − ⋅ )<label>(9)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">= ( ⋅ ) + (1 − ⋅ )</formula><p>Here, represents a weighting parameter that determines the contribution of model-based and modelfree computations (note that the and parameters refer to the parameters of the respective beta distributions for model-based and model-free value, as described in Eq.1 and Eq.2). We can then derive the point expected value for left and right options ( and ℎ respectively) by simply taking the mean of this distribution (see Eq. 3).</p><p>Finally, point expected value estimates were converted to choice probabilities based on the difference in values between the two options, with a free temperature parameter determining choice stochasticity. For example, for the right option:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">= ℎ − (10) = 1<label>(11)</label></formula><p>( ℎ ) = = ∑ <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(12)</ref> This resulted in up to 5 free parameters, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. In addition, we extracted the mean variance of task structure probability estimates for further analyses, providing an index of participants' general level of reducible uncertainty. Finally, we calculated the difference in model fit between the pure modelbased and model-free models to provide an index of model-basedness. Weighting of model-free and model-based contributions 3</p><p>Our modelling approach provides three key parameters: The update rate ( ) reflects the extent to the perceived likelihood of a given outcome is increased when it is observed. The average uncertainty is derived by averaging the variance of the estimated probability distribution over outcomes across the task. Finally, we derive a measure of model-basedness by subtracting the fit (represented by WAIC scores) of a pure model-free model from that of a pure model-based model for each participant, providing a metric representing how closely participants' behaviour reflects the use of a model -based strategy relative to a model-free strategy; this provides a single measure of model-basedness for simplicity, but we additionally conduct exploratory analyses on its component parts. While other parameters feature in the model, we only focus on those relevant to our primary hypotheses.</p><p>For comparison, we also tested three equivalent models using a Rescorla-Wagner learning rule rather than the approximately Bayesian Beta learning rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(44)</ref>. These models followed the same principles, learning model-free value estimates and transition probabilities and then optionally combining these to determine expected value, but updated estimates (whether value or probability) according to a weighted prediction error:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">+1 = + ( − )</formula><p>Where is a learning rate. Learning rates were specified separately for reward and probability learning components, resulting in two parameters and . Model free value was learned separately for left and right options, while model-based value was calculated by multiplying the transition probabilities (i.e., the probability of the left and right options leading to pink and purple balls) by the indicated reward value of each ball colour.</p><p>While the Beta learning models combined model-free value estimates and model-based estimates based on their approximate distributions, the Rescorla-Wagner models rely on point estimates and so the combined expected value was computed as follows for each of the left and right options:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">= ( ⋅ ) + (1 − ⋅ )</formula><p>Model fitting</p><p>Models were fit using simulation-based inference (SBI), implemented using the BayesFlow package <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(45)</ref>.</p><p>The SBI method involves generating simulated datasets based on the specified models and then training a neural network to learn a mapping between data (i.e., choices on each trial) and parameters used to generate the data. This model can then be applied to real participants' data and used to estimate posterior distributions over model parameters accurately. Specifically, our model used masked autoregressive flows <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">47)</ref> to learn this mapping based on 500,000 simulated datasets. Details of parameter and model recovery are provided in the Supplement. For the purpose of comparison, we also estimated optimal parameter values for our winning model (i.e., those that led to the highest probability of choosing the best option on every trial). This was done using the Adam algorithm implemented in Optax (https://github.com/google-deepmind/optax).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analyses of original Cannon Blast task behaviour</head><p>The original Cannon Blast task was analysed using the logistic regression approach described in prior papers <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">25)</ref>. Briefly, this involved predicting the probability of a participant staying with their prior choice or switching to the alternative based on whether the outcome of the previous trial was rewarded or not, whether the transition (here, the ball colour) was common or rare, and the interaction between these two factors. The intuition behind this method is that a model-based account predicts participants will switch when receiving a rare rewarded outcome or a common unrewarded outcome, and stay when receiving a common rewarded outcome or rare unrewarded outcome. The level of model-basedness can thus be quantified by the strength of the interaction between the rewarded/unrewarded and common/rare factors.</p><p>Following prior work demonstrating improved reliability of these estimates using hierarchical approaches (19), we estimated parameters using a trial-wise Bayesian hierarchical logistic regression model implemented in Bambi (https://bambinos.github.io/bambi/), sampled with 4 chains of 10000 samples (2000 warmup, 8000 samples). Interaction terms for each participant were then extracted for further analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Statistical analysis</head><p>Test-retest reliability analyses</p><p>We quantified test-retest reliability and longer-term stability using intraclass correlations <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(48)</ref>. We used consistency ICCs (also known as ICC(3, 1)), which estimate reliability based on the rank order of the observations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Modelling of confidence ratings</head><p>We verified that the quantities derived from the model were meaningfully related to participant's behaviour on the task by establishing that confidence ratings predicted by different types of uncertainty as quantified by our model. We assessed this by constructing Bayesian hierarchical trial-wise regression models predicting ratings on confidence trials from two types of model-derived uncertainty: irreducible uncertainty (i.e., the outcome probability, where a value of 0.5 represents maximum uncertainty and 0 or 1 represent minimum uncertainty), and reducible uncertainty (i.e., the variance of the distribution over this probability estimate).</p><p>We first constructed a simple model predicting subjects' choice of pink or purple asteroids based on the model-predicted probability of getting a pink or purple ball, using the following regression formula specification:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">ℎ ~ 1 + ( ) + 1| + ( ) |</formula><p>This enabled us to first verify that participants' choices on confidence trials were in line with what the model would predict.</p><p>Next, we constructed a more complex model designed to determine how confidence ratings were influenced by different types of model-derived uncertainty. This included both reducible uncertainty (the variance of the distribution over ( ), referred to as (</p><p>) and irreducible uncertainty (| ( ) − 0.5|, i.e., how far away the estimated probability is from 0.5) as predictors. We also included trial number to account for linear trends across the task, in addition to the scaling of the outcome values on a given trial, accounting for incentivisation effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(40)</ref>. This was specified as follows: Finally, we fit a simpler model that accounted for trial and scaling effects but not effects of uncertainty.</p><p>By extracting participant-level intercepts from this model, we were able to derive an index of each participant's average confidence that accounted for these factors but was still influenced by uncertainty for use in further analyses (referred to adjusted confidence). These were also fit using Bambi, with 4 chains of 10000 samples (2000 warmup). All variables were standardised (having mean of 0 and standard deviation of 1 at the group level) prior to analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Symptom-behaviour regression models</head><p>To identify relationships between symptom dimensions and behaviour, we used regression models predicting a given behavioural metric from the three symptom dimensions in addition to relevant covariates (age, gender, and self-reported task motivation; for analyses of confidence, we additionally included measures of task performance). Estimates of uncertainty ( 2 ) from the model were transformed as follows due to heavy skew:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">2 = 100 2<label>(13)</label></formula><p>Confidence intervals and resulting p-values were estimated non-parametrically using bootstrapping with 20,000 samples, Bonferroni corrected for multiple comparisons across three primary dependent.</p><p>Models predicting other variables were treated as exploratory and results are reported without multiple comparison correction. All models were constructed and estimated using the Statsmodels package for Python (https://www.statsmodels.org) alongside custom scripts. Multicollinearity was assessed using the variable inflation factor (VIF) and condition number of the design matrix, and in each case diagnostics were within the satisfactory range (VIF &lt; 10, condition number &lt; 30).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mediation analysis</head><p>We further probed relationships between symptoms and behaviour using mediation analysis. This was used to provide evidence that the observed association between the CIT factor and use of model -based decision-making was mediated by uncertainty. We estimated both the direct (CIT &gt; model-basedness) and indirect effects (CIT &gt; uncertainty &gt; model-basedness) <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(49)</ref> to provide an indication of the strength of any mediation effect. Mediation analyses were conducted using the Pingouin package for Python (https://pingouin-stats.org), with path significance and confidence intervals estimated using bootstrapping with 20000 samples.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Longitudinal analyses</head><p>In order to determine whether changes over time in behaviour were associated with changes in symptoms, we performed regression analyses predicting changes in parameter values from changes in symptoms, alongside changes in self-reported motivation and baseline parameter values. Age and gender were also included as covariates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preregistration</head><p>For our replication study, we preregistered the primary hypotheses and methods based on results from the discovery sample (https://osf.io/52awb). These pertained to analyses predicting three core behavioural metrics (model-basedness, uncertainty about task structure, and transition update rate) based on transdiagnostic symptoms and state depression/anxiety.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>irreducible (discovery β = 0.06, 95% HDI=[0.03, 0.09]; replication β = 0.07, 95% HDI=[0.05, 0.09]; Figure 3D) and reducible uncertainty (discovery β = -0.17, 95% HDI=[-0.23, -0.11]; replication β = -0.09, 95% HDI=[-0.14, -0.05];</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Sample. A) Age distribution across both samples. The point above represents the mean, with the error bars showing the standard deviation. B) PHQ-8 scores across both samples. The dashed line represents a cutoff for identifying clinically-significant depression (22), while the shaded area represents the distribution of scores above this cutoff. C) GAD-7 scores across both samples. The dashed line represents a cutoff for identifying clinically-significant generalised anxiety disorder (23). D) Illustration of sample sizes for discovery (disc.) and replication (rep.) samples at different time points. E) Age and gender in the discovery sample across multiple time points. The points and error bars represent mean and standard error of participants' ages. The pie charts represent the proportion of male (shaded) and female (unshaded) participants. F) Participants' scores on the task in the replication sample as a function of trial. The shaded area represents the standard error. PHQ-8 = Patient Health Questionnaire 8-item; GAD-7 = Generalized Anxiety Disorder Questionnaire 7item.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Computational modelling. A) Model comparison results for the discovery sample, showing WAIC scores for each model (higher scores = better fit). Fit is shown for two family of models: beta models that represent uncertainty, and Rescorla-Wagner (RW) models that do not. The winning model is highlighted in blue. B) Model comparison results for the replication sample. The winning model is highlighted in pink. C) Best-fitting model for every participant in both samples. D) Regression coefficients from a Bayesian hierarchical model predicting implicit confidence ratings from model -derived irreducible and reducible certainty metrics. Note that the direction of the reducible uncertainty (derived from the variance) effect has been reversed for illustrative purposes such that greater uncertainty predicts lower confidence. E) Associations between age and reducible uncertainty across both samples. WAIC = Watanabe-Akaike Information Criterion; SE = standard error; MB = model-based; MF = model-free; weight = parameterised weighting of MB and MF. HDI = highest density interval; a.u. = arbitrary units.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Associations between task behaviour and symptoms. A) Results from regression models predicting behavioural metrics (indicated by the title above each panel) from symptoms (shown on the x-axes) across both samples. The points represent the regression coefficient, while the error bars represent 95% confidence intervals (estimated using bootstrapping). The sub-panel shows the results of exploratory analyses predicting individual model-based and modelfree metrics. Stars above the points represent statistical significance, corrected for multiple comparisons. The top row represents analyses of transdiagnostic symptom dimensions, while the bottom row represents analyses of anxiety and depression symptoms. B) Results from regression models predicting model-basedness as assessed by the original cannon blast task (3) from both transdiagnostic dimensions (left) and state anxiety and depression (right). AD = anxiety and depression. C) Results of a mediation model testing mediation of the CIT &gt; model-basedness association by uncertainty about task structure. D) Results of a mediation model testing mediation of the PHQ-8 &gt; model-basedness association by uncertainty about task structure. Values represent regression weights ( ) and confidence intervals (estimated using bootstrapping); CIT = compulsivity and intrusive thought; SW = social withdrawal; PHQ-8 = Patient Health Questionnaire 8-item; GAD-7 = Generalized Anxiety Disorder Questionnaire 7-item; MB = model-basedness; * = p &lt; .05; ** = p &lt; .01; *** = p &lt; .001.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Longitudinal results. A) Relationships between transdiagnostic symptom dimensions at baseline and both 3 month and 1 year follow up. B) Relationships between task behaviour at baseline and both 3 month and 1 year follow up. Model-basedness scores are transformed for ease of interpretation ( = 0.3 ). C) Results from regression models predicting change (represented by Δ) in behavioural metrics across the follow-up period from change in symptom scores (top) and state anxiety and depression (bottom), controlling for baseline scores. The points represent the regression coefficient, while the error bars represent 95% confidence intervals (estimated using bootstrapping). D) Participants' scores on the task across the three time points. AD = anxiety and depression; CIT = compulsivity and intrusive thought; SW = social withdrawal; PHQ-8 = Patient Health Questionnaire 8-item; GAD-7 = Generalized Anxiety Disorder Questionnaire 7-item.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Demographic characteristics of the samples. Note that demographic data was not available for the 2 week followup sample due to a technical error.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Sample</cell><cell>Sample size</cell><cell>Age (mean [SD])</cell><cell>Gender (male / female)</cell></row><row><cell>Discovery</cell><cell>551</cell><cell>40.75 [12.32]</cell><cell>275 / 276</cell></row><row><cell>3 month follow-up</cell><cell>385</cell><cell>41.80 [12.39]</cell><cell>198 / 187</cell></row><row><cell>1 year follow-up</cell><cell>326</cell><cell>43.78 [12.22]</cell><cell>172 / 154</cell></row><row><cell>Replication</cell><cell>1322</cell><cell>41.15 [12.69]</cell><cell>655 / 667</cell></row><row><cell>2 week follow-up</cell><cell>80</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Test retest reliability and stability estimates for model parameters and extracted values over 2 week, 3 month, and 1 year intervals.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Interval</cell><cell>Sample size</cell><cell>Parameter</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">Descriptions of model parameters and extracted values. Models: 1) Pure model-free; 2) Pure model-based, 3)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Weighted combination of model-free and model-based.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Parameter</cell><cell>Description</cell><cell>Models</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Update rate for task structure learning</cell><cell>2, 3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Update rate for model-free value learning</cell><cell>1, 3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Decay rate for task structure learning</cell><cell>2, 3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Decay rate for model-free value learning</cell><cell>1, 3</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Softmax temperature</cell><cell>1, 2, 3</cell></row></table><note></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was supported by a Wellcome Trust Career Development Award to TW (225945/Z/22/Z).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data and code availability</head><p>Code and data to reproduce the analyses described here are available at https://github.com/the-wiselab/transition-learning-public.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Model-based decision making and model-free learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Drummond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Niv</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="860" to="865" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying Transdiagnostic Mechanisms in Mental Health Using Computational Factor Modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="690" to="703" />
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using smartphones to optimise and scale-up the assessment of model-based planning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Donegan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Price</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gallagher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pringle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hanlon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Characterizing a psychiatric symptom dimension related to deficits in goal-directed control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kosinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Whelan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Phelps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11305</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Doubting what you already know: Uncertainty regarding state transitions is associated with obsessive compulsive symptoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Fradkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ludwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Eldar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Huppert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1007634</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Searching for an anchor in an unpredictable world: A computational model of obsessive compulsive disorder</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Fradkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Parr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Roiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Huppert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="672" to="699" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beliefs, compulsive behavior and reduced confidence in control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Rigoux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stephan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Petzschner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1012207</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shimojo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Doherty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Neural Computations Underlying Arbitration between Model -Based and Model-free Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="687" to="699" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Humans primarily use model-based inference in the two-stage task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Feher Da Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Hum Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1053" to="1066" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disrupted state transition learning as a computational marker of compulsivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sharp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Eldar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Model-Based Planning Deficits in Compulsivity Are Linked to Faulty Neural Representations of Task Structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Txf</forename><surname>Seow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Benoit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dempsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jennings</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Maxwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>O'connell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6539" to="6550" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Doubting what you already know: Uncertainty regarding state transitions is associated with obsessive compulsive symptoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Fradkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ludwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Eldar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Huppert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1007634</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smartphones and the Neuroscience of Mental Health</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rutledge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1146/annurev-neuro-101220-014053</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-neuro-101220-014053" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Taking Psychiatry Research Online</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Associations between aversive learning processes and transdiagnostic psychiatric symptoms in a general population sample</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Communications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4179</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Promises and challenges of human computational ethology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mobbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Suthana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Guzmán</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kriegeskorte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Leibo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2224" to="2238" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Naturalistic reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Emery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Radulescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2023.08.016</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2023.08.016" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Model-Based Influences on Humans&apos; Choices and Striatal Prediction Errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gershman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Seymour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neuron</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1204" to="1215" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving the Reliability of Computational Analyses: Model-Based Planning and Its Relationship With Compulsivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Price</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychiatry: Cognitive Neuroscience and Neuroimaging</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="601" to="609" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A computational account of threat-related attentional bias</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Michely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Comput Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1007341</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Guideline of Selecting and Reporting Intraclass Correlation Coefficients for Reliability Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Koo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Chiropr Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="163" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Equivalency of the diagnostic accuracy of the PHQ-8 and PHQ-9: a systematic review and individual participant data metaanalysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Levis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Riehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Saadat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Levis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Azar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1368" to="1380" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Brief Measure for Assessing Generalized Anxiety Disorder: The GAD-7</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spitzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kroenke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jbw</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Löwe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Archives of Internal Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">166</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1092" to="1097" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychiatric Symptom Dimensions Are Associated With Dissociable Shifts in Metacognition but Not Task Performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rouault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Seow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fleming</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="451" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparison of the Association Between Goal-Directed Planning and Self-reported Compulsivity vs Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder Diagnosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kalanthroff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Weingarden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jacoby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gershkovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JAMA Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compulsivity Is Linked to Maladaptive Choice Variability but Unaltered Reinforcement Learning under Uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rouault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Wyart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1101/2023.01.05.522867</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1101/2023.01.05.522867" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Animal Behavior and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The construction and use of cognitive maps in model -based control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Karagoz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Reagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Kool</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">153</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="372" to="385" />
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zorowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Momennejad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Daw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Anxiety, Avoidance, and Sequential Evaluation. Computational Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Model-based aversive learning in humans is supported by preferential task state reactivation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Chowdhury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9616</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Peril, prudence and planning as risk, avoidance and worry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gagne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mathematical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">102617</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anxiety involves altered planning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sharp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tics.2024.11.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2024.11.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in Cognitive Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gambling on the unconscious: A comparison of wagering and confidence ratings as measures of awareness in an artificial grammar task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Dienes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Seth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Consciousness and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="674" to="681" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does cognitive-behavioral therapy affect goal-directed planning in obsessive-compulsive disorder?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Wheaton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychiatry Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">273</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="94" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mcdonogh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Donegan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hanlon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gallagher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rouault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/c5abx</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/c5abx" />
		<title level="m">Reliable, rapid, and remote measurement of metacognitive bias</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023-11-17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transdiagnostic Phenotyping Reveals a Host of Metacognitive Deficits Implicated in Compulsivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Txf</forename><surname>Seow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2883</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Optimising the measurement of anxious-depressive, compulsivity and intrusive thought and social withdrawal transdiagnostic symptom dimensions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Hopkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sidarus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/q83sh</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/q83sh" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022-09-29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reducing the Burden of Psychological Questionnaire Measures Through Selective Item Re-Weighting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sidarus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31234/osf.io/vwmkd</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/vwmkd" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2024-10-22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prolific.ac-A subject pool for online experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Palan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Schitter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zorowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Solis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Niv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Inattentive responding can induce spurious associations between task behaviour and symptom measures</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Hum Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1667" to="1681" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two sides of the same coin: Monetary incentives concurrently improve and bias confidence judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lebreton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Langdon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Slieker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Nooitgedacht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Goudriaan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Denys</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">668</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The PHQ-9</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kroenke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spitzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jbw</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of General Internal Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="606" to="613" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Brief Measure for Assessing Generalized Anxiety Disorder: The GAD-7</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spitzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kroenke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jbw</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Löwe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Archives of Internal Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">166</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1092" to="1097" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reliability of a standby system with beta-distributed component lives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Turkkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Reliability</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="75" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of Pavlovian conditioning: Variations in the effectiveness of reinforcement and nonreinforcement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rescorla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Others</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Classical conditioning II: Current research and theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="99" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schmitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Schumacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Elsemüller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Pratz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Schälte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.48550/arXiv.2306.16015</idno>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2306.16015</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2306.16015" />
		<title level="m">BayesFlow: Amortized Bayesian Workflows With Neural Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023-07-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Papamakarios</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Pavlakou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.48550/arXiv.1705.07057</idno>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1705.07057</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1705.07057" />
		<title level="m">Masked Autoregressive Flow for Density Estimation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-06-14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Greenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Nonnenmacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Macke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1905.07488</idno>
		<title level="m">Automatic Posterior Transformation for Likelihood-Free Inference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-05-17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.48550/arXiv.1905.07488</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1905.07488" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Weir</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">QUANTIFYING TEST-RETEST RELIABILITY USING THE INTRACLASS CORRELATION COEFFICIENT AND THE SEM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">231</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">mediation: R package for causal mediation analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tingley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Yamamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hirose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Keele</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Imai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://dspace.mit.edu/handle/1721.1/91154" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">UCLA Statistics/American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-01-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
